Welcome everyone to today's TerraTalk.
Today we are very honored to invite Dr. Liao Ying to talk about his research.
Today's topic is Mission ACE.
Before we start, let me briefly introduce Dr. Liao Ying.
Dr. Liao Ying graduated from the University of Bern, Switzerland.
Dr. Liao Ying specializes in space and astrophysics.
He is currently a professor at Tsinghua University,
teaching space exploration theory and practice.
Our tradition is to mute everyone,
so that the speech will be more smooth.
But before we start, please unmute yourself,
so that the speaker can hear our applause.
Let's welcome today's speaker with a round of applause.
Thank you.
I will probably speak a little faster.
Let me briefly introduce myself.
My master's degree is in astrophysics.
After that, I went to Switzerland to study.
We are still in the physics institute.
Our school has three branches.
One of the branches is called Space Science and Planetary Research.
In Chinese, it stands for 太空與新興科學.
The entire branch focuses on things like NASA and JPL.
I did a two-year postdoc at the University of Macau.
Then I came back to Taiwan for COVID-19.
I have been teaching at Tsinghua University since last year.
I teach space exploration theory and practice.
I teach in English.
Tsinghua University does not teach space science,
so I thought this would be a good place to start.
I am interested in solar systems,
such as comets, asteroids,
and space mission design.
In 2019, I took part in a competition called
CubeSat Mission Design Contest.
I am interested in space mission design.
I saw the competition in early 2019,
so I decided to take part in it.
I found two of my teammates.
We designed a mission together.
We were lucky to win first place.
Since then, I have been doing research on space mission design.
I can't say it is a rigorous research.
The topic I am going to talk about today is still a proposal.
My name is Ace.
It is a very preliminary proposal.
If you know a little bit about space mission design,
space mission design is very complicated.
It requires a lot of manpower and time to do different things.
I will explain it later.
This is a proposal from our team.
This is for another international space mission design competition,
Mission Idea Contest.
This is a proposal for this competition.
We advanced to the finals, but we did not win.
I would like to briefly explain Mission Idea Contest.
It is an international space mission design competition.
It is organized by a non-profit organization called Unisec.
It is a non-profit organization.
It is organized by universities around the world.
Each country has a local chapter.
Taiwan has a local chapter.
Professor Zhuang is in charge of it.
This competition is held once a year.
There are three stages in this competition.
The first stage is to vote.
After the judges have finished voting,
they will enter the next stage.
The next stage is to develop the paper into a complete one.
The last stage is to submit a verbal report.
After submitting the verbal report,
the judges will choose two candidates.
This competition is quite tough.
The judges are mostly professors.
Sometimes they invite a few people from the company.
We had a host of the competition that year.
Their judges are very strict.
I recommend this competition.
The judges are different every year.
The topic of 2019 is to design an experiment at ISS.
2020 and 2021 are being held.
2020 is scheduled to be postponed for a year.
This is the Deep Space Mission we participated in last year.
The definition of deep space is
the space beyond the moon.
However, they also included the mission of the moon in the Deep Space.
So, you can design a space ship to go to the moon.
This year and next year,
we will return to the Earth orbit mission design.
This is a 6U cube satellite design.
However, it requires a constellation.
You can send a lot of stars at once.
They will have different positions.
It's a bit like GPS satellites.
This is a link.
If you are interested in space mission design,
you can go to their website.
Their website is complete.
Last year, they had a talk.
Deep Space Mission Design is a difficult topic.
They had a talk with professors from the University of Tokyo.
They recorded the talk and posted it on their website.
They also posted some PDFs.
You can check them out.
I would like to talk about the background of space mission design.
First, you need to know about the spacecraft.
Spacecraft is the soul of space mission design.
I'm sorry.
I'm not used to speaking in Chinese.
I usually speak in English.
So, I might speak slowly or pause.
This is a picture of a simple and powerful spacecraft.
This is a picture of the spacecraft.
This is the attitude control.
This is the power.
This is the internal computer.
This is the command.
This is the communication.
This is the structure of the body.
This is the orbit.
You can connect the spacecraft to humans.
For example, the computer is like our brain.
Our brain receives, processes, and releases various commands.
We have a body.
Our body is the head and limbs.
Communication is like our speech, gestures, and eyes.
Power is like food.
Everyone uses a rough metaphor.
It's called understanding space.
Use freedom as a metaphor.
There are six main functions.
The first one is the body part.
In English, we call it the body.
This is a spaceship or a satellite.
In English, we call it a frame.
In English, we call it a cube.
In English, we call it cmdh.
In English, we call it at2.
In English, we call it eps.