Welcome to the Taira Talk.
Taira stands for Taiwanese Young Researchers Association.
This is an area for young researchers in Taiwan.
We hold the Taira Talk almost every week.
The format of the talk is very free and diverse.
We hope that Taiwan's academic researchers
can share their talk or practice online
according to their own needs.
The topic of the next two weeks
will be more on astronomy.
On July 2nd,
Liao Ying, a post-doctorate student from Central University,
will share a topic on planetary science.
On July 9th,
Lian Chuan-Ping, a post-doctorate student from University of Colorado Boulder,
will share a topic on high-altitude wind turbines.
This is a topic on aerospace and mechanical engineering.
Today, we are very happy to invite
Professor Wang Shu-Ha, a post-doctorate student from Taiwan University.
Professor Wang is interested in
privacy, immigration, children and family well-being.
These topics will be covered in today's talk.
The topic of today's talk is
Social Safety Net Feature in East Asia.
Julia, you can share your screen now.
Let me turn off my sharing.
Sorry.
Can you see me clearly now?
Yes.
Can you hear my children crying?
Not yet.
That's good.
Can I start now?
Let's give a round of applause.
This is a small tradition of Taira.
Please turn on the microphone
and give a round of applause to welcome Julia.
Thank you.
Thank you, Theta, for inviting me to share my research with you.
Thank you, Theta, for your detailed introduction.
Today, I will talk about
the social welfare network
and its features in East Asia.
We will cover the situation before and after COVID-19 pandemic.
I know that many of you
may not know much about social welfare.
Let me give you a brief introduction.
Social welfare can be divided into three areas,
including social insurance, social assistance, and welfare services.
Social insurance is a risk factor in our lives.
Many countries use insurance to deal with it.
However, there are also many countries that do not use insurance.
In Taiwan, we have a social insurance system
for pensioners.
Employment insurance also includes unemployment insurance.
National Insurance is also a social insurance feature.
We need to contribute so that we can benefit in the future.
Another part is social assistance.
In some cases,
everyone may face risks.
For example, if you become very poor and unemployed,
and your job does not allow you to have social insurance,
or if you encounter some changes in your family,
you may need social assistance,
including low-income households and middle-income households.
In the U.S., we have food stamps,
which are food-related relief measures.
In the U.S., Section 8 of the Housing Assistance Act
uses housing vouchers to help people.
There is also public housing in Taiwan.
In addition, there are also measures to help families
who cannot afford to send their children to school.
In addition to social assistance,
there are also welfare services.
For example,
child abuse or elderly care services
may be needed.
Whether it's public or private,
welfare services are provided by welfare agencies.
So the social welfare sector is mostly related to Hanguas.
I will focus on the social assistance sector today.
In the introduction of the document,
we often compare the social insurance and social assistance
in the East Asian welfare system.
In the East Asian welfare system,
we often compare the social insurance and social assistance.
I will explain the terms first.
The research I am going to share today
was initiated in 2019
by Dr. Ying-Ho Khoo.
Dr. Ying-Ho Khoo was invited by the National University of Seoul
to give a lecture at their school.
Dr. Ying-Ho Khoo hopes to have more international cooperation.
I think organizing research teams
is a bit like making a movie.
In my mind,
I want to do the research I am going to report in the future.
However, it takes a lot of resources
to gather all the party members from all over the world.
After this meeting,
Dr. Ying-Ho Khoo is a professor at Tokyo University in Japan.
Dr. Ying-Ho Khoo is interested in Korea.
I invited Dr. Irene from the National University of Singapore
and Dr. Chen Hong and Dr. Zhao Hsieh
from the National University of Singapore.
We organized a research team to study six places in East Asia,
including Taiwan, China, Hong Kong,
Japan, South Korea, and Singapore.
We organized a research team to study six places in Taiwan, China, Hong Kong, Japan, South Korea, and Singapore.
We relate to projects on Taiwan, China and Hong Kong.
We will compare and analyze tests on the six places we study.
There are thirty buildings with shrines in the north along theheir names.
There are twenty buildings with shrines in the north along their names.
We will compare and analyze tests on the these buildings together.
American Community Survey Aand Census Bureau,
American Community Survey,