Hello everyone, welcome to Taira Talk. Taira is an event for young researchers in Taiwan. We hold some Taira Talks every week all year round, which includes everything from liberal arts to science, engineering, biology, medicine, etc.
If you would like to share your research in the future, please feel free to sign up.
Today's speaker is Lian Chuan-Ping, and his topic is the relationship between high-level atmospheric wind turbines and their relationship with space weather.
Lian Chuan-Ping is a Ph.D. student in the Department of Aerospace and Space Sciences at Colorado University.
His field of research is data synchronization, electromagnetic transfer, and solar eclipses.
In addition to his research, he also enjoys hiking, jogging, and watching movies at home.
I'll hand over to Chuan-Ping.
Hello everyone, I'm Lian Chuan-Ping.
Today's speaker's topic is the relationship between high-level atmospheric wind turbines and their relationship with space weather.
Today, I will focus on the reason why we want to conduct high-level atmospheric wind turbines.
First of all, this is my background.
My major focus is on space weather forecast.
The method I use is data synchronization.
The solar weather we are targeting is the daily change of the electromagnetic force of the Earth's magnetic field.
We can understand it as a type of space weather.
Later, I will introduce in detail what type of space weather it is.
This is our main topic for today.
First, we will introduce what space weather is and its definition.
Then, we will talk about what type of space weather we want to forecast,
why we want to forecast this system, and how to forecast it.
Finally, we will talk about the difficulties and challenges we encounter.
These are the reasons why we conduct high-level atmospheric wind turbines.
First, what is space weather?
Space weather refers to the daily change of the interaction between the matter in space and the atmosphere on Earth.
Basically, we can understand it as the so-called weather.
In this study, we focus on the low-middle latitude electromagnetic layer of the Earth.
Its height is approximately at the boundary of the Earth's high-level atmosphere and space.
In order to forecast this system, we must first understand the composition of the high-level atmosphere.
This graph shows the height of the Earth's surface.
The middle axis is the height, and the horizontal axis is the density of gas particles.
The blue and black lines indicate the change of electromagnetic particles in height.
The orange line is the so-called middle atmosphere.
For example, it may be the part of oxygen molecules, nitrogen molecules, or oxygen atoms.
We can clearly see in this graph that the density of the middle atmosphere is much higher than the so-called electromagnetic density.
And the higher the number is, we can see that the horizontal axis is a difference of tens of times or more than tens of times or more than tens of times.
In such a high-level atmosphere, the electromagnetic layer is not very uniform.
We can observe the so-called electromagnetic irregularity, or the phenomenon of an equatorial plasma bubble.
This is one of the types of space weather we want to forecast.
The graph on the left is a wet map, and the red part represents the more electromagnetic density.
The blue part represents an area with relatively less electromagnetic density.
The graph on the right is a high-level area of about 200 to 400 kilometers.
This is a high-level area.
As for its three-dimensional structure, we can see that the graph on the left is a simulation of an electromagnetic bubble.
The three axes on the left are the height, the diameter, and the latitude.
The yellow part represents an area with relatively more electromagnetic density.
The blue part represents an area with relatively less electromagnetic density.
The so-called electromagnetic bubble develops along a cone-shaped area.
The cone-shaped area is the magnetic field of the Earth's magnetic field.
If we cut down from the magnetic field of the Earth, we can see that the so-called electromagnetic bubble is a high-level area that looks like a bubble.
If we look down from space, we will find that the area with relatively less electromagnetic density is a cone-shaped area.
This is an actual observation.
The time period is November and December 2019.
The red area represents an area with relatively more electromagnetic density.
The so-called dark area is the area where the electromagnetic bubble occurs.
The interesting thing is that it sometimes occurs and sometimes does not occur.
The video on the right shows the so-called electromagnetic bubble change every day.
We can understand it as the so-called space weather.
We can see that this dark area sometimes does not occur and sometimes does occur.
Why do we want to forecast it?
The main reason is that the U.S. government has proposed a policy related to space weather preparation.
It was released in 2015 and was updated in 2019.
Because of this policy, the U.S. military began to focus on space weather forecasts and space weather-related research.
One of the reasons is that the military relies on the wireless communications system.
When we just mentioned the irregularity of the power line or the electromagnetic bubble, the signal will be reduced or flashed.
This is why we want to carry out space weather forecasts.
In addition to the observations we just mentioned, we can also use the Formosa Satellite-7 satellite that Taiwan and the United States have cooperated with to observe the electromagnetic bubble.
This satellite has several satellites, so it can carry out a relatively wide coverage rate in space to observe the electromagnetic bubble.
Each satellite is equipped with a global navigation satellite system receiver.
This satellite can receive signals from GPS or GNSS global satellite systems.
We all know that when a radio wave or light passes through an interface, it creates a distortion phenomenon.
The so-called radio occupation observation is to use this principle to carry out a high-level observation of the power line to predict the area and location of the electromagnetic bubble.
The image on the right shows a relatively high-level global navigation satellite system receiver.
When the radio wave or light passes through an interface, it creates a distortion phenomenon.
We use this distortion phenomenon to predict the area and location of the electromagnetic bubble.
The image on the left shows the so-called high-level distortion phenomenon mentioned in this study.
The so-called high-level distortion phenomenon is to use this principle to carry out a high-level observation of the power line to predict the area and location of the electromagnetic bubble.
Usually, we assume that the location of such an interface is on the line of the electric wave and the curve of the ball.
We use this principle to predict the area and location of the electromagnetic bubble or the irregularity of the electromagnetic layer.
Next, we need to think about how to predict the system and the characteristics of the system.
When we predict a system, the most important thing is the so-called error.
We want to use error or probability to express the reliability of our prediction.
But we don't want this error to be too big or too small.
We want this error to be in a more moderate range.
It can change at any time, but we basically don't want it to happen on the right.
One of the phenomena is that you can see the error.
The width represents the error.
We don't want this error to spread more and more to a situation of infinite magnitude.
Or we don't want this error to get closer and closer to a fixed value as time goes by.
This is easy to understand.
For example, the following situation.
If the error is getting smaller and smaller as time goes by, we don't have to predict it.
Because it will become a fixed value.
So we don't have to predict the necessity of such a system.
In short, we want the system we want to predict.
The error will not be too big or too small as time goes by.
Then we think about how to predict.
In our research, the method we use is the so-called data assimilation.
It uses statistics to combine observation and prediction to produce a initial condition.
Then the initial condition is digitally simulated to achieve the purpose of prediction.
Specifically, how do we use statistics to combine observation and prediction?
Specifically, we use Bayes' theorem to update our error.
The figure on the left shows what we will get after updating with Bayes' theorem.
The horizontal axis is the temperature and the vertical axis is the probability density.
We can see that the probability density function we provided at the beginning is relatively accurate after observation update.
In terms of probability, it is a relatively narrow probability distribution.
Through Bayes' theorem, we update such a probability density function.
We can get a more accurate and realistic probability density function.
The result shown is that we will get a relatively high probability density function.
The next thing we want to think about is how to predict.
Since we have updated our probability density function through observation,
How do we get the next time probability density function?
We basically use the probability density function we just got to sample the probability density function.
Then we do several digital simulations to achieve the purpose of prediction.
The most important thing we care about when we do prediction is the error and its average value.
Prediction is a function that calculates error or probability density.
Since this is a static situation, we encounter a lot of challenges.
Today, I will talk about how to connect our scientific problems to initial conditions.
This is what the weather forecast we know is doing.
It is to connect the problem to the initial condition problem.
Now I have two groups of experiments.
One group of experiments is the control group.
The other group of experiments is the contrast group.
I simulated the spring of 2009.
There are a lot of variables.
One of the variables is the initial condition.
This initial condition contains some information about the electric field and neutral atmosphere.
In this model, it will have the so-called low-level and low-level boundary conditions.
The main part is the neutral atmosphere.
Of course, there is also the source of energy, the input of solar energy and high-density energy.
Basically, in these two groups of experiments, the input of energy and the boundary conditions at the bottom are fixed.
The only difference is the initial condition.
The final result is that we have almost the same electromagnetic density distribution.
What does this mean?
It means that it implies the following result.
At first, there may be a big difference in the initial condition of this system.
However, as time goes by, this error will gradually be reduced to a fixed value.
In fact, this is not what we want to happen.
And this is different from the actual observation.
We just showed an image of the daily change of electromagnetic density over time.
You can see that it actually changes every day.
So, if we express this change in terms of probability, it will not be reduced to a stable state.
So, a very interesting phenomenon is that when we forecast electricity prices, we also have to consider the neutral atmosphere.
If we go back to the high-density ratio just now, this is actually a very easy-to-understand situation.
In fact, the density of the neutral atmosphere is much higher than the so-called electromagnetic density.
And this density is several times higher.
You can see that the unit below this is 10 to the 5th square, 10 to the 6th square, 10 to the 7th square, 10 to the 8th square.
This is several thousand times the difference.
So, this result implies that we also need to consider the neutral atmosphere while forecasting electricity prices.
This is also one of the reasons why we are working now.
At present, we are doing high-density atmospheric wind farm simulation.
The so-called high-density atmosphere is actually the boundary condition of the bottom layer of the model we just used.
It is about 97 kilometers high.
The initial idea of ​​this study is that we do not want the system we want to forecast to be close to a fixed value.
We do not want it to be close to the same state as time flows.
Because this is not quite in line with the daily changes in the electricity layer we observe.
The above is why I am doing my current doctoral research.
If you are interested, there are more detailed information on the website.
So, if you are interested, you can google this topic.
The above is the summary of my speech.
Forecasting has many things to be confirmed and completed.
I hope that we will be able to provide such a service in the future.
Just like our low-layer atmospheric weather forecast system.
I think this is a good long-term goal for a doctoral student.
The above is my report. Thank you.
I am Ming-Hsuan, the host.
Our current video is a recording.
If you have any questions, you can choose to ask during the recording.
At the same time, these videos will be uploaded to YouTube.
In addition, we can also discuss after the recording is turned off.
If you have any questions, please ask them now.
If you want to be recorded in the video.
If you don't have any questions, let's turn off the recording.