Welcome everyone to the Terra Talk on August 6th.
Today, we are honored to invite Dr. Chen Tai-Yan.
Dr. Chen Tai-Yan currently teaches at the Department of Chemistry at the University of Houston.
She graduated from the Department of Chemistry at Tsinghua University and the Department of Chemistry at Tsinghua University.
Her Ph.D. was in Texas A&M.
She did her Ph.D. in agricultural engineering.
After her Ph.D., she moved to Cornell.
Her field of research is mostly...
Did I say it right?
I saw Dr. Tai-Yan laughing.
Her field of research is mostly single-molecule super-resolution microscopy.
Her research system is mostly biophysics.
Dr. Tai-Yan is a very good teacher.
She has given lectures in different fields and topics at Terra.
Today, she will be talking about...
As a senior Ph.D. student,
when your Ph.D. is in its second or third year,
you have gone through a lot.
When you think about your next phase,
you have to prepare yourself.
You have to ask yourself some good questions.
This will allow you to move on to the next phase more smoothly.
Let's welcome Dr. Chen Tai-Yan.
Thank you, Dr. Tai-Yan.
I am very happy to be able to participate in Project Terra's talk today.
First of all, thanks for the kind invitation.
This talk is more informal.
If you have any questions,
you can ask them in the middle of my talk.
I hope you can learn a lot from today's talk.
This is a topic we talked about in the beginning of Project Terra.
How to have a successful Ph.D. career for senior Ph.D. students.
I was surprised when I first saw this title.
It uses a very special word,
which is successful Ph.D. career.
It is very difficult to define a successful Ph.D. career.
I personally feel that every student has a different background.
Everyone has a different Ph.D. career,
so there is no specific formula for everyone.
What I am doing today is to share my personal experience
and tell you what you can do to have a positive impact on your future development.
Everyone has a different background,
so you can try it if it suits you.
I hope these tips can help you to have a better Ph.D. career.
Let me briefly introduce my personal experience.
My experience is not ordinary.
I am a slow learner in every process.
I think it is related to my personality.
I am a gentle person.
You can see that I started my Ph.D. degree in 2018.
I graduated from my senior year in 2004.
I worked as a research assistant for a year and went abroad in 2005.
Before that, I was a chemistry major,
specifically a material scientist.
My main job was to synthesize some materials
and make some luminous materials.
I was focused on synthesis.
When I finished my Ph.D. degree,
my boss asked me if I wanted to study for a Ph.D. degree.
I looked back at my classmates in the Ph.D. class.
I found that everyone was doing the same thing.
My boss told me to study for a Ph.D. degree,
or else I would have to work in the industry.
At that time, I didn't have any prior knowledge.
I was a country boy from Hualien.
After studying at Tsingtao University for a few years,
I never thought about going abroad.
It wasn't until my boss mentioned this to me
that I seriously thought about going abroad.
I was lucky enough to apply for A&M.
Since then, I have been living in the U.S. for 17 years.
When I was studying for my Ph.D. degree,
I decided to change my field.
I thought synthesis was fun,
but I felt like I was in a bottleneck.
I thought I understood how to do synthesis,
but I didn't know if I did a good job.
I didn't know how to determine the efficiency of synthesis.
I started to feel like we didn't discuss it in detail.
When doing synthesis,
we just guessed how to make it more efficient.
We didn't have a more fundamental understanding.
So when I was studying for my Ph.D. degree,
I decided to change my field.
I wanted to know more about the physics of these materials.
At that time, Neoparticle was very popular.
So I joined a lab that specializes in Neoparticle
and does a lot of electronic, light, magnetic analysis.
So I spent five and a half years doing this.
During that time,
I learned how to add a device,
how to analyze,
and how to understand the advantages and disadvantages of a material
from a very fundamental perspective.
After that,
I started to think that
when I was studying for my Ph.D. degree,
I already had an intention that I wanted to be a teacher.
When I started to study for my Ph.D. degree,
my first goal was that I wanted to go back to Taiwan to be a professor.
But then I met a lot of different people.
So in the end, I ended up being a teacher in the U.S.
Later, you can see that
from Maths to Ph.D.,
it's a bit like turning a corner.
You start to do very materialized things.
But I think the biggest turning point in my life
was when I was studying for my postdoc.
Before that,
I didn't have any background in biology.
But when I was studying for my postdoc,
I did a 90-degree turn.
I spent five and a half years doing postdocs.
At that time,
I started to learn about monochromatic biology.
The main reason was that
when I was studying for my Ph.D. degree,
I met my wife.
My wife is a neon biologist.
I thought,
okay,
we can do some research together in the future.
Let's learn something new.
But I didn't expect that
learning something new would take me five and a half years.
So I spent five and a half years in Cornell.
I was hired to Cornell
mainly because I knew how to drive a car.
So when I got there,
my main job was to build up a super-low-energy microscope,
and create software to analyze images.
That was my main job,
building instruments and analyzing things.
That was my main job.
But when I joined a new element,
my career took a big turn.
Later on,
you can see that my current research program
started to connect with neural cells.
This process is very interesting.
Okay.
If you have good support,
this is a very enjoyable process.
But it's not a typical process.
I don't recommend everyone to try this mode.
This mode has its advantages,
but I think the difficulties in the middle are quite high.
If you are interested,
we can talk about this later.
The main reason why I mentioned this is because
you can see that
I made a lot of changes in the direction of the pressure.
In the process of these changes,
I think there is one thing I often do.
I like to chat with my friends,
or I like to chat with my junior in the lab.
In the process of chatting,
the most frequently asked question is,
okay,
why do you want to study for a PhD?
When you study for a PhD,
what is the biggest challenge you face?
I've been asking this question for 17 years.
So I think,
in these processes,
you can know what everyone thinks about PhDs.
After hearing a lot of people's opinions,
I started to have some questions about
what PhDs are all about.
Last week,
last week or the week before last,
last week,
Project Tara invited Bo-Jun to share with you
what he thinks about PhDs.
He also provided a lot of very useful advice.
Here are some of the things he provided.
For example,
why do you want to study for a PhD?
What do you want to do?
How to find advice?
Some general advice.
I think they're all very, very good.
What I'm going to do today,
I still want to address
why I want to study for a PhD.
Okay.
In my personal opinion,
this is the most important of all.
If you clearly know
why you want to study for a PhD,
I think when you encounter a lot of difficulties,
it will be much better to adjust your mindset.
Okay.
When people ask you,
why do you want to study for a PhD?
I think the question you need to reflect on is,
what is the meaning of a PhD to me?
I used to hear a lot of answers.
If you have a PhD,
don't say you can independently solve problems.
You can actually create,
find new knowledge by yourself.
I think these are all very good answers.
But,
it's my own feeling.
It's my own feeling.
I think a PhD is actually a lifestyle.
Okay.
So far,
my personal understanding is that
we were born until you grew up.
We've been trying to understand
how the world works.
It depends on your professional training.
Okay.
People, things, and objects
will make you
a little bit twisted
about how the world works.
Okay.
Everyone knows that
these may be the same.
Okay.
But those little things
will basically become the tipping point
for you to make a decision.
Okay.
So I think
if you study for a PhD,
the biggest advantage is
that it is an excellent training platform.
Okay.
So when you encounter a problem,
you know how to analyze the problem,
how to define the problem,
and how to solve the problem.
Then you can explain to others
that I encountered this problem,
and what I think it should be like.
Okay.
When it's like this,
I think it should have some impact.
Okay.
These things are actually
when you do experiments,
when you do research,
I think there is a very, very big overlap.
Okay.
To a certain extent,
I think if you can imagine
a PhD as
your last training stage,
then I think
if you can learn
its essence,
I think it will be a very helpful process
for your life.
Okay.
Like I just said,
okay,
let's make a comparison.
Okay.
When you encounter a problem,
okay,
the first thing is
you have to understand
what the problem is.
Right?
Then this is the same as
when you do academic research,
okay,
you do a lot of literature research,
it's actually the same.
Okay.
At first,
when you come up with a phenomenon,
you don't know what happened.
Okay.
What you can do is
okay,
I'm going to look for more documents
to give me a better understanding
of this system.
Okay.
In this case,
you can start to define your problem.
In other words,
you can start to formulate your hypothesis.
Okay.
After that,
once you have a hypothesis,
you can do the experiment.
Then after the experiment,
you might say,
okay,
in the end,
you might fail many times in the middle,
but in the end,
most likely,
you can actually figure out something new.
Right?
Now,
after this is over,
one very important thing,
one very important training
in Ph.D. is
okay,
you need to actually
present your results.
Okay.
Tell people why this is actually important.
Then this thing
will be in your training,
in your presentation training,
to get a
proper
preparation.
Okay.
So, in my opinion,
I think the biggest advantage of Ph.D. is that
you learn a more systematic
method
to deal with
the problems in your life.
Okay.
This is a relatively broad statement.
But I think
you project
what you learn in Ph.D.
into your life experience.
I think this is the most
meaningful thing.
Okay.
So, this is
how I view the Ph.D.
So, I think
what everyone does may not be the same.
Okay.
But the underlying principle
and how you deal with things in your life
I think this really provides a
very, very good training place.
Okay.
So,
how do you define
whether your Ph.D. is successful or not?
I think
the easiest parameter is
whether you enjoy the process.
If you can enjoy
the process,
and you can
make the things on the slide
to an extreme,
I think it's a very successful
Ph.D. career.
Because the things you need
can follow you for a lifetime.
I think this is more important
than anything else.
Okay.
Of course,
some people do better,
some people do worse.
But so what?
Okay.
Paper is paper, right?
You can create new knowledge,
but it's not going to go with you forever.
Right?
You have to face new problems every day.
Knowing how to handle these problems
is more important,
I think.
Okay.
Okay, get back to this.
I think
the timeline is important.
When you're doing your Ph.D.,
there's a timeline
in your mind.
I think this is
a very, very important thing.
Okay.
I've highlighted some
more important
milestones
for your Ph.D.
In the first year,
when you first came in,
get used to the environment,
finish the course as soon as possible.
In the second year,
you'll start to have
the so-called
Qualified Exam.
Okay.
After the Qualified Exam,
you'll become
the so-called Ph.D. candidate.
You're no longer
just a student.
Okay.
You're not a graduate student.
You're a Ph.D. candidate.
Okay.
Then you start to propose
what you want to do.
Then
work very hard,
publish some papers.
In the end,
this is
okay,
pass your dissertation.
Then eventually,
do your defense.
get your Ph.D.
Okay.
So it's a very, very
general process.
This process
usually takes you
four to five years,
depending on
your research field.
Okay.
But I think
five years
has become
a more and more
common timeline.
Yes.
Of course,
I guess engineers
may be faster.
But I think
five years at the Institute of Technology
seems to be more and more common.
The good thing is
I think I've seen
more and more colleges
recently
put
some teachers
will let students
stay for six or seven years.
This kind of thing
they do have
put in effort
to minimize
these things
happen.
Okay.
So
but I guess
in general,
it should be
about five years
will be a reasonable timeline.
Okay.
In these five years,
I think
it can be divided
into two stages.
Okay.
The first stage
I call
training phase.
Okay.
The second one
is actually
networking phase.
Okay.
Training phase
is usually
if everything is ideal,
I think
the better time
is in the first three years
to put
the training
Okay.
The skill set
should have
knowledge
in the first three years
should be
almost the same.
Okay.
The fourth and fifth years
should be
focused on
networking
things.
Okay.
Networking
I said networking
is like
going to a conference
or
dealing with people
you don't know.
Okay.
Start reaching out
to the company.
Okay.
The so-called
networking phase.
Okay.
A lot of people
squeeze this
networking phase
to the last
semester.
My personal feeling
that it's too late.
Okay.
So I think
having this
timeline
is important
in my heart.
Okay.
Let's talk
about
more
simple
more fundamental
things
like
how to
do things
on the food.
I think
you can try
to make
the training phase
more smooth.
Okay.
In the training phase
I think
there are
three main points.
The first point
is
in the training
skill set
is always
an important thing.
Okay.
Not everyone
wants to
be an
engineer.
Okay.
In the industry
when you
are looking for
a job
what skills
will you list
on your CV?
The company
will look at
your skills
to decide
if you are
the person
they need.
Okay.
So
scientific skills
I think
when you
think
okay
you feel like
maybe I'm not
that into
academia
then I think
skills
will become
a very
important
element
when you
are looking
for an
industry job.
Okay.
The second
is literature.
I think
literature
is relatively
important
in academia
because
if you
want to
go into
academia
you need to
propose
a lot
of experiments.
When you
propose
a lot of
experiments
it will
not
be a
random
experiment.
So
you need to
know if
it has
a big
impact
so you
need to
go
deep
into
the
professional
subjects.
So
literature
is a
very
important
element
especially
when you
are
looking
for an
industry job.
Okay.
Alright.
Let's talk
about the
scientific
skills.
Okay.
I think
when you
join a
lab
no,
before you
join a
lab
you need to
know
what
skills
you can
learn
from
joining
this
lab.
Okay.
Sometimes
when students
are looking
for a
lab
they don't
know
what they
want.
Okay.
To be honest
I think
more than
80% of
students
don't
know
what
they
want
because
they
haven't
really
thought
about
it.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
when you
join a
lab
you
need to
know
what
skills
you
can
learn
from
this
lab.
Okay.
So,
that's
for the
presentation
part.
Okay.
I put
outreach
and
letter of
recommendation
together.
Okay.
Outreach
and
letter of
recommendation
usually
happen
at the
end of
4th year
or
5th year.
Of course,
if you
want to
go to
the industry,
okay,
let's say
you want to
go to
the industry
at the
end of
3rd year.
Okay.
I'm not
interested in
academia.
Okay.
I want to
go to
the industry.
Okay.
No problem at
all.
But at
this time,
you have to
think carefully
about
which
companies
you are
interested in.
At that time,
it's a good
opportunity to
reach out.
Okay.
Introduce them
and tell them
that I use
your equipment
and so on.
Okay.
Chat with
them.
Okay.
Exchange
information.
Okay.
Let them
have an
impression
of you.
Okay.
At the
same time,
let them
know
how long
you are
going to
graduate.
Okay.
In this
year and a
half,
if he or she
really likes
you,
then you
got an
internal
referral.
Okay.
Things
will be
a lot
easier.
Okay.
Now,
if you
want to
go to
academia,
okay,
you have
to
do
your
presentation.
If
everything
goes
smoothly,
getting
your dream
postdoc position
is not
that difficult
either.
Okay.
Next,
when you
have identified
the position
and the
target,
they will
usually
request
you to
send
a letter
to
your
letter writer
and
company
or
your
future
postdoc
boss.
Okay.
I
think
a lot of
students
have
overlooked
this
important
thing.
Okay.
Believe
or not,
I
think
when
you
graduate,
have to
start
looking
for
the
person
who
carries
the
most weight.
Okay.
I
recently
graduated
two
students.
Okay.
One
is going
to
the
academic world
and
one
is going
to
the
business
world.
Okay.
I
received a
lot of
letters
from
my
co-
advisors.
Okay.
So
you
must
know
who
is the
most
important
person
who
can
write
the
letter
for
you.
Okay.
Sometimes
your
co-
advisors
or
your
advisors
carry
your CV
or
your
statement of
purpose.
You
can
simply
say
in
your
e-mail
that
you
are
looking
for
a company
and
what
they
need.
You
can
write
more
details
about
the
company
or
the
company
you
are
looking
for.
Okay.
So
you
must
know
who
is
the
most
important
person
who
can
write
the
letter
for
you.
Okay.
I
have written
a lot of
letters.
Okay.
Not
all of them
are
very
powerful.
Okay.
I
will
write
letters
that
are
very
powerful.
I
really
know
who
this
person
is.
Okay.
I
observe
the
time
and
the
incubation
of
the
professor.
Okay.
I
will
write
powerful
letters.
Okay.
I
recommend
him for
this
position.
Okay.
This
is the
worst
letter
you
can
write.
Okay.
This
is the
worst
letter
you
want to
have.
Okay.
Not
all of
them
are
powerful.
Okay.
This
is the
worst
letter
you
want to
have.
Okay.
This
is the
worst
letter
you
want to
have.
Okay.
This
is the
worst
letter
you
need to
learn.
Okay.
Like
this.
All
right.
And
the
last
will be
a
review
little
recommendation.
Okay.
Now
come back to
this.
Okay.
Again, five
years, right?
Two phases.
Okay.
How do
you accomplish
these tasks
within five
years?
Okay.
Well,
I can't really share my thoughts on this.
Because everyone really has different needs.
So, I think that the way I usually go about it is
to think long term first.
I'm the type of person who starts to think long term and then slowly goes back to short term.
But some people like to start short term and then slowly go back to long term.
Either way is fine.
But I think that if I were to do this,
I would start with what my goal is for this semester.
Okay.
Let's say that's my goal.
How far should I go in terms of time allocation
in the first month and how far should I go in the second month?
Okay.
If I have a goal for this month,
what should I do every week?
Right?
Then you can slowly go back to how far you want to go every day.
Okay.
PhD is a marathon.
It's a five-year process.
So, in the middle of this process,
I think planned vacation is also very important.
Okay.
When I was studying for my PhD,
every summer vacation,
I'm a person who really likes to go to National Park.
So, every summer vacation,
I would force myself to go to a National Park.
Okay.
So, I've been to a lot of different National Parks.
I think that's a process that allows you to recharge yourself.
So, after these five years,
you won't feel like you're totally burned out.
Okay.
I think the most important thing is to let yourself enjoy this process.
All right?
Okay.
Finally,
I want to use this slide to summarize today's presentation.
Okay.
I think mentality is a very, very important thing.
But the most important thing is that, okay,
you can only improve when you do your presentation.
Okay.
If you don't improve, you will only feel good about yourself.
You have to really do these things.
Okay.
It won't be too beautiful at first.
But that is okay because that is not your,
that is not your last presentation.
Okay.
In this process, no matter what you do,
you are just preparing for the last one.
Okay.
So you'd rather practice as many times as you can in this process.
The more times you practice, the better.
Once you know how to fold,
you won't fold like this in the future.
Okay.
So I think it's good for you to experience a lot of setbacks.
Of course, it's hard on your mind.
Okay.
But when you fold a lot of times,
your mind becomes relatively strong.
Okay.
Then your endurance becomes very, very high.
So I would strongly recommend that everyone is able to,
don't be shy.
Okay.
You can do a presentation,
go out and do a presentation.
Even if you know you are not ready,
but still do it.
Okay.
Then, um,
last, last, last.
I think this is actually not what I wrote.
There are goals, there are opportunities, there are plans.
This is not what I'm talking about.
Okay.
This is what Zhang Zhongmeng said.
Once I listened to his speech,
I think these things are very suitable for PhD students.
Okay.
Like I said, five years is not a long time,
not a short time, right?
But in order to be efficient to accomplish your goal,
having a goal is very, very important.
Because only if you have a goal,
then you can have a plan.
Okay.
Without a goal, there is no plan.
So the goal and the plan are actually put together.
Okay.
The goal is your focus.
The plan is just a means to pursue the goal.
Okay.
Then there is a discipline.
Discipline is something that everyone should know.
Because in this process,
it's not an easy process.
Okay.
In order to really achieve to a certain level,
discipline is very, very, very important.
Right.
I believe that if you talk to a lot of junior faculty,
you will find that their life is actually very, very boring.
Okay.
It's usually a point-to-point life.
And what they do every day is basically the same.
Okay.
But it's because of these tedious processes.
Causing this routine.
Okay.
Let them become a very disciplined person.
That's because of these disciplines.
So that he can make a breakthrough in many aspects.
All right.
Okay.
So in the end, I hope to be able to use this.
Have a goal, have a discipline, have a plan.
Three yes.
To end today's speech.
If you have any questions,
I am more than happy to answer the question.
Thank you.
Thank you for Tai-Yan's sharing.
When I was listening just now,
I felt very agreeable.
It's like nodding your head.
Okay.
I want to reiterate some points.
Because I just got on the job.
I am also a junior faculty.
Tai-Yan just talked about these.
About presentation.
Of course,
Everyone is young.
When you are a Ph.D. student,
You have learned a lot of skills.
But we are more.
There is no point to pay attention to.
I think it is.
Eventually it will become a very important point.
Presentation and networking.
Tai-Yan just said.
There are some very practical practices.
Don't go to a conference without presentation.
I think this is very important.
How to interact with others in the conference.
It is a very important point.
Also,
Tai-Yan just mentioned.
The letter from your advisor carries a lot of weight.
I can't agree more.
Your advisor can push you up.
Can also push you down.
So this is a very important thing.
Do you have any questions here?
This is a fairly open space.
Everyone can ask any questions.
As long as you turn on the microphone.
By the way,
Patrick Winston's talk.
It was a reference when I was preparing my job talk.
How to speak.
YouTube video.
It is my reference.
I think he said very well.
Tai-Yan just said.
When you talk about presentation.
You have to talk to people outside your field.
My wife has heard my job talk hundreds of times.
So this is a very good way.
I can't agree more.
Do you have any questions?
You can just turn on the microphone and ask.
Can you hear me?
Yes, I can hear you.
Can you introduce yourself first?
I want to say that everyone is so shy.
Let me ask first.
I am Lin Zhanhong.
I am currently at the Leibniz Research Center in Germany.
PhD student.
It is currently the last year.
In the writing stage.
Thank you for your speech.
For the presentation and writing.
Whether it is thesis or paper part.
I think maybe.
This is what I can refer to at the moment.
Because I am currently writing my thesis.
In fact, I am more interested in asking the teacher.
I want to ask the teacher.
The first question is about cross-field.
Because I think the teacher seems to be from before.
By the way, I used to be a chemistry major.
So I should call it a senior.
Then I want to ask the teacher.
Because I see that your field seems to have changed a lot.
About this cross-field part.
The teacher just mentioned that maybe.
Enter a new field.
The fastest way is to put it first.
Find out the important fields in the first five years.
Then read it.
Then sort out your own summary.
But what I want to ask is that.
What is the teacher's opinion on this cross-field?
The teacher, do you think that in the original field.
I mean the cross-field is to say.
Is it a completely unrelated field?
Or is it a little bit combined?
But maybe.
There are some overlaps.
But it may not be completely related.
Then I don't know the teacher.
I mainly want to ask the teacher.
What do you think about the cross-field?
It's about the advantages and disadvantages of future development.
Because the other one is to see.
The teacher's post-doc has also been doing it for a long time.
According to the academic world in Taiwan, as far as I know.
It seems to be too long.
So I just want to ask the teacher.
What do you think about these things?
I think about the cross-field.
I think I can be a representative of the cross-field.
Because the field is really quite wide.
From material chemistry.
Material physics.
Then it becomes biological physics.
To neurobiology.
In fact, it doesn't seem to have much to do with it.
So I think about the cross-field.
Is it good?
OK.
So what is everyone's approach?
It's usually not so exaggerated.
Mine is more like a 90-degree turn.
The general practice is probably.
It's amazing to turn 30 degrees.
That's a safer way.
OK.
Because basically.
I think even if you only turn 30 degrees.
OK.
Then expand your research scope.
This thing is actually quite difficult.
Yes.
What about the time?
Of course, it's a very, very important factor.
OK.
I think I can be a postdoc for so long.
The main reason is because.
I have a very supportive family.
With a very supportive advisor.
OK.
Inevitable.
If you say you are missing one.
It's not going to work.
OK.
You are going to live in hell.
So I don't recommend everyone.
Is to make such a drastic change.
Yes.
What are the benefits?
The benefit is that when you come to life.
You become very unique.
OK.
You can easily find some on research.
Scientific niche.
That you can be the only one.
Who can do this.
OK.
That will become a very good one.
If you can survive.
Then you can live relatively easily.
Because you start to define the field.
OK.
Because no one is doing that.
You are the only one.
Then you define the field.
Right.
If you are the first one.
Who define the field.
Then people follow you.
Then.
Things is actually easier.
OK.
But if you say.
You just follow the direction of others.
Then you will start.
You need to be very careful.
Because.
Whatever you say.
OK.
There will always be someone.
Researcher.
Start arguing with you.
Yes.
So.
The advantage of doing cross-field research is.
You may be easier to find.
A scientific niche.
To contribute.
What you have learned.
It is also easier to find new knowledge.
Come.
Push the front of the field.
OK.
So I think that is a big plus.
When doing this.
Because you changed the field.
The corresponding price is.
The cost of time.
OK.
Can you accept it?
Can your family accept it?
Right.
Is your teacher willing to accept it?
Then this thing.
It becomes natural.
Like I said.
I think I am a lucky person.
Because.
My wife is very, very supportive.
OK.
My family is very, very, very supportive.
That.
My researcher boss.
I am a post office boss.
Tell me directly.
Wife, how long do you want to stay?
Yes.
So.
It creates a.
I think.
I can do this.
OK.
The point is.
When I do this.
How do I feel?
Do I still enjoy this process?
I think that's the point.
If I don't enjoy this process.
I have to force myself to turn around.
I think that's the meaning.
Right.
So.
Generally speaking.
I think.
If you really want to do cross-field.
Don't turn so much.
OK.
Turn 30 degrees.
It's quite similar to what you did before.
I think it's already a pretty good one.
Uh.
It should also be said that it is a more reasonable approach.
OK.
The feasibility is also a little higher.
Compared to your other requirements.
Maybe you can lose a little bit.
Then I think.
Is a good way.
Right.
That.
No.
There is another.
What other questions are there?
I said.
Is to.
Comment on the interdisciplinary research.
Then.
The general.
Thinking about.
The.
How you should actually do that.
So that.
You know.
It has a higher chance to.
Make it work.
OK.
So I think.
Don't turn too much.
That.
But you have to turn.
OK.
If you say you are doing the same thing all the time.
When you are looking for a teacher later.
You will definitely be asked the question.
Is.
How do you.
With your previous.
Uh.
PEI group.
Compete.
OK.
So I think the cross-field thing.
Must be done.
Because.
In the single field.
In fact.
Simple things.
Everyone is basically done.
Right.
Ah.
If it's too difficult.
When you start.
Your faculty position.
You don't have that much time to spend.
Right.
If you want to survive.
If.
I think.
That's not a good approach.
So.
Involve some new things.
I think it's a.
Good direction.
OK.
How much do you want to involve?
It depends on the individual's own conditions.
I hope this answer.
Yes, yes, yes.
I probably have some ideas.
That.
Another question.
I mainly want to ask the teacher.
That is.
About.
Uh.
Decide the academic world.
Stay in the academic world.
Continue to try.
Or.
Uh.
To go to the industry.
That.
This is.
Uh.
This time point.
With a change of mentality.
Is there any.
Is there.
The first one is.
Is there a clear time point?
That is.
When do you need.
Meta decision.
That's another one.
Is there anything.
How to say.
Is the point to be decided.
And the direction of the decision.
About.
This issue.
Is.
I don't know if the teacher has any suggestions.
I think.
Of course.
It's just me.
OK.
If.
You start looking for.
OK.
That.
When you're in the first year.
When.
If you say.
You have found the interview.
If the opportunity.
OK.
But you didn't go.
That.
The second year.
You have more interview opportunities.
But you haven't.
That.
I think you can.
Concede.
Turn to the industry.
That.
The reason I say that.
Mainly because.
In my opinion.
It's.
Mainly because.
In the example I see.
Once you.
Fail for twice.
OK.
You have to find another.
Uh.
So my personal feeling, again, my personal feeling.
If you are in the second year, if you have the opportunity to interview for the second time, but you still don't have the position, then I guess that maybe there are some things that we did not realize, but other, uh.
Uh.
Uh, so the committee that you see might be a problem, so I think it might be a matter of whether to think about whether to change the career path that would be more suitable for yourself.
Ok, after all, uh, I just talked to everybody. Ok, this matter of education is actually the condition itself. Of course, it's important, but we all think it's great, it's almost 50 percent.
The other 50 percent is more related to the formation of the committee of the direction of the department.
So if you say that it's not very smooth when you're looking for a teacher, you don't have to be too depressed.
You just didn't meet the right search committee at the right time.
Ok, then the department did not provide you with the direction of the department and your direction did not match.
Ok, it's less simple. It's not that you are not good enough. Ok, so I think the change in mentality does not have to be denied.
Ok, then I think that if you want to consider it bad luck, I think it's totally fine.
Ok, it's really just that this thing is too complicated and involves too many factors.
Ok, it's not that I'm going to do my best and I'm going to have a position, it's not like that.
Yes, I have a lot of friends who perform better than me in science.
In the end, they just don't have a position.
Then you would say that I am better than them. I don't think so either.
They just don't have the position they want when they vote.
That fit is not very good.
Then this kind of person goes to the industry, I think they will be crazy, because they are really good.
So I think that if you say that you are not good at the academic world and transfer to the industry, I don't think it's a sad thing.
I don't think it's necessary, because you have a very good platform that can really let you shine.
Ok, thank you for your answer. I think maybe let everyone ask.
Do you have any questions?
I very much agree.
When we were just talking about finding a faculty position, the component of luck is really big.
In addition to the search committee of the other school, who will compete with you that year?
This thing is also different every year.
Can I comment on the search committee?
We just talked about outreach.
At the beginning, we were focusing on graduate student outreach, right?
You have to do this more thoroughly when you are a postdoc.
Because you need more recognition letters.
So you really need to get to know the people in your field.
It will make it easier for you when you are a postdoc.
That's right.
It seems that someone just wanted to ask a question.
Is it?
Hello, I am.
I am a graduate student at the University of Washington in the United States.
I have been studying for four years.
I think what I just shared is a lot of success.
Mainly because I am now in a research proposal stage.
What I want to ask is how to set the vision goal when writing a proposal.
I don't want it to be too big that I can't control it.
But I don't want it to be too small that there is no room for it.
I want to set a goal and a vision.
My main career goal is to achieve my goal.
If that's the case, what should I set?
A PSD proposal goal and vision.
I think this should be your boss's job.
My suggestion is to write out the outline first.
Then discuss it with your teacher.
The teacher will provide some reasonable judgment.
After all, it's your major.
It's hard for me to give you meaningful comments here.
But I think in general, I will ask my students to show me what they think.
Let's discuss and see if what you think is reasonable.
I think you need to practice more on writing outlines.
Think about your significance.
When you write something, is it significant?
In the end, when you write a proposal, significance is the most important factor.
After thinking about your significance,
How do you approach this problem?
It's worth thinking about.
I think the earlier you write out your outline,
It's best to discuss with your teacher as soon as possible.
Because your teacher can make the most reasonable comment about your research significance.
If your teacher doesn't think your significance is high,
I think you can change the topic as soon as possible.
I think writing a proposal is something you might want to specialize in later.
I don't think many doctoral students have the experience of writing a proposal.
I think writing a proposal is a very helpful experience for your future research significance.
If you have a chance, I suggest you try to write a proposal.
When you're writing your proposal experiment,
There's a little bit of that feeling.
I think you can take this opportunity to make it more complete.
I think writing a proposal is a very helpful experience for your future research significance.
Is that okay?
Yes, thank you.
I have another question.
How independent should PhD students be?
This is related to PhDs.
Every lab is different.
But I found one thing.
I think teachers and students need some time to build their mutual trust.
If you have mutual trust,
I think if you want to provide enough evidence to support your argument,
The boss usually won't be too strongly opposed.
If the boss has a strong desire to oppose what you propose,
That means you haven't reached that level in his heart.
How do you build mutual trust?
I think it's very important to have the ability to experiment.
And can you clearly express that you are highly professional in what you do?
If you can clearly express that you are highly professional in what you do,
Even if the project doesn't work, the teacher is still willing to trust you.
So I think it takes some incubation time to build that trust.
That incubation time depends on whether the students are really professional when presenting their results.
I think it's usually the general teacher.
Of course, some teachers are exceptions.
If the general teacher sees that students can really be responsible for what they do,
And can really make things clear, complete and reasonable,
Then I guess if you want to do a new project in the lab later,
Or if you come up with something and you want to continue,
The teacher will have a higher chance of agreeing.
Otherwise, in fact, on the practical operating surface,
The problem is that the teacher's funding is actually for specific projects.
So sometimes they can't deviate.
If you propose a proposal and it deviates too far from the original proposal,
He may not be able to provide financial support.
It's not that he doesn't trust you, he just doesn't have the potential.
Does that make sense?
Yes, yes, yes.
Thank you very much.
Then my question ends here.
Okay, everyone should have heard me talk just now.
That's the end of our Q&A session.
Then everyone will turn on the microphone again.
Let's applaud and thank Taiyan.
Thank you, everyone.