Before we get started, I'm going to show you a video of the workshop.
Okay, so this is, have you seen my PowerPoint video?
This is a video of Cara's presentation.
Next week, we will have a presentation
for senior PhD students.
Welcome to listen to it.
Also, on August 13th, we will have a presentation by Mentor Mentee.
You can find the full list on our Q&A poll.
Lastly, welcome to join our members
and welcome to join our fan page.
This way, you can receive our messages in real time.
This is about the Tarot Badge.
Before you get the Tarot Badge,
you need to install PoAP.
This QR code will help you to download it.
This is a proof of participation.
Next, I will put a specific password on the chat.
You are welcome to get it.
Please note that the time limit is only two hours.
If you don't want to miss it,
don't worry, just write to Tarot.
We will help you to get it.
Now, it's time for Mentor Mentee.
I can start now?
Yes, you can start now.
I'm going to share now.
I haven't seen your share yet.
Yes, because it...
Oh.
Did I make it?
Yes, you did. Thank you.
First of all, thank you, Tyra,
for inviting me and An Li's team
and An Li's organization.
My name is Xu Bojun.
I started my career in Duke in 2019.
I have been working for a long time.
I moved to Rutgers University in July this year.
I am a Ph.D. student.
My question is...
...