Hello everyone, welcome to today's Tarot Talk.
We are honored to have Pei-Hsueh to give us a talk.
The topic of today's talk has been shown in his introduction video.
Does the deservingness heuristic explain the effect of effort, luck, and need in a redistribution experiment?
Before we start the talk, let me introduce Pei-Hsueh.
Pei-Hsueh is a PhD student from the Department of Political Science at Stony Brook.
His research focuses on the social preferences of people based on experimental methods and computational social science,
and how these preferences affect people's choices in political issues.
Before we start, let's give a warm welcome to Pei-Hsueh for his wonderful talk.
Oh, the microphone is set to be turned off.
If you want Pei-Hsueh to hear the applause, you have to turn on the microphone first.
Let's give a warm round of applause to Pei-Hsueh for his wonderful talk.
Now it's your turn.
This English is a bit awkward, but what I want to talk about today is
how people's preferences affect people's choices in equality and fairness.
I did this research with my advisor, Ruben Klein.
We're almost done, but I plan to do more analysis.
If you have any comments, please feel free to ask.
Let's get started.
First of all, there's a long-standing problem with social scientists.
Do people care about equality?
Many experiments have shown that people do care about equality.
For example, in a dictatorial election, the dictator gets a sum of money.
Even if there's no reason to give their partner any money,
they'll still choose to give a portion.
Even in a non-dictatorial election,
different experiments have shown that people do care about equality.
Scientists have also found that in a non-industrialized society,
people will punish unfair distributors.
So people do care about equality.
If we use a mathematical model to show that people care about equality,
there are several main models.
The first one is called Inequality Aversion.
It was proposed by Feyer and Schmidt in 1999.
Their concept is very straightforward.
Let's say a person's wealth has not changed.
If he has more money than others,
he might feel embarrassed and unhappy.
If he has less money than others,
he might feel even more unhappy.
If he has the same amount of money as others,
he'll be the happiest if his wealth hasn't changed.
For example, if he has more or less money than others,
he'll be happy because of inequality.
It sounds straightforward and doesn't require a mathematical model.
However, it's better to use a mathematical model
to compare parameters and predictions.
The other model is called Inequality Aversion.
It was proposed by Angiolini and Miller in 2002.
The concept is more straightforward.
People care about their happiness and preferences.
It sounds vague.
People care about their preferences.
It sounds like people don't care about themselves,
but care about others.
It's impossible, right?
Most people are not like this.
The basic idea of this model is that
people will consider others' preferences.
No matter what, people will consider others' preferences.
How can we push people to care about equality?
Let me give you an example.
For most of the wealth,
whether it's money or something else,
of course not everything,
but for most of the wealth,
if you add up all the wealth in one unit,
people will reduce the amount.
For example, if I have $100,000,
and I get $100,000,
I will be happy.
But if I have $1 million,
and I get $100,000,
I will still be happy.
But I won't be as happy as when I only have $100,000.
But if I have $100,000,
and I get $100,000,
I might feel that I don't have a good balance,
but I won't be as happy as when I only have $100,000.
In other words,
if someone is already very rich,
and he gets $100,000,
he might be quite happy.
But if this person cares about another person,
no matter how much he cares,
if this $100,000 is for another poor person,
and this person only has $100,000,
and he cares about this person,
then the other person getting $100,000
might bring him more happiness
than getting $100,000 himself.
So assuming that the editor's use of land
and the user's use of other people's use
these two conditions,
it can also be inferred that
people care about equality.
This model can also explain
why people care about equality.
But the question is,
do people really care about equality?
If we find that,
like the big boss might tell you
that there is no bad luck,
only bad luck,
and then he is not willing to donate his money
or ask for tax, right?
Or some politicians might tell you
that some people refuse to work,
and then use this to blow votes.
Does this mean that people
might not care about equality?
What people care about is actually
the so-called fairness.
Of course, fairness can have many definitions,
but what people care about
is how much effort
people should make
to get paid.
What people care about is how much effort
people should make
to get paid.
If the income in the lab
is determined by effort,
and not by luck,
the beneficiary will choose
to redistribute less.
In other words,
the beneficiary will choose
not to redistribute the wealth
according to certain taxes.
In other words,
the beneficiary will choose
not to redistribute the wealth
according to certain taxes.
In other words,
if the income is determined by luck,
the beneficiary will have more social benefits
and higher tax payments.
If the beneficiary
believes that
everyone's income
is determined by effort,
not by luck,
the beneficiary will not
receive social benefits
and lower taxes.
Recently,
I've been
talking about
why people
prefer an unequal society.
Why do people think
an unequal society is fair?
Today,
we're going to talk about
whether people
only care about
equality or fairness.
Of course not.
Most people
care about equality and fairness.
Today,
we want to
build a model
that can explain
people's preference for equality
and fairness.
Let's go back
to our model.
Let's assume
that this model
only cares about
other people.
Of course,
the degree of care
may vary
depending on the situation
and individual personality
and experience.
Today,
we want to
put the degree of effort
into the model.
Let's say
there is a decision-maker
and
there are two other people.
Let's say
one person is very hard-working.
The decision-maker
cares about the hard-working person more.
Let's say
the wealth of these two people
is unequal,
and the decision-maker is rich.
Let's say
the wealth of this person is not equal,
but the decision-maker is hard-working.
The decision-maker cares about the recipient,
and decides to
redistribute the wealth
to the recipient.
On the other hand,
if the recipient
is not hard-working,
the decision-maker
will not care about the recipient's preference
and choose to give the recipient
less money.
In order
to verify
the prediction of our model,
we designed
a laboratory experiment.
The experiment
was conducted
by the students
of Stony Brook University.
In this experiment,
we will give them
different amounts of money
based on their decisions.
So,
the money they can get
after the experiment
is determined
by their decisions
in the laboratory.
This is our laboratory,
but this is just a demo.
This is not my experiment.
So, the people here
look a little old.
This is the professor,
and this seems to be
a demo for the website.
This experiment
was not conducted
in the laboratory,
because the recipient
was in the middle of the epidemic.
So, the experiment was conducted
on-site.
This is the design
of our laboratory.
At the beginning
of the experiment,
the recipient
can choose
to give the recipient
less money
based on their decisions.
At the beginning of the experiment,
the recipient
can decide whether
to do this task,
which we call
the counting zero task.
They need to write
the answer here
and send it out.
When they get it right,
they will get a reward.
The reward for getting it right
is random.
Each recipient
can decide
how many tasks
they want to do.
They can choose
not to do it
and skip this step.
They can choose
to do up to 10 tasks.
After this task,
we will randomly
pair the recipients.
One recipient
will be designated as
the decider.
The other recipient
will be designated as the recipient.
The decider can decide
how much money
they want to earn
from this task
to the recipient.
The decider will know
how much the recipient's salary is
and how many tasks they need to complete.
In this experiment,
we use a method
called the strategy method.
This method
allows the recipient
to answer
the combination of
all the salary and tasks.
There are two salaries
and 11 different
effort levels.
There are 22 combinations.
The decider
needs to answer
the question
how much money
they want to earn
from this task
to the recipient.
In the end,
the decider
will know
how much money
the recipient
earns
from this task
to the recipient.
The decider will know
how much money
the recipient
earns
from this task
to the recipient.
In the end,
the decider
will know
how much money
the recipient
earns
from this task
to the recipient.
Our model
is called
the conditional model.
In this model,
this is
the income
of the decider.
T is how much money
the decider wants to give to the recipient.
M is
the salary
of the recipient,
$1 or $2.
E is how many tasks
the decider has completed.
T is how much money
the receiver earns.
Theta is
the weight of the decider.
Theta is the weight of the decider.
In this case,
Theta is the value of
the function of labor.
Alpha is
the parameter of
the marginal cost of the decision.
Therefore, the alpha determines
The higher the alpha,
the lower the value.
In other words,
the higher the alpha,
the lower the marginal cost of the decision.
We can determine
how much money
the decider
will give
to the recipient
based on
each factor.
We can determine
how much money
the decider
will give
to the recipient
based on
each factor.
There are
several predictions
under this model.
The first prediction is that
as long as the weight
is greater than or equal to 0,
the income of the decider
and the degree of labor of the recipient
will remain the same
or less when the income of the receiver
is greater than or equal to 0.
This is called
inequality effect.
The second prediction
is that
as long as the income of the decider
and the degree of labor of the recipient
is greater than or equal to 0,
the income of the decider
will remain the same or less.
In our experiment,
we found that
90% of the receivers
met the first
inequality effect.
In addition,
we found that
85% of the receivers
met the
deservingness effect.
In addition,
we ran a random effect regression.
We found that
as long as the
income of the viewers
is higher
than or equal to 0,
the income of the
recipients
is also higher.
If the
income of the
智lr celebrities
is better than
or equal to 0,
all providers
will offer
a higher
income than
or equal to 0.
The other
prediction is
that
we actually
specify some parameters
for the model.
We actually
assume
the weight
function.
We assume
it is linear.
If the weight
is a baseline weight,
that is,
when the collector
does not work hard at all,
how much is the
basic weight?
How much does the
collector care about
the recipient?
Another parameter is
that once the
recipient increases
how much does the
weight increase?
We use two different
parameters as an
assumption.
The first parameter
is that the
weight baseline is very high.
When the recipient
does not work hard at all,
the collector cares
very much about the
recipient.
The picture on the
left shows
that the
weight baseline
is very low.
When the
recipient does not
work at all,
the collector does
not care about
the recipient.
However,
when the
recipient increases
by one unit,
the weight
is the
income of the
recipient.
The weight
determines
how much
the collector
has to pay
to the recipient.
The higher the
recipient's income,
the higher
the recipient's
salary.
As you can see,
the two lines
on the left
are overlapping.
In other words,
the collector
does not care
about the
recipient's salary,
but the weight
baseline is very high,
so the salary
does not matter.
However,
the higher the
recipient's income,
the less
the collector
has to pay
to the recipient.
On the right,
the two lines
on the left
are overlapping.
The higher the
recipient's income,
the higher
the collector
has to pay
to the recipient.
The higher the
recipient's income,
the more
the collector
has to pay
to the recipient.
According to our
experiment results,
we can divide
these collectors
into four types.
The first type
is sensitive
to the recipient's
salary.
This type
accounts for
25% of the collectors.
The second type
is insensitive
to the
recipient's salary.
This type
accounts for
20% of the collectors.
The third type
is selfish
to the recipient's
salary.
The last type
is other.
When we analyze
sensitive type and
insensitive type,
we find that
the result
is
consistent
with our
theoretical prediction.
The main conclusion
of our research
is that
our model
considers equality and fairness.
Most collectors
have the same model prediction.
We also found that
collectors can be classified into
three types,
selfish collectors,
sensitive collectors,
and fair collectors.
Sorry,
that's all
for today.
Thank you.
This is my Twitter
and personal website.
You are welcome
to join my Twitter.
Thank you.
Before we start
the Q&A,
please turn on your
microphone.
Let's welcome
PeiXun.
Do you have any questions?
You can ask
directly.
You can also
type your questions
in the chat box.
Do you have any questions?
You can ask
directly.
Hi,
I'm Jeffrey from
Indiana University Bloomington.
I'm also a fifth-year professor.
Thank you, PeiXun.
Sorry,
it's PeiXun.
I think your topic is
very interesting.
After listening to your
experimental design,
I have some questions.
First of all,
you didn't talk much about
decision-makers and recipients.
In your experimental design,
did you design
decision-makers to give money
to the recipients?
Or did you just say
there will be a part like this?
There is no right answer.
Sorry.
He can make such a decision.
We will ask him
if the recipient's salary
is $1
or $2.
If the recipient
completes
several tasks,
how much money
does he want to give to the recipient?
He can choose not to give.
We didn't give him any reason.
How much money he can get
is determined
by his decisions.
If he decides to give more money
to the recipient,
he will get less money in the end.
In fact,
if he is a
direct recipient,
there is no reason
to give money to the recipient.
The more money he gives,
the less money he will get.
I'm a little confused.
I'm not convinced.
It depends on
how you get the income.
Generally speaking,
rich people
are generous.
However,
I don't know.
I don't think
he is generous enough.
Maybe there are many reasons
why he doesn't give money.
I don't think
it has anything to do
with strategic thinking.
I don't think
it has anything to do
with strategic thinking.
I don't think
it has anything to do
with strategic thinking.
For example,
if you win a lottery
and win 10 million,
you can give
10 yuan to the recipient.
How generous do you think
he is?
How generous
do you think
he is?
For example,
you can see that
the one who earns more
is more likely to give the money.
The one who earns less
Do you think
he is more generous?
I think
he is more generous
because he is rich.
I don't know.
Thank you for your question.
First of all,
I'm not saying
the rich are more generous.
It's not our...
First of all,
the definition of
the rich is...
I think
the definition of the rich
is...
The definition of the rich
This definition is simple.
It's not about
being generous or anything.
Of course,
this is a matter of discussion.
The definition of the rich
is very simple.
It's about
considering
other people's benefits.
The first thing is...
Let me think about
how to answer this.
The definition of the rich
is not...
It's very simple.
It's about
considering other people's benefits.
I'm not saying
the rich are universal.
For example,
everyone has the same rights.
We're not saying
In this experiment,
their income
comes from their tasks.
Their income
comes from their hard work.
The income is divided by the recipient.
Another thing is...
Our model
predicts
that the more
the recipient...
I'm sorry.
The more the decision-maker's income,
the more money the recipient should get.
But in our result,
we didn't find
that the decision-maker's income
had a significant effect.
We found that
the income of the recipient
and the hard work of the recipient
had a significant effect
on the decision-maker's income.
I'm sorry.
How did the decision-maker
see the hard work
of the recipient?
How did you present
the hard work?
We gave him information.
Actually, we asked this question.
Let me show you the timeline.
Let's say
the recipient
earned $1.
The recipient earned $1.
How much do you want to give
to the recipient?
As I said,
they have to answer 22 questions.
We will ask
the combination of income and salary.
$0 to $10
is determined
by the recipient's income.
The reason $10 is shown here
is because
the recipient
earned $10
from the real effort task.
If the recipient
earned $5,
$5 is shown.
If the recipient earned nothing,
$0 is shown.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Thank you for your question.
Before we move on
to other questions,
let me read the question
from the chat room.
Sorry,
I don't know
what your Chinese name is.
It's Jeffrey Wang.
He asked a question.
He said the experiment design
was given to the decision-makers.
I just asked him.
OK.
Thank you.
I have some other questions.
Let's see if there are any questions
to be asked.
Let me advertise
some activities for Terra.
Terra is now
issuing a participation certificate.
The certificate can be
submitted to your mobile app.
We call it
Terra Badge.
I've posted the certificate
in the chat room.
When you receive the certificate,
you need to use
a different code.
The code is also in the chat room.
Today's code is
orcaatiger425.
Terra also
has a Slack channel.
You can join it
and get to know
other friends
and activities
related to
academia.
You can also
join the Slack space
of Project Terra.
The link is in the chat room.
Lastly,
if you like today's talk
or if there's anything
we can improve,
there's a link for
audience feedback.
You can fill it in.
We'll do our best
to make it better.
Now,
do you have
any questions?
Hello.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
I'm a student
in a math class.
My background is not in humanities,
so I don't understand much.
I'd like to ask
if I'm interested
in the math model.
I'd like to know
the meaning of the parameters.
Okay.
I'd like to know
if MJ and EJ
refer to the
recipient's income.
MJ is
the salary of the recipient.
EJ is
his tasks.
These two are his income.
I'd like to know
why the recipient
uses this way of expression
but the recipient doesn't
use this way of setting.
He only uses his income
as input,
not his efforts.
Okay.
Let me think.
The main problem is
sometimes people...
Oh, sorry. You go first.
Sorry, you go first.
You go first.
Okay.
I think
when I set it,
I'd consider the difference
in the degree of efforts of two people.
Water usually flows down.
So when I find
the difference between
their efforts and mine,
I might not
give him that much.
At that time,
my data function
might be the difference of efforts.
If I consider this,
I don't know if your model
or your prediction
will be different.
I think it's a good question.
Actually,
I thought about it when I analyzed it.
Of course,
you can modify the model.
I think
the decision-maker's income
doesn't matter
whether you set it as
mi, ei or yi.
It won't make any difference.
But there is a place you can modify.
For example,
we assume that
the relationship of the line
is theta0 plus beta
times the degree of efforts
of the recipient.
According to your theory,
the function of theta
is actually the model.
We assume that
it is a theta0,
which is the baseline,
plus beta times
ez minus ei,
which is the degree of difference
between the two efforts.
I think it's possible.
It's a very good question.
I remember that
we didn't find
such an effect in our analysis.
I remember that
we didn't find
such an effect in our analysis.
I remember that
we didn't find
such an effect in our analysis.
I remember that
we didn't find
such an effect in our analysis.
I see.
So the decision-maker's income
doesn't matter
whether you set it as mi, ei
or yi.
You mean here?
No, I don't mean that.
You set it as mi, ei
or yi
in the income.
You set it as mi, ei or yi
You're right.
But what you say is
mainly about the C-harm.
You can see
how much money
the decision-maker
will give to the recipient.
For example,
if you set mi as mi and ei,
the effect of dividing
mi and ei is the same.
The effect of dividing mi and ei is the same.
The higher the income of the decision-maker,
the more money he will give.
So there's no point
in separating them.
But what you said is about the C-harm.
I see.
Thank you.
Okay.
Do you have any other questions?
If you have no other questions,
I'll turn off the recording.