Our speaker today is Yang Yun-Pu, a Ph.D. student from UCLA's Center in Performance Studies.
Her research interests include East Asian theater research, especially East Asian theater research on Taiwan and China,
as well as gender and physiological gender research and digital culture research.
Her paper is The Eructicism of Peking Opera Functions Over the 20th Century.
She is also a Collegiate University Teaching Fellow
and a Professor of Engaging Gender Performances in East Asian Theater through Digital Storytelling at UCLA's Digital Humanities Program.
She is also the winner of the Professor's Prize in International Academy of Sciences.
She is also a Ph.D. student in the Department of Theater Studies at Taiwan University of the Arts and a Ph.D. student in the Department of Chinese Studies at Taiwan University of the Arts.
Today's topic is Gender Performances, The Eructicism of Peking Opera Functions Over the 20th Century.
Let's welcome Yang Yun-Pu.
Thank you, everyone.
I will now share my first video.
Here it is.
I think everyone can see it now.
My topic is Gender Performances, The Eructicism of Peking Opera Functions Over the 20th Century.
I am currently a Ph.D. candidate, so I am currently writing my paper.
This topic is one of my papers.
In today's presentation, I will divide it into two parts.
In the first part, I will briefly introduce Meng Xiaodong, her performance style, her personal life, and her marriage.
In the second part, I will focus on how the public views Meng Xiaodong.
I will also talk about how the New York Times interpreted Meng Xiaodong from the 1920s to the 1950s.
Meng Xiaodong is a very special actress.
In the U.S., sexual harassment, sexual violence, and death are all very sensitive topics.
So, trigger warning.
Later, we will talk about topics related to sexual harassment, sexual violence, sexual violence, and death.
Everyone should be mentally prepared.
This is Meng Xiaodong, who I will introduce today.
Meng Xiaodong was born in 1908 and passed away in 1977.
If I remember correctly, she was born in Shanghai in 1908.
In 1977, she moved to Taiwan and settled down in Taiwan.
When she passed away, she was buried in a cemetery in Taipei.
I remember that someone on the Internet shared the location of the grave.
If you are interested, you can go and take a look.
Meng Xiaodong is a very well-known female veteran in the entertainment industry.
A veteran is someone who plays a male role on stage.
There are many types of male roles.
In short, a veteran is a mature male.
Meng Xiaodong is very famous for being a very good veteran.
We call female veterans.
There is a very important concept that I want to emphasize.
It is easy to say that if a man plays a female role on stage or a woman plays a male role on stage,
we generally say that this is a backstabbing.
But in the play, the meaning of backstabbing is not like this at all.
The meaning of backstabbing is that, for example, Meng Xiaodong has been a veteran since childhood.
One day, he suddenly played a female role on stage.
This is called backstabbing.
If he plays a male role on stage, this is called the job of the job.
The job is the job of the job in Japan.
So don't mix up the backstabbing concept of the stage with the backstabbing in the play.
Another example is Mei Lanfang.
Mei Lanfang is a very famous veteran actor.
So when we talk about Mei Lanfang,
we don't say that Mei Lanfang is a backstabbing woman.
We say that Mei Lanfang uses her job to perform.
But if Mei Lanfang plays a man on stage today,
we will say that Mei Lanfang is a backstabbing woman.
I hope this part can be clarified.
Meng Xiaodong's very famous part,
I think it's still the best backstabbing woman in history.
You may ask what kind of backstabbing woman is backstabbing woman.
Mei Lanfang is a backstabbing woman.
Backstabbing woman is Yu Shuyan.
Yu Shuyan is the person in the middle.
She is the founder of backstabbing woman.
She was born in 1890 to 1943.
Yu Shuyan has a very high status in the old generation.
To this day, many Beijing opera actors
still say that they are learning from the Yu family.
They think she is a teacher of the Yu family.
They think she is a legend.
A legend that cannot be surpassed.
People like Yu Shuyan are proud all their lives.
She has only received two students.
We say that sometimes other young actors
may have learned one or two plays from her.
But they are not formal backstabbing women.
Formal backstabbing women are those who kowtow to her,
kneel down to her, and give her gifts.
All famous actors come to witness
this kind of formal backstabbing women.
We say that she is a real disciple.
She has received two real disciples in her life.
One male and one female.
The male is Li Shaochun, the one on the left.
He is also very famous.
The female is Meng Xiaodong.
Interestingly,
according to Chinese culture,
especially in the era of the Republic of China,
where men and women are very important,
or in the Qing Dynasty, where men and women were very important,
it is very interesting that
people generally think that Meng Xiaodong
is a person who has really been passed down by the Yu family.
Because Li Shaochun was too busy.
Li Shaochun had a family to support.
So whoever asked him to act, he did.
Making money is the most important thing.
Yu Shuyuan is a very serious person.
She is very...
I don't think it's natural.
I didn't teach you how to act.
You act as Sun Wukong every day.
Aren't you embarrassing me?
Meng Xiaodong is different.
Meng Xiaodong,
we will talk about her marriage later.
Basically, when she studied with Yu Shuyuan,
she was single.
So she didn't have a family to support.
She also had more time
to study with Yu Shuyuan.
So in the end, people actually think that
the person who really
got Yu Shuyuan's love
and was able to learn from Yu Shuyuan
was Meng Xiaodong,
not Li Shaochun.
We will also talk about Meng Xiaodong's marriage.
The one on the left
is when Meng Xiaodong was 19
and married Mei Lanfang.
The one on the right is Mei Lanfang.
So the existence of this
little phoenix
became a very interesting topic
for gossip magazines at the time.
They thought that
the girl's eyes were female,
and the man's eyes were male.
The relationship between
the two sexes
made gossip magazines very popular.
At that time, Mei Lanfang
was already a very famous star.
A popular entertainment star.
But later,
she divorced Mei Lanfang
when she was
in her late thirties.
She married another man,
an old man.
This old man may not look
very good,
but don't think it's nothing.
Because this old man
is actually a very famous
young man in Shanghai
from the 1920s to the 1950s.
His name is Du Yuesheng.
In simple terms,
Du Yuesheng is a very famous
and high-ranking gangster.
Meng Xiaodong became his
fifth wife.
This photo
is of Meng Xiaodong
when he played the role of
Qing Dingzhu.
Before we talk more
about Meng Xiaodong's story,
I also hope to find
a small part of his
recording and let everyone
feel his singing.
But this singing
is not a very formal
recording.
In the 1950s and 1960s,
he lived in Hong Kong for a while.
When he lived in Hong Kong,
he recorded at home
when he invited
his piano teacher.
So there will be a lot of noise.
Please, Pei Xun, play it for us.
Do you have a way to play it?
Yes, I do.
Thank you.
I want to share the screen again.
This is a simple yearbook.
This amazing actress,
when she was 40,
it was her last time on stage.
After that,
no one saw her perform.
When she was 43,
she married Du Yuesheng,
who we just talked about,
the boss of the underworld.
A year later,
Du Yuesheng passed away.
Du Yuesheng was seriously ill at the time.
In the 1960s,
she moved to Taiwan.
She lived in Taiwan for a few years
and then passed away.
This is a very brief yearbook.
It's a brief overview of her life.
Before I talk more about
her relationship
with the gossip magazine,
I want to provide you
some background information.
In the 1970s,
the competition
between genders
was very interesting.
In the 1970s,
there were only male actors
on the stage.
From 1970 to 1870,
there were only male actors
on the stage.
On the stage,
no matter what the role was,
it was all played by men.
It wasn't until 1870
that some female actors
joined the industry.
Although some female actors
joined the industry,
in the society at the time,
there was always a
discrimination
between actors and prostitutes.
We can't say
it was discrimination.
In the 1970s,
1870s,
and especially 1920s,
we could see
that some female actors
were already famous.
They were good at singing and dancing
and acting,
so they switched to acting.
We could also see
that some female actors
were also taking classes
other than acting.
This was partly true,
but it was also
a problem
for some actors.
In this speech,
I'd like to bring you
to think about these questions.
First,
let's take a look at
how the gossip
from 1920s to 1950s
influenced
Meng Xiaodong
and how their
views on Meng Xiaodong
changed.
Second,
I'd like to discuss
how Meng Xiaodong
was full of
sexism.
I don't know
if you know what sexism is.
To put it simply,
sexism is
when a person's gender
is highlighted.
For example,
Meng Xiaodong is a girl.
There are a lot of gossip
about Meng Xiaodong's
gender.
Later,
we'll have
more practical examples.
So, I'd like to discuss
how Meng Xiaodong
exercised his autonomy
to resist the sexism
and misogyny of the gossip.
Third,
let's take a look
at how Meng Xiaodong
finally found
a solution
to help himself
from the gossip.
Lastly,
I'd like to discuss
how Meng Xiaodong
is a legendary actress
and is considered
to be the best
virgin in Chinese history.
However,
there are restrictions
on his status.
His status is not
100% perfect.
What are the restrictions?
First, let's take a look
at a 2020 report.
In 2020,
Meng Xiaodong was
around 10 years old.
I forgot.
He was 13 years old.
In the report,
he wrote that
he wouldn't be affected
by gossips until he was 16 or 17.
Gossips mean
his throat was damaged
or his voice changed
when he was 16 or 17.
He said he wouldn't be affected
by gossips until he was 16 or 17.
In the future,
gossips like
En Xiaofeng,
Xiao Lanying,
Chen Huifeng,
etc.
We can see
two things here.
First, the report
was highly anticipated.
Second,
Meng Xiaodong
was discussed with
other senior female students.
In the future,
female students
will discuss
Meng Xiaodong with
female students
and learn from him.
I just wanted to
show you
what the report looked like
at the time.
Most of my papers
are based on the report.
I read a lot of old newspapers.
That's what I read.
In 1926,
Meng Xiaodong was
living in Shanghai.
In 1926,
he decided to move to Beijing.
At that time,
people thought
Shanghai made a lot of money
but Beijing was a good place
for an actor.
However,
after he moved to Beijing,
Shanghai newspapers
still liked to report his gossips.
At that time,
there was no Internet,
so news could be verified.
Many fake news
like
Meng Xiaodong's suicide
were published.
Some
vulgar news
like this
were published.
When I read this news,
I was shocked.
I thought
people in the past
were not conservative.
They could write
what they wanted to say.
At that time,
there was a civil war.
Many military officials
took a fancy to Meng Xiaodong
and forced him
to move to his house.
Of course,
he didn't just
invite Meng Xiaodong to dinner.
He wanted to have sex with Meng Xiaodong.
He said
Meng Xiaodong
was not
his type.
He had sex with Meng Xiaodong
every day.
He felt
he was sick of it.
He even
forced his family
to have sex with Meng Xiaodong.
In the end,
Meng Xiaodong died
in this situation.
It was a very exaggerated news.
At the same time,
there were
similar news.
There were many
For example,
let's look at
the following news.
Meng Xiaodong
was robbed
by a general.
They said
Meng Xiaodong
was too small
to have sex with Meng Xiaodong.
After the robbery,
Meng Xiaodong was locked up
by a general
and sent to
a hospital.
Meng Xiaodong's name
was used
to
show
the sexual behavior
between Meng Xiaodong
and the general.
The 87-yuan coin
was the
size of Meng Xiaodong's
sex organ.
The 87-yuan coin
was the size of Meng Xiaodong's
sex organ.
Meng Xiaodong was
robbed by a general
and had sex with Meng Xiaodong.
In the end,
Meng Xiaodong was sick
and sent to a hospital.
There were many
exaggerated news
about Meng Xiaodong.
As I said,
these news
constantly sexualized
Meng Xiaodong.
We call it
sexualization.
It emphasizes
Meng Xiaodong's gender
and sexual
behavior.
Of course,
some commentators
couldn't stand it.
For example,
Aowong
wrote many articles
about Meng Xiaodong.
He was a fan of Meng Xiaodong.
He was so surprised
that Meng Xiaodong
became a target
of gossip.
So,
Meng Xiaodong
should imitate an actor
and marry a rich man
as soon as possible.
Then, no one
would gossip about Meng Xiaodong.
At that time,
many actresses
thought
it was impossible
to show off on stage.
So,
Meng Xiaodong should find a time
to marry a rich man
and live a happy life.
He shouldn't show off anymore.
After all,
it's easy to be sexually harassed.
At that time,
people still thought
public women
were relatively
uncivilized.
For example,
prostitutes were
public women.
So were actresses.
I'd like to add
that
the idea of
public women
still exists
in the 60s, 70s,
and even in the 70s and 80s.
When I read
the records of Taiwanese actors,
I can see that
some actresses
are attracted by marriage
on the stage.
It's a common concept.
However,
it's not the case today.
As I said,
Meng Xiaodong was gossiped.
So,
Meng Xiaodong
moved to Beijing
and married
Mei Lanfang at the same time.
However,
it was well-hidden.
No one knew about it,
except close friends.
No one knew about it.
Let's talk about
Mei Lanfang's family.
Before Meng Xiaodong,
Mei Lanfang had two wives.
The first wife was Wang Minghua.
The second wife was
Fu Zhifang.
Fu Zhifang was also an actress.
I heard that Wang Minghua was also an actress.
However,
Wang Minghua passed away early.
So, I couldn't find his photo.
Fu Zhifang was also an actress.
Then,
she became the second wife of Mei Lanfang.
Wang Minghua didn't have children.
Then,
from
1926,
when Meng Xiaodong moved to Beijing,
and many gossips started to talk about him,
to 1929,
basically,
no one knew
about Meng Xiaodong's whereabouts,
suicide,
marriage,
or sexual abuse.
It was a maze.
You could find different stories in newspapers.
So,
until now,
for example,
this news report
was published in
1929,
and was published in
February, 1929.
They said that
they published
these four photos
and discussed
where Meng Xiaodong was,
who he was,
and what he said.
I'm afraid it's a problem,
but not a problem.
Some people said that
Mei Qi,
which means Mei Lanfang,
was about to give birth.
Mei Qi's son
used a mirror.
Then,
as you can see,
these four photos
were taken
from right to left
and ordered,
asking kiss
and being kissed by others.
They were also giving advice for
sister and Sister Ning.
So,
they published
gossips photos
to discuss where Meng Xiaodong was and
finding it very interesting.
We mentioned that
gossip reporters
always wanted to find Meng Xiaodong,
but at the same time,
how could these photos
be posted on Beiyang Newspaper?
Did they
deliberately
take photos of Meng Xiaodong?
We don't know.
At the same time,
on February 9th,
a few days later,
there was another photo.
This is a photo of Mei Lanfang.
On the right, it says,
What are you doing there?
On the left, it says,
I'm taking a photo here.
On the right,
it says,
This is a photo about
Mei Meng.
On the right,
it says,
Meng Xiaodong.
On the left, it says,
Mei Lanfang.
Do you think
these two words
are written by different people?
To me,
these two words
are used to discuss
the relationship between
Mei Lanfang and Meng Xiaodong.
We say that
Mei Lanfang and Meng Xiaodong
are getting closer
and getting married.
But
can they live a happy life?
Maybe not.
Because we just talked about
Mei Lanfang and two wives,
Wang Minghua,
and
Fu Zhifang.
Fu Zhifang is described as
a very jealous person.
I didn't live in that era.
I don't know them.
So I don't know if Fu Zhifang
is really jealous.
But the report said
Fu Zhifang regards Mei Lanfang
as his own
exclusive mate.
He doesn't allow
anyone to get close to Mei Lanfang.
Another report said
everyone
hopes that
Mei Lanfang and Meng Xiaodong
can get back together.
At that time, there were a lot of gossips.
Some said they were divorced.
Some said they were together.
The report said
everyone wants Mei Lanfang
and Meng Xiaodong to be together.
They are a perfect couple.
But
Fu Zhifang doesn't want
them to be together.
Because he thinks
Mei Lanfang is his exclusive mate.
So he doesn't allow anyone
to get close to Mei Lanfang.
So
when these two
use exclusive mate
to describe Mei Lanfang,
it shows
that
in the drama,
in the sexual scenes,
the female actors' power is obviously weaker
and they are more likely to be harassed.
They are more likely to be sexually harassed.
They are more likely to be involved
in the gossips.
However,
in Mei Lanfang's home,
we can see another
sexual dynamic balance.
It's not as traditional
as we think.
It seems that
men have more power.
On the contrary,
Fu Zhifang seems to have more power.
Moreover,
when they
describe Mei Lanfang
as their exclusive mate,
it seems that
Mei Lanfang is also
being sexually harassed
by Fu Zhifang
as her exclusive mate.
They describe Mei Lanfang
as a piece of meat.
It's a piece of meat
that everyone wants.
So we can see
that Mei Lanfang is also
being sexually harassed by Fu Zhifang.
In this news article,
some people
describe Mei Lanfang
as a piece of meat
that everyone wants.
Basically,
Mei Lanfang came to the U.S.
to perform in the 1920s.
In this news article,
Mei Lanfang came to the U.S.
to perform in the 1920s.
When she came back to China,
she was very popular.
She was very popular.
On the other hand,
her mother
died at the same time.
Mei Lanfang was very sad.
The worst part of this news article
is that
Mei Lanfang not only
felt sad for her mother's death,
but also wanted to
deal with the two beautiful wives.
The two beautiful wives
are not Wang Minghua,
but Fu Zhifang and Meng Xiaodong.
Meng Xiaodong is the one
who is fighting for the two women.
Mei Lanfang is very sad.
The gossip media
likes to show these things.
The gossip media likes to show these things.
The way these articles are reported
is very meaningful.
It's not just about
discussing their family affairs.
Then,
in 1932,
Mei Lanfang and Meng Xiaodong
officially divorced.
Meng Xiaodong said
their relationship is always very good
me and Wanhua
Meng Xiaodong said
we also have no need to bother many people with separating
he meant that it's good to be separated
he was very polite
it's also mentioned on a report
about their divorce
so
then
I will show you
what I circled
Meng Xiaodong's key difference
before that
he said it's good to be separated
in 1933
so you can see
in 1932
he said it's good to be separated
in 1933 he got angry
because
the news wrote many awful things
and it's very serious
some even said
Meng Xiaodong was cheating or something
in 1933
there was a warning
and at the same time
a lawyer said
Meng Xiaodong
hired me to be his lawyer
so if anyone
dare to write nonsense
we will sue you
so Meng Xiaodong
Meng Xiaodong
started to use the newspaper
as a counterattack
to his independence
this is a warning
so
let me read it
the warrior, Meng Xiaodong,
was a child and very good at study
he was not very good at reading
he was not very good at studying
and he never learned
so
this is a warning
he can't stand it
Meng Xiaodong thought it was annoying
he wanted to stop telling gossips
but the interesting thing is
when I was looking for newspapers
I didn't find so many gossips
I think one possibility is
that those newspapers are gone
they didn't stay until today
the second possibility is
maybe those gossips
are not published in the newspapers
they are more like a
gossip
clip
And then after he published
that warning
he
Later on, he began to worship
I'm sorry to worship Yu Shuyan as a teacher
Then here we will
It will be involved in how he
turn that is the actress
in the drama circle
status
So when I read the magazine
I will also see a very interesting phenomenon
is that they discuss the actor
They call her Mingling
The male actor is called the female spirit
But why is the male actor not the male spirit
Or the female actor is not Mingling
Just this way of classification
In fact, it has already shown the society at the time
He is the whole
is the sexual imagination
The male actor is the famous Mingling
The actress is a female actor
Then
He
Mo Xiaodong
One of the ways to turn this way
It's very
Very ironic
His way
His way of sarcasm is
How do you turn a girl
In the drama circle
First of all, you have to have a super famous
Male teacher
You can't go to a female teacher again
Because the actress has already been looked down upon
What's the use of going to a female teacher
You must find a famous male teacher
And this male teacher must be respected by everyone
And then on stage
How does he show himself
You can't play yourself
You can't play your own style
Because no one cares about your style
You have to play Yu Shuyuan
You have to play Yu
You are not
For example, you are playing Zhuge Liang on stage today
You are not playing Zhuge Liang
You are playing Zhuge Liang
Only through this way
To make others feel
You are a good actor
Because you are better than those other male actors
There is a way
Like Yu Shuyuan
So like Yu Shuyuan
Is a very important point
So in this whole
Within the scope of gender performance
Meng Xiaodong, he blurs
The boundary between the male spirit and the female spirit
He
He is no longer just a female spirit
He is also a male spirit
Because he is better than male actors
Can perform Yu's Zhuge Liang
Zhuge Liang
Then we said
Before
When he was 13
The report said
If he grows up to 16 or 17 years old
He will definitely be like these women
It's the same
But
This situation is
After he lost to Yu Shuyuan
There are very different changes
For example, there is a report that says
There is a special case
He is Meng Xiaodong
All female actors
Anyway, female actors are female actors
But there is a special case
He is Meng Xiaodong
Or they will
Keep talking about Meng Xiaodong's voice
Then say
Meng Xiaodong's voice is
Better than Tan Fuying
Better than Ma Lianliang
Better than Yan Jipeng
Better than Wang Youzhen
All these
Sorry, Wang Youchen
So all these names
All these names
Are very famous male students
So when they put Meng Xiaodong
This name and other famous male actors
When comparing
It means he can already succeed
Can't say it's a complete success
But at least he challenged
In the industry
Gender rights
Then another one
This report
Just show you the title
Li Shaochun's Qi Yuanbao
Worth a compliment
Compare with Xiaodong
We just talked about
Yu Shuyuan's life
Two disciples
One is Li Shaochun
The other is Meng Xiaodong
From this title alone
We can see
Obviously this commentator
He thinks Meng Xiaodong is better
Because if
He thinks Meng Xiaodong is worse
Why take Li Shaochun and Meng Xiaodong
To compare
He can say
Li Shaochun's Qi Yuanbao is worth a compliment
Much better than Meng Xiaodong
He doesn't need to compare with Meng Xiaodong
Of course it's because Meng Xiaodong's performance is better
So Li Shaochun is also very good
But not as good as Meng Xiaodong
So I have to compare with Meng Xiaodong
So again
We have seen
When he was in his 20s
When people talk about actors
Talking about female actors is talking about female actors
Talking about male actors is talking about male actors
The age and age of women are not related
But now he broke that boundary
Then
In 1943
When he studied with Yu Shuyuan for about six years
Unfortunately, Yu Shuyuan passed away
Then he wrote in the newspaper
A report
This is my English translation
But the original text is
Unfortunately, I am a woman
Then there is no way to complete the teacher's training and guidance
Then
The second
Then the fourth line
He wants to say
Fortunately, I still have a lot of male colleagues
Senior and junior
They will continue to perform
Then they will
They will pass on the style of Yu Shuyuan
And me
I have no achievements
We just talked about
He is blurred
The boundary between male and female actors
But in this report
He blurs himself very much
I think this
I think this article is actually a very interesting thing
Meng Xiaodong is a bit
He is a bit cynical
So when he said
Unfortunately, I am a woman
I just can't do it very well
Fortunately, I have a lot of seniors
He really feels that way
I'm not very sure
What is he thinking
But this way of writing
You can feel
He is a woman
But he wants to learn the fish
He has some resentment
Not so simple emotions
He has some very complicated things in it
These very complicated emotions
Including the one in the drama
Gender and then
And all the time
Everyone thinks that female actors
Because I feel that what conditions are born
Will make them unable to play well
Although Meng Xiaodong is very
He said he had no achievements
But in fact, in the later newspaper
A lot of people describe it
Fish succulent
Or I would say
Fish succulent is dead
The only way we can hear
It's only Meng Xiaodong
Meng Xiaodong
I went out to envy
This happened in Shanghai
He said no
He said I was not angry
I don't want to break the tradition
My teacher never taught me
I have to come out to admire
There is a very interesting point
You must come out to admire
Who invented this
It's Meilanfang
It was started in Shanghai
When Meng Xiaodong said
It was a new trend
But at the same time
It may be to a certain extent
Back then
Upset
I thought it was a matter of course
And
The last point
Let's talk about
The style of the fish
What kind of restrictions did Meng Xiaodong bring
Let him get a lot
And a lot of viewers love him
Both Meng Xiaodong and Meilanfang
Will perform at the birthday party
So the gossip reporters started to move
I want to see them perform together
So
The point here is
After he lost to Yu Shuyan
He became a very good performer
The performance was worth it
I even feel that after Yu Shuyan died
I can only rely on Meng Xiaodong
But you can't control these things
Don't talk about his gossip
These things
Don't let everyone talk about his gossip
There are some more detailed stories
I won't say anymore
As we say, he's in his 20s
Some unconsciously
Although he's not like before
However, these things
Are not able to completely avoid
Moreover, this will also hurt
It feels that
His realization is to learn from others
He's not able to create his own ranks
But I think this is a
In this era, sometimes there will be some
Unnecessary restrictions
You can't ask a person
To completely
Time is almost up
I quickly tell you
I hope that everyone remembers
What we discussed
From 1920 to 1950
The public
The public and gossip
About what happened to Meng Xiaodong
We just said
From the beginning
He was considered as a woman
And was constantly misinterpreted
After he lost to Yu Shuyan
Everyone saw
His achievements in the art of fish
And see him in the art of fish
And we have to recognize one thing
It's because he lost to Yu Shuyan
It's because he learned fish well
So everyone recognizes his achievements
If he lost today
Any excellent female teacher
Maybe everyone won't think so
Then
So all the way we can see
Everyone gossip
From misinterpretation
To respect
To see him as a good artist
But at the same time
It's not like
We will discuss the art of fish
It's not like that
There are some restrictions
Then
How did Meng Xiaodong
Resist those
Misinterpreted reports
Mainly
Mainly I answer this question
I'm using
Meng Xiaodong's report on the police
It's gossip news
He also uses newspapers to respond
These reports
That is to say the newspaper as a public space
Then you can use it
To attack you
The third point is
How did Meng Xiaodong
Find a way
To get him
In this way
I personally think
Because he worshiped Yu Shuyan
He worshipped Yu Shuyan and studied very hard
Let the public think
He is the male version of Yu Shuyan
He is the only one who can be considered
He uses a male teacher
To be the shield
Of course he did well
To draw these gossips
The last point we said
He performed
Actually, it's all about performing his teacher
What are the restrictions on the teacher?
On the one hand, of course
Perform your teacher
Don't let those gossips
Completely away from you
As long as there is an opportunity
The gossip media will still be
The reporter will still be active
The second is that you perform your teacher
But what you perform is always his style
You can't create your own style
Yes, and finally
I want to show you
A trailer
Then ask Pei Xuan to prepare
Help me broadcast this trailer
This trailer is a movie
Mei Lanfang
2008 movie
Mei Lanfang is played by Li Ming
Meng Xiaodong is played by Zhang Ziyi
To be honest, it's not a particularly good movie
Because the family had a lot of
Rebellion and unhappiness
How can you write my ancestor like this
So some parts of this movie
It's pretty beautiful
Especially inside
There is a
Mei Lanfang's
Friend is Qi Rushan
He later came to Taiwan and became
Taiwan is very famous
Famous people in the cultural world
It's also very serious
Because I think it's with the Kuomintang
Anyway
Anyway, it's fun
If you are interested in knowing more
You can also watch this kind of movie
Then if you are interested
If you know more, you can
Google different things on the Internet
Please help me broadcast this documentary
Thank you all
It's not a documentary, it's a movie
Miss Meng
Mei Daye
See you on stage
Who destroyed her lonely dream
You dare
It's for Mei Lanfang
Know
What do you have
Just say it
Mei Lanfang and Meng Xiaodong
It turned out to be this sentence
Meng Xiaodong will never meet Mei Lanfang again
Say it again
Meng Xiaodong
Let go
You dare to lie to me
Because you can't leave Mei Lanfang
Who is your sister
Tang Xiaohong
You dare
Thank you
My speech ends here
Thank you all
Thank you Yunpu
Thank you for his wonderful speech
Now it's time for Q&A
Does anyone have any questions?
If not
I'll ask the first question
I want to ask
In that era, including the small newspaper
Who is the main target?
Who reads newspapers today?
Because most people
They read the newspaper
Can't completely say
Not a real literate
He read the dictionary
He doesn't want to be a poet
What green-daisy history poems
I remember, just
I used to read Poetry Dream
It was for example that their
poetry
this is the people more or less
I think
first of all, the Red Dragon dream was passed down
primero, la playa comprehensivamente
gradually collapsed, there is a relationship
so
I don't know what to say about them
I believe it is
There must be some people like the Red Dragon dream
Anyway, the family is
After the family comes to the middle
Then come to see those gossip
right
But to say
In the end
Who is the one who sees it completely?
I think
I think the people who see it
It's very wide
It's from
Very wide, but not to everyone
Because after all, many people are literate
But the problem is that you are really
The kind of high class is really
The kind of literate
More aristocratic
Then they are quite ignorant
I want to ask a question
That is to say
So Meng Xiaodong is in that era
Is the first person to worship Nanlaoshi as a teacher?
Is there anyone else doing this in the future?
I think I see it now
I see it now, I think he is
The first person to worship Nanlaoshi so formally
It wasn't before
But everyone might just learn a play
Or say a few words
So that probably doesn't count
Is the real worship
Then is there anyone after him?
Because there are still a lot of female teachers today
Can't say a lot, there are still female teachers in the drama world today
Yes
Thank you
May I ask
If you have any questions
You can ask now
Or if you want to post it in the chat room
I can also help you
Ok
There is a question in the chat room
Is it qualitative research?
Or can it be quantified?
I think I should be considered qualitative research
After all, it is file research
Then analyze
Some articles
Can it be quantified?
This is a good question
Because I did a digital paper before
Then I have put a part of
The file I collected
Is it quantified?
But I think
That quantification is still very shallow
It's more like
All about these gossips
For example, in different cities
Then there are a few
Then there are a few different newspapers
Some cities are also more popular
But this algorithm
There are still some problems
Because you say where the newspapers are the most
Of course, Beijing and Shanghai are the most
But can this explain
Can it be said that it is not popular in Wuxi?
Because it is also very popular in Wuxi
But the newspapers in Wuxi are not as many as those in Beijing and Shanghai
I think
It can be quantified
But there are many traps to be careful
In addition to gossip newspaper
Are there any other sources?
About this
I use gossip newspaper
But some of my other articles
For example
Female actors wrote their own memoirs
Something like this
Then some will
There is one thing I think I can
Just clarify
Why is most of it gossip newspaper?
Because the newspaper did not want to write them
Just these people
They want to discuss more serious things
He didn't want to write these gossips
So this is why I found
Most of them are gossip newspaper
Or what kind of newspaper
Source
Then I have a question
It may be related to this
So at that time, the newspaper
Will not discuss at all
These
Artistic things
Or they will discuss other forms of art
But they feel that the newspaper is not enough
Or why?
For them
This is not art at all
For them, this is like today
For example
Will Jay Chou and Tsai Ing-wen say it is art?
It doesn't seem to be
It's just a popular entertainment
I seem to be a little disrespectful to Jay Chou and Tsai Ing-wen
Sorry
Anyway, in that era
The newspaper is a popular entertainment
You don't think it's art
Popular entertainment is like
Like today's stars
Who is in a relationship with who
Who got married and divorced
Just this feeling
So do you think Jay Chou will discuss these things?
Maybe a lot
Especially
I didn't talk about it in this speech
Probably
Around 1930
There was a shooting case
It's also related to Meng Xiaodong
Anyway
The gossip is widely spread
What do you say about Meng Xiaodong's admirer
Then I'm not happy that Meng Xiaodong is married to Mei Lanfang
And then I'm going to shoot Mei Lanfang
It's about shooting
Of course, the newspaper will report it
But
For gossip
But in general
They may publish a lot
It's a drama advertisement
You can see
What kind of play was played today
But they won't
Write some exaggerated gossip
So I mean
So these newspapers won't write about
Artistic comments on the drama
Or do they actually have any
Artistic comments are not included in the newspaper
According to the newspaper of that era
They will write artistic comments
But they almost only comment on male actors
And it's very serious
That kind of comment
For example
For example, he said
Someone played Si Lang Tan Mu
Then he based on that Si Lang Tan Mu
How to sing each sentence
And then make a super detailed comment
So even in Meng Xiaodong
It's like
It's considered
The first person in the old god
Even after the first person
These shocking newspapers
I still don't want to comment on his drama
I remember that
I have seen some
Not so many
More actually appeared in a newspaper
Called Beiyang Newspaper
That Beiyang Newspaper is basically
Meng Xiaodong's fans
I can't say that the whole Beiyang Newspaper is reporting Meng Xiaodong
But the editor-in-chief of Beiyang Newspaper
Sha Dafeng and several comments in it
They are all Meng Xiaodong's fans
So they reported a lot about him
Whether it's gossip
But because they are fans
So their gossip won't be that bad
They will
There will also be some positive news
About his performance
But first of all, the fans' eyes
Are all with rose filters
So they may also write more
You know
It will be more beautiful
Thank you
Does anyone else have other questions?
Or do you think
I don't speak clearly
Want me to clarify again
How to determine
Gossip newspaper
Is it exaggerated
How to determine
The topic you discussed today
The impact on the aftermath
Okay, first of all, I think
We can't be sure if the gossip newspaper is exaggerated
Because after all
We are not from that era
And even if we are from that era
Everyone will have a different opinion on one thing
I think the only thing I can do
Is to compare different gossip newspapers
To discuss
What they present
What is it
So I'm not going to comment
What the gossip newspaper writes is true or false
That's not important
What I want to discuss is how the gossip newspaper discusses Meng Xiaodong
And the topic I discussed today
The impact on the aftermath
Should refer to contribution
I think
What I care about the most
Is the right to speak in history
And the competition between genders
So what I'm going to discuss
So what I'm going to discuss today
To be honest
I don't care about Meng Xiaodong's story
Whether it's true or false
Whether those comments are true or false
The point is that I want to know
In that society
Through a story like Meng Xiaodong
Their contribution between genders
And the whole country
From the country to the Beijing Opera
To the family
How is their gender
Interaction between power and language
This is what I want to know the most
And then I want to know through this story
To understand that period of time
How the language of the whole society
How does the right to speak work
I hope this answers your question
Then I have another question
If the audience still has you
That is to say
In the process of speaking
That's the second wife in the south
When she reported to her husband
That is to say
Then you mentioned
It seems that this power relationship
It's a bit convoluted
I think it seems
I'm not sure
My doubt is
Many times
You only call one person
It should be said that many times
Kindness seems to be a
Special attack on women
It doesn't sound like
A power relationship computer
But a
A special way to target women
Because
Continue
I just want to say
I want to say
I hardly hear anyone say
A man is kind
But you often hear people like to comment on women
So this is a
I'm repeating
It's a way to target women
Instead of a power relationship computer
I think you're really good at this
I think it's here again
Showed
I think it's about gender
The dynamic and power relationship
I think he seems to be
It's hard to say
It's fixed every time
That is to say
There may be a general trend
But if you look closely
It can be divided into a lot of things
And I totally agree
The kindness of women
Kindness is a plan
But at the same time
They can target this matter
Is to make a big article
For example, they never talk about Wang Minghua
Kindness, they only talk about Fu Zhifang
I think this matter actually reflects
Fu Zhifang at home
He does have power
Because you go to see other
Other is the actor
The relationship between them is that private life
You hardly see anything like Fu Zhifang
Almost all
What do you want to do
If you want to have an affair with someone, have an affair
Then their wife is in the position of the victim
I will add another example
He is not in the Republic of China
He is in
Dorothy Cole
I suddenly forgot
Anyway, it was during the Ming and Qing dynasties
Everyone usually thinks
The status of women
It feels like it's all over
Suppressed by men
But there are also scholars
They will do some research
If you look closely
The relationship in the family
You will find that the male owners
Men are fighting outside
As an official
Then stay away from home
But actually at home
Daughter and son
Support the whole family
So their status
May not be as low as everyone imagines
He used this method to discuss
Sexual power sometimes
Not so absolute
It's like a man
Thank you
Is there any audience
Any questions
If not
I will turn off the recording first