In today's talk, we have Tao Yizhe.
His topic is Taiwan bilingual policy and education review.
The speaker is a teacher with physical education, health education, and English teacher certificate.
He has studied in the US, Europe, the Ministry of Education, and the University of Queensland, Australia.
His research interests include professional development, education, and sports-related issues.
His doctoral research topics include language learning, cross-cultural communication,
how to find language learning experience,
long-term bilingual education experience,
and the participation and observation of Taiwan education and society in recent years.
It is the first time in the country that a bilingual policy and education review can have a deep understanding of macroeconomic analysis.
According to our TARA tradition, we will turn on the microphone to welcome the speaker.
Are you ready?
If you are ready, let's give him a round of applause.
Thank you.
Are these guests in Taiwan or in the US?
Can I know the background of the audience?
I am in the US.
Dr. Chen Tian-Yuan.
What about the others?
Can you turn on the microphone?
I don't know why you are here.
But I will start now.
I thought it was yesterday.
The time you sent me seems to be yesterday.
I didn't schedule anything yesterday.
So, I may not be here for a long time.
If I have a chance, I will share it with you.
I am a teacher in high school.
I am in the second year of Zheng University.
I am also a professor in the Center for Calculus in Zheng University.
I teach calculus.
As you can see in my resume,
I have worked with a lot of organizations.
Let's get back to my background.
I am a senior student.
I majored in PE.
But I like English.
I took the English exam in high school.
When I was in college, I wanted to major in English.
So, I took the English exam.
I don't need to take the exam now.
I just need to apply for the exam.
So, I got my license after graduation.
There are not many PE majors in China.
I also have an English license.
English helped me a lot.
So, I may share it later.
I hope to observe and comment on the state of Chinese in China.
But I still have some ideas.
This is related to my learning experience.
When I was learning English,
my English teacher had little influence on me.
We all learn by ourselves.
The point of self-study is that
the Ministry of Education has been talking about the direction of education.
I learn English not for the exam.
So, I started to apply English in my daily life in middle school.
So, this is how I do it.
When I went to school,
I would ask my classmates to try to interact with me in English.
At that time,
I was 46 years old.
When I was in my teens,
it was hard to take the college entrance exam.
It was not easy to take the exam at that time.
It was too late to prepare for the exam.
It was hard to speak English,
listen to English music,
and check the English list.
However, this kind of learning experience
was helpful for the exam.
So, it also influenced
my objective view of the current topic,
the policy of bilingualism.
Anyway,
I got the scholarship from the Ministry of Education.
Then, I chose the Human Movement Studies
at the University of Queensland, Australia
as my major to study
in the Department of Science and Regional Studies.
At that time,
my research was focused on...
As I was studying in the Department of Science and Regional Studies,
I got the scholarship from
Sports Coaching and Training.
It was focused on the direction of natural science.
That was the general trend in Taiwan.
However, when I went to Australia,
I followed my teachers.
They went to areas like
Sports Psychology, Sports Education,
Sports Society,
and the disciplinary area.
Therefore, my doctoral thesis
was focused on direct research.
I studied the topic
of a local organization
representing the Olympic Games.
The key word is
Workplace Learning.
Workplace Learning is an area
that I use.
I studied the professional talents
in the area
and how to develop professionally.
The Olympic team I chose
was actually
the Olympic diving team.
If you go to Australia in 2000,
you can get a gold medal
for diving in a row.
If you have a certain understanding
of sports,
you know that diving is usually
dominated by China.
Why did Australia get a gold medal
for diving in a row?
Because they hired
foreign coaches.
Especially,
Chinese elite coaches.
Therefore, my research topic
was to study how these people
learn and develop
through cultural exchange.
Of course, the focus
was mainly on the coach himself.
For example, how did he get
his professional skills?
Of course, it has to do with his
professional experience or
where he has taught.
However, there is an important point
about their cross-cultural communication.
In other words,
their language,
because the requirements in Australia
are different from Taiwan.
Foreigners go there
to learn
in their official language.
For example, in Taiwan,
if you know,
like Howard,
but we still send
translators for him.
This is the difference in nationality.
However, in Australia,
no matter where you work,
even if you are a chef,
or a professional,
you have to use
their official language to communicate.
Therefore, this is a challenge
for foreign coaches,
especially for non-English-speaking countries.
Therefore, my research topic
was to ask them how they learned
their language.
In this process,
I integrated my own
master's training,
personal interest in long-term English,
and the training
in my research.
Therefore,
I have this part
of my language policy.
The most important thing is that
in fact, in the country of 2030,
or the policy of 2030,
before it started in 2017,
I had been teaching
for more than 15 years.
In 2000,
when I was working
in a school,
or when I was
a teacher,
I was actually
trying to teach
all-English or
sign language sports.
Therefore,
I have 15 years of experience in this area.
Because of this situation,
I have become
a problem for many
domestic
frontline workers,
teaching staff,
or those who
criticize
the policy.
I have no problem with
this.
However,
in theory,
I may not be able to
implement the framework
of English.
Therefore,
I have to learn
not only from
the experience of
ethics,
but also from
the experience of
science.
Therefore,
in addition to my
major,
I have been
teaching
for more than
15 years.
This is also
a major
interest of mine.
This is also
a major
interest of mine.
This is also
a major
interest of mine.
In addition to
studying in Australia,
I went to
the United States.
Before I went to
the United States,
although the English
I learned in Taiwan
was not typical,
I still found
some differences.
For example,
their everyday English
was different from
our training.
This made me
think about
what I should do
to improve my English.
For example,
when I traveled to
Europe,
I went to
the International
Olympic Youth Conference
in Greece.
I noticed that
the official language
was English.
I noticed that
the official language
was English.
We're the
scholars of Taiwan,
Japan, and Korea.
We're all based in LGBTQI community.
But I was the
moderator of
the Japanese and Korean
oral posters yesterday,
which means I am the host of them.
But I was the moderator of
the Japanese and Korean
oral posters yesterday,
which means I am the host of them.
I have a good feeling about the details
of the post.
I have a solution, of course.
So, today I'm going to
talk about a few
key issues.
And how far
the research has gone.
Let's see if we can interact.
This chart
shows
my language learning.
I'm learning
PopFish,
and I'm using
language in my daily life.
I'm using language in my daily life.
That's about it.
As I mentioned earlier,
if you're interested,
you can google my name.
You'll find
many comments
and articles.
Besides my book,
I have many other articles.
If you're interested,
you'll find
many articles
and articles
Chinese
In my opinion
Shuang Yu should
go further
rather than
looking for
so-called
non-exams
subjects
like sports, art, music
and so on
He is still learning
Chinese math
calculus
biology
and so on
When it comes to sports
he suddenly changes to bilingual mode
This is a
very interesting question
If you look at it
from many perspectives
In Taiwan
Shuang Yu
has a...
Let's take a look at this chart
Why is there so much discussion
in Taiwan
so far?
There are basically three reasons
Three perspectives
The first one is
a mess
To be honest
Shuang Yu is obviously
going to drop out of school
Taipei City
will announce 100%
Shuang Yu will drop out of
high school
In fact, they are also
moving in this direction
All schools in Taiwan
have been
looking for
Shuang Yu program
Shuang Yu teaching
or Shuang Yu class
including high-level EMI
So if you happen to be
in the United States
studying
In fact, before 2013
you were relatively smart
Because you
People believe you can
EMI
That is, you can teach in full English
But we
are from the same city
But more teachers
educate
and learn
acquire their teaching experience
locally in Taiwan
So their Shuang Yu policy
There is no way
So in this situation
what I said
Three kinds
One is a teacher
will say this policy
Just kidding
Opposed
The second is like us
Because we think about its benefits
You get a lot of benefits
of these people
Or you have seen
That is,
English can really
lead us
At least we can
quickly push ourselves
or learn foreign things
This is what we think is good
So YES
In the middle, he did not understand
He just like Wu Bing
will drift
In this case, you will find
that all policies are the same
He just voted
I just finished voting last week
YES, I vote for you
Or NO, I vote for you
All the same
So I may
talk about this first
The first question
In the end, Shuang Yu country
What are you doing
Shuang Yu policy
This
He is not in 2017
He is in 2000
He is a think tank
in Hainan
You go to read that
Taiwan's English policy
In addition to our traditional understanding
English teaching
Taiwan's English teaching
I think it is quite successful
It should be said that the so-called success is
We
Our
English is at least better than Japan and Korea
At least better than Japan
I don't know why
Maybe because
Our relationship with the United States
Or
Taiwanese
Watch a lot of HBO
Japanese should watch
But
This is learning English
English
But now you have to be comprehensive
To many subjects
Even industrial
There are some banks in Taiwan
They are now holding Shuang Yu demonstration area
The question is
Why do we have Shuang Yu
Is Shuang Yu class in English class?
What if the teacher
I can't teach Chinese
What to do
There are some teachers who want to do Shuang Yu
Some are like us
I think
Where is the beef
Is there any place
This is all
A very interesting
So this question
Everyone is like this
Everyone has an answer
Different answers
But back to a
Level of tool value
The answer may be this
Just for
Take it as a
Weapon
It is a tool
It is a tool for communication
It is a
Our National Development and Reform Commission
And so on
Claimed
Can let us sell to the world
Especially the English class world
Because they are still in the world
Leading
Whether in technology
Or
Leading on many systems
The so-called lead is
That is
They are stronger
To be honest
It's all relative
Then we can follow these
Powerful people
They can understand us faster
it is good
This situation
Why 2030 Shuang Yu
Shuang Yu
policy
of course
This question
country
No special
You may have a bottom in your heart
I just talked about two thousand years
Tainan Gang
Think of this strategy
Then you
Since Tainan Gang
You will think of some color problems
That
in fact
It is very clear that
He is actually
a
Going to America
Strategic policy
That is to say
No matter how much you talk about
But now
Two months ago
We all know that Pelosi flew to Taiwan
Then why not
Li Keqiang is in Taiwan
My question is like this
It means that Shuang Yu
Policy is actually in
language
Do you say
Weakened Chinese
Someone proposed
Didn't we all say that Guo Wenke
Zhou Wenke is even a university teacher
Shuang Yu
Of course he also has his thoughts
But why did he let people
Study English
That is obviously
Have his
The consideration of our partnership
Just like our New Southbound
He doesn't want to
Put all the eggs on the shore
He wants
How kind
Especially to report the correct answer
So this is what you see
This situation
So this situation is
We want to say
So you have to understand
In the end
This policy
What are those people thinking
what
and so
This is also
Then you think about it
Then I want Shuang Yu today
What do I think about it
Why is the environment so noisy
You may have
Think about it slowly
I think this is
This is a low part
Then I personally feel
Shuang Yu
For Taiwan
The reflection of the education system is very good
because
He
We are talking about cross-fields now
That is actually
English
Non-English class
He is actually helping to some extent
English class
What is English class doing
Our English class is actually
Many are in
Preparing for the exam
Early reading and writing
Writing words
Understand grammar
Write some short texts
In the past ten years
Twenty years
The country began to test
Listen
But he still didn't get the number
So it becomes our students
Used to learn English
So when it comes to real foreigners
I can't speak a word
So I think Shuang Yu
At this time
Not only expand his
English learning
In addition to imagination
He is also
Will return to one
If you put it
Think clearly about this matter
You will find out
Teacher
Can use the right words
To solve the problem of our long-term education
Is to focus on the exam
Instead of application
Of course the exam is also an application
But that is to say
The exam is expected
That may be three years later
That time
Or the usual period
But I'm talking about the applicability
The breadth and depth is
You may
In this situation
You may think in
Ordinary
For long-term application
Then international
I think this is a
Shuang Yu to
An opportunity point
This is probably the case
This question is a bit
Professional Shuang Yu
Teaching
So probably
Needless to say
Take a look
I should have a question
Let me see
I think it's still simple here
Just say ok
If Shuang Yu
Today
In
Our purpose
Everyone has a certain idea
Then maybe a speech
Can be done
Then you will meet one
When Shuang Yu goes to class
In fact, if you
I'm going to college
How to teach
In fact, it is called ENI
Written here
But now
For example, you
You have to put your subject in full English
In fact
This is also the case in the international market
Many international schools
I'm not talking about universities
Research Institute
International
When everyone is looking for a job
ENI
Then go to ENI
That's all
No competitiveness
Of course, under middle school
That is to say, he may have a lot of teaching
Strategy
Then use some of his subject
Theoretical framework
Then go to Shuang Yu teaching
This part of the domestic people are less talking
It's just me
I can think of this thing
Of course, because I have a book
So probably this situation
I speak faster
Shuang Yu teaching
In fact, in the end
How does he say
He didn't say you think
It's important that you do it
but
He wants to go back to a learning site
Because we all know that students actually
The gap is very large
So there are people using that screen gap
He will expand
Weakness
With that kind
Their imagination is English
Home is better
So this one
Cultural language
What capital is pulling more
So when the teacher was on
There is also a
Maybe he studied English
So he decided to read science
Still have to read English
Now Shuang Yu
Simply put, it's actually Shuang Yu
He will meet one later
Whether you are well prepared
Can students accept
Always a problem
So he is a teacher
A two-way interaction
So you teach any class
You teach any client without Shuang Yu
Also encountered this problem
So it becomes
The reflection inside is very important
The teacher's sensitivity
Because the teacher has power
Of course now students
They start to have a say
They will criticize you
So this becomes
This duality becomes important
But another level of Shuang Yu
I also mentioned here
It is also less mentioned in China
Must consider language and culture
Duality and equality
it is good
Because many of us
You can show English
Very awesome
But this is a bit like
It's a bit like saying
Self-respect
I think this mentality is very bad
A better mentality should be
Equal to each other
For example, when we are today
When Shuang Yu was teaching
Uh
You see a lot of English teachers
When a lot of Shuang Yu teachers are in class
His blackboard is full of English
Then he speaks a lot of English
Then he tried to teach
Well, that's fine
If you can absorb
I will expand your experience
But I think Shuang Yu
Another level is
You should put your own good things
Use the language that the other person understands
Teach him
Just this is called English
So for example, when I go to
Sports class
In addition to going abroad
Some sports
I will also work hard to teach students
Put your own good things
For example, martial arts
Martial arts
What do you know
Teach foreigners
For example, this time you use English
You don't have to learn from others
But you have to put your own good things
Teach others
Even if we are in the United States
When I was studying in New York
When I was studying in Australia
We want to cook a Taiwanese dish for each other
That concept
You know our good
Then
You teach your good
Hamburger for me
I introduce my delicious
I'll give you a pancake
This is mutual
So language design
Shuang Yu course design
I will consider this
Won't go over
But they have to come over
I think this part is quite important
I also think this is
If the Ministry of Foreign Affairs is pushing the Shuang Yu course
There must be something local
International
Local
This thinking
Ok now back to me
Maybe
Maybe these
Maybe with us
This
Because we all have the right
What is the current level of domestic and foreign Shuang Yu research
If you
Some of you who come to listen today
I think this is
Probably the same
That is to say, this is a very good graduation topic
Because in addition to the journal
There has always been a need
There are idols
P1
There is a need for this kind of journal
There are people who make people confused
We will use different methods
We will find different problems
Then use different methods to solve it
Because it always has
A mysterious color
People will be together because
I don't understand
Ha ha
It's like this at the moment
Shuang Yu
Research in China
at present
There is
Continuous output
That foreign trend
Foreign trend
Especially in the field of language
There are also many
Then I have
If you look at this field
I think there is a very interesting place
I will introduce one here
Such a piece
This one is about Spain
One of their case studies
White Linguist
I think this one is more interesting
Because he
Just like all research
In one
This kind
Direction
Will produce a lot
Sometimes the opposite
found
Basically he is talking about this one
Will Shuang Yu
Affect the amount of physical activity
This research question
Ask this
That
In fact, the amount of physical activity
Is the imagination of everyone in the gym
I want you to come to the gym today
I usually hope you have
Exercise
Don't say what kind of technology
You just
Heart rate increase
To run a few thousand steps
Sweating
Then I think you have reached
Certain requirements of the gym
So his thinking is
If I come in today
Will it cause this
Positive or negative
What is their relationship
Ask this
But this question
In fact, you use another department to ask
For example, I brought you in today
Mathematical ability
Does it affect the teaching section?
Wait a minute
Will it cause good or bad
He asked you
So you can see from this one
He is
Selected
Some key words
Then he hopes
Students can achieve moderate
Vigorous physical activity
Medium strength
Moderate
A little tired
Physical activity
Then he defined it as
MVPA
The teaching mode he uses is
CLEAR
Compton Language Integrated Learning
The so-called bilingual teaching mode
Very popular in Europe
Then he went to intervene
So one of the groups is
CLEAR mode
Experimental group
Experimental group is normal teaching
The thinking is like this
Then go
Quantified to start doing
How does he do it
He just let the students
Put that
Maybe a calculator or something
He talked about that thing
Measure his activity
Then test
A few weeks
Of course you
There is a fact of teaching
So he knows
He wants to invite
One of the participants is
CLEAR teacher
Come to teach
That
Before the result
I thought they had another group
Research
They found it would affect
The so-called
Obstruction
Reduce students' physical activity
There was another team before
It's like this
Because the amount of language is too much
Leading to a decrease in student exercise time
Is this side
Hit him
Hit him here
No
Look at this
% of time per session spent on
MVPA
Use CLEAR
Do you see the average value?
GENERAL
35.15B
The control group of CLEAR
Obviously high
OK
Probably
A lot higher
Boys and girls have
His instrument
The amount is shown
Very simple research
Then he will explain now
This result
Why is that so?
The previous explanation said because the teacher
Too much nonsense
Language orientation
OK
Let me tell you
Because he used something
This table
COMMUNICATIVE TEACHING STRATEGY
That is to say
What
The way the teacher uses
REFORCING THE MESSAGE
THROUGH THE COMPLEMENTARY NONVERBAL COMMUNICATION CHANNEL
That is
We say
When the teacher teaches in Chinese
So I'll tell you
Use more
POSTURE, GESTURE
Or EYE CONTACT
You
Like this
NONVERBAL
You can say this
This is one
His strategy
The second
ADAPTING THE LANGUAGE USED
TO SUIT THE STUDENTS' LEVEL
See people speak human language
See ghosts speak ghost language
According to the student's level
To adjust his
INSTRUCTION
Even sometimes
I really use bilingual
Not all English
He may not understand this student
So he thinks this is
Will make the student understand
That
Another reason is that
But this has nothing to do with the student's level
His explanation is another
Because of the student's attention
In order to understand the teacher's English
Is there a student interview here?
The teacher explains something
We will pay more attention
OK
He said this
If we don't pay attention
Then we
We wouldn't have been able to play
OK
So the student should be very focused
So his explanation is
Because the student is focused enough
Understand
The student's physical activity
He justified
To explain why
Physical activity will be good
So it's interesting
From my professional point of view
I think this is interesting
I dare not say ridiculous
Because the previous article
The article talks about
Because the teacher said too much
OK
I want to say
You didn't see the previous article
You can see it here
What is it called?
Physical
Look at a good article
This may be Q2
Tier 2 or above
Q1
Both are good articles
Then
From my professional point of view
I said that it can be published
What does it mean?
It means that the current research
This aspect
The gap is still very large
Very large
This is what I mean
So actually
At present, my understanding is
Research on scientific research
Mostly
Besides review
What is the topic?
This is one
The other is similar to this
Is
Experiment
Case study
Accurate design
Or
This kind of field
Actual observation
Then
And so on
Or the teacher himself
Domestic is also doing
The teacher himself
Design
Design a course
Then look at the amount of students' language
Double language
See if his wisdom has improved
Or learn motivation
This is one I have seen so far
But it has a lot of details
Just this teaching strategy
He has a lot of scenes to play
Because you are all teaching
Strategy
You just have a multi-fidelity
Maybe another one will be made
The problem is what do you want to do with this one
His
The contribution on the table becomes
I have to look at the paper again
So this is currently
I think
I think he is a
If you are
This part of the words
Can also talk
Because cross-border double language policy
Can also do
Because some people have been misunderstanding
Say
Because the time is an hour
I want to ask
Do you mind
Let's enter the Q&A time
I have to finish
So what I mean
This becomes
He can do a lot
Including national recognition
Can do
He can do a lot of material
So the conclusion is the front
Some key points
Everyone knows that the national strategy is like this
We have to consider
How to use it
Take it as your own
Then because of the double language
After all, if it is related to the educational field
He is actually a
It's a science and art
So if you order a meal, you have to go
Figure it out
Because I want to listen to the audience today
Everyone is a talent
I believe in the future
Taiwan's double language
There has always been a chance
These detailed policies are still
Especially in the second part of the country
The country is currently like
The teacher who wants to take the double language
He himself does not have a foreign language level
So this is a problem
Then the science and art part actually has a lot of
There are many gaps and different directions
It's worth it
To study
The above is my sharing today
With
Five-point conclusion
Thank you for your listening
There is no
How to face the gap between the rich and the poor
I feel
This is from social science
If I am a policy maker
Of course I will hope
Divide resources
To the disadvantaged
All the way
This is
I think this is
Not just in Shuangyu, many
Many departments
There are also many infrastructure
Do it like this
For example, there is a road here
Do I have a road in the east?
Then you also see
It becomes
I think this is all
The government is doing it, because now
In fact, this part of the home network
Because in Taiwan
Even Lidao, he has a network
So now there is
Online, so he actually has nothing to do with Shuangyu
Become resources
Give you a computer
Then there is a match for you, this is not a problem
He knows that talents can be sent to you
I think this is the policy end
Or the executor is doing it
He tried to do this
This is from a structural point of view
Everyone knows the answer now
Or go back to a
Screen gap
I am not very rich
I am a middle school
Our home
Still personal
Investment in Shuangyu
The psychological
Should be imagined
No matter how much you give
No interest in learning
There is no way
So the screen gap
Taipei
The resource environment is good
English is still bad
So in a way
Resource allocation or screen gap
It's just a structural problem
It looks like a problem
The real problem is back to the executor
itself
Did he block his antenna
This is my answer
You
What angle do you look at this
You should emphasize
Just
They have no way to
Open that antenna
Because we say there are many
Many people are ignorant
So the focus is on
Besides the policy
Is there any possibility
More friendly environment
That friendlier environment
Maybe it's not just
Close this kind of
You give him a flat screen
Computer or
Or a visual problem
He may have some
Some other accessories
Other problems include that
Maybe because I know some
Just
On the execution side
Or say
Students
If he is not interested
How do you deal with it
This is a problem that stimulates the group
Colleagues and their own
Some family factors
This is not a single face
Can consider
This is the answer I can think of
Then there is another one here
Is the applicant
The problem is
Although the education language and related areas
There is a lot of discussion about the bilingual education policy
But the public in Taiwan
The impact of this policy is limited
How should we make the public
I think Taiwan
Taiwan
It should not only be bilingual
Is everyone
Because the common people are mostly
I care more about his daily life
For example, you said
You said that Caiqi
Cai's stall
he
Does he value bilingual
Does he have a cell phone
But the news he may see
It's not what we care about
His same level as us
Different
So if you say you
You want this bilingual
Is to make everyone feel important
Should be able to enjoy
His
Sweet story
So I mean the bilingual policy
Your propaganda
I think I do a lot
Because you are now in Taiwan
The street is full of bilingual
Public transportation
Excessive
Our COVID-19 propaganda
There is also English
So I don't think it's in the media
Or policy announcement
This part is not
But it is clear that Taiwan is doing it
But the problem is
Because he has no way to let the general public
To use bilingual
So I mean
If you ask this industry
Bilingual policy is to open up
The opportunity for international talent to operate in Taiwan
Because of us
Talent
It should be said that our current population
Group
With that kind of culture
Distribution is still local
This is what we are talking about
What this province
Hakka
There are some new names
But we have fewer English-speaking countries
You really have to distance
To let everyone know more about the necessity of this policy
Just take Tianmu
Tianmu itself is a
Tianmu and Xinyi District
Why was it built as a bank?
Demonstration area
Because he is there
There are people from English-speaking countries
In this situation
He can't buy vegetables in Tianmu
He can't speak Chinese
He has to use
He can only speak English
Then we say that we don't really understand these people
He has to use
Appropriate English to interact with him
But you have to talk a little bit
Then this is what I said
Every day must
You don't have to promote this situation
He has to learn
So in the long run
Bilingual policy
What we are doing now
How do we let talents come in?
English-speaking willing to come
Then he can
Live everywhere in Taiwan
Work
and so on
Then naturally we were talking about those
People who don't really understand him
Let me go to Australia
You are in the United States
There are Indians around
There are
Anyway, non-Americans
Then we all have to
Communicate in the same language
If it is like this in Taiwan now
We communicate in the same language
It's called Chinese
But now there is one more
The second language is English
Then he will
Become a must
That's called Affordance
Because there are many foreigners
Now it's called Guangdong
But in case the future is long-term
Then it will become a
Let's take the past
Taiwan speaks more Minnan language
Later
The civil war retreated
Chinese
Mandarin becomes
To speak like this
Then it will be mingled
That's how it is now
So the policy
Too much is just an expression
The reality is
People come in
He lives here
We naturally understand
The necessity of bilingual
This is
Can go longer
That's another way
I want to add
Of course this process needs to wait
And then the other
During this waiting
Our bilingual skills in the cloud
Express
B
Sentence pronunciation
Use words
Will
Inevitably run out of Taiwan
English or bilingual
I am with
Domestic education ideas are the same
This is
reasonable
Bilingual development direction
So this is also
Also OK
This is the specific
That is
Our Taiwanese bilingual
Taiwan is bilingual development
Will
Is there a line with Singapore?
With Europe and Spain
Or many regions
Achieve bilingual and different
Direction of cultural scenery
above
Thank you
Does anyone have any questions?
If you want
You can turn on your microphone
Speak like this
If not
Let's end the video
Thank you
See you next time
Bye