From now on, we'll move on to the recording part.
We'll put this speech on YouTube as well.
Please go there to replay it.
Ding, please share your screen.
Okay, before I share my screen,
let me tell you who I am.
I'm Chen Dingwen.
Thank you for the introduction.
I'm Dingwen Zhang, also known as Chen Dingwen.
I'm a post-doctoral researcher at the University of Göttingen in Germany.
I think TARA is an interesting organization.
I like its purpose and purpose.
It's to help young people in Taiwan
and young scholars to have a platform
where we can communicate with each other
and get to know what everyone is busy with
and what research they're doing.
Why do I know about TARA?
It's because I saw it on Facebook.
I don't know why, but one day,
this ad popped up and I thought,
is this a young scholar from Taiwan?
It's T-Y-R-A.
A is association, R is researcher.
T-Y-Y is what?
Young scientist?
Young researcher.
Y is young.
T is Taiwan.
I thought, as a young scholar from Taiwan,
I should join a group like this.
When I was a kid,
I spent most of my high school and college years in Taiwan.
I only had the chance to do research in Europe
when I was a doctor.
To me, TARA is a whole new world.
I know that most of TARA's members
are from the U.S.
I wanted to meet friends from the U.S.
to see if they were doing ecological research like me
or if they were interested in soil,
or if they were doing research on evolution.
I really wanted to meet these people,
so I joined this group and joined their activities.
For example, they have a teacher-student program.
In this program, they help young people in Taiwan
and those of us who have gone abroad to study.
We help them on their way to study abroad,
so that they can make a difference.
We can also share with them
what we have learned and experienced
during our journey of studying abroad.
So that they don't go down the wrong path
or find a better way
to explore their future career development.
OK.
This is a brief introduction to TARA.
I'm going to start my speech.
I don't want to make this
a formal and serious presentation.
If you have any questions
during my presentation,
you can ask me anytime.
Of course, I know that
there may not be any formal questions.
I also have a small request.
If you don't mind,
could you please turn on your camera
so that I can see your faces?
OK.
If you don't mind,
could you please turn on your camera
so that I can see your faces?
I want to know if you find this part
particularly difficult to understand,
or if you find this part particularly boring,
or if you find this part particularly interesting.
I can explain further.
If you don't mind,
could you please turn on your camera
so that I can see your faces?
OK.
I'm going to start my speech.
First, I'm going to share my screen.
I'm going to try to
make good use of my time.
I know that we only have one hour today.
What do you see now?
Do you see
the screen that I'm sharing?
Lin, do you see the screen
that I'm sharing?
OK.
What you see now is
the structure of the root of the plant
under the ground.
When you zoom in,
what do you see?
Have you ever thought about this question?
Are there any creatures
that we don't know
or haven't seen?
I'm a soil ecologist.
I'm particularly interested
in the evolution of
soil animals.
At the same time,
I'm a mentor.
I joined Taira's
mentor project.
I also teach some college students,
even PhD students.
I'm also a podcaster.
I'm actually running a podcast
in 2020.
It's a bit scientific,
but it's called
Do You Read Paper?
It's about soil ecology.
Some of you may know me
and I'm glad you can
participate in my speech
and listen to me
share my work and learning process.
This is a typical
mountainous forest
in Europe.
If I tell you
that there are
thousands of
animals in this forest,
what can you see
from this photo?
In fact, you can't see them.
Where are they?
They live
in these fallen leaves
and in the soil
below the fallen leaves.
If you dig
a piece of soil,
you can see
the surface of the soil.
It's about 5 cm wide
and 5 cm deep.
5 to 10 cm.
In such a small space,
you can see
a maze-like structure.
You can see
the fallen leaves
at the top
and the solid soil
at the bottom.
In such a small space,
it will produce some
environmental kinks.
For example,
water has a kink.
When rainwater falls,
the fallen leaves are wet
and the soil is full of nutrients.
In such a small space,
which is very different
in terms of
geological value and
environment,
it can accommodate
all kinds of
different creatures.
We call such a space
a soil.
But in academia,
we will also use
a term called
detritivores.
We will assume that
it eats these
plants and animals.
So it is also called
a ten-year-old detritivores.
Living in
this
maze
or fallen leaves,
you can
think about
how many of these
animals
can survive
in a square meter
of soil.
We can see
10,000 to
2 million detritivores.
This is an amazing number.
Think about how many grains
you eat a day.
But in such a
small space,
you can see
so many individual animals.
How many of these
animals can survive
in a square meter of
Wendai Forest?
Most of these
detritivores are very small.
Although the size of
their body is large,
most of them are
smaller than 1 cm.
Of course, there are also
centipedes, centipedes,
and spiders that
are larger than 1 cm.
We generally call
small centipedes
and small centipedes
as small centipedes.
However,
there are also
small centipedes
that are smaller
than 1 cm.
For example,
the centipede
is a small centipede,
which is
a small centipede.
We call it
However,
also there are
medium and
medium-sized animals.
Why is it important?
Because when you
study animals,
the first thing
you will learn is
how to classify them
according to their size.
Medium-sized,
large-sized,
and medium-sized.
In addition,
you can see these
are also medium-sized.
There are some special ones
like centipedes,
centipedes,
and synphyrenes,
polyporynes,
and scorpions.
I will not explain
the term here,
otherwise we may not have enough time today.
What other medium-sized animals
like centipedes and
centipedes are?
They are also medium-sized animals.
I like
centipedes very much.
What is a centipede?
You should listen to my podcast.
It should be in the fourth episode.
I have introduced
a science book on centipedes.
Let me explain it to you.
Centipedes are not
centipedes.
Centipedes are not insects.
Strictly speaking,
centipedes are not insects.
Centipedes can be considered
one of the six main species.
Centipedes are now classified
as spiny centipedes.
In the past, centipedes were classified as spiny centipedes.
Centipedes are now classified as spiny centipedes.
Therefore, centipedes are the
close relatives of insects.
How long has centipedes
existed in the history of
chemistry and evolution?
Centipedes have existed since the ancient times.
Centipedes are one of the
first species of centipedes
that came to the earth.
Centipedes are one of the first species of centipedes
There are 9,000 species of centipedes in the world.
We can classify them into
four different species,
30 different species.
The first species is
Entomorphia.
It is a more obvious species.
Most of them live on the surface.
Centipedes are
more expressive.
Most of their food
comes from plants.
Most of their food comes from plants.
Another species is
Podromorpha.
This species has a more variable shape.
Compared to the centipede
Entomorphia,
Podromorpha has a shorter spring.
I will talk about the spring later.
Podromorpha is a species
that lives in the soil.
It does not need to use spring.
Most of the spring of Podromorpha
is relatively short.
There is also Nenepleona
and Simipleona.
These two species of centipedes
are round and look like mice.
I remember a classmate
who likes to study Simipleona.
And a Taiwanese student
studying the centipedes
at a teacher's lab.
He specially studied the Simipleona,
who has symptoms
of this wood plant.
The centipede
was very cute.
Centipedes live onLAUND very cutely
and grows on the surface.
But the Nenepleona
looks like the Centipedes,
but sticks out.
So they mostly grow
on the surface.
The centipede
has an important feature.
Can you see my sign?
I hope you can see it.
The centipede jumps
because it has a
bouncy structure
at its butt.
This bouncy structure
helps it resist
the attack of the centipede.
So this thing
can make it leave
its original position.
That's why it's called a centipede.
What does a centipede do?
Centipedes have
the ability to regulate
microorganisms in the ecosystem.
Centipedes can also
affect the group of soil
or promote
or change the
fallout in the soil.
It also affects the
chemical cycle of the soil
and helps the plants.
The role of the centipede
in the ecosystem
is not only to be a
nourisher,
but also to be a
separator.
The centipede can be
a primary decomposer
and a secondary decomposer.
In addition to being
a primary decomposer
and a secondary decomposer,
some centipedes can also
be a nourisher.
Centipedes can also be
a nourisher
in the soil.
For example,
some spiders or
nourishing ants can eat centipedes.
Centipedes have a softer body
compared to
other ants.
Their body is softer,
so centipedes are
more delicious than
other hard ants.
Nourishing ants, spiders, ants, etc.
They are also considered
as food for other species.
So,
this is the first part.
I promised you half of the science,
and the other half is
half of the academic.
OK, do you have any questions?
Let me see if there are
people I know online.
Oh, I see some people I know.
I'd like to say hello to all of you.
If I didn't have time to say hello just now.
Okay, I'll stop here.
If you have any questions,
or if you don't understand
what I'm saying,
please feel free to
ask now.
I'll give you about
one minute to ask.
Does it look like there are no questions?
OK.
Let's continue.
Why do we want to know
about
centipedes?
Since centipedes
are very important
to the ecosystem,
why do we want to know
about centipedes?
Because centipedes
are very important
to the ecosystem.
Of course, centipedes
have a certain impact
on the ecosystem,
but we don't know
enough about them.
So we want to know
who they are,
why they are here,
and why these species
can survive here.
Why it's them,
not others?
In 1975,
Anderson
came up with an explanation
to explain why
there are so many
centipedes in the soil.
Why are there so many centipedes
in the soil?
As I said,
there are tens of thousands
of centipedes per square meter.
Why are there so many
centipedes in the soil?
Why are there so many centipedes
in the soil?
He summed up
that there are a lot of food resources
in the soil.
Second, we don't know
what they eat.
They eat different kinds of food.
Third, the soil
has a high level of environmental sustainability.
This was his idea
in 1975.
Now it's 2022,
almost 50 years later.
What have we learned?
How far has the research
progressed in the past 50 years?
Is there any new hypothesis
or new technology
that can help us
answer the question
why there are so many
centipedes in the soil?
Why are there so many
If you dig a soil
and put it under a microscope,
you can see
centipedes,
and centipedes.
Ecology tells us
that if you study biology in college,
you may learn about
ecology, biophysics,
and biophysics.
Can we use the knowledge
we learn
or the knowledge
we learn in school
to explain the phenomenon
we see?
This is my research.
I study the biological geography
and their evolution
in the ecology of centipedes.
The question asked in the biological geography
is what is the distribution pattern?
Is the biological geography
from low to high
along a certain gradient?
For example, along the gradient of the sea level,
along the gradient of temperature,
along the gradient of water.
This is the issue
that biological geography deals with.
What is the issue
that the ecology of centipedes deals with?
What is the interaction effect?
Do they have some special features
that can help them live in that place?
What do they eat
to maintain their species?
The third issue
is the evolution of biology.
The question asked in the evolution of biology
is what is the origin of biodiversity?
How do these diversities
come from?
Do they change from less to more
or from more to less?
What changes
besides the shape of the body
and the different features?
Do they have some genetic basis?
Is this related
to the interrelationship
between species?
Can the organism
create or develop
its own niche,
its own ecological position,
its own opportunity
to reproduce more
or to diversify?
This is the content of the evolution of biology.
I'm using
a framework
called CTPE,
Community Trade and Phylogenetic Ecology.
In Chinese, it stands for
This is actually
a more comprehensive discipline.
It requires knowledge
other than the traditional
community ecology.
It also requires the concept of
evolution of biology
or system development of biology.
How does it study?
Assuming that
you can see the composition
of different species
on an environmental scale.
You will see
certain characteristics
of these species
in observation,
so you can
divide them into different species.
We will infer
the characteristics of
these species,
and assess
what happened to them.
Are there any processes
that lead to
the results you see now?
What are these processes?
There is a book in 2016
written by
Mark Barron.
It is about the theory of
ecological communities.
In this theory,
he tells us that
the structure of the community
is made up of
four main processes.
The first process
is the selection process.
It is also called
the filtering process.
The second process is
the drift process.
It is a random process
that affects
a small group of species.
The third process is
the dispersion process.
The reason why the species
are divided into four
processes is because
the species are
divided into three
processes.
The fourth process is
the seeding process.
In my view,
a group of species
is mainly affected
by these four processes.
It is not what you see now.
The ecological processes
you see now
are the results of
the filtering process.
If you see that
the shape of a group of species
is very different,
it is the result of
the dispersion process.
It sounds logical,
so it can be done.
Let's take a look at
the results of my
previous research
on land animals.
The filtering process
plays a role in
the group of species we study.
Here are two examples.
One is a worm,
and the other is an ant in a jar.
This is a study
we did in Changbai Mountain,
Northeastern China.
We surveyed
the growth of
a species in a group of worms
along 10 different heights.
We looked at the shape of
its body,
and the proportion of
the dark and light colors
in the group.
We found that
the higher the height,
the lower the amount
of egg in the soil.
The higher the height,
the lower the amount
of egg in the soil,
and the darker the color
in the worm group.
The color of the body
is an important shape
of the worm.
This is the reason
why the color of the worm
is different.
Another example is
a project I'm doing
in the tourism area
in Indonesia.
This is a project
we did two or three years ago.
We surveyed ants in jars
and collected them
in a sprayer.
We looked at the characteristics
of ants in jars
and collected them
in a sprayer.
We found that
in four different environments,
such as tropical rainforests,
rainforests,
rubber fields,
and zoological gardens,
the characteristics of ants
in jars
and their
habitat patterns
were selected by the environment.
This is the pattern.
How did the environment come about?
The degree of degradation of the environment
was caused by man-made development
and the way the land was used.
As a result,
these special-shaped ants
were selected.
You can see the shape
of these species.
In addition to the color of the body,
what else can you see?
The size of the body
and the shape of the body.
To put it simply,
we can divide the shape
into two different categories.
One is called Beta-nitrate
and the other is called Alpha-nitrate.
Beta-nitrate refers to those
that are related to the environment,
such as the durability of the environment,
such as the color of the body.
You can think of it
as a Beta-nitrate.
In addition,
the shape of Alpha-nitrate
is related to the way
the ants feed.
This is related to the way
they use resources.
If you observe the shape
of a species in a group,
there may be similarities
and there may not be similarities.
You can see that
there are three groups
in the three boxes on the right.
Take a closer look
at which ones are similar
and which ones are not.
The shape of the three ants
in the three boxes on the right
is the same,
but the color is different.
Take a closer look
at the size of the body.
The size of the three ants
in the three boxes on the right
is the same,
but the color is different.
You can see that
if you observe its shape,
you can deduce that
in addition to filtering,
Alpha-nitrate is similar
in the same group.
For Alpha-nitrate,
the Alpha-nitrate difference
is relatively large
in the same group.
The pigmentation
that I just mentioned
is the body color change
of the insects along the height.
This shows
that the body color
is a beta-nitrate
and the alpha-nitrate
can help the insects
live on higher altitudes.
What is Alpha-nitrate?
It is related to food resources.
How do we study
food resources in soil animals?
What do they eat?
In the early days,
they simply put an insect
under a microscope
to see what contents
are in its intestine.
This technology is very good
in the study of
soil particles.
In the early days,
after 50 years,
what new methods do we have?
In the lower left corner,
you can see a
Trophy Image Parameter.
This is another study.
This is the practicality of
making insects.
We have chosen four
more common methods
to study different
insects by
using different methods.
The first method
is the method of stable isotopes.
This method can help us
know what is the feed
of a species in the soil food network.
Is it a feeder or
a first class separator or a feeder?
This is known by
stable isotopes of
alpha-nitrate.
We can also know
what is the source of
the feed of
a species in the soil.
Is it directly
eaten by plants
or those that have been
sterilized by bacteria?
This is a long-term
accumulation process.
It takes a long time
to see the change
in stable isotopes.
Compared with this,
neutral epiphytase,
neutral fatty acid,
can help us know
what is the feed of
a species in the soil.
For example,
this metabolism is
shorter than that of
the same species.
So we can know
what is the feed of
a species in the soil
for several weeks
to several months.
The second method
is digestive enzyme.
These two methods
have been used for a long time,
but they are still very useful.
Digestive enzymes,
such as fiber,
and cytosine,
can help us know
what is the feed of
a species in the soil.
Is it fiber or bacteria?
Bacteria have cytosine.
Finally,
we need to decrypt
an animal to see
what is the feed of
a species in the soil.
We found that
these four methods
are not related to each other.
It is difficult for us
to use one method
to decrypt
the other three methods.
The analysis results
show that
the four methods are
equally important.
They reflect the
different aspects of
the whole process
from swallowing,
digesting,
absorbing,
chronicling,
to its body tissue.
So,
you can see
how complicated
this thing is.
In addition to the shape of
the shape of the
shape of the
and other
more abstract
aspects,
we also have
studied
that
many Species
are
more exemplary
than other
forms of
life.
The original
species,
there are seven
different species.
Let's see
if the gene
and the bacterium
are the same
number
or not.
We found
that the gene
and the bacterium
are the same number.
Next,
we study
the larvae.
We study
the bacteria
related to the larvae
and the same number
of the larvae.
Are they related?
I think
it's interesting
that the larvae
are not only the native species,
but also the species
living on the snow.
Let's see what the larvae
eat on the snow.
In winter,
or in summer,
there is no snow in summer,
and there is snow in winter.
Let's see
if the larvae
will eat
under the snow
or on the snow.
There are
three different larvae.
We found that
there are two species
living on the snow.
Their same number
and long life
show that their food
comes from snow,
not from soil.
Another species
grows between
snow and
fallen leaves.
Its same number
and bacteria
I like this research
because it uses
two different methods
to answer
an interesting question.
What do the larvae eat
on the snow?
It's not the same as
what we usually know.
So,
we used the shape
to see the similarity
of the shape
or the relationship
between the shape
and the larvae.
What is the ecological process?
Is it the filtration process
or the division process
that affects
the group formation of
the larvae?
Next,
we will talk about
the evolution
of the shape
and the formation
of the species.
This is the multidimensional shape.
When you put different species
on an evolution relationship tree,
such as the system of evolution
or the evolution tree,
what will you see?
You will see these three species,
these three round species,
like the mouse species,
come from the same evolution value.
So, here you will see
a system of evolution.
On the shape,
you will see a system of evolution.
Another situation is
that you see these three green larvae.
Although they are all green,
they come from different evolution values.
These three round larvae
come from the same evolution value.
These three green larvae
come from different evolution values.
This is the difference.
Do they come from the same evolution value?
The more similar species are,
the more similar they are
on the shape.
So,
we use the relationship
between species.
This relationship may be determined
by the DNA sequence
and compared.
We look at the difference
in the DNA sequence.
Is the difference in the relationship
related to the shape of the species?
Then we can
understand the evolution process.
What I just said is
similar species
should be said
to be similar species.
The shape of
similar species is generally similar.
This is a necessary result.
We call such a phenomenon
a system of evolution
with a system of evolution.
The nature of the
jump worm
is composed of
neutral fatty acids.
Neutral fatty acids allow us to know
whether the source of food
is mainly bacteria or plants.
Neutral fatty acids
also allow us to know
how the jump worm adapts to temperature.
We find that
most of the neutral fatty acids
related to physiological
and temperature adaptation
show a system of evolution.
However, those fatty acids
related to food resources
do not show a system of evolution.
What I just said is
the growth of
germin.
The growth of germin
is related to
the stable number of germin.
The growth of germin
is related to the source of food.
In contrast,
the relationship between
germin bacteria and the number of germin
is not so strong.
Instead, it is related to
the system of evolution of germin.
What does this show?
It shows that these bacteria
may be a symbiotic bacteria for germin.
The relationship between germin and germin
is relatively close.
Germin may be a food,
so it is the same number as germin.
The number of germin reflects
the position of germin in the food network.
Therefore, these bacteria
can be a food
and the number of germin
can reflect the food network.
So this thing can be linked together.
What else does the evolution of germin
have in common?
We asked the question
how do these species come from?
You can put these species
together as a database.
These species in the group
are actually a part
of a large database.
A subset.
These species
have a database first,
and then they are selected
or divided into different groups.
What is the evolution process?
We asked
how this database was formed.
On a historical context,
from ancient to modern,
how do these shapes change?
How are these species formed?
There are two hypotheses.
You can imagine
that I just introduced
a vertical natural belt
at Changbai Mountain in the northeast.
The height of the peak.
Do these jump worms
evolve at high altitude first?
Or do they evolve separately
and then expand?
What you see now
are three arrows in the middle.
The three arrows point to the group.
Among the groups,
these three species
all come from the same evolution.
So it is possible that
there is a group first,
this is the base,
and then the process of germination
occurs in it.
So this germination speciation
is a relatively recent process.
That is to say,
it is possible that
there are three species
and then the species changes.
Compared to this,
you can see that
it is the same as this green frame.
This frame is a specific evolution.
But the three green jump worms
in this frame
come from different evolution.
It is possible that
these three jump worms
are formed first
and then some ecological effects
occur in this frame.
So there are jump worms first
and then ecological effects.
So it is called oligopersistence.
The one in front is speciation,
recent speciation,
the most recent evolution.
The one behind is
a relatively old group,
a relatively old species,
they spread and gather together.
So on a high altitude or
at an altitude of a mountain range,
is the jump worm first
or is it formed
at different altitudes?
These are two studies
in my previous research
that are more representative
of the formation of jump worms
and the evolution of jump worms.
The question is
how these jump worms are formed.
This study is a wide-spread
jump worm
that we have investigated
and it is actually
a wide-spread jump worm.
We think it has only one form.
So we can only identify it
as this kind,
Leptosuchus longinus.
But we use DNA
to compare its sequence.
We found that
there are not only one type
in Göttingen and周遭.
In fact, there are three different types.
We call them lineages
because we are not sure
how far the relationship between them is.
How far is it?
It is so far that they have separated
when they were in Myosin.
This is a process of millions of years.
So we think
it may not be
the same species.
We also found
an interesting phenomenon.
These three different lineages
mean that
they prefer different
genotypes.
The first lineage
prefers farmland,
the second prefers forest,
and the third prefers grassland.
It seems that environmental filtering
plays a certain role here.
Environment makes
these jump worms
have some DNA division.
But we know little about it.
We do not know
what shape can
reflect these divisions.
We only know that its form is the same,
or it is different.
French tells us
that these three lineages can only
separate two lineages.
The two lineages 2 and 3
cannot be separated at all.
What is the difference between 1 and the other two?
The only difference is
the ratio of the difference
between the two hairs on the side.
So the color, body size,
or scale distribution
are not known.
We can't find one
to explain the difference
or the reason why
they prefer different genotypes.
But we know that
genotypes have an impact on
the DNA division of jump worms.
Let's go back to the research
in Changbai Mountain, northeast China.
In this research,
we found more than 20 types of
jump worms.
We want to explore
what causes
more than 20 types of jump worms,
not only 5 or 10.
Are these jump worms
related to
the evolution of
the environment
in ancient times
or now?
According to some statistics,
we know that
these jump worms
may be related to
the pH of soil
and the type of rock.
When did Changbai Mountain
form?
Changbai Mountain is the
red star
and the dotted line.
After the dotted line,
Changbai Mountain
was formed.
But these jump worms
have already been
divided into different types
before they formed.
Obviously,
these jump worms
are related to
the evolution of
the environment
in ancient times.
Therefore,
the evolution of
3D organisms,
3D soil organisms,
and 3D jump worms
is not a major factor
in the evolution of
3D organisms.
In fact,
the evolution of
3D organisms
can explain
the existence of
3D soil organisms
in ancient times.
OK.
We still have some time.
Next time,
when you observe
these soil organisms
with some special means,
we can think about
what caused
these
colorful soil organisms
to eat different foods
and live in
different environments.
After 50 years,
it seems that we have
a new understanding of these soil organisms.
So,
this is the method
I use for my research.
In general,
when we do ecological research,
we look at the environment
in which these soil organisms
grow.
In the study of soil,
we generally measure
the amount of water in the soil,
the pH value of the soil,
and the amount of carbon in the soil.
We also do some measurements
of microorganisms,
such as the amount of microorganisms,
the speed of microorganisms' breathing,
and the composition of microorganisms.
These are environmental variables
that affect the environment
they grow in,
including their food resources,
some of their physical and chemical
non-living factors.
In this environment,
we will identify
which species they belong to.
The composition of these species,
the composition of all individuals,
is called a group.
So, we will get
a group of data
about the soil organisms themselves.
During the identification process,
we will look at the shape of their bodies.
They look different.
We can classify them into different species.
But we also have to think about
whether they have the same food resources.
So, we have to know
what kind of food they eat.
This part of the data
is called the shape of the data.
Finally, we can draw DNA
from these species.
Then, we will make a series of DNA
to make their cyanobacteria.
Based on these cyanobacteria,
we can deduce
the evolution process
or the evolution pattern
in the past.
This can tell us
the system development of these species.
It can also tell us
the formation of the species
and its shape.
So, this DNA series
can be called
the fourth type of data.
I just said
that I am a data analyst.
I specialize in data analysis.
So, most of my work
is to analyze these four types of data
to see their relationship
or the difference between them.
Based on this analysis,
we can answer
which ecological processes
are filtered,
divided,
or dispersed
to affect the biodiversity
of these species.
We can also find out
why these species exist.
Let me summarize.
Filtering and
dividing are
the two main processes
in Markvillain's
selection process
and the ecological process.
So far,
these two processes,
especially the filtering process,
show the shape of
the body color.
If we want to know
the process of diversification,
we may need to use
some shapes related to food resources.
This must be achieved
by using stable isotopes,
neutral fatty acids,
enzymes, and long-distance microorganisms.
These four different ways
to study
the food resources
can help us
better understand
their food sources
and food faces.
This includes
swallowing, digesting,
absorbing, and digesting.
The whole process
of
getting nutrients.
In addition,
regarding the evolution process,
we found that most of the shape
is systemically developed.
That is to say,
the more similar species
are more similar
in shape.
However,
their food sources
are different.
What did I just say?
The more similar species
are more similar
in shape.
But the food they eat
may be different.
The more similar species
are more similar
in shape.
In the 3D system,
we know that
3D soil organisms
do not evolve
from high altitudes.
Instead,
the current evidence shows
that they come from
several older species.
Then,
through some ecological processes,
or environmental filtering,
they can gather together.
Next time,
when you walk into a forest,
you might as well
take a look at the soil
and see if there are any animals.
Try to find
these cute little animals.
That's my report.
Thank you very much
for giving me this opportunity
to talk about my research.
I also want to thank
everyone who has supported me
in the past,
including my teachers,
colleagues, friends,
and assistants in the lab.
That's all for my report.
I'll stop sharing now.
I didn't expect
that there are
16 people in the audience
who don't know me.
Thank you.
Do you have
any questions?
If you don't want
to turn on the microphone,
you can type your questions
in the chat.
I'll help you ask.
No one has
any questions,
so I'll ask first.
Ding Wenxiang,
you mentioned that
the amount of carbon dioxide
is related to the altitude
and that the altitude
is related to the body color.
Are you implying
that the body color
and the amount of carbon dioxide
are related?
What you showed
on the chart
is that the amount of carbon dioxide
is related to the body color
and that the body color
and the amount of carbon dioxide
are related.
Logically,
we can understand that
the body color
and the amount of carbon dioxide
are related.
But the data
show that
the body color
and the amount of carbon dioxide
are not related.
I can't find
the same altitude
with different body color
and see the difference
in the amount of carbon dioxide.
Do you have similar data?
In theory,
the number of
insects
in the same altitude
should be quite common.
So in theory,
you should be able to find
the same altitude
with different amount of carbon dioxide
But this is
a bit strange.
Why is the amount of carbon dioxide
related to the body color?
This is an interesting point.
You just said
that we can find
different points
on the same altitude
and see if the amount of carbon dioxide
will affect the body color.
I can say that
it should not affect the body color.
Of course,
from a mechanical point of view,
it is difficult to find
a mechanism
to explain
why the amount of carbon dioxide
will affect the body color.
As I said,
the UV ray
may be harmful to the animal.
So it must have a deeper body color
to resist or protect it
from such strong UV rays.
It may be easier to say this.
But you remind me of a point.
In fact, when we were doing the research,
we measured
three points on this altitude.
No,
we measured five points.
These five points
were finally analyzed
as a random factor.
So we don't really care
about the difference
between the five points
on the same altitude.
Our question is
the difference between different altitudes.
Whether it is the difference
between the altitude
and the amount of carbon dioxide
in the soil,
we want to find
the one that can best explain
the body color distribution
of this group
in statistics.
In statistics,
but you will find
that it is more difficult
to understand.
So your data
is still taken by you,
instead of doing
a meta-data analysis.
Most of what I just said
is my own actual research
and data.
The real meta-analysis
is the relationship
between the four methods
of soil erosion.
That is the meta-analysis.
We still like to go out in the wild
and actually measure the material
to see what the animals look like.
I prefer to sit in front of the computer
and analyze the data.
I need my colleagues
and friends
to provide the first-hand data.
Then we have the opportunity
to reuse their data
and ask different scientific questions.
So I really appreciate
and cherish their contribution
to soil biology.
Of course, everyone
has to find their own niche
and partition
in order to
find what they like
and share the knowledge
with their colleagues.
Some of my colleagues
are very good at
soil biology,
and they are also
very good at
identification biology.
In this respect,
we are just a
complementary role.
Do you have any questions?
I don't want to be recorded.