Today is October 8th, 2022, Taira Talk.
The speaker we invited today is Ms. Zheng Huaijie.
The topic she will talk about is
Jupiter Hub, a mini studio,
an open science cloud base.
Let me briefly introduce Huaijie's background.
In 2010 and 2013, Huaijie obtained a master's and a master's degree in Taiwan University.
In 2015, she went to Cornell University
for a PhD in Earth and Atmospheric Science.
In 2021, Huaijie joined a research team at the University of California, Berkeley.
She is now working as a post-PhD researcher
on the Jupiter-Meet-the-Earth project.
Today, Huaijie will teach us about Jupiter Hub.
She also mentioned that you don't need any background knowledge or program design skills to participate in this talk.
However, if you want to store Jupiter resources at the same time during the talk,
you must prepare a Google or Microsoft account.
Please prepare for the third part of the talk.
That's all for my introduction.
Let's give the floor to Huaijie.
Thank you, Shi-An.
Thank you for your introduction.
It's an honor to be able to invite Tara to give a talk.
My last talk was in January this year.
I would like to share with you what I am doing at UC Berkeley.
Instead of sharing, I would like to focus on Jupiter Hub.
I would like to share with you what Jupiter Hub is
and why we call it the cloud base of open science.
How it can transform our practice of open science.
Let's get started.
I would like to share with you what I am doing at the moment.
I would like to add a little bit.
My field of expertise is earth science.
To be more precise, I am studying earth physics,
rock science,
meteorology,
and astrophysics.
What I am doing at the moment is
using a lot of satellite data
and model analysis
to monitor and understand the changes in ice and snow.
For example,
you can see a satellite here.
It orbits the earth
and emits green light.
When it hits the ground,
the satellite will receive the reflected light.
Based on the reflected light,
we can calculate the distance between the satellite and the earth,
and convert it to the height of the earth.
If we can do this repeatedly for an ice cube,
we can get an ice cube
with the time passing by,
the height of the surface,
or the thickness of the ice.
Then we use some physical models
to analyze
the factors
that affect the thickness of the ice cube.
It sounds cool,
and I like it.
However, most of the academic activities
that I am doing now
are similar to what you are doing.
We need to study
and explain our research
to others,
including colleagues
and people
in different fields.
In addition to research,
we also have teaching activities
where we write software
for others.
I have done some of these.
Here are some pictures
of what I have done
in the past few years,
including developing a software
called KARS.
I also wrote a website
called GMT Tutorials.
In short,
I teach others
how to draw pictures
using GMT software.
The picture in the lower right corner
is from a paper
I published in 2019.
At that time,
I discussed with the paper publisher
how to make some materials
that can be more efficient
and faster
to convey
some new knowledge
of the paper
and make it
into a news article.
Back to our topic today,
we are going to talk about JupyterHub.
How can we change
the academic activities
we do every day?
Before we talk about JupyterHub,
let's talk about
the concept of Jupyter.
If I were to explain
what Jupyter is,
I would say that
Jupyter is an open
data science...
Sorry. Jupyter is an ecosystem
composed of open data science tools
and a community
of open data scientists.
There might be some professional terminology here,
so I'll explain a little more.
The so-called tools here mean
that if you want to complete
a task,
the tools you use...
For example,
Photoshop
is a tool
for video editing.
Matplotlib
is a tool
used in Python
for scientific mapping.
Something like that.
As for the word
open,
it's a little vague.
To be honest,
many different aspects
are considered to be open.
For example,
it can refer to the tools you use.
The source code
may be public,
and anyone can modify it.
On the other hand,
the way you collaborate
allows as many people
as possible to participate
and contribute and discuss.
Anyway,
the core concept of
the word open
is
not to be excluded,
but to allow as many people
as possible to participate
in what you are doing now.
So we have a lot of tools.
Some tools are software,
some tools are hardware,
and some tools
are used to describe
how software and hardware
interact with each other.
These tools are different
from other tools.
Think about it.
If you put a tool under a tool,
a screwdriver may be used to lock the screw,
and a crowbar may be used
to twist the wire.
These tools are independent.
In data science,
the so-called tools
often rely on each other.
For example,
if you want to use Matplotlib today,
you have to install Python first.
After installing Python,
you can install Matplotlib,
and it will work.
If you draw the interdependence
between different tools,
you will see a picture
that looks like a network,
or a food chain.
So we tend to
call the interdependence
between tools
and their interdependence
an ecosystem.
An ecosystem like Jupyter
is not very old.
The concept of open science
has only appeared
for about 20 years
so far.
You may feel shorter.
In the first ten years,
it was in the early stages.
Not many people
were completely exposed
to this concept.
One of the most likely
time to accept this exposure
is 2015.
At that time,
Lego released
the first gravity wave observation
in human history.
It shocked the world.
They won the Nobel Prize
in 2017 or 2018.
Lego
did more than
this.
Of course,
they are very good
at writing articles
and building observatories.
But they also have
an open science department.
This department
has compiled all the data
about the gravity wave observation
and posted it on the Internet.
Everyone can
go to their website
and click on their link.
You can re-execute the code
and draw the same picture
as in their paper.
I will share
my video later.
You can click on the link
to see what it is.
After 2015,
if you use Twitter,
you may see
more and more people
on Twitter
saying
how great the open science department is.
It can make me do things
I couldn't do before.
For example,
this person used his phone
to analyze the data
of CIMIP-6 on the train.
If you don't know what CIMIP-6 is,
it is a global
climate simulation database.
It generates
TBG data every day.
The data
is huge.
It is not easy
to analyze the data
on the train
with a smart phone.
What's more,
NASA has announced
that
next year, 2023,
will be their open science year.
They have a big project
called TOPS,
Transform to Open Science.
Starting from next year,
it will take about 4 to 5 years.
They will
manage and
publish the data
in a big way.
After next year,
they will
adopt a new model,
a more open science model,
to manage and publish
their data
work flow
and research results.
This is a trend.
We can see this trend.
Everyone is talking about it.
Of course, thanks to the development of technology,
we now have
different ways
to practice
open science.
Here is an example.
We know that open science
is a very common term.
There are many
different ways to practice it.
Here is an example.
You can see
these pictures.
Let's say there is a researcher
named Jim.
He just wrote a cool paper
and published it.
He wants
more. He wants to say
that he wants this paper
to be
supported by
other people.
He wants everyone
to be able to
see his paper,
check for errors,
and even
re-examine his experiment,
improve
his calculations
in the paper.
What can he do?
Here is a method.
He can use
Jupyter Notebook.
In this file,
he can put all the details of the research,
including narrative text,
including city code,
including
many interactive
or non-interactive icons,
as well as more background resources,
such as primitive data,
multimedia,
and software, etc.
After he has
this Jupyter Notebook,
he can put it in a
network storage
so that everyone can read it.
A more popular storage is
GitHub.
He can put it on GitHub
so that everyone can see it.
After uploading,
he does more things
to make
this storage
called
Finder Ready.
Simply put,
he can provide additional information,
such as
what kind of software
you need
to run the notebook
in this storage,
such as Python,
R,
Julia, or Matlab.
He can provide
background information
and make a
set of files.
He can arrange
the files.
When all these things are ready,
we can use
a tool called
Docker
to
make this entire storage
into
an
independent
image.
It's like
a mini
execution environment.
In this environment,
you can
use the same environment
to run these programs.
Now, all you have to do is
share this Docker image
to other people around the world.
Then other people
can perfectly reproduce your research
without
additional installation of
many beautiful softwares.
The above is
one of the examples
of open science.
It allows people to
quickly save
their own research materials.
How does JupyterHub
contribute
to
the
data science process?
If I were to
explain what JupyterHub is,
I would say that
JupyterHub is a tool
that provides
convenient data science environment
on a shared computer.
What is a
shared computer?
Simply put,
suppose you have
a computer in your lab,
and everyone can log in
and do something on it,
such as
writing articles, processing data,
writing papers, and so on.
The server
you can log in to
and store
the CPU or GPU
resources in it
is called a shared computer.
Traditionally,
I guess some of you
may have used it,
such as SSH,
to a remote server and do something on it.
Of course,
you have to install a lot of things
in order to do
what you want to do on the server.
JupyterHub
eliminates these steps.
It provides some pre-set
configurations
so that you can
go to the server
without doing anything
and start
your data science analysis.
Here is a picture
of the concept
of JupyterHub.
You can imagine
that there are a lot of people here.
They are going to store
a machine like this.
JupyterHub is running on the machine.
Everyone has to pass a verification first.
When they successfully
log in to the machine,
JupyterHub will provide
several standard interfaces
for them to choose from,
such as the Jupyter Notebook interface.
Then they can start
storing the computing resources
in the machine
through this interface.
Note that the computing resources
are separate from JupyterHub.
JupyterHub
can also prepare several
different computing environments.
For example, it can prepare
a Python environment.
If I need it,
I can log in to JupyterHub
and call the Python environment
and say I want to use Python this time.
At the same time,
JupyterHub can also prepare
another environment
that is completely built
on different tools.
If others want to use it,
they can call it out at any time.
So JupyterHub
is a layer of disassembly
of such a work structure
to make it easier
for open science and cooperation.
Here is another example
to explain
how JupyterHub
can achieve
the goal we want,
that is, the goal of sharing the environment.
Let's say there is a professor
named John.
He is now leading
a large-scale research project.
This large-scale research project
has already
pre-configured
the software he wants to use.
For example, he may want to use Python
for the first time.
He says this is the environment I want.
How does JupyterHub
tell others
to use this environment?
We provide a method
that allows JupyterHub
to cooperate with
the IT staff of the school.
JupyterHub will send
an application form
to the IT staff
and say
this is the environment
I want to design.
This is the environment I want to provide.
These environments
will be configured
in a configuration file
for the IT staff.
After receiving this file,
JupyterHub will
refer to the settings
and open
a thing called Workspace Manager.
In this example,
Workspace Manager is JupyterHub.
So I call it JupyterHub.
The IT staff will open JupyterHub
in the computer of the school.
JupyterHub will read
the file provided
and configure
the work environment
you need,
including Python,
etc.
Finally,
JupyterHub will run
on the cloud server
of the school.
After it is configured,
it will generate
a Docker file.
It's a bit like...
If I talk too much
and you don't understand,
please ask me later.
It will generate a Docker file
and
a URL.
After
getting this URL,
you can send it
to anyone
including students
and their collaborators.
They can connect to
the JupyterHub login page.
As long as
they can verify their identity
and log in,
they can save
the JupyterHub
running on the cloud
and all the
environment configuration
are ready.
No need to install anything else.
This is the concept of
sharing the environment.
That's all for the introduction.
Since this is a mini workshop,
let's try
what JupyterHub is.
The JupyterHub we want
is
a Kalisto
organization.
Kalisto
has
two
non-profit organizations
in Canada.
Their main goal
is to
provide
high school teachers
in Canada
with sufficient resources
to teach students
how to do
data science
and
various teaching modules.
Their
own JupyterHub is called
KalistoHub.
JupyterHub is the name
of the tool.
The tool
is used to
connect the tool
to the cloud.
KalistoHub
is the Kalisto
organization.
They use JupyterHub
to connect
the Kalisto
organization
to the cloud.
This is
my video link.
This is Kalisto's
website.
I will continue to share my screen.
Can you see that I am
on Kalisto's page?
Yes.
Can you hear me?
Thank you.
There is a KalistoHub
icon in the upper right corner.
Click it.
You will see
that you can
log in.
Log in with your account.
It will ask you
if you want Google or Microsoft.
You can choose what you want.
I have Google.
This is my
Berkeley account.
I will show you.
When you log in,
you will see this screen.
You are preparing.
Oh, this is not what I want.
Let me do it again.
I want to log in a new one.
Log in.
Log in with my Gmail.
OK.
After you log in,
you will see a page like this.
This page is
one of the standard
interface of
Kalisto.
We usually call it
Notebook interface.
Is everyone OK?
Do you need to wait?
I am OK.
Is BlueJeans
available?
Can you show me
if you need
more time?
He can raise his hand.
But I am not sure
what will happen.
Oh, OK.
Oh, Weiwei.
Let me pull out the chat window.
Now you can use the chat window
to let me know where you are.
But I don't know how to pull it out.
Anyway,
let's continue.
When you see this page,
it means you have successfully logged in
to Kalisto Hub.
You have successfully logged in
to Kalisto Hub,
and you have started using
the computing resources provided by them.
There will be a
file list here.
You will see a file called
Getting Started.
You will see a page
like this.
This is how
Jupyter Notebook
looks like
under the Notebook interface.
You can see that
this is a Notebook file.
It looks very diverse,
but if you click twice
on each block,
you will see their
original information.
The original information
is actually some words.
These words
are written in Markdown format.
So when you are in editing mode,
you can edit as you like.
For example,
I can type blah blah
under this block.
Then,
when you click Run,
it will re-
change this block to display mode.
Like this.
You can see blah blah
under this block.
As I said,
this is a Jupyter Notebook,
so you can also
compute directly on it.
For example,
we can add some blocks
under this Notebook
by clicking Add.
We can click
a block
and type
Hello World.
In the upper right corner,
you can see
what is the core
of this Notebook.
Here it says
Python 3,
which means that
when you click Run,
Notebook will run
these programs
in Python.
For example,
I can type
hello world
and
print a.
After typing,
if you click Run,
it will run this program
in Python.
If you want to add
more columns,
you can also
change the block type
from Code
to Markdown.
You can type here
like
Today is
Ira's speech.
After running,
it will become
the narrative text
in your Notebook.
What I like
about Python Notebook
is the narrative text
The Markdown
supports LaTeX,
so you can type
mathematical formulas here.
For example,
I can type
what?
Q
equals
OK
times
partial T
partial X
This is a
Parallelism.
Then a Parallelism
will appear.
If you traditionally use LaTeX,
it's hard to mix and match like this,
especially when
there is Chinese in your article.
Traditionally,
LaTeX is very difficult to process
Chinese content,
but
in Jupyter Markdown,
because it
originally supports UTF,
you can perfectly
mix these two things together.
It's very convenient.
Is it OK so far?
Should we pause or continue?
I'm OK.
Do you have any questions?
Although there may be something to trouble you,
I always look at the chat box,
so if there are any questions
in the chat,
can you interrupt me a little?
OK.
Or if you see someone raising their hand,
you can interrupt me at any time.
I will help you pay attention to these.
You can continue.
Thank you.
We just talked about
Jupyter Notebook and Core.
These two things are separate.
Depending on the user's needs,
we can switch between different cores.
So let's switch to a different core.
Let's try not to use Python now.
If you move the mouse
to the menu above,
then select Kernel.
Then,
at the bottom of the Kernel,
there is a Change Kernel.
You will see that
there are two cores in Callisto Hub.
One is Python, the other is R.
Let's try R.
Now,
this Jupyter Notebook
is running R,
not Python.
If we re-run
Hello World,
it will...
Oh, this part is still useful.
Because there is also this part in R.
But the syntax of R itself
is like this.
This part of Python
cannot be executed.
Something like this.
Run.
It will execute
this part of the program
in the way of R.
If you draw a picture on it,
for example,
let's quickly make an X.
This is the program of R,
so if you don't understand,
you are welcome to ask me anytime.
But now,
I have to set five data points.
Then draw these five data points.
Then I can press
Shift and Enter
to run this program.
Then it will call the jpg in R
to draw this thing.
For the jpg in Python,
the jpg in Python
is also similar.
Now,
we change the kernel
back to Python.
Change.
Then we bring it to the bottom.
Let's try it.
Use Python to draw.
In Python,
you have to enter some jpgs first.
For example,
here,
I call
matplotlib and
numpy
to do things for me.
Then,
roughly like this,
you can draw a picture of Sine.
You can see that these two pictures
look very different.
To some extent,
they are actually two different jpg sets.
The one above is R.
The one below is Python.
Of course, if you want,
you can also save this picture.
We can add one more command,
and we call it
test.png.
After drawing,
after re-executing,
test.png
will appear in the file list.
If we go back to the file list,
File,
File, then Open,
you will go back to the file list screen.
You will see that
a new file called test has appeared.
Open it,
you can see this png file.
You can also select it,
and then download it.
The download button is
here,
this part of the top row.
You can download it to your own computer.
The above is a simple
way to operate
the notebook interface.
You can find that we are really using
JupyterHub,
the computing resources provided by Callisto
to help you do some scientific analysis.
Of course, it also has
some traditional
4-in-1 operating modes.
If you move the mouse
to the New
on the list,
press it,
you will see several options.
You can open a new notebook.
You can also open other types of files.
There is a file here
called Terminal.
After pressing it,
you can turn on
a traditional terminal,
and then operate
what you want to operate,
such as LOS or
PWD, etc.,
anything you want.
What I want to show you here is
the so-called installation settings.
This command needs to wait,
because it uses
Conda,
a settings software,
to install the settings.
It's a software,
and sometimes it takes a long time.
But...
It looks like there's still some time.
Oh, I'm out.
You can see that
it's already pre-installed.
There are a lot of settings pre-installed,
including...
For example, in Python,
because I'm more familiar with Python,
you can see that
there are
Dask,
a set of parallel algorithms,
and then, for example,
there's Geopandas,
a set of geospatial data,
and then, for example,
there's also
HDF5,
a set of HDF files,
as well as
a variety of
other kinds of
settings.
Of course, there's also Matplotlib here,
and other different
visualizations, such as
I think it should have Cborn installed.
Cborn is
probably here.
Scientific analysis is more common,
like SciPy,
or non-Python files.
As you can see,
if someone can help you
pre-install these settings,
then you don't have to
spend so much effort
to install the settings,
and deal with the problems of
each other's reliance.
Sometimes these problems
will greatly hinder
the progress of a research.
So, is it still OK here?
If it's still OK,
we'll move on to the next stage.
I'm OK.
OK, OK.
OK, let's go back to
the file list.
In this file list,
we just talked about
Notebook Entry,
which is a traditional
Github interface.
I want to introduce
a relatively new
interface called Lab.
The way to save it is
to cut off the tree
in the file list,
and change it to Lab.
Then,
enter it.
When you do this,
you will enter
another interface
called Lab.
If you need
some information,
you can go back to our video.
There should be steps
in the following videos.
The interface of Lab
looks a little different
from that of Notebook.
The biggest difference is
that the interface of Lab
consists of many different small panels.
For example, the left panel
is for file browsing,
and the right panel
is for test.png.
You can click twice
and the right panel
will show the test.png.
Of course,
the Notebook is already open
and you can see the information
is still there.
So they actually
store the same server,
but with different interfaces.
What can we do
with the Notebook?
You can see
a blue plus sign in the upper left corner.
Click it
to open the start page.
In the start page,
you can choose
what kind of content you want to start.
You can start a notebook
with Python as the core,
or with R as the core.
Or you can
start a terminal
and do the same thing as before,
like start with S.
As I said,
the best selling point of Lab
is that it has different panels
for window browsing.
The advantage of doing this
is that you can compare the two.
For example,
if you go back to the iPad and Notebook
and move to the bottom of the page,
and click the right button
to see the list,
you can see that there are a lot of lists.
One of them is called
Create New View for Output.
Click it.
This picture will move to a new panel.
You can move it around.
It's like
many powerful software
these days.
You can compare it with different pictures.
For example, I can re-draw one.
I'll change it to Cosine.
Re-draw.
Oh, this is also a comparison.
But I can change it.
Copy.
Do the same thing.
But here I want to make it Sine.
Re-draw.
Then you can compare this picture
with this picture.
And so on.
JupyterLab
also supports a lot of other
not only Notebook,
but also a lot of other file display modes.
For example, if you click the PNG file,
it will jump out of the PNG file.
If you click the CSV file,
it can also display the CSV file
in a display way.
And so on.
It also has
some more gorgeous settings.
For example,
if you move to the
list above,
there is a list called
Settings.
The first one is Scene.
Here you can choose
whether to use
bright colors or dark colors.
The default is bright colors.
But I prefer dark colors.
So I'll change it to dark colors.
Let's see what happens.
It's dark colors.
In addition,
you can do more customization.
For example,
if you open Settings,
there is a Language.
But at the moment,
there is only English language.
But we can install Chinese language.
For example,
if we go to Terminal,
and use pip,
to install...
What's the name of this package?
It's called
JupyterLab
Language Pack.
Chinese.
Taiwan.
Something like that.
Install.
Then it will start to install.
That's right.
You are now installing
the package you want on
a server called CallistoHub.
After installation,
you need to re-organize this lab.
Just click on Re-organize.
Then the whole lab will be re-organized.
So,
if you go to Settings,
Language,
you should see Chinese.
You can choose Chinese or Taiwanese.
Go in.
Then Reload.
The JupyterLab with Chinese version
will appear.
Maybe it's not that perfect.
You can see some of them are not translated.
Because the JupyterLab
translation project
is still in progress.
They are all public projects.
So if you are interested in contributing,
you can ask me.
I can send you the link.
But you can also google
the translation project link.
So far, I don't know if you have any questions.
OK.
I don't see any questions.
That's great.
It seems that everyone is very
into the situation.
I don't know.
Does everyone follow?
I'm following.
It doesn't matter.
OK.
Because if you want to repeat it later,
you can refer to my first video.
There should be some details in the video
to explain how to do these things.
The last part,
I want to share with you
some of the functions of Hub.
So if we go to
the menu,
File,
and then the second one,
you should see the Hub control panel
or Hub control panel.
If you don't know how to install Chinese,
it's called Hub control panel.
Click it.
A control panel will pop up.
Wow, it's so bright.
If you don't mind,
I'll turn on a light.
Because it's getting dark here.
I'll be right back.
OK.
On this control panel,
you should only see two options.
The first option is
to stop
the server just now.
Now,
click it.
Let's try to click
this dot.
Now the server has been stopped.
If we go back to the previous page,
you can see
the server is unavailable or unreachable.
Because the server has been stopped.
But we can restart it.
So,
we can click here
to restart.
Or we can go back to the previous page
and click Start My Server.
It's up to you.
Let's restart it.
OK.
It's done.
The preset interface will be
the notebook interface.
But you can see
the generated files are still there.
The test.png is still there.
However,
if you switch to the lab interface,
you may find something
different.
Let's take a look.
OK.
If you click
the menu,
you may find the Chinese file is gone.
Why?
Why is the file still there,
but
the Chinese file is gone?
Here,
I'd like to use this observation
to explain the full line
of JupyterHub.
If you are a JupyterHub
administrator,
you can set the files or structures
in JupyterHub
which parts can't be changed by the user,
and which parts can be changed by the user.
However, when you finish this server,
it will reset.
The file we installed just now
has been reset.
If you want to re-install JupyterHub,
you have to install it again.
However,
the administrator can also decide
which parts can be saved
by the user forever.
In other words,
if you just generate the files
in those places,
you can save these files.
Every time you restart JupyterHub,
these files will not disappear.
For example, the test.png
will always be saved
in this server.
As far as I know,
there is a time limit
in Kalisto.
If you don't log in
for more than 10 days,
your file will be deleted.
Every hub
has its own rules.
For more details,
you can refer to their settings.
If we go back to the Control Panel,
you will see a Token.
In the upper left corner,
there is a Token.
If you click on it,
you can see some
complicated things.
Most of the things here
are used by the administrator.
However, I want to talk about
the things below.
For example,
if you click on the
OAuth application,
JupyterHub
is compatible
with OAuth.
This means that
according to the administrator's
own ideas,
they can use
third-party account information
to enter
JupyterHub verification.
For example,
Kalisto Hub
uses your Google account
or Microsoft account
to verify.
However,
JupyterHub
in our team
uses GitHub account
to do third-party verification.
The advantage of doing this is
that the administrator
can save a lot of time
in managing users and their accounts.
Because you are
distributing this responsibility
to third-party groups.
I personally think it's good
because you can imagine
that almost every researcher
has Google
and GitHub.
If you can use these accounts
to log in to GitHub,
it is very convenient.
OK.
That's about it.
In the same video,
I will also put
some screenshots.
Let's take a look.
Notebook Entry,
Web Entry.
If today
JupyterHub is running on a large
Google cloud
or Amazon cloud,
it may provide
an option
when starting the server.
It may say
how many CPUs do you need
for this server?
You can choose
to run a large server
or a small server.
Kalisto is a free hub,
so it provides
all users
with one CPU.
That is,
you can only use one CPU
to do things.
This screenshot is
taken from my research hub.
You can see that
we can open up to 64 CPUs.
In fact, there are 64 CPUs
plus GPU options.
It's more luxurious.
The other screenshot
is only
seen by the manager of the hub.
You can see
some
If you are a manager,
you can see
how many people are using this hub,
who are using it,
and who haven't used it for a long time.
You can
stop it.
If you find any abnormal usage,
you can turn off their hub.
Then they can't continue to use it.
Something like that.
Let's take a look at
the manager's interface.
There is a problem here.
It's almost an hour,
so I want to stop
to see if there are any questions.
I have a question.
If Kalisto
is a user,
how should you use it?
Good question.
If we go back to the hub,
you can see
in the Getting Started
notebook, there are some links.
You can click on these links.
For example,
you can click on
Kalisto Jupyter and Python Basics Notebook
in Preparation.
Then
this hub will start
retrieving the resources
stored on GitHub.
Then copy a copy to the hub.
After they are done,
your hub space
will have more resources.
These resources
are the resources you can use to learn.
It's out.
This is the new notebook I just retrieved.
This notebook teaches you
Python.
There is a YouTube video
here.
You can watch it.
You can watch it like this.
There are some other things
at the bottom.
You can add text statements
and run these programs.
Let's see what happens next.
Oh, there is a video.
I'd like to watch it, but I'll watch it another day.
So it's like a teaching hub.
It's a teaching hub.
There are various teaching websites.
Yes, it's a teaching hub.
If we go back to the
previous lab interface,
you can see
if you click on Reorganize,
a new folder.
If you click on it,
you can see a lot of things in it.
This is what you just downloaded.
In addition to the previous notebook,
there are many other notebooks
that you can refer to.
In short,
it's a large-scale resource
that is provided to
elementary and junior high school teachers
for their use of data science.
You can see
what modules have been created.
In addition to using this method to browse,
Calista also provides resources.
There should be another Calista Learning Module.
If you click on it,
you will be connected to another page of Calista.
There are a lot of learning modules at the bottom.
So if you are a teacher today,
you can say,
which module do you want your students to learn today?
Just click on it.
Then the content of the module will be directly
retrieved to JupyterHub.
Or you can ask your students to click on it themselves.
Students can use their account
to directly execute
what's on it.
There are many other resources here.
One of my favorite resources
is that they have
the content of
cooperating with indigenous people in North America.
For example,
if you click on it,
there is a trap.
You can use data analysis
to see
which side of the trap
is the best for catching fish.
It is a learning module,
so when you click on it,
it will be retrieved to your hub.
Then you can start
doing these interesting data analysis.
Oh, I'm done.
Okay, it's here.
Then you can see
what's here. Let's try it.
Oh,
there is a map.
This is an interactive map.
You can drag and drop here.
This is
a fishing ground near Vancouver.
And so on.
So Callisto
provides a lot of teaching resources
to help you familiarize yourself
with data science.
Of course, for you,
there is JupyterHub.
It looks cool.
These data
are all
going through
Callisto.
Is it an organization?
Do they need to be certified?
How do you decide
whether or not to upload these data?
Callisto is a kind of project.
It is a project of cooperation between two organizations.
Two
non-profit organizations, NPO.
It is a cooperation project.
These two organizations
have a team
to maintain Callisto.
All the modules
are written by them.
But the data they use
should be from somewhere else.
For example, the fishing data
is from the local
tribe.
Then it is imported.
In addition,
there are also a lot of public data on science.
They should use those public data
to show
how data science works.
I see.
Thank you.
Actually, there is one last part.
If you are satisfied,
we can stop here.
It's okay.
We can continue.
Really?
If you
think it's okay,
I will talk about the rest of the video.
The last part
is
to provide you with more resources.
In addition to
Callisto Hub,
there are many
other Hubs.
For example, a commonly used Hub service
is Binder.
Binder
is used to
turn a GitHub
storage into
a Hub that can be executed
immediately.
For example,
this is an article I posted
last year.
Its
supplementary information
is
a
GitHub page.
You can find a link
on this GitHub page.
Let me see if I can
switch to that page.
Oh,
this GitHub page
is the supplementary information
of the article I just posted.
There will be a link
to Binder below.
If you click on it,
you can start something called Binder.
It will take you to a place
similar to Jupyter
on the GitHub page.
You can
review the information
in this article,
and then
re-create
each image in this article.
There are
many details to explain.
This is Binder,
another service provided by GitHub.
It looks like this.
This is
related to earth science.
It's called Pangeo Cloud.
It's kind of
semi-public.
As long as you are doing earth science,
you can use their service.
After registration
and review,
you can start using their
JupyterHub deployed on
Google Cloud and Amazon.
You can directly save
cloud computing resources
on JupyterHub.
It's cool.
Of course, there is Callisto.
We won't talk about it.
If you think
Callisto Learning Module
is a bit complicated,
or you want a quick
learning resource we recommend,
there are two.
You can refer to them.
You can directly
go to the hub
and enter the terminal,
or you can enter any of them.
You can enter any of them.
These two are actually
the storage on GitHub.
You can put all the
content on the hub.
For example,
let's use League
as a reference.
Copy and go back to the hub.
Open the terminal.
Paste it.
After you paste it,
you can see
a demo JupyterGit
in the main folder.
There are a lot of things
when you click on it.
Let's take a look.
There is an ip1v here.
This is an iPython notebook
that can be executed.
Other notebooks should be
in the folder,
such as intro Jupyter.
You can see all kinds of
introduction to Jupyter tools.
In short,
there are a lot of learning resources here.
You are welcome to
try it out
at any time.
In the last two or three videos,
I want to briefly explain
that if you really
like JupyterHub,
and you want to
install JupyterHub for your
research team,
what should you do?
First of all,
JupyterHub provides
two standard versions.
One is called The Littlest JupyterHub.
This version
is specifically for
small teams,
between 0 to 100 people.
In short,
it is simplified.
You don't have to spend
a lot of effort.
You can install it on your
lab server
for your colleagues or students.
The other version is
JupyterHub on Kubernetes.
This version
is specifically for
large cloud
installations.
For example,
JupyterHub installation
on Amazon
or Microsoft Azure.
This version is for
hundreds or thousands of people,
or JupyterHub installation
on a supercomputer.
If you want to install it,
choose one
that suits you.
Even so,
you may still feel
that the technical performance
is too high.
After all,
most people are not
good at it.
Of course, we also see this difficulty.
In 2019,
some of us
in the Jupyter team
at Berkeley
established a non-profit organization
called 2I2C,
or the International Interactive
Computing Collaboration.
The purpose of
this non-profit organization
is to provide
various open science
and technology services.
One of the most
developed services
is to provide
research teams or organizations
to install and manage
their JupyterHub.
Most of their
funding comes from
the John Zuckerberg
Initiative,
the one on Facebook.
However,
they also receive
funding from
the International Interactive
Computing Collaboration.
The Callisto
and Pangeo
hubs we just saw
were set up
by 2I2C.
However,
Binder and our own
research hub are not.
Our own research hub
is more gorgeous
because we have to test
a lot of things.
Our hub looks like this.
Let me show you.
It should be here.
I don't think I can start.
Looks like I have to wait.
I'll come back later.
So,
what we want to achieve
through 2I2C
is that
one day in the future,
as a researcher,
all your research activities
and academic activities
can take place on the cloud.
Your own research team
will collaborate on the cloud.
You have to save
HPC computing resources
and use JupyterHub
to log in.
The school itself
may have a JupyterHub.
When you have a lecture
or a lecture,
you can use their hub
to give others
what you want
them to learn.
Even if you attend
an international conference,
this conference
may have a hub
for the participants
to log in
and learn new skills
through the hub.
That's about it.
Finally, I want to say
that all the progress of open science
is not done by ourselves.
There are many
community members.
For example,
what I can share with you today
is a tribute to
our entire research team
at Berkeley,
JupyterMeteors.
I put all their people here
and let you know
what the JupyterMeteors
project is doing.
Thank you very much.
If you have any questions,
you can contact me
by text message
or via ZXL.
You can contact me anytime.
This is my last video.
Thank you.
Thank you, Huaijie.
If you are interested,
you can turn on the microphone
and give Huaijie a round of applause.
Let me
find the
POAP code.
Let me find it.
If you have any questions,
you can ask now.
Thank you for your applause.
Let me write down
the POAP code.
Thank you for your participation.
Thank you.
I have a question.
For your first video,
do you want to
share it on
Tyra's website?
Otherwise,
your sharing
should be only temporary.
Let me think about it.
I can share it
to the participants.
Absolutely no problem.
This video will be released soon.
But I don't know if I can share it on the website.
I will contact you later.
No problem.
Also,
I have a question.
Many
quantum computing
companies
do similar things,
such as
sharing their
computing resources
on the cloud.
Do you
write the code
on Python
and upload it to their server?
They will run the code for you.
Their hardware is different,
but they will run the code for you.
Actually, this is a more traditional way.
A more traditional way
to use a supercomputer
is that there is
something like a work processor.
You have to
upload your
code to the
work processor.
The work processor
will deploy
and decide
how many computing resources
to run your code
at what time.
Finally,
the result will be packed
and sent to you.
This is a more
traditional way.
The way we promote now is
to save
the part of the work processor.
JupyterHub itself can be used as a work processor.
As long as you use the right
structure, such as Kubernetes,
the actual
technical details are a bit complicated.
I will make it simple.
As long as you use
the structure of Kubernetes,
you can
use JupyterHub
as a scheduler.
As a work processor,
you can decide
how many resources
you want to use
at the beginning of your script.
You can use several nodes,
several clusters,
and then you start running.
JupyterHub
and Dask,
Dask is a suite of parallel algorithms
I just mentioned,
with Dask's
external components.
As long as you use Dask,
you can
open a few
control panels
in JupyterHub
to monitor
how many CPUs
you use
when running
these program codes
in real time.
If you have questions,
you can ask me
in the chat room.
Thanks for watching.
It seems that
the gun has disappeared.
It's okay. Let's wait for it.
If you have questions,
you can ask me
in the chat room.
If you have questions,
you can ask me
in the chat room.
Thanks for watching.