Can you see it now?
Yes.
OK.
Hello, everyone.
I'm John Yu-nan.
You can call me Alan.
I'm a Ph.D. student at Rice University.
I'm studying computer science.
I'm in my second year.
I'm doing research on
interpretable machinery
or explainable artificial intelligence.
My goal is to explain
why this machine learning model
can make such predictions.
I want to explain
and convince people
that this prediction result
is not random.
OK.
Let me introduce myself.
I used to study in Taiwan.
I'm a master's student.
I used to work in
a recommendation system.
If you have questions
about the recommendation system,
you can ask me.
I'll try to answer them.
OK.
I studied math in college.
Before I graduated from
my senior year,
I didn't know how to code.
I didn't even understand
a line of code.
I want to encourage
those who still want to code
not to give up.
Everyone has a chance.
Keep working hard.
Everyone has a chance
to do this.
OK.
Today,
I'm going to talk about
I just want to say
it's too inspirational at the beginning.
Anyway,
I'm not a master today.
I'm just an ordinary
sophomore PhD student.
If you want to interrupt me,
just turn on your microphone
and interrupt me.
OK.
Let's get started.
Today's outline
focuses on four points.
First,
explainable artificial intelligence.
Next,
explainable machine learning.
There are two types of machine learning.
First,
explainable machine learning.
For example,
you may have heard of
decision tree.
In decision tree,
we can see
the model itself
is explainable.
The other type is
neural network.
deep neural network.
It's fully connected.
It's a black box model.
It's not explainable.
You don't know
the learning weight.
You don't know the learning weight.
So,
we need an explanation
after learning the model.
After learning the model,
we need to learn
an explanation model
to explain the model.
This type of learning method
is called post hoc.
post hoc is after prediction process.
OK.
After this,
I'm going to talk about
the application of XAI.
If you are not a computer science
background,
you may wonder
what's the use of XAI.
I'm going to talk about
the open source package
to make an explainable model.
Now, everyone uses Python.
I'm going to talk about
two open source packages.
I'm going to tell you
what is XAI.
XAI is not an unimaginable thing.
If you have a prediction model,
and you want to make it explainable,
everyone has a chance
to step into this field.
OK.
Now,
I'm going to talk about
what is XAI.
Artificial intelligence
has many applications
in our daily life.
For example,
deep mind
has created AlphaGo
to play Go.
It can scare
human experts.
Yes.
A while ago,
deep mind gave
AlphaTensor and
AlphaProtein.
In fact,
they are for reinforcement learning.
They are for
reinforcement learning.
They can be applied
in daily life.
For example,
medical diagnosis.
I give you an X-ray,
and you hope the machine learning model
can tell if you have a brain tumor.
Then it will tell you
if you have a brain tumor.
Or you can tell
the machine learning model
if you have a cough
or symptoms.
Tesla Autopilot
is an
autonomous vehicle.
It will not detect
any object.
It will give you the best way
to drive the car.
Next is voice recognition.
For example, Alexa.
I don't know if you have used
a smart speaker.
When you speak to the speaker,
it will detect your voice
and convert it
to English.
Then it will
request the service
from the online server.
Recently,
there is a popular
speech-to-speech
in Meta.
This kind of
AI application
is becoming more and more common.
It is hard for us
to know why
these models make these judgments.
For example,
if you go to a doctor
and he presented a
medical diagnosis model.
You input all your symptoms
into this model.
He will say,
you just have a cold today.
Why do you make this judgment?
Or if Tesla gives you
the best
autonomous driving
route plan,
do you really think
he won't be in trouble?
In this decision-making process,
if you can provide
what features
this model learned today,
or if it senses
a pedestrian passing by
and stops,
or if it detects a green light
in front of it.
If this kind of
why process is provided to users,
it can actually
increase people's
credibility in
machine learning models.
So,
the whole XAI
is actually doing one thing.
It wants to provide
a reasonable reason to users.
For example,
what features did this model learn?
Or what did this model see?
Or did this model learn
two or three features
that led me to make
this prediction result?
XAI is improving
this process.
For example,
this autopilot on the left.
What does XAI want to do?
We actually want to provide
why this autopilot
will give you
a safe route plan.
So, you have to tell users
that because my model
detects people,
my model detects
no cars within 50 meters.
For example,
the medical diagnosis
on the right.
The medical diagnosis
is like
persuading a doctor
or a patient
that because I
see a tumor
in the X-ray of your brain,
I frame it,
so I judge your brain tumor.
This action
doesn't seem
so necessary
in the whole
prediction process.
But if you provide
this step to users,
why this step,
users will feel
very confident
about your decision
model.
Of course, there are many applications
that I haven't mentioned,
such as stock market trading.
For example, if you buy
a stock,
the price of the stock
has already fallen
to the point of fracture.
If you sell the stock,
the price will not
fall below $100.
If the model is wrong,
it will ask you to sell it
because the price of the stock
may fall below $100.
You have to convince
the trader
that because I see
a tumor
in the X-ray of your brain,
your prediction model
is credible.
There are several points
related to this.
First, you have to convince users.
Second, you have to provide security.
Another important thing
is some legal things,
such as GDPR.
A while ago,
Facebook was called
to the European Parliament
or Google CEO
was called to the U.S.
House of Representatives
was called to scold.
In fact,
these privacy data
or personal data
are not provided
to users
in a reasonable
or safe way.
You can't use these features
unconditionally
as a basis
for training models.
If you can provide these methods
to users through XAI
and say
I use these features
today
and provide you
some personal
recommendations or predictions.
In fact, users
will be more at ease
that you have used these things.
Even if it is privacy data,
it is better than
using XAI.
This is the reason
why XAI has attracted
more and more people
in the past 1 or 2 years
or 3 or 4 years.
OK.
Next,
those are
some high-level
things.
Let's talk about
some
more
scientific things.
If we are doing
image classification,
we are judging
the model
whether it is good or not.
We are training
a model of image classification.
We can't say
this model
is good or not.
Of course, we can say
it is a prediction.
For example,
we can predict
the label of this image.
However,
we can say
this image is a frog.
Does this model
really learn the characteristics of a frog?
In other words,
does it really learn
the head of a frog?
Does it really learn
No one knows.
It may learn
that most of the frog images
are because the frog
stands on the pond and the lotus.
So it catches the characteristics
of the pond and the lotus.
We don't know this.
Why?
When a model like this
learns the model of
pond and frog,
will it predict the wrong?
We don't know this.
Through this AI,
we can see
which part is important.
In the end,
if we get the final explanation
that the reason
the model is a frog
is because it has
a very representative head,
then we know
this model is actually learning
the right direction,
instead of catching some
background loopholes
or shortcuts
to improve
the AI.
For example,
let's say
there is a test
to see if you are
a COVID classifier.
As we all know,
there is a high probability
that you have a fever or a sore throat.
Let's say you only have a cold.
If you only have a fever
or a sore throat,
the test says you are a COVID classifier.
Then you are panicking.
If we want to
judge whether
the machine learning model
really learns
the features we want,
for example,
we provide some X-ray photos.
It will say that
the COVID diagnosis
is not only based on
the two features,
sore throat and fever.
If we
provide
this prediction result
to the user,
we can detect
the features
and the user
will be happier.
Okay.
Let's drink some water.
To sum up,
AI and XAI
are actually
a cycle
of prediction.
If we don't have
AI prediction,
we don't need to
detect the features.
XAI will not appear.
XAI is
mainly
trained by
a model.
The prediction model
has the ability to detect
the features.
You can see
a dog here.
There is a prediction model here.
It detects that it is a dog.
Why?
Maybe the dog is lying on the ground.
Most dogs are lying on the ground.
I learned the features
on the side.
It detects that it is a dog.
Or maybe
it is orange.
It detects that it is a dog.
We don't know.
It is a black box model.
We need another
XAI model
to open the black box.
We need another XAI model
Then we can see
why the picture is a dog.
Because the dog has thin eyes
and special ears.
Because of the learning
of this feature,
the picture is
judged to be a dog.
At this time,
XAI model is very credible.
Because we know
it learns in the right direction.
Instead of
learning other features
to create the prediction result.
This model,
prediction model,
is more credible.
OK.
That was
an explanation of
a big concept of XAI.
Let's go deeper.
I am not sure
if you are all
CS background students,
professors,
or PhD students.
Today,
I am going to give a high-level
talk.
We are going to
learn more about
the current
XAI
SOTA techniques
to execute
the explanation.
OK.
Before that,
let's take a look
at the different scopes.
There are global and local.
I am going to talk about
the global.
We are looking at the model.
For example,
the image classifier
in total
cares about the features.
For example,
let's train
a model
for dog
classifier.
We want to know
what this model cares about.
For example,
dogs have different ears.
So, ears are the features
this model cares about.
This is the global scope.
What is local?
Local is to explain
what each image cares about.
For example,
if we want to
do the global,
we have to look at the classifier
in all dogs.
What features does it care about?
But in the local scope,
we have to look at
each image.
This image cares about
the dog's face.
the dog's tail or ears.
In the local scope,
each image cares about
each image.
Each has its own advantages.
If we want to look at
whether this model is credible,
we can use global.
For example,
in total,
the autopilot model
detects
traffic lights,
pedestrians,
or obstacles
on the road.
In total,
we use global.
In the local scope,
in this scene,
in this second,
the sensor detects
this street scene.
Because it has something,
it can provide something in the next second.
When we analyze
the street scene
every second,
we have to use the local model.
The local model
provides a more
restrictive
explanation to the user.
This is global and local.
Next, there are two
different manners.
One is intrinsic and the other is post-hoc.
Intrinsic means
the model itself has something to explain.
What is something to explain?
For example,
decision tree.
At the end,
the model predicts the result is C.
We can start from C
and go back to C.
For example,
when the model makes a decision,
what are the conditions
to reach the
final prediction result?
The model itself
has something to explain.
We can know
from the model's decision
what features it has
or what condition it has.
This is the intrinsic model.
On the right,
if you have heard
some Machine Learning lectures
or courses,
you should know about BERT.
In BERT,
there is a
tension score
for each word
in the model.
For example,
I put a sentence
in the BERT model.
For each word,
there is a positive or negative sentiment.
Each word
has an added value
in terms of
positive or negative sentiment.
For example,
love is positive.
Love is a positive
tense.
This
high-level
contribution
is the tension weight
in the model.
So we can use
the importance of words
in terms of
model prediction
to determine
why this sentence
is a
positive
prediction result.
We can use
the importance score
to make the prediction result.
The two models
I just talked about
are Intrinsic
and Prediction.
Next is
Post-Hoc.
I will talk about
why I focus on
Post-Hoc.
Most
machine learning models
use black box models.
For example,
I build a deep learning network
and stack some blocks
and
connect them to
a convolution.
These prediction models
have good results,
but I don't know
what they do inside.
For example, I don't know
what features they learn.
This black box learning
requires
Post-Hoc.
After the model training,
I need to provide an
explanation
for the prediction model.
This model
is common
in daily life.
For example,
let's build a
recommendation system.
We use
neural network
to train the model.
At this time,
the recommendation system
is not explainable.
So we need a
explainable model
to explain the model.
The Post-Hoc model
has two scopes.
One is global,
the other is local.
For the global model,
I need to see
what features
the neural network
focuses on.
For the local model,
the neural network
focuses on
18 years old,
male,
Asian,
Chinese,
and Taiwanese.
So I need
a high level
model.
Each model
has different features.
I need to provide
different models
for each model.
In conclusion,
these two models
are the mainstream.
Intrinsic and Post-Hoc.
Today,
I will focus on
the Post-Hoc explanation.
Later on,
I will focus on
the local model.
Local model is
common in daily life.
For example,
the recommendation system.
OK.
Now,
let's talk about
Intrinsic and Local.
Here is a picture.
This is an article.
For example,
I say this article
is important.
Why?
Because it detects
ENT23 or
natural tenacity.
So,
through this,
I can tell
which word is important.
users
why I use this article
to make a prediction.
It's because
my model detects
ENT23
or natural tenacity.
This way,
users can be convinced
that their prediction
is correct.
OK.
This is
what Intrinsic
provides.
OK.
What is Intrinsic Global?
As I said,
Global focuses on
the model.
For example,
we design a CNN model
which is
a representation
of image classification.
OK.
Why does CNN
successfully detect
the image of a cat?
It's because
it detects the cat's head.
If we extract
a layer
of model weight
from CNN,
we can see
that this model
does a convolution
to some features
resulting in
a model prediction.
OK.
If we extract
this feature map
from the model,
users can see
that
their prediction
is correct.
This is
the process
of Intrinsic.
Intrinsic is
a model
which has
a function
to make a prediction.
Or a model
can extract
a component
to make a prediction.
This is
the process of Intrinsic.
OK.
The other thing
we focus on
is PostHoc Explanation.
PostHoc Explanation
is divided into two steps.
The first step is
the black box model,
which is our prediction model.
We have data and model
to train.
The next step is
the explainer,
which is our machine learning
model to explain
the prediction model.
OK.
Then we need
to know
whether the explainer
is correct or not.
We don't need to
trust the explainer.
We can use
many different metrics
to determine
whether the explainer
is correct or not.
The most famous metric
is the sharp E-value.
If you have
a background in economics
you need to calculate
the contribution of each feature
to the prediction model.
We use
the sharp E-value
in Game Theory
to create
the correct answer
and do the evaluation.
OK.
The explainer has many
methods, such as SHARP
and LIME.
These methods
have one
big drawback.
If we want to do
the local explanation,
we need to provide
an explanation for each picture.
The most common
method
is to
provide
an explanation
for each picture.
We need to have
100,000 pictures
to provide
an explanation for each picture.
We need to provide
This process
is very slow.
These methods
have some drawbacks.
Of course,
some people say
we have a good
SHARP
and Game Theory
I will explain
why we can't
use SHARP
to provide an explanation.
OK.
What is SHARP E-Value?
SHARP E-Value
is a tool
to provide
an explanation
for model prediction.
To create SHARP E-Value,
we need to know
the important score
of each feature.
We need to know
the important score
of each feature.
What do we need to do
to know the important score
of each feature?
It's simple.
Let's say
we have 4 features.
5. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
We need to know
the important score
of each feature.
We need to know
the important score
of each feature.
For example,
we need to know
the important score
of Job and
Marital Status.
We need to know
the important score
of each feature.
We need to use
the only combination
of all features.
We need to use
the only combination
of all features.
For example,
we need to use
the only combination
of Job and Marital Status.
We need to know
the important score
of each feature
in the Sharp Eval.
What will happen?
If there are only
5 features,
all combinations
will be 2 to the power of 5.
So, it's 2 to the power of 5.
If I have
2,000 features
in the recommendation system
in a big company,
it will be 2 to the power of 2,000.
A user needs
2 to the power of 2,000.
I have 1 billion users
today.
The calculation process
is endless.
So,
why can't we use the Sharp Eval?
It's an NP-hard problem.
Its complexity
is too high.
We can't use
a low-complexity method
to verify
our calculations.
So,
we use the word
Sharp Eval
to explain
the important score.
It's possible, but not realistic.
Why?
It takes too much time
and complexity
to calculate.
So,
we can't use it.
Oh, I forgot to mention
the following.
For example,
I only care about Job and Marito.
If I remove the other three,
what will happen
to my model prediction?
What will happen
If I remove
Balance, Job,
and Marito,
and only consider Age and Education
in my prediction model,
the prediction result
can't be returned,
but it can be returned.
What does it mean?
These three features are important.
So,
we can use
this iterative process
to find
the important score
for each feature.
This is Sharp Eval.
If you know economics,
you will feel
this is quite
intimate.
OK.
If we can't use
Sharp Eval,
what can we do?
This is my research.
I want to
speed up
the process of
explanation.
Because
when we do
local explanation,
each user must
provide a customized
explanation result.
As I mentioned,
each customized explanation
is a model
to explain the prediction model.
This process
takes a lot of time.
For example,
if you give a recommended result
and ask the user to wait
10 seconds,
the user can't
accept it.
If you ask the user to wait
10 seconds,
the user will click
the upper left corner.
This is the work
I did last year.
This work
aims to
speed up
the operation of
Sharp Eval
and provide the
user with an
explanation result.
As I mentioned,
I want to
go through all the combinations
of the feature set.
For example,
each feature set
is important to the model,
isn't it?
Some features
are not important
to the model.
Can we get this information
after training the model?
Yes, we can.
We can take out
the weight of the model
and see that
feature 1 and feature 2
are not important.
Feature 1 and feature 3
Feature 1 and feature 5
are not important at all.
We can take out
feature 1 and feature 5
from the combination
of Sharp Eval.
For example,
we want to have
2 squares,
so we need 32 squares.
We can take out
the number of times
that we need to calculate.
It may be 2, 2, 4, 6, 8,
4, 5, 4, 2... 14 times.
It's actually half the process.
This process can
speed up the calculation
of Sharp Eval
and turn this into
a user's acceptable
waiting time.
Finally, provide the user
with a faster
explanation result.
This mathematician
is actually expressing that
in Sharp Eval,
we need to go through
all the features.
We turn it into
the importance of
the interaction between
feature and feature
through the weight of the model.
We take out the unimportant
and calculate the approximate
Sharp Eval.
We take this Sharp Eval
and provide the important score
of the explanation to the user.
This is the spirit
of this work.
As you can see,
this work
has an application scenario.
Today, we trained
a prediction model
to predict
whether the income
is high or low.
We can use our model
to explain the trained
prediction model
and then provide
the reason.
For example,
if you are a part-time worker,
you will be judged
as a high-paying worker.
This model
can be used
in a faster way
to provide
an explanation
to the user.
You can see
the blue bar on the left
is the
ground truth
Sharp Eval.
We use the method of
economics and theory
to calculate the
Sharp Eval value
for this feature.
As you can see,
even if we take out
the unimportant feature
and interaction,
the Sharp Eval
score
is very close to
the Sharp Eval.
We can't say it's exactly the same
because we took out
some combinations.
It's faster,
but we don't lose
the Sharp Eval accuracy.
When we provide
the importance of each feature
to the user,
we can say that
for our model,
whether it's high-paying
or low-paying,
we can provide
the score
or the important
ranking result
to the user
as a reference
for whether
they want to believe
the prediction model.
The next step
is to
speed up
the calculation
of the Sharp Eval.
Instead of
speeding up the process,
we can train
a model to learn
the distribution
of the Sharp Eval.
This can
provide
a faster
prediction result.
Why?
For a traditional
DNN model,
each user
needs a
customized result,
so we need
an explanation model.
To predict 100,000 users,
we need 100,000 models.
Here, we only need
one model
to predict all users'
explanation results.
This process
is what we call
an explanation process.
Why?
For a deep learning
network,
we can send 100,000 users
as data
to the network
and the network
will produce 100,000 different results.
We don't
need
an independent
explainer
to
respond to all users.
This training
process is another
part of my work.
It is about
whether we can
learn from
positive and negative
samples.
For example,
if we
cover up
an important feature
such as
a dog's eye,
the model will
still make the same
prediction
when it
detects
a dog.
This can
help us
explain.
For example,
we want a model
to detect a dog.
We can give
an explanation
that the dog
cares about
these features,
so the model will
make the same prediction.
We can also give
a negative example.
For example,
the model will
know that
the dog's
negative sample
is a dog.
When the model
detects positive
and negative samples,
we can learn from
the model.
We want the model
to get closer to
the positive sample
and further away from
the negative sample.
This process
is called
contrastive learning.
We want to know
what is right
and what is wrong.
We want to
have a better
distance between
right and wrong.
Why is there
a fine-tuning process?
It is because
the shoppy value
has a strong
support of
economic theory,
so
if we can
create
important scores
that have
shoppy value,
we can
provide
at least
to
machine learning engineers
or higher-ups
to evaluate
whether the
explanation is
believable.
First, we can make
people happier.
Second, we
want to keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We don't
use any
shoppy value
as a label.
We can use
shoppy value
as a label
to keep
shoppy value
away from
explanation.
We can use
the result
to make people
believe that
we are not
creating
important scores
randomly,
so
we can
make people
happy.
Third, we
want to
keep shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We don't
use any
shoppy value
as a label.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
shoppy value
away from
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
fine-tuning.
We can
keep
fine-tuning.
Finally,
I saw
a meeting
No.
Our study is
based on
this individual feature.
Thank you.
Thank you, Alan.
Someone at the group
asked about
mask size.
Mask size?
You mean
the size of the mask?
Yes.
For example,
a dog's eyes.
If
your mask
is
smaller than the eyes,
this mask is valid.
OK.
When we do this,
we can't
make it smaller than the nose.
For example,
if you ask
the size of the mask,
we don't
restrict
the mask size.
But I know
someone restricts
the mask size.
Why?
If the mask size is too large,
it will cause
a negative effect.
Or
it has different
purposes.
Or
it only selects
a few important features.
If the mask size is
too small,
it will cause
a negative effect.
But if the mask size
is the same as
the original image,
it will cause a negative effect.
OK.
Do you have any questions?
OK. Thank you.
I think it depends on the person.
For example,
if the mask size
is
the smallest
feature
of the eye,
it will exceed
a pixel.
I don't know.
I don't know how to answer this question.
Or
sometimes I feel
the size choice
is subjective.
This choice
is made by someone.
Someone
knows
the components
are large.
For example, the eyes are large.
For example, the mask
is not random for every pixel.
It is random for every 4x4 pixel.
Random for every 6x6 pixel.
Someone
does it this way.
But I think
we don't know
the pixel model cares about.
It may be the upper right and lower left
or the upper left and lower right.
Something like this.
If we give such a strong assumption,
I think model training
will be difficult.
This explanation model
Of course, what you said
is exactly right.
It is really like this.
In fact, someone criticized
this kind of explanation.
It is about
covering
the eyes.
In fact, it is possible that
this kind of mask was not done well
at the beginning,
so the final result
is not so comprehensive.
Yes.
This is possible.
I think this question is super good.
OK.
It feels like
there are no new questions
in the chat room.
Then
let's thank
YuNan again
for his speech today.
Thank you, everyone.
How do I stop?
Let me clap my hands.
Thank you.
Thank you for your support.
How many people are there today?
I can't count.
Today, I see
the highest number of people
is 32.
That's a lot.
I found a lot of people.
Is it related to the field?
But no one helped me
to post on Facebook.
I'm kidding.
For example,
I have given a speech before.
I am a physics major.
There are five people in total.
Maybe
everyone is curious about this.
I don't know how to start.
I don't know either.
But I'm glad to have this opportunity
to share my knowledge.
Otherwise, I have to contribute
to the social resources.
Social resources.
Are you Gao Hong-An?
No, I'm not.
I'm not from Taiwan.
It's okay.
Okay.
Thank you.
I have a question.
I suddenly want to ask you a question.
For example,
in your first video,
This one?
Yes, that one.
The one about the matrix.
This one?
Yes, this one.
Do you automatically ignore
all the x1, x1, x2, x2
in the matrix?
We don't discuss
our relationship with ourselves.
We don't discuss our relationship with ourselves.
There is no meaning
in the definition of this question.
Yes, because ShopEvalue
is still ourselves.
Yes.
Our group is still ourselves.
So we don't discuss it.
Of course, our relationship with ourselves
is highly related.
Yes.
Actually, I don't know
how to share it.
Okay.
Let me think about it.
I might stop recording now.
Okay.