Welcome to today's Taira Talk.
Taira stands for Taiwanese Young Researcher Association.
It's an organization for young researchers in Taiwan.
Every weekend of the year,
we hold an event called Taira Talk.
The format of the talk is free and diverse.
We invite academic researchers from different fields
to share their research results,
practice online speech skills,
or share their experiences with potential partners.
The topic of today's talk is
Ph.D. in Physics at the University of Notre Dame.
The topic of today's talk is...
As you can see from the PowerPoint,
the next two weeks' talk...
The next two weeks' talk is...
The next week's talk is...
Let me see.
I forgot.
The next week's talk is...
The next week's talk is about mechanical learning.
The same time.
At 6.30 p.m. on Sunday.
Sorry.
At 6.30 p.m. on Sunday, October 29.
The next week,
the next week,
we will hold a new session.
The same session is held at 6.30 p.m. on Sunday.
It is a talk about economic science.
If you are interested,
you are welcome to follow Tara's post
and Tara's talk.
Today's speaker is Mr. Xu.
He graduated from National Tsinghua University in 2009.
Later, he came to Cornell for a Ph.D.
a Ph.D. in physics.
In 2017,
he obtained his doctorate.
After graduating from Cornell,
he came to the
University of Newfoundland-Myanmar
Condensed Matter Theory Center.
In 2020,
he got a Ph.D. from the University of Newfoundland-Myanmar.
His main interest is
the new phenomenon of quantum many-body system.
His main focus is
inter-winded symmetry,
topology,
and many-body interaction.
Today, he is going to talk about
topology and quantum computing.
Let's follow Tara's post
and welcome Mr. Xu.
Hello, everyone.
Today, I am going to talk about
the relationship between topology and quantum computing.
I will try my best to be scientific.
If you have any questions,
please feel free to ask me.
First of all,
I am a quantum theory physicist.
Today, I am going to share
how a quantum theory physicist
can contribute to the topic.
As you can see,
I am looking for
postdocs and Ph.D. students.
If you find this talk interesting,
please feel free to contact me.
Today, the audience comes from different backgrounds.
I would like to explain
what quantum theory is.
Quantum theory is
condensed matter theoretical physics.
We are studying
quantum theory.
I am not an experimenter.
The tools we use are
computers and pens.
What is quantum theory?
Quantum theory is an equation
that describes the materials
in nature,
and the special materials
in the lab.
All of these materials are
solid or liquid.
This is condensed matter.
As you can see,
this is a diagram.
For example,
this is a two-dimensional material.
It is like a piece of paper.
These black balls
are all atoms.
This is a fairly microscopic scale.
If you look at the size of the atom,
you can see that
there are different scales
in a two-dimensional material.
The scale is hexagonal.
This is just a diagram.
What we are studying
is different materials
with different scales.
You can imagine that
there are atoms next to each atom.
According to quantum mechanics,
there are different activities
around the atom.
What we are studying is
those atoms
in a background like this,
with different scales
in a two-dimensional material.
What interesting things
will happen?
This is the topic
for those who are interested
in quantum physics.
I also want to talk about
what we often hear.
It is very important
for people who do
experimental physics,
especially in quantum mechanics.
What is the relationship
between theory and
experimental physics?
Most important discoveries
in history
in the past 100 years
were made by experiments.
In some experiments,
people found
amazing things
in the material.
Let me give you
an example.
For example,
in the past 100 years,
you can see that
since 2003,
the discovery of superconductors,
superfluid,
superfluid in etheric ocean,
even the famous high-temperature superconductors,
and some important
superconductors were discovered.
These were discovered
by experiments.
These are
four Nobel Prizes.
They were discovered
by experiments
or plans
to discover
special phenomena
in the material.
Then,
theoretical physicists
tried to
understand
the phenomena
in the experiment.
However,
this is not always the case.
Sometimes,
it is the theory
that makes the prediction first.
Then,
experimentalists
tried to see
the predicted phenomena
in the real system.
Sometimes,
these big discoveries
can also be discovered.
However,
this is not always the case.
The reason is that
for superconductors,
this is today's topic.
Of course,
I will explain what superconductors are.
For superconductors,
it is difficult
to make such predictions.
Then,
what I want to do
is to
predict
how to find
special superconductors
in theory,
and
predict
how to make
special superconductors
in theory,
and how to design
special superconductors
in theory.
This is
the focus of my research.
Then,
now,
I will
use a more
physical way
to describe
the problems
that physicists
are studying.
Here is the problem.
You may have seen
the periodic table in high school.
There are so many elements
in the periodic table.
There are more materials.
Because not only these elements,
you can choose
several elements
and combine them
into different compounds.
So,
you can find
tens of thousands
of materials
in nature
or in the lab.
But it sounds
like it is
a very difficult problem
to study the nature of materials.
Why? Let me give you an example.
For example,
let's look at this one.
Cu is copper.
Copper is a very common
material, right?
But today,
I will make some changes
to the copper.
I can remove
some electrons,
neutrons,
and neutrons from the
nucleus.
Then, I can jump
to the next one,
Ni.
It is just next to it.
But their properties
are very different.
Copper has no magnetic properties.
But we know that
Ni is also
magnetic.
So, their properties
are very different.
Now,
let's focus on
one element.
Let's focus on C.
C means carbon.
So,
you can use carbon
to form
this complex 3D structure.
Then, you get diamonds.
If you put
these carbon atoms
into
this 2D structure,
and there are many layers,
then it will be
copper.
It is also carbon,
but it is totally different from diamonds.
If I only take one layer,
then it will be
copper.
It is totally different.
Then,
the blue circles are
carbon.
Although they are all
made of carbon,
their properties are very different.
For example,
diamonds
are very good
solvents,
but
copper and
silver are very good solvents.
Although
these two are solvents,
if you really
pay attention to the numbers,
their
solubility is still very different.
Although you don't have to
care about the unit,
but if you just look at the numbers,
you will know that they are very different.
10 to the power of 8 and 10 to the power of 6
are 100 times different.
Even if
the elements
don't seem to be much different,
or even the same element,
but you build it
into different structures,
their properties can be
100 to the power of 8.
It sounds like
it's a big deal
for people who study materials.
Because there are so many different materials
that can be made in nature
or in a laboratory.
Do we have to
study them one by one?
It takes a lot of time,
manpower, and material resources.
It feels like
it's not a solution.
In fact,
this is not how research is done.
The way we approach
this problem is not
one case by one case.
This is what we do.
Logically,
we classify
so many different materials
according to their
relative properties.
For example,
I classify
red materials
according to their
relative properties.
Then we ask
why the properties of these materials
are the same.
For example,
this cartoon example
is based on
the theory of
quantum physics.
We want to know
why the properties
are the same.
It means that
we don't care
only about the properties
of the materials.
We want to ask
what happened
to make
all the materials
red.
We care about
the size of the materials.
Each ball
represents the size of the materials.
For example,
all the balls are red
because the materials are red.
In fact, the materials are not red,
but they all wear red hats.
We want to know
the size of the materials.
This is a cartoon example.
In fact,
it's not true.
In such a small scale,
the important thing is
that quantum mechanics
becomes very important.
Quantum mechanics
already exists in everyday life,
but because the general scale
is too large,
we can't see the effect of quantum mechanics.
However, quantum mechanics
becomes very important
in the microscopic scale of electronics.
So what we are going to study
is how quantum mechanics
affects the behavior
of these electronics
to make the materials
have certain properties,
such as their color, etc.
Let's use a more academic way
to describe this problem.
It's like this.
What we are studying
is that there are many, many electrons
that spread
in different materials.
These materials
have different lattices,
just like the hexagonal lattice
I just showed you.
They also have different shapes.
But when I say many,
I mean
a lot,
like 10 to the power of 23.
That's a lot.
To study this problem,
I can't
ask a computer
to simulate it.
Because there are too many of them.
A traditional computer
like this
can't run
a brute force simulation.
A computer can't simulate
so many examples at once.
What's more,
there's another point
that makes it more complicated.
These electrons
don't move separately.
They interact with each other.
So this makes
the problem more complicated.
Another point
is that
different lattices
have different effects.
Different lattices
have different shapes.
For example,
this is a hexagonal lattice.
This point and that point
have two different colors,
meaning two different atoms.
I can also show you
a triangular lattice.
Look at the complex structure.
These lattices
can have different atoms.
So these are
different lattices.
Their symmetry is different.
So I need to
not only study
the problem of electrons,
but also look at the environment
of these lattices,
the environment of electrons.
In fact,
these lattices have many symmetries.
There are 230 different symmetries
in nature.
And
it's not just
the materials in nature.
There are various systems
that can be created
artificially in the laboratory.
For example,
cold atoms
can be cooled
to a very low temperature
to control
how they interact with each other.
So even systems like this
can be
done very well
in the lab.
So it feels like
there are many
difficulties.
There are many
complicated things
in it.
So if we want to
deal with such problems,
we have to find a way
to simplify such problems.
This is a very difficult thing,
because the materials
are very complicated.
So you have to understand
the theory behind it,
and then use simple but understandable
methods to understand
what happened
at the electron level
in the microscope.
This is a very challenging thing.
But at the same time,
everyone is willing to do this.
The reason is that
this is a very rewarding thing.
To understand the nature
and the nature of materials
is a very interesting thing.
But at the same time,
to understand the theory
behind these materials
can have
various applications.
For example,
about 40 years ago,
or 60 years ago,
physicists and
materialists
spent a lot of
time and effort
to understand
how a semiconductor works.
So now we have
all kinds of convenient mobile phones.
We are entering the age of computers.
Another example is
superconductors.
The theory of superconductors
has been
widely understood
for a long time.
Now,
people have started to
make large magnets.
This is
the LHC ring
that has been used
in the Swiss particle accelerator.
These are
some examples.
If you are able to
understand the material
in detail,
there will be
some practical applications.
So,
how should we
simplify such a complicated problem?
To put it simply,
due to quantum mechanics,
electrons will move
together
at extremely low temperature,
which is
close to absolute zero.
That is,
although there are
so many electrons in
10²³,
they will not move
and disturb each other.
They tend to do
the same thing.
So,
even if the material is
of a very different kind,
or even the structure
of the atom
is different,
and the sample is made
in a different lab,
it does not matter.
Due to quantum mechanics,
there will only be
one mode of action,
but not infinite.
Only a few kinds
are likely to occur,
and all electrons will move together.
So,
to study the theory of material,
what we need to do
is to study
the collective mode of action
of electrons at low temperature.
Then,
we need to find a way
to classify these modes
into different kinds.
As long as we can do this,
we can do it.
So, we don't need to study
each material individually,
and each material is different.
These so-called
universal collective behavior
actually have another name,
which is phases,
or you may have heard of
images,
images of materials.
Then,
if we want to
classify these
different images
in quantum materials,
we need to have some rules
so that we can say
that the collective behavior
of these electrons
is one kind,
and the collective behavior
of those electrons
is another kind.
So,
more than 100 years ago,
there was a great physicist
named Randall.
Randall proposed that
we should break
the collective behavior
of these electrons
by symmetry.
For example,
the most familiar example
is the magnet.
The reason why
the magnetic field
and the magnetic field
are similar is that
if you zoom in
and see what the electrons
are doing,
each electron has
a magnetic field.
This magnetic field
is like a magnet.
You can imagine
these spins
as if there is
a small arrow
in the electron,
and these arrows
point from the south
to the north.
So,
the magnet has this kind
of magnetic field.
The symmetry
of the magnet
is that
these small arrows
cannot rotate at will.
If it is not in a magnet,
these small arrows
can rotate at will
in the electron.
It does not have to
point in the same direction,
but because it is
in a magnet,
each small arrow
has to point in the same direction.
This is symmetry destruction.
Another example
is this picture.
What is this?
This is a
experimental picture.
They used
a very small
carbon needle
to scan the surface
of the material.
This is the picture they obtained.
I don't know if you can see it,
but there are
little white things here.
Those little white things are atoms.
But you can also see
a relatively large amount
of lines.
This tells us
that if the material
is clean enough,
the size of the atom
is much smaller than the lines.
But we can see
a wave-shaped
line.
This is a
quantum state.
This quantum state
destroys
the symmetry
of the material.
This is
a translational symmetry.
Those are
two different examples.
Now,
let's talk about superconductivity.
Superconductivity is
also an example.
an interesting quantum state.
As we all know,
superconductivity
is a perfect
conductor.
Its resistance R is zero.
If you can
make a wire
with superconductivity,
the wire will not heat up
because there will be no damage.
You can pass the wire
from one end to the other
without any damage.
This is superconductivity.
There is another
characteristic of superconductivity.
It does not like magnetic field.
This is called Meissner effect.
Superconductivity
is a perfect conductor
and it rejects.
These characteristics
can only occur at a very low temperature.
Otherwise, most of the
wires are made with superconductivity.
Because the temperature
must be low enough.
This is
why a very popular
research topic
is to find out
if there is superconductivity at room temperature.
Let me
show you
what I mean
when I say superconductivity is zero.
Let's say this material
is a superconductor.
You add a current
to it
to measure
its voltage difference.
Then you can get superconductivity.
If it is
a superconductor,
when you lower the temperature,
it will
suddenly become zero
at room temperature.
However, if it is
a non-superconducting metal,
its voltage
will only
decrease but not reach zero.
This is the special feature of superconductivity.
This is
a practical example. This is a ball.
When the ball is at a low temperature,
it will also become superconductive.
So
we just said that
there are two
important properties of superconductivity.
One of them is
that its resistance will be zero.
But what happened
to the superconductor
when it became zero?
In fact,
I just showed you this picture.
This is a gold bar.
The black part
is the atom.
The atom is moving around the atom.
You can imagine
that the two atoms are moving around
and interacting with each other.
There are a lot of atoms.
What happened in the superconductor
is that
the atom and the atom
decide not to
move separately.
They want to
move hand in hand
and group by group
in the gold bar.
So
they will form
an electron-bound state.
This kind of electron-bound state
is called Cooper pairs.
The reason why they are willing to do this
instead of individual electron-bound states
is because
this is less energy for them.
So
when they form
this pair of Cooper pairs,
all these Cooper pairs
do the same thing
together.
This is because of the quantum mechanics.
So these Cooper pairs
do not move
one to this side
and the other to that side.
They all do the same thing.
So
they do not collide with each other
and cause damage.
This is why there is no electron-bound state.
Because all these Cooper pairs
are moving in the same direction.
They do not collide
and cause damage.
And
if we want to
look at them from the perspective of symmetry destruction,
because electrons
can form this kind of
pair of electrons,
but they can also
destroy these pair of electrons at any time.
So from this perspective,
the number of electrons is irregular.
OK, so
I just gave you three examples
to see
how to use symmetry destruction
to understand the collective behavior
of electrons.
But this theory is not perfect.
In the experiment,
we gradually found that
although some systems have the same symmetry,
although they have different symmetries,
some of their
observational phenomena are exactly the same.
Then there are other examples
that their symmetries are different,
but
their symmetries are the same,
but their material properties
are very different.
So this means that
symmetry destruction
is not the only
tool we should
use to understand
the collective behavior of electrons.
It seems that
we still need other new ways to distinguish them.
In the past
40 years,
actually,
30 years,
we have learned that
symmetry destruction
is not the only
tool we should
use to understand
the collective behavior of electrons.
In the past 30 years,
physicists have learned that
symmetry destruction
is a very important concept
in mathematics.
By using symmetry destruction
to understand materials and physics,
we have made a lot of progress
in understanding materials.
In 2016,
the Nobel Prize for Physics
was awarded to
Thorpe material.
Thorpe material
was used to understand materials.
Here,
I would like to
use the simplest way
to explain what Thorpe is.
Because this word
looks quite unfamiliar.
After all, it is a translation word.
In English, it is called topology.
In mathematics,
Thorpe is a very
large field.
However, when we use it to understand
materials,
we only use some of the concepts.
Now, I will give you
the simplest example
that I hope you can understand.
So,
let's not look at materials.
Let's go back to what Thorpe is
in mathematics.
First,
let's get out of the reality.
Let's use a more abstract way
to think about it.
Let's say I have two spaces.
The blue space is my base space.
The red space is my target space.
Let's say
the blue space
is a circular path.
Let's say
the blue space
is a circular path.
The other space
is a point.
It is a point
that can rotate on a plane.
The point
can rotate
from 0 to 360 degrees.
Let's say
I define these two spaces.
I can ask
what is the
one-to-one relationship
between these two spaces.
What does it mean?
Let's say
each point
has a point.
What is the
pattern of this point?
I am asking
what is the angle
of each point.
What is the direction
of each point?
What is the possibility?
Let's look at
the first example.
Let's say
I put a arrow
on each point.
In this example,
when I turn around
and ask how the arrow rotates,
you can see
each arrow rotates a little bit,
but not much.
This situation
is totally different
from this situation.
In this situation,
when you walk around
the circle,
the arrow rotates 360 degrees,
which means
the arrow rotates a full circle.
In this example,
when you walk around
the circle,
the arrow rotates
two times.
Theoretically,
if you continue
to walk around
the blue circle,
you can walk around
the whole circle
and not only this.
You can walk around
the whole circle
and not only this.
In this example,
you can use
a winding number
to describe
the rotation of
the red arrow.
The winding number
is the number
of the circle
of the circle.
The winding number
is the number
of the circle
of the circle.
Or you can imagine
the winding number
as a label
to mark
the different situations.
Or you can imagine
the winding number
as a label
to mark
the different situations.
Or you can imagine
the winding number
as a label
to mark
the different situations.
Now you can ask
how to apply
the mathematical definition
on the materials
and how to find
the rotation of
the arrow
The answer is
usually the blue space
is the kinetic space of the arrow
so it is related to
the kinetic space of the arrow.
The red space
is the
position of the electric wave function.
For those who don't know
what is the electric wave function
you can imagine
the position of the electric wave function
as
each arrow
points to a small bell
and the bell
has a red arrow
with only 10 arrows.
You can imagine
the arrow
points to
the different directions
on the bell
so you can imagine
the bell
as the bell.
It is similar to the example
I showed you
The arrow
points to the
different directions
on the bell
and the bell
has a red arrow
with only 10 arrows.
I have just
explained
the meaning of
the elliptic
and how to define
in the materials.
Is it because
the elliptic has a special nature?
Even though
the elliptic
has a special nature,
if the
experiment
doesn't show
the elliptic,
it is just a
definition of the elliptic.
The answer is
the elliptic
has a special nature
when the
elliptic
points to the
different directions
on the bell.
What does it mean?
Let me give you
a famous example.
It is called
integer quantum Hall effect.
What does it mean?
Let's take
a metal or
a semiconductor film
and measure the
cross section
of the current I
with the
current V
and the
current I.
If you take
the ratio of
V and I,
you can get
the Hall resistance
rho h.
If the experiment
is done at room temperature,
many materials
and physics
do the experiment
at the university.
You can ask
how the Hall resistance
changes with the
size of the magnetic field.
I can tell you
it is a linear change.
The bigger the magnetic field,
the bigger the Hall resistance.
However,
if you do the experiment
at low temperature,
you will find
the result is very different.
As the magnetic field
gets bigger,
you can see
the curve is like a step.
What's more,
we call it
quantized plateaus.
It is one step at a time.
What's more,
if you look at
the value
of Hall resistance,
you will find
it is
one over
a whole number.
This is the amazing part.
This part,
h over e squared,
is a universal constant.
It is just a value.
You can think of it as a fixed number,
26kΩ.
However,
this part, one over c,
tells you c is a whole number.
In other words,
if you read its value,
it is 26 divided by 2,
which is 13.
Similarly,
26 divided by 3, 26 divided by 4, etc.
Why is it amazing?
The amazing result
is because
people found
different experiments
from different people
to get the same result.
However,
the result is exactly the same.
The value is
exactly
negative 9 times of 10.
So,
it is very strange.
These values
become
the common unit
of quantum mechanics
in the end.
So,
it is very amazing.
In 1982,
a quantum theorist
found that
the reason behind this result
is that
the electron
goes around
2, 3, 4, etc.
So,
the result is
exactly the same.
However,
I don't have time
to explain
why it is so.
So, this is the first
characteristic of top material,
which is that
the conductor
is the value of
the whole number.
The second
interesting characteristic is that
if
this square
is a two-dimensional
top material,
we can find that
there is an electron
going along the same direction
on the edge of the sample.
So,
these electrons
just sit on the edge of the sample.
There is no electron inside.
Moreover,
they go along the same direction.
So,
this characteristic
can be seen
in almost all
top materials.
So, this is the second interesting characteristic.
So,
after the whole number
quantum Hall effect,
we found that
it is not just a wave model.
In fact, many metals,
semiconductors, or solvents
can have top characteristics,
which means that
they all have the transmission characteristics of the whole number,
and they all have electron flow on the edge.
Now, I want to ask a question.
How can I define a top superconductor?
That is to say,
when electrons form a qubit like this
at low temperature,
in the case of
a two-dimensional qubit,
can I also have a top characteristic?
The answer is of course yes.
So,
let me give you a definition first.
That is to say,
how do I define a top superconductor
according to the definition
we just explained?
All the important information
related to the superconductor
is hidden
in the
kinetic energy of an electron itself,
and when it
forms
a qubit,
what is its wave function?
So, simply put,
if you want to describe a superconductor,
any superconductor,
basically what you care about is
what is its kinetic energy before it forms a qubit,
and what is its wave function
after it forms a qubit.
As long as you know these two things,
you can basically understand
most of the
properties of a superconductor.
So,
using those two things,
the kinetic energy of a single electron
and the wave function of a qubit,
these two quantities,
C and Δ,
I can construct
a three-dimensional superconductor.
I'm just showing it off,
but you don't really need to understand it.
In short, it's a superconductor
constructed by those two quantities.
From this superconductor,
I can play the game I just played,
construct and define
two different spaces.
The first space is still
the kinetic energy of an electron,
but the second space
is not just a qubit,
but a three-dimensional superconductor
because it's a three-dimensional superconductor.
So you can imagine
it's just a qubit,
and it can rotate
in a three-dimensional space.
I can ask
if there is
a circle
between these two spaces.
You can imagine
this
three-dimensional
superconductor space
is a qubit,
and it can rotate
in a three-dimensional space.
That's pretty much it.
There is a very famous example,
which is
a P-wave superconductor.
If you have
heard of
related physics,
or know more about
this is a famous example.
What is the thing
that rotates here?
It's the wave function of
the cooper pair.
You can see it's rotating around
on its qubit.
Another important property is
that in this special
superconductor,
the magnetic field
of the electron
must be the same
as the magnetic field
of the qubit.
It's a Pauli Exclusion Principle.
Statistics
must be the same.
OK.
Next, let's ask
what properties does this superconductor have?
Here comes the important part.
Remember
the second type of
superconductor properties I mentioned?
Is there electromagnetic flow
on the boundary of the sample?
In the
semiconductor,
we can say
there is electromagnetic flow
on the boundary of the sample.
But in the superconductor,
you can still find something
on the boundary of the sample.
But the special example
is not an ordinary electron.
It's a special example
called Majorana.
So it is
only on the boundary of the sample.
But how special is it?
The special thing is
it is the same
as its antiparticle.
It is a special example
of antiparticle.
OK.
These are some examples.
For example,
if you have a 1-dimensional superconductor,
you can find Majorana particle
on the boundary of
the 2-dimensional superconductor.
It is 0-dimensional.
If you have a gray 2-dimensional
superconductor,
you can find a 1-dimensional
Majorana mole
on the boundary.
If you have a 3-dimensional superconductor,
you can find a 2-dimensional
Majorana mole
on the surface of
the 3-dimensional superconductor.
But what I want to emphasize today
is that in this 2-dimensional example,
there is an additional place
where you can find Majorana mole.
That is to say,
if the magnetic field
penetrates the superconductor,
you will form a lot of curvatures.
That is to say,
the magnetic field penetrates the superconductor.
In the middle of these curvatures,
you can also find
a 0-dimensional Majorana mole.
OK.
Then,
when this kind of
2-dimensional superconductor
is 1-dimensional or 2-dimensional,
people are particularly
interested in it.
Because it has quantum computing
as a possible application.
If we want to talk about quantum computing,
we have to focus on
this 0-dimensional Majorana mole.
So it is 0-dimensional and energy is 0.
We call it Majorana zero mole.
There are a lot of
research shows that
it is proposed that
using
the curvature
generated by the magnetic field
I just mentioned
to form the Majorana mole,
to form the so-called qubit.
The qubit is
the qubit in quantum computing.
So what is a qubit?
In a traditional computer,
in a traditional computer,
we know that there are a lot of 0s and 1s, right?
Then the qubit
is the thing
0 and 1
corresponding to the quantum computer.
But it is no longer
just 0 and 1.
There are different numbers.
But I don't have time
to go into that part.
So I will
mention
what are the benefits
of using the Turp superconverter
to do quantum computing.
Why do we have to use the Turp superconverter?
The advantage of using the Turp superconverter
to do quantum computing is
quantum computing
has always been
a possible problem that everyone cares about.
For example,
if you put a quantum computer
in an environment,
it can do
very powerful calculations,
but due to environmental impact,
it will still be affected by the environment,
so it will lead to errors in the calculation.
And if the error rate
is too high,
quantum computing will not be established.
But if you use
the Turp superconverter
as the material
to do quantum computing,
this qubit,
the smallest computing unit,
is not
in the same place.
Instead,
I can take two
relatively distant currents
and the Mariana Zero Mode
as a qubit.
In other words,
if I have some
local noise
in this environment,
it will not destroy
the information in this qubit.
Because I can't
affect the two Mariana Zero Mode
at the same time.
I usually only affect one side,
but not the other side.
In this case,
you have to affect
both sides at the same time
to affect the calculation.
So this is why
everyone says that
using the Turp superconverter
is the best way
to do quantum computing.
It is also a way
to do quantum computing
with higher convergence rate.
Finally,
I want to say
that it sounds pretty good,
right?
If there is a Turp superconverter,
we can use it
to build a quantum computer.
Why haven't I heard about it?
The reason is
what kind of material
is a Turp superconverter?
The answer is
almost none.
In other words,
the existence of a Turp superconverter
is actually a quantum material
that has been predicted
by theory.
But what kind of
actual material
is a Turp superconverter?
Then you can find
the Mariana Zero Mode in it.
This is a big problem.
Although there are
a lot of papers
claiming that
they have seen
the Mariana Zero Mode
in their system,
I think it's fair to say
that our community
can't really
have an experiment
that is very confident
that they have
seen a Mariana qubit
in their system.
I think this is
a direction that
we are still working on.
Although I don't have
enough time now,
I will mention
that my research
is to use
various different
theories to find
different strategies
and systematic recipes
to predict
a Turp superconverter.
Theoretically, after making
such a prediction,
I will make a proposal
to my experiment partners
hoping that they can
really find the material
and verify whether
the material is really
a Turp superconverter.
In the last few minutes,
let me give you
one or two examples.
For example,
you don't need to know
what it is.
I just want to emphasize
that this material
caused a stir
20 years ago.
People think
this should be a Turp superconverter
because many of its properties
look like a Turp superconverter.
But in fact,
the Mariana Zero Mode
in the nest was not seen.
Later, it should be a few years ago,
people found that
some experiments were wrong.
In fact, this kind of superconverter
is not a Turp superconverter.
It is not a Turp superconverter,
and it must be
a superconverter
at a very low temperature.
These are the shortcomings of this material.
In the past,
we proposed
that experiments
should be able to pull
or push it,
or grow it
on a mold of different sizes
in an experimental way,
so that its size
is extended or compressed.
In this way,
my collaborators
can see
some experimental pictures,
but I just want to tell you
that you can see
the quality of the material
can be greatly changed
by pulling
or compressing it.
In theory,
we can predict
that when it is pulled
or compressed to some extent,
this material
can be easier to become a Turp superconverter,
and its temperature
will also increase.
So this is
an example of what we did
in the past.
There are some other works,
but I may not have time to mention today,
so I will only show you
this cover image.
We have done various works,
and the first example
is that
we proposed
how to design
the material
so that the query of the Kubernetes
is in the same direction.
In this way,
it is easier to get a Turp superconverter.
Another way
is to introduce different
symmetries
to make the material
have the Marana Zero Mode.
We also did
other things,
such as using math to
deduce some Turp invariants,
and then using
machine learning
to systematically
go through
the database
with
thousands of materials.
It is difficult
to find
the Turp superconverter
directly,
but by using
the Turp invariants
or machine learning,
we can systematically
find which materials
are more likely.
I don't have time
to talk about these details today,
so I will stop here.
If you have any questions,
please feel free to ask.
If you add a magnetic field,
you can create
a vortex.
Yes, the magnetic field
cannot be too large.
If the magnetic field is too large,
the superconverter will be
rejected,
and the magnetic field
will destroy the superconverter.
So we are talking about
a magnetic field
smaller than the critical B field
to create a vortex
Okay, I see.
Thank you.
Hello.
I am teaching
at Chengda Electronics.
I started
doing quantum computing
around April this year.
To be honest,
I have studied
modern physics,
and the physics I just mentioned
are too profound for me.
I would like to know
from the perspective
of physicists,
that is,
if we want to do
image processing,
the special point
of image processing
is that we can take
a picture of millions of pixels.
In other words,
even if we only need
8 bits for a pixel,
I may need
8 million bits, right?
For a quantum computer,
it may be 8 million bits.
8 million qubits.
In the case of IBM's
more powerful quantum computer,
it may only have
about 80 bits.
I would like to know
that physicists think
that the difference in the number
of qubits,
if we want to break through
an order, for example,
to make it 10 times,
for example,
from 80 to 800 qubits,
how can we make
a breakthrough?
I think this is
a very good question.
Now,
various companies
have their own
favorite physical system.
For example,
Google has its own,
IBM has its own,
and Microsoft has its own.
So the method I'm talking about
is the method
of quantum computing.
Its advantage is that
I don't know
their actual experiment.
Now they are
very serious about
this project,
so I don't know
their current progress.
But I can tell you
that this path,
topological quantum computing,
its advantage is
that it is very small.
That is to say,
the size of these vortexes
can be very close.
Then it can be very small
compared to other methods,
such as IBM's method.
So it has a way to scale up.
That is to say,
when they have a way
to make a qubit,
in theory,
they have the potential
to make more
qubits.
In addition,
I'm not
an expert
in quantum computing algorithms,
but in theory,
if it is
more fault tolerant,
you don't need
many physical qubits
to make
a real qubit.
So this is
the potential
I can see
in quantum computing.
But I don't know
whether it can be done
in 5 to 10 years.
But I think there is a chance.
Otherwise, these big companies
wouldn't invest so much
effort, right?
They are doing this
very seriously now.
I have a second question.
It's also
from my research.
We have a big problem
with quantum computing.
Quantum computing has
an uncopyability.
When we want to
measure a qubit,
we can only measure it once,
and the quantum state
is gone.
We wanted to
find a solution.
Then I asked
a teacher
who makes materials.
He said a very
well-known
supercomputer
can be used to
measure a qubit,
and the quantum state
is gone.
I'm not sure
if there is
any real
experimental evidence
in your field,
or
if you haven't
heard of it.
Actually, I don't know
the theory of supercomputing.
I need to read
the article.
Otherwise,
I don't know
what it means.
But this is
a problem.
I can imagine
when you do the measurement,
it collapses to a state.
Maybe there is a way
to reconstruct
the original state.
I've heard
some talks
trying to do this
with machine learning.
That's right.
But
we can
discuss it later.
We can discuss it
offline.
I think what Mr. Xu said
is right.
We found that
we have to use machine learning.
That's something
we did recently.
We used deep learning
to solve it.
But I think
physicists may need
to solve
these two problems.
I think these are
the two bottlenecks.
Interesting.
We can discuss it later.
Thank you.
Hello.
Please go ahead.
I can't
turn on
the camera.
So I will
speak directly.
I'm a professor at
the Department of Mass Physics.
My name is Gao Xianzhong.
I have a question.
Someone asked
if you are a
topological superconductor
and
you are a type 2 superconductor
and you add a magnetic field,
there may be
a zero-dimension
marinara mode
near the
vortex core.
I want to ask
that
in general,
in many cases,
when you add a magnetic field,
it doesn't
form a single flux core.
For example,
it may form
a Bricose-off-Lattice.
There will be many cores.
Yes.
Are these
cores
equal to
the magnetic field
on the material
divided by the magnetic field of the unit?
This is a good question.
I haven't
thought about it.
It sounds reasonable.
We can discuss the details later.
I want to
emphasize that
I only draw one here,
but if it is
an application like
quantum computing,
it really needs a lot.
Because it is
a pair of
vortex plus
a zero-dimension
marinara mode.
It is not
a single thing.
Of course, we don't
only need one core.
We need many cores.
I think
the question you just asked
is very important.
If we need many cores,
we need to know
the size of the material
and the magnetic field.
I haven't thought about it.
I can't answer you
precisely now.
We can talk about it later.
Let me
ask the question in the chat.
Hello, I am Xiong Weiren.
I am currently doing research
in the Central Academy of Medicine.
It is said that electrons
have the same
mode of action
at extremely low temperature,
such as superconductivity.
But what is the direction
of superconductivity
at room temperature?
Let me
try to understand
your question.
What I said
at the beginning
is that
in fact,
there are several modes
of action at extremely low temperature,
such as superconductivity
or magnetism.
Or the charge density wave
I just showed you.
Electrons will
show the pattern
of the beam.
There are several patterns.
One of them is superconductivity.
But we can ask
what is the nature of superconductivity?
Is it helpful
in application?
The answer is that it has no damage,
so it is very good.
We hope to apply it
to our daily life,
such as various appliances
or wires,
right?
That's why people want to
ask if there is superconductivity
at room temperature.
Is there any way to see
superconductivity at room temperature?
That's the motivation.
But you can ask
if there is
actually a way to do it.
Recently,
many articles
are trying to
say that they have seen
superconductivity at room temperature,
but there are some controversies.
The general principle
is that you have to add a lot of pressure.
There must be a trade-off.
You can see it
at low temperature,
or you can see it
at room temperature,
but you have to add a lot of pressure.
That's what I've heard so far.
Of course,
there are some famous examples,
such as the so-called high-temperature superconductor,
which is also
negative 200 degrees C.
It's still very low-temperature,
but it's over 100 degrees higher
than the original one.
This kind of high-temperature superconductor
relies on the progress of the material.
That is to say, they make
some copper-based superconductors.
It's obviously a ceramic material.
It should be insoluble,
but at low temperature,
at minus 200 degrees,
it may become a superconductor.
Another direction
is to understand
such a feature,
which is a high-temperature superconductor,
its surrounding physical mechanism,
and then
to find out
if the surrounding physical mechanism
can amplify the behavior
in different material families.
Some people also pursue
this kind of logic
to see if there is any way
to make other materials at room temperature,
without adding a lot of pressure.
I hope I have answered your question.
Thank you, Mr. Xu,
for your wonderful speech.
Is there any other material
that may not be a superconductor?
For example,
double-layered stainless steel?
Hello?
Can you hear me?
Yes, yes, yes.
You can talk about the last part.
Does it stop at double-layered stainless steel?
For example,
double-layered stainless steel?
Oh, I see.
Is it possible that
double-layered stainless steel
is a candidate?
Yes, yes, it is possible.
That's a good question.
Double-layered stainless steel
is a very popular material recently.
It is a double-layered stainless steel.
It can actually be done.
Then they will turn it
in a small angle.
The reason is that
it can be used to
control the interaction between
electrons and electrons,
or the size of the interaction
between the two.
If the interaction is more effective,
the superconductor
can have
all kinds of different
quantum states.
One of them is the superconductor.
It has not been fully
confirmed yet,
but many theories,
including some of my own work,
predict that
in such a system,
when you have some
parameters on the material,
how to adjust them,
it is indeed possible that it is a top superconductor.
So this is possible.
Some of my past work
has also predicted
a lot of double-layered materials
similar to stainless steel,
like the hexagonal material just now,
where each atom is not
carbon, but some other
transition metal, etc.
There are some other
atoms in the cycle table.
If you put it there,
it is another type of
transition metal that can be
collagenized.
Those can also be
torn apart layer by layer
with 3M tape.
I have some work to predict
that it may also be a superconductor.
Okay.
Next question.
Hello, I am Hong Shi-An.
I am currently doing my PhD at NIST.
Since I have not studied
topological quantum
QC, quantum computing,
I would like to ask
which two states
can be used
as 0 and 1?
Why can it be immutable
to localized noise?
This is a big question.
For more details,
I can recommend
a very good
review article
called Review of Modern Physics
by RMP.
In general,
it is not only
0 and 1.
Generally,
it does not have to be
topological quantum computing.
As long as it is quantum computing,
it uses a quantum state
to store information.
In the quantum state,
it is not
100%
or 1%
but
a probability.
For example,
50% is 0,
50% is 1,
etc.
It is a spectrum.
It is not
limited to
0 and 1.
It can store information
in various proportions.
There are more ways
to store information.
When you ask
what 0 and 1 are,
it does not have
a direct correspondence.
It is difficult to explain directly.
Simply put,
I did not say
that qubits can be used
to store information.
For example,
half-quantum vortex
can be used
as a qubit.
There are many qubits.
All of them
can have
high degeneracy
in such a state.
Many configurations
have the same energy.
When you do
some braiding
to exchange
their positions,
etc.,
you can jump
from one degenerate state
to another degenerate state.
This is a
kind of operation.
Hilbert states
can store
information
corresponding to
only 0 and 1.
It is not easy
to explain in detail.
If you have
any questions,
we can
discuss offline later.
The reason why
I say it is
immune to localized noise
is that
the qubits are
composed of
a pair of half-quantum vortex
and a pair of
degenerate states.
They are entangled,
but they can be
in two different places.
When you jump from
one degenerate state
to another,
you can only
jump from
one degenerate state
to another
by braiding.
Other operations
are not sensitive to noise.
That's why I say
it is immune to localized noise.
Unless you have
a special noise
that can
braid two different qubits.
If you can
find a noise
that can do this,
it can't be immune
to localized noise.
I hope I can
answer your question.
Okay.
The last two questions
are from the same person.
Hello,
I'm Zhang Zhiyuan.
I'm currently studying at Tsinghua University.
I'd like to ask
if Marijuana
Zero Mode
is stable
or
will it decay
after some time?
Also,
do you always
use the first law
or do you use
different methods
to study the theory of
denatured states?
That's a good question.
The first question is
that it is an eigenstate.
It is a Hamiltonian
eigenstate,
so it is a stable state.
Theoretically,
it shouldn't decay
Another question is
that I don't use the first law.
I have a lot of
collaborators who use the first law.
What I do is
from
mean field theory
to
mean field theory,
renormalization group,
diagrammatic calculation,
and
we also use
k-theory
to deduce the
unchangeable number,
topological invariant,
and then work with
collaborators using the first law
to calculate
the number
deduced
from the
material library.
OK.
That's all for
the first part of the
Q&A.
Please turn on
the microphone
to thank
Professor Xu.
Thank you.
Let me
turn off
the recording first.
OK.