TARA is an organization for young researchers in Taiwan.
We have a TARA Talk every week on the weekends.
The format and content of this talk are very diverse.
Academic researchers can come here to share their research results,
practice giving presentations,
or get to know potential future collaborators.
Next week and the following week,
we will have a presentation on quantum physics and machine learning.
If you are interested, you can sign up for our presentation announcement.
You can also scan the QR code to sign up for future presentations.
You are also welcome to follow TARA's Facebook and Instagram.
If you are interested in becoming a member,
you can scan the QR code here,
or use the link in the chat.
We have a special Slack channel for TARA members.
We will share various activities, work opportunities,
or new information in the relevant fields.
You are very welcome to join us.
In today's event, we will also issue a TARA badge.
This is the NFT blockchain.
The TARA badge looks pretty good.
I will put the relevant information in the chat later.
You can take a look at it.
At the end of the presentation, we will announce the receipt of the badge.
It requires a password.
We will announce it at the end of the presentation.
If your phone cannot install the POAP app we use,
you can leave it after the presentation.
We will discuss how to solve it.
Let's get back to the topic.
Today's speaker is Lin Shujing.
Shujing completed her university and master's degree in Taiwan.
She studied medical imaging and brain science
at Zhongshan Medical School and Yangming University.
During her university days,
she trained as a clinical radiologist.
During her master's degree,
she studied fMRI analysis in the brain function group of Dr. Long.
she studied neuroscience at UBC University in Canada.
During her master's degree,
she studied the connection between functional neuroimaging
and the cognitive functions of neuropaths.
She focused on neural network analysis.
Currently, she is a research fellow
at Montreal Neurological Institute in Canada.
She is on a business trip in Germany.
Based on Chaira's tradition,
please turn on your microphone
and welcome the speaker.
Are you ready?
3, 2, 1.
Thank you for your cooperation.
I will stop sharing the screen.
The stage is yours, Shujing.
Thank you.
Hi, everyone.
I'm at the hotel in Munihae.
I hope the internet connection is stable.
I hope there won't be any problems.
If there are any problems,
I will try again later.
Please bear with me if there are any problems.
Okay.
Today, I'm going to talk about
neuroimaging.
What is neuroimaging?
What I'm going to talk about today
is a paper in MNI.
This paper was accepted
last year.
I will mainly talk about the main points.
I will also talk about some details.
I will put the reference in the end.
You can read it if you are interested.
Or we can discuss it later.
My title is a bit long.
Neuroimaging can predict
the effect of a patient's treatment.
Let's take a look at the topic.
It's a bit slow.
First, I will talk about
the general background information.
This is not related to
what I'm going to talk about today.
It's mainly for the general concept.
The main point is
what I'm going to talk about today
is an application.
It's an application using multivariant.
Why do we use multivariant
instead of univariant?
Univariant is a more traditional method.
It can indeed increase your statistical efficiency.
But it's too simple.
You can't know much about it.
There are many new evidences.
There are many different diseases.
Neuroimaging, neuroinflammatory,
and other diseases
are not caused by a single factor.
If you use univariant,
you can't see the other important details.
The advantage of using multivariant
is that you can see the multidimensional association.
You can find a comprehensive effect
instead of a single number or variable.
In this way, you can know more precisely
the relationship between your data and clinical trials.
The research I'm going to talk about
is mainly used in Parkinson's disease.
It's a clinical trial.
The main purpose is
to see if the baseline data
can predict the improvement
after the treatment.
This is our central idea.
Next, I'm going to talk about
the research I'm going to talk about.
First, I'm going to talk about
neuropsychology.
What is Parkinson's disease?
It's a disease related to action.
The main cause is
a neuroendocrine in the brain.
For some reason,
we can't tell you what the reason is.
the neuroendocrine gradually dies.
On the right,
in the normal human brain,
this place is called the substantia nigra.
There are many black cells,
the so-called dopamine neurons.
But in the patient,
the black cells are gone.
They become white.
These cells are dead.
They can't transfer the neuroendocrine
to other areas of the brain.
This will cause many clinical symptoms,
including exercise and non-exercise symptoms.
The so-called exercise symptoms
we often hear is resting tremor.
If the patient is sitting,
his hands will keep shaking.
Or non-exercise symptoms,
such as cognitive impairment,
or some patients have insomnia, etc.
Because it's not just a professional exercise symptom,
we say that
every patient is a little different.
So we say it's heterogeneous.
Everyone is different.
It's not just the so-called dopamine system that's affected.
Other neuroendocrine systems are also affected.
So we think this is also a so-called multifactorial disease.
It's not just a single factor that affects this disease.
The current treatment includes
the first and most common,
which is drug control.
Usually, this drug control
is quite good for most patients.
But for some, I don't know why,
they don't react well to this drug.
If this is the case,
we can consider another way,
called deep brain stimulation.
Deep brain stimulation is actually very invasive.
But for some patients,
it's a very effective treatment.
But it has one drawback,
which is that it's very invasive.
Neuroendocrine is actually buried in the brain.
This electrode connects to a battery.
The battery is placed in the patient's chest.
About every five years,
the battery in the chest needs to be replaced.
But it's very invasive.
Not every patient can do this kind of surgery.
So far, we have another way,
which is the one I'm going to talk about today.
I don't know what to do with it.
Because we usually call it
hard-focus ultrasound.
This method uses
precise positioning with the help of imaging
to see which area of the brain
needs to be stimulated.
The hard-focus ultrasound
is a similar way of surgery
to damage the brain tissue.
This will cause the brain to
change the connection of the brain circuit.
After the change,
it can improve some problems in the movement.
I saw the news a few weeks ago.
There is news like this in Taiwan.
It seems to be about MRI navigation
to teach ultrasound therapy.
It sounds terrible.
I will talk about the hard-focus ultrasound.
It's easier.
But the problem is,
although this method
can work well for many patients,
not everyone
can get the same result.
This is what we are still wondering about.
Why?
So we might think
it's because we need some predictions
before the treatment.
And these predictions
are not for the whole group,
but for each patient.
So we need to predict the result
to see if the patient
is suitable for the treatment.
Another important question is
we need to understand
what is the actual effect
of the ultrasound.
Although the treatment
is very effective so far,
we are still not 100% sure
how it works.
So this is also an important question.
Next,
let's talk about the main purpose of this research.
This is a simple way
to show
what we are doing.
I'm not sure
if I have a laser pointer.
Let me see.
Okay,
I have a laser pointer.
There are two main ways.
The first one
is to see
if we can use
the pre-treatment data
to predict the post-treatment results.
The second one
is to see
if the clinical results
after the treatment
can be explained
by the pre-treatment results.
Can the clinical results
be explained
by the pre-treatment results?
We mainly use
multimodal neural imaging
and clinical data
to see
if we can achieve
the two goals.
Let me briefly introduce
our patients.
There are only
35 patients
with Parkinson's disease.
These patients are monoclonal.
They are more affected.
Originally,
we planned to receive
at least 50 patients.
However,
this clinical trial
was conducted in Spain,
which is our partner.
However,
COVID-19 happened
halfway through
the clinical trial.
The Spanish side
seemed to be slightly interrupted.
Several patients
were unable to
enter the clinic.
These patients
are monoclonal.
They are treated
with focus ultrasound.
After the treatment,
after 24 hours,
MRI imaging is performed
to see
if the focus ultrasound
reaches the desired level.
The white arrow
is the so-called lesion.
It is the effect
of the focus ultrasound.
This is the so-called
subthalamic nucleon.
I did not see
the whole process.
However,
according to my lab boss,
the whole process
took a long time.
Let me take a sip of water.
The patient
was treated
with focus ultrasound.
After positioning,
the focus ultrasound
reached the brain area.
At the same time,
neurosurgeons
continued to
perform ultrasound
to see
if the patient's symptoms
had improved immediately.
At the same time,
neurosurgeons
checked the temperature
and the condition of the patient.
According to the patient's
immediate response,
if the patient's symptoms
had improved,
they would stop the ultrasound.
The whole process
took about 1-2 hours.
On the right,
we can see
the difference
between the two
types of motor symptoms.
These are the motor symptoms
assessed by neurosurgeons.
You can see
these four types
of motor symptoms.
They all improved
very well.
From baseline
to
our baseline,
the patient
was treated.
Three months later,
the patient was treated.
This is the fourth month.
You can see that
their treatment was very good.
The performance of the ultrasound
is good.
As for the actual method,
let's take a look at it
because there are too many details.
In short,
we use structural imaging
and functional imaging.
Structural imaging
refers to TY-weighted MRI imaging.
The first step is to
perform the imaging.
The imaging process
involves a lot of processing.
In the end,
what we need
are some numbers.
In functional imaging,
we need these two numbers,
F-alph and Re-alph.
F-alph refers to
the low fluctuation
in the racing set.
It's a bit like
the quantum number.
Re-alph refers to
the regional homogeneity.
It refers to how similar
the regions of the brain are.
In structural imaging,
what we need are
the gravimetric density and
the gravimetric atrophy,
which refers to
how much
the patient's
brain shrinkage
has shrunk.
These are the four
different numbers,
and we put them
into our analysis.
This is our
multimodal neural imaging phenotype.
In statistical analysis,
we use
multivariate cross-correlation,
which is the same
as POS,
partial least square.
In this way,
we can see
the relationship
between two different data.
In this experiment,
the two different data
refer to images,
which are the features
of the brain.
The other data
refers to how much
the patients have improved.
This is a simple graph.
If you're not familiar with
POS,
this is a simple graph
of X and Y.
The purpose of POS
is to find the
X times A1.
A1 refers to
the weighting of X.
We find the
X1 times A1
plus X2 times A2,
and so on.
We find the linear combination
and the linear combination of Y.
These two combinations
are closely related to each other.
They are maximally co-variated.
In this way,
POS will think
that this is the pattern
that we observe.
This is the relationship
between the two features.
In addition,
we will do a lot of
statistical methods
to determine
what we observe
is meaningful in statistics,
including permutations and boosts.
The purpose of boosts
is to see
which variables
are important
and which are not.
These variables
are brain areas
or clinical data.
We need to see
which variables
are important
and which are not.
This is another graph.
It's a bit like
a simple
progress bar.
In this progress bar,
we have FMI and T1,
which are functional and structural data.
In terms of clinical data,
we calculate
how much
the baseline and month for
have increased or improved.
The first analysis
is to use
two sets of variables.
The first set
is imaging
and the second set is clinical improvement.
In the process,
we will also put
covariables,
such as age, gender,
and how long the patient has been sick.
We will remove
these covariables
in a linear way,
so that we don't have to
worry about these factors
when we look at the results.
The second analysis
is to see the difference
between baseline and month for,
not just baseline or month for.
It's to see the difference between them.
The other set of data
is clinical improvement.
We also put
some covariables in here.
Next,
we will look at the results.
The main results
are shown on the right.
The main result
is to see
the X-weighting
and Y-weighting.
The bigger the X-weighting,
the more important
the Y-weighting is
to the patient.
If we look back at the results,
these bars
are the weightings
we just saw.
This is the simplest way
to show
the results.
This is the clinical data,
and this is the imaging data.
How do we interpret this?
You have to look at the bars.
If they are
all positive,
you can see
that the bars
are positive.
The bars are positive.
If the bars
on the positive side
are on the negative side,
the bars on the negative side
are on the positive side.
The bars on the positive side
are more.
The bars on the negative side
are increasing.
are decreasing.
Of course,
we don't put this on paper
when we write paper
to make it more beautiful.
This is another picture.
In addition to the
positive and negative
bars,
the left upper corner
also tells you
how much
the image
is related to
clinical data.
In short,
about 82%
of the data
can be interpreted.
This is quite high.
It means that
what we see
can represent our data.
When we do
permutation,
this is the result of permutation.
It also means that
it is related to statistics.
These are the improvements.
There are comprehensive
motor improvements,
or rigidity,
or tremor,
which are specialized improvements.
In short,
these improvements are related to
imaging.
These two pictures
are structural.
They include
small brain,
superior parietal lobe,
or deep brain.
This is grammatical density.
It is also seen in
superior parietal lobe,
pecuniary parietal lobe,
and small brain.
So,
what we see after
clinical treatment
is that
these improvements
are related to
these brain areas,
not just single brain areas.
The second result
is that
we use the difference
between baseline
and month 4
as our
imaging data.
The same is true
for the two groups
of the same image.
The two images
are related to each other.
We draw the same picture
in this way.
We see that
90% of the data
is explained
in this way.
This is also quite high.
We also see that
these clinical improvements
are related to many brain areas.
In terms of functional brain areas,
we also see some
in frontal lobe,
paracentral,
precuneus,
hippocampus,
and temporal lobe.
In terms of functional
brain areas,
we also see many
including small brain,
C-section,
and even in
precuneus.
We can also say that
the effect of this treatment
is not limited to single brain areas,
but many different brain areas.
In particular,
there are many small brain areas.
At the beginning,
we were surprised
that there are so many
small brain areas.
Later on,
we found a way
to explain it.
Later on,
we found a way
to explain it.
First of all,
we can use baseline
to predict the effect
after the treatment.
In other words,
when the patient's
post-treatment effect is greater,
the number of brain areas
will be relatively higher.
In other words,
patients with
strong treatment effect
may show
more atrophy.
may show more atrophy.
In other words,
the patient's brain
shrink more,
and less gravitational
density.
In other words,
the patient's brain
shrink more,
and less gravitational
density.
In addition,
the patient's brain
is not in single-brain area,
but in many different areas.
In conclusion,
if the patient's
MRI
shows
severe atrophy,
the treatment
may be better.
In other words,
ultrasound treatment
can be used on severe patients.
The second part
is the difference
between the baseline
and the pre-treatment patients
As we can see in this way,
many posterior brain areas
appear on the MRI.
This yes
depends on the function
and the structure of patients.
This depends on the function
These posterior brains
although the patient's
target is in the subthalamus
although the patient's target is in the subthalamus
in that brain area,
the effect of the treatment
is spread out in that area
to the frontal,
to the parietal,
and to the cerebellum.
There is an important link
from the midbrain
to the cerebellum.
There is a long white line
in the middle.
The brain connects
the brain areas.
The effect of the treatment
is spread out from the midbrain
like a telephone line,
to the parietal.
It's not that the treatment spreads from the brain
to the head
to the brain
It's not that the treatment spreads from the brain
to the head
so we can see a significant change
in the brain
and the brain becomes an important indicator.
We done this a year
and I'd like to know
which type of patient
we should focus on
but
how can we do more?
I mean
how can we
push the current
Parkinson's treatment
to a single patient
I mean how can we
push the current treatment
to a personalized level
There are many ways we can do
not just group-wise
say, he is sick
then we can do that
and if he is not
then we can do another way
or if he is this type of patient
then we can do that
because there are many patients
who can't do it
so we need to
design the treatment
for those patients
another thing we can do is
before clinical trial
we carefully select the patient
some patients are suitable
some patients are not
this is also a way
or we can build a lot
in a mathematical or engineering way
to build the so-called brand model
to use these models to predict
the after-effects
we can also do
the so-called disease subtyping
that is, patients are not all the same
there may be many different subtypes
and different subtypes
may be suitable for different treatments
and so on
so
let me talk about business
our lab
is currently doing the so-called
precision medicine
especially in neuroendocrine
the lab also developed
a NeuroPM Bot
its purpose is to let you do
a lot of different analysis
this is the main
a little bit like you
open this toolbox
and see what it looks like
our toolbox can actually
use a lot of different data
not just the image
in addition to the image
of course you can also
use clinical data
cognitive function detection
or blood or gene
and so on
this interface
our toolbox
can be used for visualization
it can see which brainstem
is important
and then
this is a flowchart in paper
see what you need today
if you want to do
disease subtyping today
you can use this module
this is called CTI
if you want to do other parts
you can go here
if you have multi-modal imaging
you can do other things
if you only have a single image
there are so many kinds
you can use ESM
ESM is mainly
look at where the disease
starts in your brain
to find the source of the disease
the other one is to see
the relationship between different modalities
or
on this side
the so-called fingerprint
you can see
if you want to
visualize a patient
how much effort
does it take
to restore a patient's brain
this kind of information
is more effective
in developing design
I personally
have more experience
in this part
other people in our lab
have more experience
this is my lab code
you can download it
on the lab website
CTI is mainly
disease subtyping
and disease staging
if you have a lot of patients
let's say
Parkinson's disease
we can find
these three
if there are three different
we can find these three
at the same time
we can see
if this patient is
the most like a normal person
he is not so sick
so the color is light
or he is already
very serious
that is more red
so we call it
pseudotype
if you use imaging
how serious is the disease
we call
estimated disease severity
this is the result
in the paper
let's say there are a lot of normal people
Alzheimer's disease
and Huntington's disease
we use CTI to
classify them
they have their own
trajectory
Alzheimer's disease
their estimated disease severity
which is pseudotype
is very similar to
clinical indicators
and Huntington's disease
is related to their disease stage
so we get these pseudotypes
actually it is quite meaningful
finally
this should be the last
sharing time
we are currently preparing a
workshop
the time will be in spring or summer
we haven't decided
the location will be at Montreal Neurological Institute
if you are interested in
coming to Montreal, you can try it
there will be two days
the first day will be
I-GET-TALK
there will be students
or postdoc session
the second day will be
hands-on workshop
we will introduce
how to use NeuroPM toolbox
or other precision medicine
toolbox
we will ask people to
introduce to you
we haven't decided
the time or the content
but if there is any news
we will put it on the lab website
roughly
this is
what we are going to talk about
the paper on
focus ultrasound treatment
if you are interested
you can read it
I have saved a lot of details
this is the paper on
toolbox
there is a manual
this is the funding agency
thank you
any questions?
someone
want to ask a question
yes
me
ok
hello
I am Charlene
I want to ask
when you use ultrasound
to treat your brain
will the
dopamine
in your brain
recover?
frankly
no
we have
clinical trial
for a long time
I haven't seen
the latest data
but
according to clinical trial
I can tell you
there is no such thing
but the purpose of ultrasound
is to
cut off
the brain
and make a lesion
the whole
dopamine
recovery
the whole loop
will be cut off
it will
improve
the whole process of
dopamine transmission
in theory
we can't see
the regeneration of dopamine
but we can
change the way
dopamine is transmitted
in the brain
in a physical way
ok
thank you
I want to ask
the time and strength of
ultrasound
should be considered
yes
that's right
I haven't been to
Spain
to see their actual operation
but I know
neurosurgeons are
well-prepared
to keep positioning
and test other
well-known data
indeed
the strength
must be strictly monitored
the treatment time
depends on the patient
so
from the beginning to the end
the strength and time
depends on the patient
they will move their hands
like this
to see if the motor
has improved
if they find
the motor has improved
they can stop
the ultrasound
I've seen
other papers
like
to see if the data
for example
the temperature of
the brain
will rise
to what degree
is safe
how strong
and so on
if
we want to
apply the results
to the clinical trial
we will discuss with
neurosurgeons
to see if
we can
apply the results
to the clinical trial
we do have
a plan like this
but we haven't started
yet
Thank you
I also have a question
outside the door
you mentioned
a lot of treatment
I'm wondering
if quantified
has side effects
yes
usually
after the treatment
within 24 hours
they scan the MRI
to see the lesion
the picture I showed
in the slide
and also to see
if there are any other
complications
in the brain
after 24 hours
the patient will come back
for follow-up
they will
based on the clinical trial
called UBDRS
to assess
the whole process
to see if it is good
and other
quality of life
to see if there are
other complications
indeed
there are
two patients
were removed
due to complications
one of them
should be
better
but worse
so
we need to discuss
why
they did
a series of
assessments
the general question
is about
your background
why did you
switch from medical imaging
to neuroscience
I was
interested in
imaging
especially brain imaging
when I was
an intern
I was an intern
in clinical trial
at that time
we had our first
research institute
we wanted to
apply the imaging
in clinical trial
to
neuropsychiatry
not just
X-ray
I was interested
and I read
a lot of books
when I was
an intern
I wanted to
apply MRI
to patients
with mental
or neuropsychiatric
diseases
but
due to other reasons
I chose
FMRI
although
I did other
experiments
first
I wanted to do it
and second
I could only apply to
neuroscience
in Taiwan
many students
apply to
radiology
medical physics
but
there is no
radiology
in Taiwan
thank you
for your answer
do you have
other questions?
if not
I will
ask another question
thank you
for your speech
I am not a
neuroscientist
I am curious
what do you think
is the most difficult
part of this research?
collecting patient's data
or marking
brain areas
which part
do you think is the most difficult?
I think the most difficult
is how to
write the result
clearly
so that patients
can see it
it is hard
but I am not collecting data
we are collecting data
I know they spent a lot of time and effort
but
for me
the most difficult part is
when we see the result
how do we
calculate the weighting
we see in PRS
we say weighting is important
but if you tell a neuroscientist
I see this weighting
he will think
you think it is useful
but I don't think so
I want to know
how to treat patients
so we spent a lot of time
thinking
how to write the result
clearly
in a language
that is suitable for
clinical doctors
so that they can know
the result is effective
for me
the most difficult part
is when we explain
these variables
the relation between positive and negative
is very complicated
we need to
write it in several layers
the first layer
is to explain the result
positive or negative
the second layer
is to write
because it represents
the physiological meaning
in this process
we spent a lot of time
but luckily
when the paper was sent
the feedback
was good
most people understood
so we took a deep breath
that sounds really good
thank you
it was special
because I studied English
so we never
have the same field
but you have
clinical and academic
you need to communicate
like engineers
and physicists
you need to communicate
thank you
do you have other questions?
countdown
thank you
for your participation
thank you again
thank you
Sujin
we have
a questionnaire
I will turn off the recording