Hello everyone, welcome to Taira Talk.
Taira is a friendly environment for young Taiwanese researchers,
and we hold Taira Talk every weekend throughout the year.
The format and content of this speech are very free and diverse,
and academic researchers can come here to share their achievements
based on their own qualifications, practice online lectures,
or get to know future potential researchers.
Please join the audience on the right.
Today's speaker is Yan Zhiyun.
She is currently a PhD student at Paul Glincher University of New York,
Professor of Neuroscience and Economics.
Her main research focus is on collecting long-term data
from mobile apps to explore the relationship between
individual daily activities and their risks and time preferences.
Today's speech is a part of the data sharing.
The results of today's sharing have already been reviewed in the first round,
and are currently being reviewed,
so she welcomes any suggestions and ideas.
If there are any questions during the speech,
she can interrupt, right?
Yes, you can interrupt or ask questions if you don't understand.
Yan Zhiyun, I'll leave the next part to you.
Let me share the screen.
Okay, good.
Do you understand?
I don't know why I suddenly have echo.
Do you still have it now?
No, I don't think so.
The topic of my speech today is
First of all, thank you everyone for coming to this event.
what my PhD thesis is doing.
We all know that risk and uncertainty
are closely related to many of our choices in our lives.
For example, whether to get vaccinated.
In Taiwan, we don't think it's risky to get vaccinated.
But in the US,
many people don't want to get vaccinated because they think it's dangerous.
Or in another domain,
for example, do you want to invest in virtual currency?
These decisions are actually risk and uncertainty.
So a person's preference for taking risks
actually greatly affects whether he is willing to make these decisions.
So when we researchers study,
we put this concept
a person's individual willingness
to make this kind of risky choice
called risk preference or risk additivity.
a person's individual willingness to make this kind of risky choice
Whether it's economics or psychology,
we usually think of risk preference
as a more stable psychological trait.
There will be differences between individuals.
But more and more research shows that
our risk preferences are actually between individuals.
There will be systematic changes.
It's very dynamic.
So we want to know
what kind of factors will cause
whether it's between individuals or within individuals
So in the past,
our gender is a factor.
Our gender is a factor.
In the past,
women are usually more at risk
in terms of financial risk.
Women are usually more at risk in terms of financial risk.
Or older people are more at risk
in terms of financial risk.
Research also shows that
if you have a good cognitive ability,
you are more willing to take some risks.
Your mental well-being is also a very important factor.
If you are a person with anxiety,
you are usually associated with risk avoidance.
This is a factor that causes differences between individuals.
There are many factors that cause it.
For example,
human or animal research shows
that your metabolic state
may affect your risk preference,
but in a relatively short time scale.
In fact, the good or bad weather
may also affect your level of risk acceptance.
There is a more interesting study
that says that if the weather is pretty good today,
this is a study done in New York City,
the probability of buying a lottery ticket is also higher.
This is an incidental good news.
It's not as if you think the weather is good today,
so you feel good.
So you are willing to do something
that you think will make you feel better about these risks.
So you are willing to do something that you think will make you feel better about these risks.
For example, buying lottery tickets.
Of course, there are other studies that point out
of course, there are other studies that point out
that in fact, after the 2008 financial tsunami,
people became more risk averse to investment.
This is a major life event
that affects your level of risk acceptance.
So there are many different factors
that affect your level of risk acceptance.
So we can find that the topic of risk aversion
is actually studied by many people in psychology and economics.
And it's been studied for decades.
And in all these years of research,
you find that there are so many different factors
that affect the so-called risk aversion.
It's actually very difficult to know
a unified cost-of-risk-preference dynamic.
So what my PhD thesis mainly wants to study
is how to put all the factors together
So we have two main goals.
The first is to establish a data-driven
domain general risk preference ontology.
So this concept is to give a more comprehensive definition
of risk attitude or risk preference.
So compared to the past,
the most recent research is usually a single
risk measure or a single survey or a single
task developed by economists.
So in our experiment,
we not only use a single risk attitude measure,
we use a survey and task-based measure.
We also include a lot of different psychological traits,
such as your cognitive ability,
demographic data,
mental well-being and personality.
We put all these things together
and we did a PCA,
which is the Principle Component Analysis,
to determine what the covariance is between these
traits related to risk preference in the past.
And then we want to know
and these things usually only measured once,
but we will do a repeated measurement,
and we will do a longitudinal experiment.
And we will have a chance to get
more static and dynamic risk preference.
When we have the ability to make a more comprehensive
definition of risk preference,
we want to know if the environmental state
and the state of life of the victim
will affect the change of risk preference.
So, in the end,
we hope to establish
whether there are any risk preferences
in his life.
and whether there's a significant correlation
with the risk preferences we measured.
These are the two things I'd like to do.
Next, I will introduce how we do this experiment.
Overall, we collected a lot of different
So, we have a total of 14 self-report surveys
and two main economic choice tasks.
We measured demographic characteristics,
cognitive ability, mental health, and personality.
These are all factors that have been proven by past experiments.
We put them all together and measured them.
We conducted eight weeks of tests.
These surveyors did a total of 93 instruments.
In these eight weeks, they did experiments every day.
Each instrument has a specific deployment schedule.
Some are done once every two weeks.
The different colors on the top are the surveys
that have been measured many times.
For example, we measured your anxiety,
and your personal health questions.
This is related to depression.
intertemporal task
risk and ambiguity task
I will talk more about these tasks.
I will also talk about the activity tracker.
We do a one-time schedule.
We do it every day for eight weeks.
We try to make them do it every day for less than three minutes.
We divide the longer schedule into several days.
They only do it once,
but some of them will be divided into smaller documents.
This is the demographic.
DOSPR is an economic development tracking tool
for measuring the likelihood of different domain risks.
how willing you are to take the risk.
The risk may be at the moral level,
the risk may be at the moral level,
the economic level, or social level, and so on.
CRT is Cognitive Reflection Task.
CRT is a test of cognitive ability.
BSI is a task related to mental health.
DOSPR measures how likely you are to take the risk.
CRT is Perception.
It measures the benefit you get from this task.
LORT is Life Orientation Task.
LORT is Live Orientation Task.
UPPS is Impulsivity.
IUS is Intolerance of Uncertainty Survey.
Reverence Metrics is IQ Test.
BIS-BAS is Motivation System Survey.
BIS-BAS is Impulsivity Test.
UPPS is Multiple Measure.
Those are more important than getting an IQ Test,
like Movement Ability,
and TAS is used to measure risk.
BIS-BAS is a small game
where the testers
have to choose
between the two Gumball Machines,
the $5 machine
and the $0 machine.
BIS-BAS tests the testers
to see how willing the testers are to take the risk.
Ambiguity test
is when you don't know
how many chances you have
to win the prize.
So you don't know how many chances
you have to win the prize.
Intertemporal test
is when you have two choices
to win the $5 prize
or the $15 prize.
Intertemporal test
is when you have two choices
to win the $5 prize
or the $15 prize.
Intertemporal test
is when you have two choices
to win the $5 prize
or the $15 prize.
Intertemporal test
is when you have two choices
to win the $5 prize
or the $15 prize.
Intertemporal test
is when you have two choices
to win the $5 prize
or the $15 prize.
Intertemporal test
is when you have two choices
to win the $5 prize
or the $15 prize.
Intertemporal test
is when you have two choices
to win the $5 prize
or the $15 prize.
Intertemporal test
is when you have two choices
to win the $5 prize
or the $15 prize.
Intertemporal test
is when you have two choices
to win the $5 prize
or the $15 prize.
Intertemporal test
is when you have two choices
to win the $5 prize
or the $15 prize.
Intertemporal test
is when you have two choices
to win the $5 prize
or the $15 prize.
Intertemporal test
is when you have two choices
to win the $5 prize
or the $15 prize.
Intertemporal test
is when you have two choices
to win the $5 prize
or the $15 prize.
Intertemporal test
is when you have two choices
to win the $5 prize
or the $15 prize.
Intertemporal test
is when you have two choices
to win the $5 prize
or the $15 prize.
Intertemporal test
is when you have two choices
to win the $5 prize
or the $15 prize.
We also use these parameters
to feed the risk-choice models
to our data.
We also use these parameters
to feed the risk-choice models
to our data.
We use these parameters
to create our model
This allows us to know
what the parameterb
or what the parameter's expectation is
You can think of these alpha parameters
as based on the alpha parameters
in EXPECT UDILY model
Since we have such a model
we fit it into a single logistic function
with maximum likelyness
The gamma parameters are used to measure
the choice of noise in the task
So we include these parameters
in the variables I just mentioned
alpha, m, and gamma parameters
So this is what we have
Let me talk about it a little bit
There are also these model fitting parts
Let's talk about our test subjects
We have a total of 123 test subjects
They are found in the CrackList
and in NYU's Psychology Research Participant System
But most of them are from CrackList
So most of them are not students
Out of the 123 test subjects
there are a lot of people who have completed the whole experiment
This is a two-month experiment
but there are still a lot of people who have completed it
So we have a pretty high compliance rate
and there are 115 subjects who have completed all the experiments
We exclude some subjects
because from their choice
we know that they don't seem to be doing the experiment seriously
Or they did some very irrational behavior in our task
This is also one of the criteria for excluding test subjects
In the end, we include a total of 96 test subjects
in our final analysis
So next I'm going to introduce
the result of our PCA
The result of this PCA
is that we used the four principal components
to represent all of our data
The four components in the front
contain a total of 46% of all variances
Let's talk about the risk-choice ratio
In fact, we are repeatedly measuring
So we have a lot of risk-choice ratios
So before we created this PCA
we used the mean value to represent
the tasks that have been measured many times
Then it is represented by their average value
So in this table
I have colored it
The loading in this PCA is greater than 0.2
So it means that in this principal component
these variables are more important
We can find that
mainly in the first principal component
It mainly contains these tables
related to mood and mental wellness
and impulsivity
which is the UPPS document
and intolerance of uncertainty
In fact, the intolerance of uncertainty
is measured by the psychiatrists' table
to measure the degree of uncertainty
of a person
They often use this table
to relate to anxiety and depression
So we can find that
the table designed by the psychiatrists
is more related to the anxiety
and depression
The table designed by the psychiatrists
is more related to the anxiety
and depression
We can find that
the table designed by people in different fields
is more related to the anxiety and depression
We can find that
The second principle component
is the tasks designed by economists
It mainly contains
the variables in the second principle component
It mainly contains the variables in the second principle component
We can find that
in this survey
we can find that
there are common variables in the second principle component
We can talk about it
In fact, there is a big debate in the research of risk bias
Is it a survey
or a game designed by economists
The measured risk bias is your real risk bias
A part of the research is actually discussing
which measurement is more reliable
which measurement is more general
to measure the so-called risk performance
There is a debate
However, we found that the survey and the task
are highly related
It is worth noting that
the task is related to financial risk
Indeed, in the task, they are asking about money
The other related is the risk to health
and the risk to safety
Recreation is less related
Recreation is the relation of others
It is not so closely related
The third and fourth are the remaining variants
The third is the ver Komponent
This mainly inhaled all the change related to the task
The fourth is the current variance
This mainly in the third Principal Komponent
This principle Komponent is used as a single vector
to build dynamic risk preference ontology.
How do we move from dynamic risk preference ontology to dynamic?
The way is
These models are model-free variables and model-based variables.
These variables have a relatively large loading in PCA3.
So we use these loading.
I just said that when we create this PCA,
we actually use the mean value.
So what we're going to do is
we're going to take the different 8-week data
and represent the different 8-week risk additive-related variables.
We do metric multiplication.
Let each indicator have a different risk additive score every week.
After the multiplication, each indicator will have 8.
We have a total of 96 indicators.
So there are 96 indicators and 8 data points for each indicator.
So it will become a matrix of 8 times 96.
Then we get the weekly risk component score.
One thing to remember is that
a relatively low risk component score indicates a higher risk tolerance.
A relatively low risk score means that you are more willing to take risks.
This is actually just the relationship of positive and negative numbers in math.
So you just need to remember this kind of relationship.
What we're going to do is,
like I just said, how do we put our goal 1 and goal 2 together?
We want to see how the risk component score of these 8 data points
is related to the different 8-week sleeping time duration and working time duration.
So we want to know, for example,
whether the total length of sleep at T-1 will affect the current T-1 risk component score.
At the same time, we also want to know,
for example, the relationship between the previous week's risk component score and this week's risk component score.
So we did a regression based on this relationship.
So if we write this regression out, it's a bit like this.
You can think of this P3 as the risk component score for this week.
What we want to know is,
how much of the previous week's sleep time duration can predict the risk component score for this week.
We also added this variable,
which is the risk component score for the previous week,
to control the autocorrelation.
Then we added the dummy variables for each victim.
Then we also asked,
after completing this regression,
how much of the residual can be explained by the previous two weeks' sleep time and the previous two weeks' risk component score.
Then we also added the variable for the sleep time,
which is the risk component score for the previous two weeks,
to control the autocorrelation.
We also added the variable for the work time,
which is the risk component score for the previous two weeks,
to control the autocorrelation.
So we did a total of different regressions.
Finally, this graph shows the beta value coefficient for this activity.
This is the level of sleep.
At each time point, t-1, t-2, t-3, and t-4,
we found that sleeping at t-1 significantly predicts the risk.
So this is the only significant result we found.
These two graphs show the risk of the previous week,
and whether it has a significant impact on the risk of the next week.
We found that it does.
We also found that the predict power of other activities
did not significantly affect the risk of the next week.
So this is the result we found.
To conclude,
the domain-general-risk-attitude ontology can be used
to capture the relationships between your daily life
and the dynamic of psychological properties.
The sleep time can predict risk-evaluation changes.
The conclusion from the results is,
if you had more sleep the previous week,
you will be more willing to take risks the next week.
So, this conclusion can tell us that
a simple physiological thing can affect our risk-preferred changes.
So, this is the conclusion we have so far.
We have also found that
your sleep level can also significantly affect
the negative mood of the next week.
So, if you had more sleep the previous week,
you will be more willing to take risks the next week.
So, the sleep time can predict a lot of things.
So, this is what we have found so far.
So, this is the end of my presentation.
Thank you for listening to my presentation.
Thank you, Ziyun, for your wonderful presentation.
Thank you.
Can I ask a question first?
Sure, go ahead.
So, I want to ask,
why is it that the more sleep you have, the more risk-tolerant you become?
What I want to ask is,
is risk-tolerance related to self-control?
Does it need self-control or not?
For example, the less sleep a person has,
the less self-control they have.
I don't know if this is correct.
If it's correct, then it's still incorrect.
If it's correct, then...
Sorry, I'm just...
Please continue.
No, I mean...
It sounds like the less self-control you have, the more...
You can't take risks.
You want to take more risks.
Yeah, because...
I think it's related.
Yeah, I've seen that too.
It's because of the lack of self-control,
so they take risks.
That's right.
For example, drinking too much or something like that.
I want to know more about this.
I think it's mainly because...
First of all, we have measured the so-called self-control trait.
We found that the trait has nothing to do with our risk attitude.
That's the first thing.
I think this relationship...
The relationship we're trying to explain is...
It's because you might...
Actually, I think the logic can be explained on both sides.
If we're talking about the logic of this story,
it's because you slept better last week,
so you might be in a better mood this week.
When you're in a better mood,
you might have a higher expectation for something risky.
You might be more optimistic.
So you might want to say,
I'm more willing to take this risk.
That's true.
You just said that...
I've seen this study too.
If a teenager doesn't sleep well,
if he's sleep-deprived,
he might not be able to calculate some of his behaviors.
You can't do an effective calculation.
He might not be able to do it.
He might do something risky.
I've seen the direction of the study.
So when I came to this conclusion,
I was actually thinking about how to explain it.
The explanation we wrote in the paper
is probably to explain it in this way.
The so-called repeated major risk
is actually more like financial risk.
Strictly speaking,
it's either no or zero.
It's in a positive domain.
It's not in the negative risk domain.
So the teenager's risk is more likely to be lost.
But our risk is more like the risk in the gain domain.
So there might be such a difference.
So, for example,
the research here can't infer that
the more you sleep,
the more you want to go to the casino.
I think maybe...
I'm just curious.
If you put it that way,
I don't think there's a way.
I think you put it very well.
We're not particularly...
If you sleep well,
if you face some risky things,
you might be more serious about it.
You're more serious about evaluating
or calculating what the risk is.
Because some things are actually...
Of course, after the assessment,
you're willing to take the risk.
That risk may be...
Before you have the assessment,
you don't have the information,
you don't have the concept.
Because after you sleep well,
you're more mentally prepared to do this.
You need more calculative resources.
Some calculations.
So if you put it that way,
you might be facing some
risky choices that might benefit you.
Then you'll have a better chance to do it.
Even if it's taking risks,
but it's actually a good decision for you.
I think there are actually a lot of
different scenarios.
It feels like you see this result,
and then you have to come up with a story to explain it.
So actually,
it seems like you have to see different results.
It's also quite possible to use...
There may be a lot of contradict results.
It's true that it happens a lot.
I think this result is quite interesting.
I can understand what you mean.
Because I've seen a lot of papers.
They put the risk...
Like you said, it's a lost domain.
They see risk as a negative thing.
But you're using tolerance here.
So you can understand that
a person would be more willing to
take the risk reasonably.
About those tasks that require risk but are beneficial.
In terms of the nature of our task,
you're actually willing to take the risk.
The expectation is actually higher.
Because if we calculate it,
you always take a safe risk.
Because you get 5 dollars.
But if you calculate the risk-free choice,
our design is higher than 5 dollars.
Do you have any other questions?
If you have any questions, you can ask them directly.
I have two questions I want to ask.
I think your design is really...
You put a lot of factors into it.
It's quite rigorous.
I have two questions I want to ask.
The first one is...
Because the age range of your audience is quite large.
From 18 to 67 years old.
I imagine that at different ages,
their life activities would be quite different.
For example, some people have retired.
Some people are working.
Some people are young and still in school.
Is there a difference in age or gender?
The second question is...
When I was collecting the demographic,
I was quite curious about
whether it was related to social status.
I feel that social status also affects
the degree of risk you can take.
Especially in the financial sector.
Do you think there is a difference in life activities at different ages?
I haven't analyzed this yet.
But I think there should be.
But if you just look at the age and gender variables,
and compare it with the risk-taking behavior,
we can see that people who are older
are less likely to take risks.
But we don't see a significant difference in gender.
We did ask more questions about social status.
We asked about their academic background.
We also asked about their financial status.
We asked a lot of other questions.
The variables I mentioned are not what we asked.
We have more questions to ask.
But I don't have time to analyze other information.
So I haven't taken a closer look.
But we did ask a lot of questions.
We also asked about their drinking habits.
We asked about their smoking habits.
We still have a lot of questions.
But we haven't taken a closer look.
Anyone else has a question?
If you have a question, please ask.
Hello.
Can you show us what the app looks like?
Oh, sure.
I'd like to take a look.
I'll stop sharing my screen
and show you the screenshot.
Okay?
Sorry.
I remember I don't have it in my IRV.
Okay.
This is what our app looks like.
It's like a map.
Can you see it?
Yes.
This number means how many tasks you have to do.
The user can click on it.
After clicking on it,
like what I mentioned in the report,
the rich tasks or surveys.
If you don't complete a task,
you can get this gem.
You can buy this gem
to decorate your avatar.
This is the avatar.
This is one of the ways to design your avatar.
It's like completing a journey every week.
After you complete it,
you can open this gem.
But this gem doesn't mean anything.
We'll actually give them money.
Every time you complete a journey,
the map behind it will be different.
On the left,
because it hasn't completed these tasks,
the map behind it hasn't been opened yet.
This one is already done,
so the map behind it will come out.
It has different styles.
I think the interface design is quite beautiful.
I can share the company of this app to you.
We use this design app to do experiments.
So it's mainly this data cube app
to do our experiments.
This is what I just said.
You can design your own style.
You can make the user more engaged.
But the most engaged way is to give them money.
We give them weekly payment for the user fee.
We'll also give them extra bonuses for the tasks we do.
So it's meaningful for them to make those choices.
It's not like they're done and that's it.
We really give them a corresponding reward
based on their choices.
So that's about it.
If no one has any questions,
I can ask one more question.
I'm sorry.
I don't think this is a question.
I don't know if you've read
the Noise book published by Daniel Kahneman last year.
I just read it.
I've heard of it, but I haven't read it.
I strongly recommend it.
I think this research sounds like
a term invented by him called Occasion Noise.
The difference in decision-making between people
depends on mood and physiological feedback.
He mentioned something called
Stable Pattern Noise.
He said that this is the biggest difference
in group decision-making.
But there are very few documents being reviewed now.
I just saw that you did age and gender.
You said there's a difference.
I'm curious.
When you were reviewing these documents,
how did you feel?
Why do you think
this demographic
is difficult to review
or study?
That's about it.
I think the difficulty lies in
the fact that this topic
has a long history.
So there are a lot of documents.
And the most difficult thing
is what I just said.
How do you define the so-called risk preference?
Risk preference is a very difficult thing.
It's a very abstract construct.
It's not like other things.
I don't know.
But I have to say
how do you say
this person's risk preference?
It's really hard to measure
with a single quantitative table.
So if you use different quantitative tables
to measure,
you might get different results.
Because what you might ask
is different from what other people ask.
And the so-called risk
has a lot of different domains.
There are a lot of different areas of risk.
I might be a person
who is very willing to
ride the cloud car.
But I'm actually very afraid of socializing.
For example, I may not dare
to publish a different opinion
in a company.
These two are actually risks.
But in fact, their areas
are very unrelated.
So I think
this is the most difficult part.
It's really hard to have
a unified risk preference definition.
In addition to what I just said,
in fact, this topic
has been studied
by economists, psychologists,
and psychologists.
People from different fields
have different research methods.
The thinking of different research methods
is very different.
Because this is a very cross-field
and very important research topic.
But everyone's research method is different.
And the face of concern is also different.
So it becomes that there are
documents everywhere.
There are a lot of documents.
It's just that it's really difficult
to have a single conclusion.
And there are a lot of...
For example, gender.
There are a lot of different conclusions
just about gender.
Even if there is
that kind of meta-analysis,
you will find that
there are actually a lot of
different conclusions.
So I think this is
a very difficult place.
I'm sorry.
I just...
In that book, it says
that there are very few documents.
But you just said
that there are a lot of documents,
but the conclusions are different.
Yes.
What do you mean by
very few documents?
Can you say that again?
Do you mean gender and age?
Gender and age are your research.
But Conleman said
that it should be considered
a difference in domain.
Do you mean different risk domains?
Yes.
I was originally a very risk-taking person.
I thought you said...
But suddenly...
If I were a judge,
I was very sensitive.
Then I suddenly saw this person.
I thought of my son.
I was very sensitive.
He was talking about this.
OK.
He said that
there is less research in this area.
Yes.
What do you mean?
Sorry.
I thought you just said
gender or that.
Because I think
this is more like
the difference in personal experience
for your risk preferences.
Personal experience,
or the so-called...
We actually want to find
environmental factors
to see if these environmental factors
affect you.
But in fact,
I think it's hard to study.
Because it's hard to measure.
It's hard to ask too many
personal questions.
In addition,
like we used to study,
there is very little
long-term research.
So without long-term research,
it's hard for you
to really capture
the events
that this person will encounter
in his life.
Because usually,
for the example you just mentioned,
it's a bit like
this event is very...
In fact,
it's quite unique.
It's very special.
It's like meeting your own child
and then being sentenced to death.
This kind of
personal life experience
is hard to know.
In addition,
it's hard to ask
such a private thing.
RRB also has to be saved for a long time.
So I think our researchers
try to work towards that direction.
It's just that
you have to do what you said.
It's really...
It's an event
for you.
This kind of
risk-benefit difference
is really
quite difficult to do.
But gender and age,
these two,
because it's a more
stable factor.
So many people
have done this research.
Got it.
Because it talks about
the environment.
For example,
the weather
seems to be
less than 10%.
And then
the personality
seems to be
higher.
It's about 20% to 30%.
So...
I'm sorry.
At the moment,
the related personality
has a higher
risk-benefit ratio.
Is the current research
relatively easier to do?
There are quite a few.
But I think...
I think it's mainly
like what I just said.
It depends.
If you are a psychologist,
you may not be so interested
in the personality.
So it depends
on who is doing the research.
Psychologists
may be very interested in this.
So...
There's another thing.
If you want to know
the risk-benefit ratio,
you need to know
the impact
of this risk-benefit ratio
on the next action.
What's the next action?
Everyone cares about
different things.
So...
To answer your question,
there are a lot of researches
on the personality
and risk-benefit ratio.
But what's the point
of this research?
It depends on
what you want to ask.
Okay, thank you.
So...
About the reference documents...
I don't think I saw...
I think you...
I think I posted it
on my personal website.
Is it not completed yet?
Because I want to...
You mean this research?
Yes, the reference documents.
If you want,
I can send it to you.
I've finished
a manuscript.
But...
This research
is...
I posted
Nature Communication.
After reviewing it,
it was rejected.
So I'm reviewing it now.
I hope to post the next one.
I want to change it.
I want to share
my manuscript
in public.
So I'm still changing it.
So I didn't...
At least on our lab website,
I didn't post it.
But if you want,
I can send it to you.
Okay.
Thank you.
That's about it.
I can put
my email
in my chat.
If you want,
I can send it to you.
I think there was a question
in the chat.
How to raise your hand?
Was the question answered?
I'm sorry.
I didn't notice the message.
Is that person still there?
Found it.
Is there anyone else?
Okay.
Thank you.
If no one has a question,
I'll ask the last question.
No one has a question?
Right.
Like...
In experimental economics,
if you want to control
the risk,
to see the impact of the risk,
or to control the risk
in the lab,
do you usually use
hold and load retax to test it?
You've seen so many tasks.
Do you think there is
a better alternative
or suggestion?
If it's based on
the teacher's idea,
the task I'm doing now,
it's relatively simple.
Because it controls one of the options.
Always is the same.
You just change it.
But you just said that
the numbers on both sides will change.
It makes the task easier.
So...
Maybe...
There won't be problems
caused by the task itself.
Because I know some researches
say that some tasks
are too difficult,
so they can't be calculated.
Our...
Our task
is designed differently.
One option is very simple,
and the other...
There's only one variable.
But...
I can't say that
it's the best option.
So...
I think...
Experimental economists
have been developing
new experiments.
So...
For us,
we want to simplify
the experiment.
Thank you.
Any other questions?
If not,
it's time to
say goodbye.
Thank you, Ziyun.
Thank you, everyone.
Let's...
Let's stop here.