Welcome to today's TerraTalk. I am the host for today, Zhang Yanyong. Today, we are very honored to invite Dr. Hong Shaoming, a physical psychologist, to introduce his research interests to us.
Today's research topic is the complexity of unconscious processing. What else do we need to be conscious of?
Before starting today's lecture, let me introduce Shaoming first. Shaoming graduated from the Department of Psychology of NTU. After obtaining a degree, he obtained a Doctoral Degree in Neuroscience from Duke University, Singapore National University Medical School.
After obtaining a Doctoral Degree in Singapore National University Medical School, he came to the University of California, L.A. to do post-doctoral research.
For most of his research, he asked the question, what is consciousness? Can we process unconscious information? What is the relationship between attention and consciousness?
In order to answer these questions, he spent a lot of time designing experiments. His research tools include psychological and physical methods, magnetic reflection, and recently he has also started to use a brain map and eye tracking devices.
Before we welcome Dr. Hong Shaoming, I would like to ask everyone to mute their microphones so that our speakers can hear our applause.
Let's give a round of applause to thank Shaoming for bringing us today's lecture.
What do you want to explain behind the experiment? What do you want to explain? I would suggest that you pause between the entire research and let everyone ask questions. You can ask more details, etc.
If there are no questions, let's start.
As Dr. Hong mentioned, today we are going to talk about the complexity of unconscious processing.
In the end, I want to spend a little time to discuss if I can prove that unconscious processing is really very complicated.
What do we want to do with consciousness? Why don't our brains be like a computer? We receive an input, process it, and then throw the output out.
We don't need to be surprised by the outside world. Why do our brains need to be surprised by the outside world?
In the end, there will be a little discussion.
As usual, I usually define what consciousness is before I talk. At least what is consciousness in this framework of discussion?
The consciousness I want to discuss is basically related to the content, not the state.
These two are more common.
The meaning of the content is, for example, if I pick up this cup now, I don't know if you can see me.
Anyway, when I pick up the cup and I am conscious of this cup, it means that this cup has entered my consciousness.
The state is, for example, I am very bored now, and after five minutes you may fall asleep.
After you fall asleep, before you have a dream, you are in an unconscious state.
The state is not what we are going to talk about today.
It's all about the sensory stimulus that didn't enter your consciousness.
The consciousness we are going to talk about today is also focused on visual awareness.
We often talk about visual awareness.
I will mix visual awareness with consciousness.
When I say consciousness, I am basically talking about visual awareness in this talk.
The experiments I will show you later and the research I usually do are mostly focused on the visual level.
It doesn't mean that these things can't be discussed in the sense of hearing or touch.
It's just that today's focus is on visual awareness.
Why am I interested in the study of unconscious processing?
One of the points is that according to the information theory,
they have a little estimate of the amount of information we receive every second of our eyes and the content we can probably realize.
The amount of information that the eyes can receive is about 10 to 80 bits, so it's a lot.
We can receive so much information every second.
But the content of our real consciousness is a bit controversial.
It's about a few dozen to a few hundred, up to a thousand bits per second.
You can see a very, very, very big difference.
Simply put, of course, the message is transmitted.
From the moment your eyes receive the message to the moment you realize it,
a lot of information is lost.
Another possibility is that when we process external information in the brain,
even if we process it, the information has never entered our consciousness.
But it's still processed by our brain, and it might still affect our behavior.
What I'm interested in is what kind of information these messages are.
What kind of unconscious content can the brain process?
What kind of information can affect our behavior after processing?
Today's menu is very simple.
I'm talking about three things.
First, I'm going to talk about some early research.
I'm going to talk about some early research.
I want to convince you that a lot of things we think we've seen,
or we think we've realized,
like the two words I just said, I'm going to mix them up.
We don't actually realize or see these things.
These are classic psychological or intellectual research.
Second, I'm going to talk about my main research.
Do we just ignore the things we don't see?
No.
We found in a lot of research that the information we don't see,
the information we don't realize,
your brain can still process it, and it can further affect your behavior.
Finally, let's spend some time talking about why we need to see,
why we need to be aware of,
why we need to feel the outside world,
why we need to have experience.
You can feel it from the use of label symbols,
from the first to the third,
which is more and more speculative.
The third is basically my own personal guess.
You're welcome to jump in and discuss.
For the preliminary part,
I'm going to spend some time convincing you that a lot of things we think we've seen,
but we haven't.
The first is a very common example.
When we look at a picture,
we intuitively think that our visual system or our eyes
are like a camera or a camera.
We look at all the details.
For example, if you look at this picture now,
you'll see an animal in the middle,
a lot of flowers and grass,
and I've seen a lot of details.
The next thing I'm going to show you
is a bit like what we used to play when we were kids.
It's called...
I kind of forgot what it's called now.
But anyway,
what I'm going to show you is that I'm going to move this picture
to one of the places,
and then I'm going to move this original picture and the changed picture
back and forth.
If you look at this picture now,
you can remember all the details,
or you can capture all the details in your eyes.
Once I move it,
you should be able to see it very clearly.
Let's try to see if you can see it.
At this time,
we're going to use the YES function we just talked about.
There should be a hand symbol on the far left of your screen.
When you see
where these two pictures are different,
please press YES right away to let me know.
Okay, let's get started.
These are two different pictures.
There's one little thing that's different.
We have a person who is very good at it.
I saw it in an instant.
Okay, then...
He pressed NO again later.
So now it looks like everyone hasn't seen it yet.
I'll give you another ten seconds.
Then I'll announce the answer.
Oh, some people saw it.
Great.
Then I'll announce the answer.
The answer is here.
This point is different.
So this is called change blindness.
What does this mean?
When we think our visual system
sees the outside world,
it will actually capture all the details.
It's not.
Your visual system will actually ignore a lot of details.
What we think we see is actually not what we see.
So when I make a little change,
I'll show you what's the difference between the two pictures.
You actually can't find it.
Okay, that's the first example.
The second example,
in fact, it's still the same.
Okay, that's the first example.
The second example,
in fact, it's still change blindness.
I think this example is very cool.
It's a progressive change blindness.
Okay, this is actually a video.
I'll play this video later.
It will change slowly.
It's a dynamic thing.
Once you see any change,
please press YES right away.
Okay, let's get started.
It's actually a constant process of change.
You might think this is a static picture.
No, it's a video.
Do you see any difference?
Because I've seen it many times.
Now I can clearly see that
it's not the same as it was at the beginning.
Okay, I'll give you five more seconds.
Did you see it?
Some people started to see it.
Okay, I'm going to stop here.
Our video has been broadcast here.
This is what the video looks like at the beginning.
And this is what it looked like just now.
You can see that the color is very different.
This is a progressive change blindness.
In fact, this thing is right in front of us.
But such a big color change,
my visual system can't capture it.
Again,
many times we think
we have seen some changes in the outside world.
Or we actually see the outside world very clearly.
In fact, it may not be true.
Let's show you another more famous example.
I want to broadcast the video first.
After the broadcast,
I'll talk about what this phenomenon is.
What you have to do in this video is
to count the people who are wearing white clothes.
Maybe some people have seen it here.
Because this is really very famous.
People who study psychology must have seen it.
Anyway, others, you can try it first.
What you have to do later is
to count the people wearing white clothes.
How many times have they played basketball?
It's that simple.
Let's get started.
I don't know if you have successfully counted 15 times.
Now the key question is
Did you see a big star on the screen just now?
If you see it, please press Yes.
If you don't see it, please press No.
I want to see your answers.
I will continue to broadcast the video.
It seems that half of the people here have seen it.
Half of the people have seen it.
Half of the people have not seen it.
I will continue to broadcast the video.
Let's take a look at what happened in the middle of the video.
What happened in the middle of the video
when you were counting the people wearing white clothes?
This is a classic psychological phenomenon called
Inattentional blindness.
For example, when your attention is focused on
counting the people wearing white clothes,
even if something strange happens in a very close place,
you still can't see it.
You can't bring these things into your consciousness.
This is called Inattentional blindness.
You can't see these things without attention.
This phenomenon is very famous.
This phenomenon is called Invisible Gorilla.
It is a visual stimulus that is very easy to see.
However, under a slightly difficult situation,
this visual stimulus disappears in front of you.
Finally, I want to talk about a more recent experiment.
Although this experiment is very recent,
the questions answered or the questions you want to answer
are related to something that has been discussed for many years
in the field of neuroscience, psychology, and neuroscience.
Is it true that our eyes feel those colors?
Let me put it this way. Is it true?
In physiology, if you know,
the amount of tracking cells around our eyes is
much less compared to our fovea,
which is right in the middle of the eye.
In other words, if you look at it from a physiological point of view,
the things we see around our eyes should not be very saturated.
The color we see should not be very saturated.
It's a little blurry and black.
But subjectively, we don't feel it.
Subjectively, we think,
I also see the color next to it.
For example, there is a lake next to me.
I also see the color of that lake.
Our subjective experience seems to be a little inconsistent
with the evidence in physiology.
In the past few decades,
there have been many experiments that want to explain to everyone that
you feel like you can see the color of your corner of the eye.
In fact, it is not necessary.
This experiment was published two years ago.
Basically, the whole process of the experiment
is very similar to the traditional experiment.
It's just that they used a VR system.
The question they want to ask is,
if you say you can see the colors around your eyes,
why don't I change it secretly?
If you can see those changes,
that means you can really see it.
Because you really read those colors.
If you can't see it,
maybe the colors you see around your eyes and corner of your eyes
are not as rich as you think.
Their method is very simple.
It's a VR, a virtual reality goggle.
After putting on the goggles,
I will ask them to look at a scene.
For example, here is a rural scene.
Some small houses and so on.
They don't have to do anything.
Their job is,
I might give you a few seconds.
You're just looking around.
In the last trial,
they will slowly turn the places
outside your eyes into black and white.
The amount of changes will be from the most difficult to the simplest.
The simplest is 10 degrees.
The most difficult is 32.5 degrees.
32.5 degrees is the center of your eyes.
About 30 centimeters out of your hand,
there is color in the middle circle.
The rest is colorless.
So even the least obvious situation
is obvious to us.
If you imagine that
the 30-centimeter circle in front of you is colored,
and everything else is black,
will you notice it?
People instinctively say yes.
How many people noticed it at this time?
About 20%.
So about 80% of people didn't notice it.
Only the 32.5-degree corner in the middle is colored.
The rest is not colored.
Most people will say,
I didn't see it.
It's the same as before.
There is color.
It's normal.
This once again proves that
what we thought we saw,
for example, in this situation,
is the color of the corner of our eyes.
We really didn't see it.
Because if we didn't see it,
once it's changed,
we should be able to notice the change.
But we can't.
Through these four different demonstrations,
I want to convince you that
in everyday life,
when you open your eyes,
many things you think you've seen,
you've noticed,
are actually not there.
If you are convinced that
many things in the outside world,
for example,
we're talking about the visual world now,
many things in the visual world
haven't really entered our consciousness.
For me,
the next instinctive question is
what happened to the things you didn't see?
Have they been processed by our brain?
Or did our brain choose to see some things
and throw away the rest?
This is the main part of today's lecture,
which is my own research.
Here,
I've chosen two studies to discuss with you.
The first study is related to the attraction of the face.
We want to show that
the attraction of the face,
even when you don't see that face,
can also be extracted.
It will affect how you distribute your attention.
The second study I want to talk about
is a little more complicated,
which is the processing of language.
I want to show that
the processing of language,
even when you don't see the key word
or some sentences,
you can still extract
the words you can't see.
These grammatical errors
will be processed by your brain
and further affect your behavior.
It's very abstract now,
but it will be clearer as time goes on.
First, let's talk about
the study of the attraction of the face.
Why are we interested in this?
The study of the attraction of the face
has a long history.
There are many theories.
Objectively,
if we don't care about any theory,
from the perspective of a normal person,
how do we know that a face is beautiful?
Objectively,
we need a kind of conscious deliberation.
In other words,
we need to be mindful
of every face we see,
and then say,
I like this face.
It's attractive to me.
I don't like this face.
We need to look at each face,
spend some time and effort
to judge whether it's beautiful
or not.
However,
this kind of intuitive thinking
is contradictory to the results
or answers given by traditional psychology.
What does this mean?
In fact,
psychology basically implies
a very automatic
or even very internal
or very small
mechanism to deal with the attraction of the face.
What does this mean?
For example,
many studies,
including recent or earlier studies,
found that
a very short presentation time,
that is, I show you a face
and the time is very, very short,
can let you judge
whether it's attractive to you or not.
We're talking about short,
short to, for example,
this is 100 milliseconds,
that's 0.1 seconds,
and there are even some
that are short to 13 milliseconds,
that's 75 hertz of a computer frame,
which is a flash.
In fact,
in such a short time,
the audience can still judge
whether this face is beautiful
or not for him.
This seems to imply that
we don't actually need
the so-called deliberation,
don't have to spend a lot of effort
to look at that face,
judge whether I like it or not.
In addition,
earlier baby studies also pointed out that
if you show the baby some pictures,
pictures of the face,
the baby will prefer
a face that is more attractive to them.
These attractive faces
are of course also defined
by adults,
which is a more beautiful face.
Show the baby
and find that they will spend more time
staring at those
more beautiful faces for them.
Okay,
this implies
whether to judge
or read something,
whether a face is beautiful,
is a very early
study,
or even an early process.
Okay,
this is basically the basis
of our experiment.
If there are
these past research foundations,
then we propose an assumption
that perhaps the attractiveness of the face
can be read by us
when you have not seen the face at all.
How do we prove this?
Here I have selected a few experiments
to explain to you.
Okay,
this is our assumption.
The first question we ask is
whether the beautiful face you can't see
has some advantages.
What does this mean?
In fact, if you know a little bit about
the psychology of the human face,
many studies say
that beautiful faces
have many advantages.
For example,
in general,
people will spend more time
paying attention to these faces,
spending more time
looking at these faces.
What we are actually asking here
is something similar.
Is it possible that
these beautiful faces
even if they are hidden by us,
I will talk about
how we hide them later,
it will still show some advantages.
The way we ask here is
whether these beautiful faces
after we hide them,
it will still be easier
to enter our conscious state.
In other words,
when in unconscious state,
its processing may be more efficient
or simply faster.
I will explain later
what is this
intraocular suppression.
Let's talk about
the general way we use
is to find a face database.
Here I just want to tell you
that the faces we use
are all emotionally neutral.
They are all faces
that the collector has never seen.
The important thing here is
that these faces are relatively neutral.
Some collectors even told me
that sometimes our faces
look a little scary
because I don't want them
to have too much emotional information.
I don't want emotions
to become another factor
to affect our experiment results.
Another point is
in this experiment,
we have a main experiment.
After the main experiment,
we asked him to rate it.
Is this face beautiful
or not beautiful?
So in the main experiment,
they don't know
they shouldn't consider
anything related to
facial attractiveness
because it has nothing to do
with their work.
This is actually quite important.
Let me explain
how we make things
invisible in this experiment.
How to make things invisible
to the collector.
Conceptually,
he is actually...
Please say.
Someone is asking a question in the chat.
Do you want to answer now
or will you leave a time later?
I will ask a question
at this time.
But I can...
Wait a minute.
This is a real face.
This is a Karolinska Face Database.
Karolinska is a face
made in Sweden.
You can see
their clothes are the same.
No makeup or light makeup.
I will continue.
I encourage you to...
If it's a quick question like this,
but if it's a more complicated question,
I encourage you to ask
between research and research.
OK.
I want to talk about
how we make things invisible.
The method we use
is a method
related to binocular rivalry.
What does binocular rivalry
or binocular competition mean?
When your left eye
and right eye
show very different images,
for example, a human face
and a house,
or a straight line
and a oblique line.
Instinctively,
we think
what we see
is a stack of these two things.
Maybe a human face
and a house.
It's not.
Our visual system
will choose one of them
and let you see it.
For example, a human face.
After a while,
you see a house.
Then you see a human face
and a house.
This will continue.
In other words,
our visual system
will choose
an image on one eye
and show it to you.
The image on the other eye
is basically suppressed
and invisible.
This is called binocular rivalry.
Your eyes are always
in a state of rivalry.
You don't usually feel it
because what you see
is very close.
There is a slight difference.
But basically
they are fused together.
So there is no rivalry.
But occasionally
there can be a rivalry.
If you are interested,
I can talk about it later.
But anyway,
when I show you
two very different things,
there will be
a binocular rivalry.
In 2005,
Nelson and Christophe Koch
found that
if your two eyes
are always in a state of rivalry,
what if I make
one of your eyes
look very strong,
very colorful,
and keep flickering?
Like this.
We call these things
Mondrian's.
This is related to
the painting
by the Dutch painter.
It was brought from there.
Mondrian's
keeps flickering
on one eye.
On the other eye,
you show it
what you really want to see.
This experiment
is a human face.
What will happen?
At first,
this human face
will not be seen at all.
We can hide
this human face
under the flickering
for a few seconds.
In this experiment,
we measure
something called
suppression time.
How long
can this thing
hide in
our unconscious state?
Let's assume
that a beautiful face
and an ugly face
can be hidden
for a different time.
Why?
Because in the time
we hide,
although you can't see the face,
but the processing
of a beautiful
and ugly face
is different.
This is our assumption.
Once you understand
this concept,
the experiment itself
is very simple.
Every time we present
a face,
maybe on the left or right,
there will be two groups
of flickering things
to suppress
the consciousness of the face.
After each trial,
we ask him
where the face appeared.
Basically,
we just make sure
he didn't trick us.
He really saw this face.
After this experiment,
we get
how long
each face
can be hidden
in the unconscious state.
Again,
we call it
suppression time.
We have a lot of faces,
but for me,
at this time,
after collecting this time,
I don't know
which face is beautiful
or not.
After the experiment,
we will do
a rating
that they didn't know at first.
We want to judge
how beautiful
this face is.
We use all the faces
in the experiment
and ask them to rate them.
Next,
we will divide
these ratings
into less than 4
which is an ugly face,
and more than 5
which is a beautiful face.
You can see
there is a big difference
between the two
in the score.
This is a very simple homework.
After this homework,
we can know
which face
is beautiful
for the subject,
and which face
is not beautiful
for the subject.
You can imagine
that these two faces
are a little bit different
for each person.
In this experiment,
the definition of
whether a face is beautiful
is subjective
by the subject.
Everyone has
a group of beautiful faces
and a group of ugly faces.
With these two faces,
we can calculate
how much time
these two faces
need to spend
to enter
our conscious state.
If you have
heard this once,
I guess you
probably have some guesses.
At this time,
I want to say
that your guess
should be correct.
Beautiful faces
usually enter
our conscious state
earlier and faster.
In fact,
the analysis
is not so intuitive.
Let me explain
what this figure
is talking about.
You can probably
look at the first column first.
You can see
the two dots
and then a bar.
The red dot
is the time
a beautiful face
needs to spend.
In other words,
the red dot
is about five seconds.
The blue dot
is the time
an ugly face
needs to spend.
So,
the first five seconds
are not enough
for the victim
to see the face.
The bottom
is the difference
between the two dots.
The y-axis
is on the right.
What we are doing
here is
a three-part ANOVA.
We also discussed
whether the gender
of the victim
and the gender
of the face
interact.
In other words,
we wanted to see
if the beautiful face
is a girl,
and whether it is
more useful
for the male victim.
On the other hand,
whether the beautiful face
is more useful
for the female victim,
we did not find that.
So,
I will not discuss
the gender
of the beautiful face
in the future.
Anyway,
what we found here
is that
the victim
usually
sees the beautiful face
earlier.
This implies
that
during the time
the victim
cannot see the face,
the beautiful face
seems to be
processed more efficiently
or faster.
So,
during this time,
we know that
the beautiful face
has a shorter
suppression time.
A longer
suppression time
is like
what I just said.
You will see
the beautiful face
earlier,
even if we hide it
so that you cannot see it.
Next,
we will
ask
why
this happens.
Here,
we have
another assumption.
Perhaps
even if you
do not see
the beautiful face,
it will still
attract your attention.
This is like
what happens
when we face
the beautiful face
that you can see.
The beautiful face
attracts your attention.
How do we
prove this?
We use a paradigm
that world scientists
love to use.
It is called
Post-Nurse Cuing Paradigm.
It does not matter
what the name is.
What does this mean?
Imagine
your homework.
If you have done
any psychological homework,
there is always a cross
that you stare at.
After you stare at it,
if I give you a cue,
for example,
it appears on the left.
For example,
this is a very handsome face.
After it appears on the left,
I give you a target.
In theory,
your performance will improve.
Why?
Because your cue
attracts your attention
to that place.
If the target
appears in the same place,
your performance will be better.
For example,
this is the case.
You see a handsome face
and then you see a target.
Then I ask you to judge
whether the orientation
is to the left
or to the right.
Very normal,
very general
visual homework.
What does the picture
below mean?
The green area
is usually called
Cuing Effect.
This is what I call
It means that
at the beginning,
about 200 milliseconds ago,
the receiver's reaction
will become faster
and better.
The black dot
is the location that has been cued.
Just like the situation
you just saw above.
Its reaction speed
will be faster than
the uncue location.
After about 300 milliseconds,
this mode will reverse.
The receiver
in the place
that has just been cued
will react slower.
Then the place
that has not been cued
will react faster.
This thing
in this field
is usually called
Inhibition of Return.
It sounds complicated.
It's actually very simple.
I'll show you a cue
that appears on your left.
After a while,
it disappears.
Your visual system
is looking for
a target
in the first 300 to 400 milliseconds.
If you can't find anything,
your visual system
will say
that there's nothing there,
so we're going to
look for other places.
So if the target
appears
in the original place,
your performance will be worse
because your visual system
has already started
to look for other places.
It even has a
suppression effect
on the original place.
This is called Inhibition of Return.
Why am I talking about this?
It means that
this has something to do
with the result
we're going to find later.
What do we do
in this experiment?
Basically,
we show them
two faces at a time.
One is pretty,
one is not pretty.
Then we use
this bright stimulation
to suppress it
so that the receiver can't see it.
Then let it make
a very simple judgment.
The line is to the left,
the line is to the right.
This is the same as
what I just said.
It's easy to judge
if this tilt
is to the left or to the right.
Then we ask it a lot of questions
to make sure
it really didn't see this face.
Then we can also
do some calibration
to make sure
we can always show
the correct brightness.
If you make your face
very bright,
sometimes they will
suddenly see that face.
So we will have
a trial-by-trial
calibration.
If you're not interested in this,
it doesn't matter at all.
We do a lot of color balance.
The only thing you need to know here
is that you can see
this cold face is black and white.
Because we even
remove the color.
We don't want the color
to affect the result of the experiment.
Then we adjust the brightness
to the average brightness
of the ugly face
and the pretty face.
At this time,
you can guess
that after seeing
a pretty face
or an ugly face
that you can't see,
which side
of your performance
will be better?
Instinctively speaking,
it seems that
you see a pretty face
and your attention
is drawn to it
and your performance
will be better.
In fact, we found that
it's the other way around.
The red dot
is the visual performance
of the invisible pretty face
that they can't see
after they see it.
The visual performance
of the visual work
is the red dot.
The blue dot
is the performance
after they see
the ugly face.
You can see
that most collectors
have the same pattern.
After they see
a pretty face,
their performance
will obviously deteriorate.
There is a pretty obvious result
overall.
Here is my explanation.
This is what I just told you
about the Inhibition of Return.
This is a
long-distance explanation.
Simply put,
the time it takes
for us to show the human face
to the collector
to see the real target,
which is the thing
on the left and right,
is more than one second.
It's very long
and falls into
the Inhibition of Return.
We think
it's possible that
after the collector
sees the pretty face,
the target doesn't show up.
He has gone somewhere else
and the target only shows up.
So his performance
will deteriorate.
Whether it deteriorates
or improves,
it means that
the pretty face
has attracted
some kind of attention
to you.
That's the first point.
The second point is that
there may be
another form of
attention
here.
It means
some kind of
feature-based attention.
What does this mean?
When the invisible
pretty face
appears,
your attention
may be placed
on that face,
on that pretty face.
At this time,
if I ask you to do
another assignment,
it's hard for your attention
to be drawn
from that pretty face
to that invisible face.
So your performance
will deteriorate.
This is also a possibility.
It's a bit like
in your daily life.
If you see
I really don't want to
mention Jin Cheng-wu.
If you see
Xin Yuan-jie
walking past you,
at the same time
he asks you to do
another thing,
you may be distracted
by him.
The performance
of the assignment
you do
will deteriorate.
This is also a
possible phenomenon.
These are two different
possibilities
that can explain
the results here.
I promise you
not to talk about
too much control.
I'll just talk about one.
One possibility
is that
maybe between
a pretty face
and an invisible face,
for example,
the skin condition
is a bit different,
or the hair volume
is a bit different.
So these
more local things
actually determine
our results.
Our approach
is to turn
our face over.
If our experiment results
are really determined
by these local things,
our experiment results
should disappear.
Indeed,
if it is determined
by these local things,
our experiment results
should look the same.
If it is determined
by the face,
the result will remain.
You can see
when we copy,
only when the face
is upright
will we find
this phenomenon.
As long as the face
is turned over,
you can see
that his hair
and other features
are still there,
but the result
disappears.
This proves
that this is
really a human face phenomenon.
In conclusion,
if we hide
these attractive faces
that are attractive
to you,
these pretty faces
will be easier
to enter
our medical content.
Our theory
is to imply
that the brain
deals with
these attractive faces
more quickly
and efficiently
when they are
unconscious.
On the other hand,
if we hide
this face
so that the recipient
can't see it,
we find that
the face
they can't see
if it is attractive
can still
affect our attention
and further affect
their next
very simple
visual performance
behavior.
I hope
that these
tips
have convinced you
that attractive faces
are not only
easy to deal with
in daily life
but also
affect our behavior.
Even when I hide
this face
and you can't see it,
it still changes
your behavior.
Let me pause
here
to see if
there are any questions.
There are some questions
in the chat.
You may...
Yes, I can see them.
Let me see.
I just saw
Zhang Yanyong
say,
Wait, that's me.
Um...
Okay.
Let me start
with this one.
If the recipient
says there is no emotional face...
Say there is no emotional face
is a little scary.
Oh, okay, okay.
So this
emotion
in this...
These faces
have no emotion.
This is
defined by
the creator
of the face database.
When they create
these faces,
there are many situations.
So you can
take out
a happy face
from the face database
or a sad face
or an angry face
from the face database.
I take out
a neutral face.
So in other words,
when doing this experiment,
if the recipient
tells me
he feels
very strong emotions
in these faces,
I will take
the recipient away.
I hope
that answers
the question.
So...
This is
a very good question
about image.
Because there is
an early study
that found that
a...
They use...
What they do
is more...
More...
Interesting.
They show
the naked body
to everyone.
They found
that
the naked body of a girl
has an effect
on the attention
of the male recipient.
This is
similar to our paradigm.
He can't see
the naked body.
But they found
that they have
an effect on attention.
The naked body of a man
has an effect
on the female recipient.
They also found
that the naked body of a man
has an effect
on...
The male
gay recipient
also has an effect.
So your image
will determine
which visual material
affects you.
In our research,
we didn't ask
this question.
Because we didn't even
see the effect of gender.
And we don't
have that many people.
So...
I can't answer
if it has anything to do
with image.
Yes.
Let's
look at the next question.
Uh...
This is
a question from Zhang Yiping.
How long
does it take
to hide different visual materials?
Which visual material
will be found?
Yes.
One of the key points
is the visual material...
I'll tell you
the whole question.
My method
is to hide
things
so that
people can't see them
and become blind.
Then throw in
the visual material
and see which
visual material
comes out first.
That's right.
But the key point
is that these visual materials
should be
two different
visual materials.
For example,
the first example
is the face
and the house.
That...
can affect
the sound
we explain
too much.
Because it may
not be attractive.
It may just be...
For example,
your visual system
may like square things
or round things
or something like that.
So the general practice
is that your visual material
should look a bit like.
In the next experiment,
it will actually
talk about similar things.
For example,
you want to control
his...
Like in this experiment,
we control the color
or its brightness,
etc.
Let us...
The only change
in the sound
is only one or two.
This way,
we can know
that in the end
if they are processed
and there is a time difference,
what is the time difference
that affects?
Then the blind spot
of the visual
is that
we have another experiment
that is trying this thing.
OK.
Maybe we can
talk offline
later.
The material of the eyes
is not,
but...
In fact,
at the beginning
of the introduction,
I said that
I have been doing eye movements recently
because I am interested
in how to use eye movements
to further study
my past research.
If you are interested,
we can talk later.
Why are there
so many questions?
Sorry.
Attractiveness
is asked
by subjective rating.
Attractiveness
of a baby.
In fact,
I was not very accurate
just now.
Attractiveness
is defined
by adults first.
So,
for example,
in the study
of a baby,
it is said that
it will find
a group
of faces
that adults
think are beautiful
and some faces
that adults
think are not beautiful
to show the baby.
So,
the interesting thing
is that
these children
may be born
a few months
or even younger.
They have not yet
learned
the social rules
of the situation,
but they will
pay more attention
to the more beautiful
face
and spend
more time
looking at it.
This is why
some people want to claim that
face-to-face
or face-to-face
attractiveness
may be a very early
process.
In fact,
I do not have to
learn
to achieve it.
Yes,
then,
is it related to
symmetry?
In this experiment,
I did not manipulate,
but
many studies
on face-to-face
attractiveness
will discuss
whether the face
is symmetrical,
for example,
is your face
a
public face
or an average face
will greatly affect
whether this face
is beautiful or not.
In my experiment,
because
I did not want to manipulate
how to make a face
beautiful
or how to make a face
not beautiful,
so my approach is
to catch these faces
and let my collector
judge whether they are beautiful or not.
My guess is
that if I can
control the aspect ratio,
for example,
the same face
and make it more symmetrical
or more asymmetrical
to affect its attractiveness,
similar results
should be replicated.
OK,
that's about it.
I will continue,
otherwise we may not finish.
OK.
This is the first experiment.
I hope
I have convinced everyone
that a face
is actually
when you do not see
your brain
can read a lot of
relevant information.
The second is to talk about grammar.
As I just said,
this concept
will be a little more
complicated than
the previous one,
but it is not really complicated.
I will talk about
what I want to talk about
grammar.
Generally speaking,
grammar
has a lot of
different levels.
For example,
each word
has a different
lexical category.
It may be a verb,
a noun,
or a connected word,
etc.
The grammar I'm talking about
is
when we read
a sentence,
the ability to
put different words
in the right place.
Generally speaking,
we would think
this is a high-level ability.
Why?
Because I need to
calculate something,
I need to know
that this word
should be in the first place,
that word should follow
that word,
so it is a
high-level ability.
For example,
if I show you
some words now,
these are very
simple words,
so you can see
that I can understand
every word,
but I'm just
arranging them now,
so you don't understand
what this sentence is for.
If I want to understand it,
I usually need to
arrange it in the
right place.
Once it is in the
right place,
you may understand
in a second
that this sentence
is about this thing.
The question I want to
ask in this experiment
is that
when our brain
does not see
these words,
how do we
get this information?
This is the
main problem.
Then I will
tell you about
a series of
research that
we have done.
In fact,
when we study,
of course,
we don't use
such a complicated sentence.
We can,
but this is the
first stage,
so we use
some simpler sentences.
I use some
three-word sentences.
These sentences
are normal,
correct,
and legally reasonable
sentences.
There is this
subject,
verb,
and the two verbs
are not legal
in English.
These are the
sentences we
really use.
You can see
birdseedworms and
birdseeddrinks,
so birds eat
and drink.
Drinking
these two verbs
together is
an incorrect
grammatical form.
If anyone here
is doing language
or psychological
language studies,
we also control
the font
of these words
and their length
to ensure that
like we just
talked about
when we do
these experiments,
we can see
if the lower
or different
faces
have been
properly controlled.
We just need to
tell them that
we have
controlled the
other faces.
We want to
make sure
that the main
difference between
these two situations
is that
one is
legally reasonable
and the other
is legally
unreasonable.
The question
is how
do we prove
that our
brain
can't see
these keywords
and still
be able to
correct
grammatical errors
when we can't
see them?
Our approach
is very similar
to what we
talked about
earlier.
Our approach
is to
show the
subject
the first
two words
so that
they can
clearly see
the first
two words
so that
they can
have some
grammatical
expectations.
After
this,
we have
some
catch tasks
to make
sure that
the subject
can see
the first
two words
and
make sure
that
the subject
can read
the first
two words
in
each trial.
The
key point
is the
detection
task.
We are
measuring
the suppression
time.
How long
will it
take for
the
two
words to
be seen?
The
red bar
is the
time it
takes to
see the
word.
The
red bar
is the
time it
takes to
see the
word.
The
red bar
is the
time it
takes to
see the
word.
The
time it
takes to
see the
word,
the
difference in
their
reaction.
Is it
really because of
grammar?
For example,
if you look at
the words we
use,
one word is
always a
verb,
one word is
always a noun,
maybe the
difference between
the two is
the verb and
noun,
or maybe the
noun and
the verb
look a little
different,
so the
effect should
disappear after
the grammatical structure
of the sentence
is destroyed
because there is
no grammar at
this time,
but you
look at the
following two
words, the
key word is
actually the
same.
In these two
experiments,
our effect
disappeared,
which means
that we
found that
the phenomenon
really needs
that word to
be hidden
unconsciously,
that is,
it is
still the same
key word,
the effect will
disappear.
The next
question we ask
is actually after
several years,
the question we
ask is that
this kind of
experiment seems to
still rely on
us to see
the grammar error
in the end
because the
receiver sees
and then the
reaction
sees the
reaction,
so is there
a possibility
that we
must see
such an
experiment result
?
Is there
a possibility
that we can
prove that the
grammar error
itself can
really be
independently
processed
unconsciously?
Our approach
is that
otherwise we
hide the
whole part of
the sentence
and then
we will
hide it
and then
there will
be a few
advantages.
I will
tell you later
that our
approach
is to
hide the
real word
or the
fake word
in English.
At this
time, you
can see that
there are
some different
conditions here,
such as that
it can be a
grammatically
reasonable word
or it can be
a grammatically
unreasonable word
or it is
a fake word.
The
fake word
actually has
nothing to do
with our
analysis,
just that
we have to
balance the
amount of
words that
he can't see
if he can
handle the
two words
that he can't
see,
half of the
sentence,
which may
affect
how he
judges the
grammatically
reasonable and
unreasonable
words.
There are
two points
here.
The first
is that
they can't
see the
words hidden
in the
front.
We have
run some
tests to
see if
it has
anything to
do with
grammar,
so the
point is that
he can't
see the
words in
front and
he doesn't
know if
the key
words are
grammatically
wrong or
correct,
but in
this case
we still
find that
when the
word is
wrong,
its
reaction
speed
is
slow.
In the
earlier experiment,
we found that
if I let the
recipient read the
first half of the
sentence,
when the
last word
does not
match the
grammar of
the
sentence,
it will
enter our
conscious state
earlier.
This is
a bit like
the concept
of discussing
the face
at the
beginning .
At this
time,
the words
that do not
match the
grammar will
even be faster.
On the
contrary,
in the last
experiment,
we let you
see that
if you read
a sentence
that you
can't
see at
the beginning
,
even if
you don't
know if
the
word is
grammatically
correct or
wrong,
your
reaction
will
be faster.
For some
reasons,
our brains
tend to
deal with
grammatical
errors more
quickly.
Of course,
there are
various experiments
in psychological
linguistics
.
When you
read something,
if there is
a grammatical
error,
it will
become a
more salient
stimulus.
Sometimes it
is more
popular and
we see it.
However,
this is the
second experiment.
I hope that
these experiments
will convince you
that the
grammatical
processing of
sentences
sounds like a
relatively
high-level
cognitive process
that can also
occur when we
don't see
words.
Let me
answer a
few more
questions.
There is a
problem that
Chinese reading is
less affected by
order.
This is a
good question.
I have not
tested this experiment
on Chinese
users.
I have
always wanted to
try it.
There are
two
relative
theories.
One is that
Chinese reading is
relatively less
affected by
order.
Word order
is less
important.
Perhaps this
effect will not
come out.
The other
is that it
still works
and is
not
affected by
order.
It just
doesn't
affect us
to read the
sentence.
This does
not mean that
the brain will not
notice that
there is a
problem with
the
order.
The
question I
want to
ask is
whether it is
logical to
be
educated
by
grammar
and
cognitive
behavior
.
This is the
first experiment
I did as a
Ph.D.
At first, I
couldn't find
any results.
Then I found
that this may be
a test of
English ability.
It is possible
that
grammar is
relatively
detailed.
You may
need a
lot of
things.
For example,
you may need
native speakers
to be able to
distinguish the
correct words
from the
wrong words
.
Although I
didn't do a
formal test,
I agree that
the degree of
familiarity with
this language
or the
degree of
education in
this language
may greatly
affect the
results of
this experiment
.
In other words,
the interpretation
of
Yan Yong
is right.
After long
training,
you know
what is
legally
reasonable and
what is
not
.
This is
a bit
complicated
because
everyone will
discuss what
can enter
the unconscious
from the
conscious.
A common
example is
driving.
When you
drive for the
first time,
everything is
very conscious
because you
have to pay
attention to
what you
should
step on
.
After
training,
the degree of
familiarity will
allow something
that was
supposed to be
conscious to
enter the
unconscious process
.
In my
imagination,
this experiment
is actually
a bit
similar to
that process
.
I have
finished
answering
.
I am going
to
enter the
last stage
of
today.
Before
that,
I hope I have
convinced you that
the attraction of the
face and the
processing of the
sentence
can be
processed
when you do
not see the
key material
, which is
the face
or the
character.
In fact,
we do more than
this.
We also
do, for
example,
the integration
between
vision and
hearing,
or the
processing of
meaning,
which is
the
processing of
meaning.
We also
found that
if you see
something you can't
see,
its reaction
is different from
the reaction
you want to
do next.
It will
interfere with
your next
reaction.
Most of
these are
visual messages.
Many visual
messages
can still
be processed
by your
brain
even if
you do
not see
them.
These results
show that
even if
your brain
does not
see them,
some messages
can be
processed by
your visual
system.
With these
results,
the next
reasonable question
is why
our brain
should not
be like a
computer
where we
input
the