Welcome to today's TerraTalk. I am today's host, Zhang Yan-Yong.
We are very honored to invite Dr. Chen Qian-Yong to give us a speech.
Today's topic is from the base to the surface.
The impact of aquatic plants on the surface of the environment and sedimentary sediments in the environment.
Before we start, let me introduce Dr. Chen Qian-Yong.
Dr. Chen Qian-Yong is currently a postdoctoral research associate at Oak Ridge National Lab.
Her main job is in the Hydropower Resilience and Sustainability Project.
Her Ph.D. is in the UIUC Archaeology Department.
Her main focus is on Interfacial Gas Transfer and Sediment Dynamics in Environmental Flows with Aquatic Vegetation.
She is currently in Oak Ridge.
Of course, she does a lot of modeling and numerical simulation.
Before she came to the UIUC and got her Ph.D.,
she got her Bachelor's Degree in Physics from Tsinghua University in Taiwan.
Then she got her Master's Degree in Fluid Mechanics from NTU.
Without further ado, let's welcome Dr. Chen Qian-Yong to give us a wonderful speech.
Thank you for the introduction.
My name is Chen Qian-Yong.
I am currently a postdoctoral research associate at Oak Ridge National Lab.
I am honored to be able to give a lecture on Hydropower Resilience and Sustainability on Taira's platform.
As I mentioned earlier, I expect the audience to be from all walks of life.
So I will try to make my presentation as general as possible.
I hope that everyone will be able to understand some of the topics in the Hydropower Resilience and Sustainability project.
I will mainly focus on the research topics during my Ph.D.
I will introduce how hydropower resilience affects the surface of the environment, and the mechanism of subsurface sedimentation.
I hope to make some small extensions and introduce some of the most popular research topics in our field.
As I mentioned earlier, I hope the whole process will be easier and more discussionable.
If you have any questions, please feel free to contact me.
I will briefly introduce my background.
I graduated from Tsinghua University and majored in physics.
I went to Taiwan University to major in fluid mechanics.
After that, I moved to Illinois.
I majored in soil and environmental engineering at the University of Illinois.
I am a Ph.D. in hydropower engineering.
I just finished my master's degree last month.
So I just moved to the National Laboratory of Hydropower in Tennessee for the first week.
I am a Ph.D. in environmental sciences.
My research during my Ph.D. is mainly focused on hydropower.
Although I am now at Oak Ridge, which is famous for numerical simulation,
my work during my master's degree is mainly numerical simulation.
However, during my Ph.D., I mainly do experiments and image processing.
Basically, I will place different hydropower structures in my hydropower experiments.
I will simulate hydropower in a real environment,
or I will simulate hydropower in a real environment,
and see how it affects the flow of water.
Then we will use high-resolution laser imaging to do hydropower testing.
I will explain the more detailed experiment settings and methods later.
My main field of research is applied in environmental fluid mechanics,
fluid flow experiments, and theory in ecological hydropower.
Before I get into my research topic,
I want to spend some time to introduce
what the Department of Applied Environmental Engineering is doing.
I also want to explain what the Department of Applied Environmental Fluid Mechanics,
fluid flow experiments, and theory in ecological hydropower are.
I hope to give you some basic concepts.
You may have some questions about why I am studying applied fluid mechanics in the Department of Applied Environmental Engineering.
Because people generally have an impression of the Department of Applied Environmental Engineering
that it is about building houses or buildings.
In fact, it is not like that.
The Department of Applied Environmental Engineering has a very wide range of things to study.
For example, if you can see the English name of its department.
It is called Schedule of Engineering,
In fact, in Chinese, we should refer to it as Civil or Jameson Engineering.
Then in Taiwan, generally speaking,
we separate the Department of Applied Environmental Engineering from the Department of Applied Environmental Engineering.
Then, like TAIWEN and JIAUCHEN State University,
there is a Department of Applied Environmental Engineering
and the Department of Applied Environmental Engineering lacks Opining Institute,
a branch of the Department of Applied Environmental Engineering.
Then ChengDinh University,
even has a department of Applied Environmental Engineering.
In addition, the Department of AppliedEnvironmental Engineering is allowed to study mainly heavily in China,
In fact, like in the United States,
generally speaking, the Department of Applied Environmental Engineering and the Department of Applied Environmental Engineering are integrated into a department.
So we call it Civil and Environmental Engineering.
In the field of Applied Environmental Engineering,
in fact, it includes structures, geotechnical,
or transportation, etc.
Then the field of Applied Environmental Engineering is mainly divided into water quality, air pollution, and green energy.
Among them is the water resource engineering, natural disasters, climate change, etc.
are all in the field between Applied Environmental Engineering and Applied Environmental Engineering.
In fact, there are a lot of professors in the Department of Applied Environmental Engineering in the United States
are engaged in research on this area.
OK, good.
Here I want to ask you a question.
I just talked about water resource engineering,
which is the field of my Ph.D. main focus program.
When it comes to water resource engineering,
generally speaking, you will think of what it is about,
what this field is doing.
That is, everyone can express their own impression.
When it comes to water resource engineering,
what do you think of?
Does anyone want to share?
Let me talk about it first.
OK.
I may be a little awkward.
What I think of intuitively is to build a water dam,
or to build a channel, something like that.
Yes, yes.
Yes.
OK, does anyone else want to share?
When it comes to water resource engineering,
what do you think of?
OK.
Everyone may be a little shy.
In fact, I just talked about building a water dam and then a channel.
That's right.
This is indeed what water resource engineering is doing.
Well, roughly speaking,
I like it very much.
Our university has a course
called Water Resource Engineering Discussion.
And in this course,
when the teacher is talking,
I like to use this picture
to roughly explain what water resource engineering is.
Basically, it actually
puts all the water,
that is, the water cycle in the natural world,
to do research on each different component.
I personally like to divide it into
four different sub-fields,
such as aquatics,
groundwater,
aquatics,
water resource planning,
and management.
As I mentioned earlier,
building a water dam or a channel
is more like aquatics.
Because you may have to calculate some fluid mechanics
to know that
what you are going to build
for your dam and base.
So it's actually a bit cross-referential
because you still have to
do some structural engineering
with the traditional earth and wood.
Because they understand the structure
and we understand fluid mechanics.
But water resource engineering is actually mainly
I like to divide it into these four.
I'm actually mainly focused on
environmental fluid mechanics.
And this thing can actually be said to be
one of the components in fluid mechanics.
But it can also be said to be
a university door that comes out independently.
Environmental fluid mechanics
is actually mainly about
how matter
spreads and spreads
in the natural world.
This natural fluid can be water
and it can also be air.
For example, the emission of factory smoke.
And then there's the construction of a water reservoir.
And then the impact on natural water flow.
And then there's the waves of the ocean
and the sea cycle.
Or even the typhoon.
Because I just mentioned that
your natural fluid can be water
or air.
So typhoon
These are actually
environmental fluid mechanics
research areas.
And then I've been talking about
a fluid phenomenon.
It's turbulence.
It's called turbulence in English.
This Chinese can actually be called turbulence
It can also be called turbulence.
So if you've ever been on a plane,
you must have heard of it.
We often have turbulence on the plane.
What about this turbulence?
In fact, in fluid mechanics,
It's also a very popular
It's also a very important topic.
Like the famous physicist
Richard Feynman
once said
Turbulence is a
It's been around for over a hundred years.
And then it hasn't been completely solved.
A complex physical problem.
So what exactly is turbulence?
Turbulence can be said to be a kind of fluid
Fluid state
What about when the flow rate is very small?
Fluid is a layer-by-layer fluid.
They don't mix with each other.
And then this state
We call it a flow.
But when you
When the speed of the object increases,
The flow of the fluid
There will be a wave-like pendulum.
And then the frequency of the pendulum and the government
The flow rate will increase faster and faster.
So when the fluid reaches
When it's past the transition stage
It will enter
A state called turbulence
When it reaches this speed
In fact, you can find that the flow becomes
It's no longer clear.
You can't track
Every flow
It's from the beginning to the end
How does it flow in the middle?
And then there will be a lot of small whirlpools in the flow.
Then these whirlpools
We call it turbulence or turbulence.
The scientist here
Propose a parameter
It's called Reynolds.
And then use this parameter
We can assess
That's how messy this flow is.
It's basically a
The ratio of fluid inertia to fluid viscosity
So the bigger the Reynolds number
It means that the fluid is more chaotic.
A simple example is a bee and water.
Like bees, we can know
It's very viscous.
So it's your molecule.
That's your Reynolds number.
The Reynolds number is very small.
So basically
We say honey
This kind of thing
It's not so messy.
Not turbulence
But like water
Especially in a natural environment
Like a waterfall
Basically because it's very viscous
So once your inertia is very fast
Your Reynolds number is big
You'll find that it's basically very messy.
And then it's easy to produce this kind of turbulence.
In the natural world, in fact,
Most of the fluids belong to turbulence.
So turbulence is studying environmental fluid mechanics.
Is a very important indicator
Yes, and then like a river.
And then the volcano erupts
In fact, it's all a kind of turbulence.
A phenomenon on the environmental fluid
Yes, so my research is basically
The concept of fluid mechanics and turbulence
Applied to ecological fluid mechanics
What is ecological fluid mechanics?
It is to explore the interaction between fluid mechanics and ecology.
So it can be roughly divided into three major areas.
One is fluid mechanics
One is what we call geological geometry and ecology.
Interaction between each other
Interconnection and influence
Just give a simple example
It's like if I have some beavers.
That's what we call the water in the river.
That should be in Chinese.
Because the beaver basically builds the water dam.
We call it beaver dam
Once this beaver
It belongs to an ecological phenomenon
And then these animals are in the river.
Built a dam
After the dam is built, it will change the fluid.
Change the fluid
It may change the entire river bed.
So the whole geological geometry will change
After the geological geometry changes
It may come back to affect you.
This reasonable ecology
Because you have changed the geological
Maybe it's more suitable for them to survive.
So it becomes more
Or become more unsuitable for survival
Then they will become less
So it's actually a mutual
How to say
An ecological chain that affects each other
Ecological geometry is currently in the water resource project
It's a relatively new
And a more and more popular field
Mainly because people began to realize
The importance of many ecological projects
Like the redwood forest on the bank of the river
The existence of redwood forest
It helps to naturally block the waves
Then reduce the erosion of the river
From the perspective of biodiversity
At the same time, it can also provide different species
An ecological habitat
At the same time, the large trees on the bank of the river
Also play a similar role
Okay, so much
I hope to take advantage of the time in front
Have a little concept with everyone
What I did
What kind of field
Now it's time to enter my topic
My doctoral research
Mainly doing experiments
To explore
When I have these aquatic plants in the water
It's not looking at the river now
Is looking at aquatic plants
What about those plants
How to change the flow of water in physics
And then change the flow of water
Nisa's whirlpool and the glory of the air
But in fact
The bottom bed of Nisa
And the transmission
And the glory of the air
It's always been an environmental scientist
A very concerned research topic
That's because Nisa's flush and transmission
It's going to change the river for a long time
Or wetland or river
Or the terrain of the coast
In fact, in these places
Many different aquatic plants grow
And then the other side is
The amount of water
In fact, this importance
Basically everyone should be very clear
We can simply use
These two pictures as examples
Like the left picture
It means that the amount of water is relatively low
The right picture is a fully nourished lake
So we can clearly find
When the amount of water is low
This lake will greatly limit
The development of the entire creature and the entire ecosystem
On the contrary, it is a system
In an environment where nourishment and air exchange are strong
The development of aquatic life will be relatively smooth
And the ecosystem will be more diverse
In addition
The transmission between air and water
It will also affect the entire regional climate model prediction
Like IPCC
We call it the Intergovernmental Climate Change Committee
The study report in 2001
It specifically pointed out that
River, lake, etc.
The water and air exchange in the inland water area
This is on the water and air exchange
There is a large proportion of this emission
So it takes more research
To make further and more accurate estimates
And then do some more accurate
Modeling to do the whole
Especially the correction of the regional climate model
But the important thing is
In the case of inland water
In fact, aquatic plants play a very important role
And their distribution is very wide
But past research
In fact, there is no consideration of the existence of aquatic plants
Most of the time, it's just a simple stream
Then in a river with nothing at all
Run
In fact, more and more scientists have found
This kind of simplification is actually not very
Does not match the real nature
So there are those errors
So in the past few decades
In fact, many geophysicists
They will start
Find a way to discuss
Aquatic plants affect the environment
The impact of this stream
Then we can roughly put
The impact of aquatic plants is divided into two categories
That one category is when we
When there are plants in the water
It will block the whole stream
The whole operation
So it will reduce the flow rate of the river
Then change the flow of the entire river
The second point is that it has changed the flow
So the turbulence in the water will increase
Here is a simple example
It can be seen from this video
When a stream flows from left to right
Then if there is a pillar in the middle
When it's in the middle
Behind this pillar
There will be two turbulent currents in different directions
At the same time
Assuming that there are many in the water
A plant group like this
Then the whole stream will basically be
Various turbulence
And become very chaotic
In addition, past research has also proposed
That is, with the density of the plant group
And the proportion of plants immersed in the water
The strength and characteristics of the flow
And the flow will be completely different
The so-called immersion ratio refers to
The proportion of plants in the water
So it can be from
It's completely in the water
We call it Emergent Vegetation
It's the whole thing that emerges in the water
And then it's submerged in the water
That's Submerge
Under different immersion ratios
It will produce
The size of the vortex
And the whole
The flow will be completely different
The main generated turbulence
Can be divided into two according to their magnitude
One we call
Stem Scale Turbulence
That's mainly the turbulence in the video
It's like
Behind each plant
Generate horizontal rotation
This vortex
So then the scale of this vortex
It's with my plant
This pillar
Uh, the plant is called the meridian
But if it's a pillar
It's related to its diameter
Yes, so we call it
Stem Scale Turbulence
The other one is
When my whole plant group
Dive into the water
Just like this picture
When you dive into the water
The top of the plant group will be because
The speed of the upstream and downstream water flow is different
Because there is no plant on the top
So its water flows faster
The downstream
Because there are obstacles
So the water flow is slower
What about the upstream and downstream flow differences
Will produce a
Vertical ratio
It's a vertical
Rotating vortex
What about this vortex
Its magnitude is
It will be bigger
Compared to my plant root
What caused the stem scale to be bigger
That's what we call
Uh, Canopy Scale Vortex
And then these two magnitudes of the vortex
Will be in the water
Transmitted to the surface of the water
Or even the bottom of the bed
To affect the water surface
The rate of erosion
With the bottom of the bed
The whole mechanism of sandblasting and floating
Yes
What about the main purpose of my research
Is to do experiments
And then to understand
Is the aquatic plant
How to influence
These two questions
Is
It first changes the flow
And then how does this flow affect
That's
Uh, our Air Water
Gas Transfer
And that's
The suspension of my bottom bed
Yes
Okay, so what's next
I'm going to introduce a little bit
My experiment method and settings
Oh, yeah, that's it
I don't know if you have any questions
That is
If you have any questions
You are welcome to interrupt me at any time
That is
Because it may be different fields
And then sometimes it's too fast
Is to put some
Maybe general
General people don't understand
Things to say
Just bring it directly
So if you have any questions
You are welcome to interrupt me at any time
Yes
Uh, I have a question
Ok
Is
Maybe before you start
This kind of rigorous
Before the lab experiment
There will be some
I have a question
Is
Uh, you do research in this area
In addition to
Physics
And this kind of physical
Basic science
To understand
You will need to understand
Aquatic plant
Is it biological
Or plant-related
Background knowledge
Basically
If
You have this knowledge
That's probably the best
Because
Uh
For example, when we set up the experiment
We will think about it
Uh, my plant
That one
What am I going to use to represent the plant
That's like my experiment right now
I'm using
I'll talk about it later
I'm using a harder one
That kind of acrylic
That hard
Acrylic
It can represent
Is a special plant
It's the plant
The plant is harder
That plant
Harder
The state
We can have
There are several special species
And then if you understand this ecology
You will know
OK, these species
Where is it mainly distributed
Like a river mouth
Or a more upstream river
So we can use this knowledge
To design our experiment
Let it go as far as possible
Just in physics
With
With real
To match
It's either
It's you
It depends on whether you want to be flexible
The
Aquatic plant
Or
Say
The kind of plant
Yeah
So
Uh, for me
I dare not say
I
I know a lot about ecology
Because I am also
I started to get in touch with this field during my PhD
So I started to go
With
It's like talking to ecologists
That
So actually this is also quite
It takes a combination of cross-fields
That
Actually in
Uh, after the speech
I will
Share some
Very interesting topics
Is that we have some
Cooperate with biologists
And then do fish
With
Water research
I will add this later
Um
Understand
Thank you
This is a very
It's a very good question
Ok
Then
I will continue
So now I'm going to talk about my experiment
Settings and methods
So basically
The aquatic plant I use
Is a
Circular aquatic plant
What about the water flow
Is driven by two different
Uh, the plate rotates in different directions
To drive
And then we can use
Control the speed of the plate rotation
To control the flow of different water flows
That
This one
Is my aquatic
Uh
Is the photo of the experimental aquatic
So basically
This is not very big
It's the whole
Uh
The section of the test
It's about 200 centimeters long
And then the whole width
It's actually only 15 centimeters
Yes
So in this experiment
I just mentioned
I use a lot of acrylate
To simulate a plant with a higher hardness
That experiment
In fact, I also have
Do experiments with softer plants
But in this study
We mainly focus on
I mainly want to share with you today
Is
Simulate some of the results of harder plants
In addition to that, we are at the bottom of the bed
Also laid a 10-centimeter layer of sand
Is to simulate
Is the natural river
Natural river state
Because there will be sand at the bottom of the bed
Otherwise, how do I see the whirlpool of sand
Yes
So I just
I also laid a layer of sand
And then finally
I put it
Uh
Test
Is to test
Water flow rate and
Measurement instrument of nutrient concentration
Let me tell you a little bit about it
I use it to measure
Uh, the water flow rate tool
We call this system
Called PIV
The full name is Particle Image Velocimetry
So the whole system is basically
Made up of three important components
Is
First of all, we have to put it in the water
We call it Neutral Volume
Powder particles
The so-called Neutral Volume means
Uh, the density of its particles
Has to be about the same as water
Then it can float evenly in the water
And flow along the water
Then we need a high-intensity laser
To illuminate these powder particles
And then finally
A high-speed camera
To capture
Each time point
The location of each powder particle
That's like
This picture is
Uh, my whole raw image
Photos taken
So these points
The highlights are actually those powder particles
And then what happens next
Once we have each time point
After the location of each powder particle
We can compare
It's the first two
Uh, in the first two images
Different time points
The relative location of the powder particles
And then calculate
The direction and distance of these particles moving
And then we'll
Because we know
We can shoot us
Uh, it's the camera
The time frame
The frame rate
So we know the frame rate
We know how much time it takes
Between each frame
And then we have this
Displacement
We can go
Calculate the speed of its movement
And then with these fluids
It's these fluids
The movement speed of the powder particles
We can use it to represent
It's different locations
The flow rate of the water
That
As for how to measure the rate of surface oxidation
We are in the water
Put it in what we call
This chemical substance called hyaluronic acid
That hyaluronic acid
It will, uh, melt in the water
To react with the oxygen molecules in the water
And then it consumes the water's oxygen
And then when the oxygen in the water is exhausted
What about the time?
We can use the right picture
It's this picture
Uh, the oxygen concentration
To monitor the entire process of reoxidation in the water
And then
And through
It's the time it takes to reach the saturation concentration
To calculate the whole
The rate of surface oxidation
How much
That
In addition to oxidation and flow rate
What about
We're going to set up another set of experiments
To calculate the entire bed
It's, uh,
The concentration of nitrogen in the water
That
How to do it
We are through lighting
And then by the brightness of this image
To distinguish
It's the position of the nitrogen particles
And then calculate
It's the concentration of different nitrogen particles in the water
That's like this video
We can see
The nitrogen particles that are suspended
It's going to be on the white projection screen
It's a little bit of a reflection
And then we can set a threshold
And then we're going to determine that every pixel
It's
What's its intensity
And then this threshold
If it's higher than this threshold
Then these
These pixels we'll
Just treat it as
Uh, water
Because it's white
But if it's lower than this threshold
It means it's this little bit
Particles
And then we're going to set it up
It's the nitrogen particles
And then
And then you can calculate
The entire water
The concentration of nitrogen in this water column
Okay, so
Uh, according to the PIV
We measured
We got the two sides of the flow
And then there's the image analysis
To analyze the concentration of suspended nitrogen
That's why
With these two things
We can try to answer the first question
Is
How does the aquatic plant affect
The bottom layer of the river
Before we discuss this question
Let's first understand
How does the river wash the bottom layer
The nitrogen is washed up
What is the mechanism of this nitrogen suspension
In fact, this principle
Uh, it's a little bit like this
When the storm comes
How do people get blown up
Yeah, it's
Uh, it's actually the speed of the fluid
It's about the pressure
So we can put the picture
What about this object in this picture
Imagine it's a person
Or nitrogen particles
That's because the bottom layer has friction
So generally speaking
When you get close to the bottom layer
The flow of wind or water is relatively small
The further away from the bottom layer
The higher
In fact, it flows faster
When the fluid is through the human body
Or when the nitrogen particles
The upper flow rate is faster
The lower flow rate is slower
So, uh, it's actually like
How does the plane take off
This Bernoulli
Uh, this principle is a bit similar
That
The pressure above will be smaller
The pressure below is greater
So provide a
Because of this pressure
It provides an upward force
But
What we need to understand is
General air and water
Basically
It's a chaotic mess
That's what I just mentioned
It's like a typhoon
The wind basically
It won't keep blowing
That's what we look at
In terms of speed profile
In fact, this profile
It's an average speed profile
When the wind speed is low
People basically don't move
It's a momentary rush
To blow people
Just give
Blowing is
Uh, even leaving the surface
So there's actually more research
Point out that
What about the mechanism that actually starts the nitrogen floating
It's a momentary high-intensity water flow
That's what we call
The nest flow or the mess flow
What about the general river flow
The mess flow is mainly caused by the friction of the bottom bed
And we're going to go through this
The mess flow generated by the friction of the bottom bed
With its own
Nitrogen is the speed of the sink
To make a balance between the two
And then we can push out a
To predict a different flow rate
The profile of the river's nitrogen concentration
Then it's like this profile
Basically, it's based on this theory
It's been pushed out
And then with the previous experiments
The density of these nitrogens
It's basically a match
But I just mentioned a little bit
What about the past model
Only suitable for considering
There is no aquatic plant
There is no structure
Once there is a aquatic plant in the water
That's like I mentioned before
The whole flow will change
So what about my entire speed profile
It won't look like this
That's from recent research
It's when there's a plant in the water
Ah, this theory of nitrogen selection
The model is not suitable
That's because the old model only considers
Just like I just mentioned
Only consider the bottom bed
The effect of the friction of the bottom bed
What about the picture on the left
The horizontal axis represents the size of the bottom bed
And then the vertical axis represents the flow rate of the river
That's a very obvious trend
You can see that when the flow rate of the river is greater
The more nitrogen is transmitted downstream
But that's what we found
What about these color data points
It means that there is a plant
So this prediction mode
It can only be in line with
These points are without any plants
So this thing tells us
When we have aquatic plants
We must consider at the same time
The flow rate produced by aquatic plants
So if we look at the picture on the right
It's when we consider the bottom bed sensitivity at the same time
What about the flow rate produced by plants
These data in the case of plants
It matches the model of this theory that we modified
In addition to this
What about the overall flow rate effect
It's not just two plus
In fact, in addition to considering the bottom bed sensitivity
In addition to the flow rate produced by aquatic plants
The interaction between the two flows
It will produce an additional flow structure
That's what we call Coherent Structure
What about this structure
It's usually in the back of the plant
Or the place before and after
And then close to the bottom bed
So this animation on the left is
One of our experiments
Red means faster
Blue means slower
Then we can find that the inside of the plant group
It's the inside of these pillars
The water flow is actually very chaotic
And then when you get close to the bottom bed
There will be some high-speed water flow
It's the red part
And then with more sand grains
So we have to put this model
What we call Coherent Structure
This kind of interaction can also be considered
So we are based on the plant
The average speed of the internal water flow field
A new theoretical model
And then the whole river
Divided into two layers of structure
What about the average speed of the upper layer
Close to the fixed value
So we call it the average speed layer
And then in this layer
It's basically the sensitivity that can be ignored
So in this layer
The main mechanism of sand grains is from
We just mentioned that the gold of the plant
The back of this
This kind of water level flow
What about the water flow at the bottom
We call it the boundary layer of the bottom bed
So in this layer
It's the mechanism of sand grains
It's actually mainly from the bottom bed sensitivity
And the gold of the plant
And I just mentioned
The Coherent Structure of the interaction between the two
So all three of them have to be considered
At the bottom of this place
And then finally
What about the new theoretical model
With us in the water
What about the data obtained from the experiment
The three pictures represent
The density of sand grains under different currents
The circle is our experimental data
And the virtual line is our theoretical model
So the new theoretical model is roughly
It's in line with the experimental data
So we can look forward to
This new theoretical model
Can replace the old model
It helps people to be more accurate
To predict
It's in the case of aquatic plants
The density of sand grains
This will help us
The whole river, lake, wetland
Those sand transmission
And the geological environment
There is a more accurate prediction and understanding
Okay, so we're done with the bottom bed
And then we go back to the surface
We're going to see
The flow structure produced by the plant group
How does it affect the surface of the water
The process of gas transmission
What about the gas transmission of the water table
It's mainly controlled by three big mechanisms
And one of them is
I've been emphasizing
It's the structure in the water
That is, the vortex in the water
Wait a minute
My pointer seems to have run away
Okay, that's it
What about the other two main mechanisms
It's the wind on the surface
The mechanism of this blow
And then there's my wave motion
It's my wave
But in general
In larger water bodies
Like lakes and oceans
Water table wind and waves
It's the main influence
Surface gas transmission and erosion mechanism
But for smaller water bodies
Like rivers or smaller lakes and ponds
In fact, the flow structure in the water
It's the main influence mechanism
And that's what I'm going to do
The main part of the study
What about the old theory
In fact, it's mainly for simplified rivers
That is, again
That is, they ignored the water body influence again
And this model is
It's like this
What about the surface of the water
There's a very thin layer of fusion
And then the air in the water table
You can use this
This mix
In this fusion
By spreading
From the surface through the fusion
Transmitted to the water
And the flow produced by the bottom layer
That is, the whirlpool in the water
There's a certain chance
Transmitted to the water table
And then to increase the entire surface layer
The spread of fusion air
And then it increases the whole air
The speed of transmission in the interface
What about this model
It must be based on different flows
Make some assumptions to estimate
That is, the water
The time period of the whirlpool transmission to the surface
That is, behind us
This TS
What about this TS
It basically follows different flows
And there are different estimations
So in the case of plants
We have to do more for this old model
Especially this TS
To make further corrections
In order to discuss the distribution of different plant groups
The impact on the flow
We experimented with three different plants
That is, one is what we call fully emergent
It's basically my emergence ratio
That's one
And then there's the other half
Half of it is in there
And then there's the main part
Most of it is in there
These two situations
So there are three different kinds
And then we also set
The density of two different plant groups
The main reason is like I mentioned before
Is that the difference in density and density
Will directly lead to different flows
And then it affects the structure of the entire fluid
And the transmission rate of the surface gas
And then there's the experiment of each group
We also control the flow of different water
And then reach different Reynolds numbers
And then we're going to talk about the structural characteristics of the flow
It's a little stuck here
Okay, so this is our
PIV primitive image animation
And then from this animation
In fact, we can already see
That's the difference in the flow rate
Under different immersive ratios
Like the picture on the left
It's fully emergent
And then we can see
These pink particles
It's going to be a little messy
There's one behind the plant
We can actually see
It has a kind of vortex
A vortex of rotation
But in the other two
It's the immersion ratio
When it's less than one
We can see that
It's above the plant group
There will be a more vertical motion
And then we're going to
Do the flow rate analysis for it
And then it's even more obvious
It's in a fully emergent situation
Basically, the flow is very messy
And then the entire flow rate
The profile is basically the same
But when I was in the water
What about the bottom and the top
There will be a very obvious difference
So you can see that the top is basically red
It means that the flow rate is faster
What about the bottom
Our flow rate is slower
The profile of the average flow rate
It's even more obvious
You can see this feature
In addition to the data of the speed plant
We can further use this speed plant
To calculate and quantify the flow rate
The strength in each flow field
The blue area represents
The area with a stronger strength
And the red one means that the flow rate is weaker
So when the growth ratio is 1
It's in a fully emergent situation
The main flow comes from the stem scale
That's what I just mentioned
And then the distribution of these flow rates
It's basically relatively even
It also represents the flow rate of the entire flow field
It can be represented as
Use the average value of the flow field
To represent
Because it's basically distributed more evenly
But when the growth ratio is less than 1
The top of the plant group
Because of the difference in flow rate between the two layers
It produces a very strong canopy scale
It's more dominant in the whole system
So at this time, the entire flow rate of the flow field can be used
The maximum value of the flow rate
That is, it is usually at the top of the plant group
To represent
Make a more dominant value
Then go back to our Modify model
So according to the result of our experiment
We use different characteristics
The strength of the flow to change the original theoretical model
Then I don't think I'm going to do it one by one
Just explore the details of the theory
Then I quickly summarize this point
That is, when the ratio of the plant group is 1
In a fully emergent situation
We use the average strength of the flow rate of the entire flow field
To estimate the previous one
That is, the time of this stream transmission mentioned earlier
Then finally get this new Modify model
When the ratio of the plant group is less than 1
We use the maximum flow rate of the flow field
To estimate the time of this stream transmission
Then finally we compare the theoretical model
The prediction and experiment data of the theoretical model
The left picture represents the case where the ratio is 1
The right picture is less than 1
Then the horizontal axis represents the strength of the water flow
The strength of the flow structure
Then the vertical axis represents the gas transmission
That is, the rate of oxidation
So the general trend is
The stronger the flow rate in the water
The faster the oxidation rate of the water table
But there is an interesting phenomenon here
We can find that in two cases
When the Reynolds number is less than a certain value
The rate of prediction of the entire model will be slower
It's slower, sorry
Then when the Reynolds number is greater than a certain value
The rate of prediction is shakier
Do you remember the beginning
I mentioned it when I introduced the flow
The so-called Reynolds number
It is a parameter used by scientists to describe how chaotic the flow field is
What about the range of different parameters?
It can describe whether the flow field is in the flow
Overflow or flow state
So this result tells us
What about the mechanism of the transmission of the entire surface of the gas
Will be affected by the flow state of the flow field
The flow state of the flow field is changed
So let's summarize
The whole study tells us a few points
That is, the technical message
The first point is through our research results
We can know the existence of aquatic plants
First of all, it will reduce the flow rate of water
But at the same time, it will also increase the structure of the flow in the water
Just make the water more chaotic
Then it leads to sedimentation, subsoil sedimentation, whirlpool
There is also an increase in the transmission rate of surface gas
In addition, we are based on different plant groups
The ratio of sedimentation and water flow interaction
The flow of this structure that produces different levels
We can propose a new physical model
Then consider the impact of aquatic plants
Then more precisely
To predict the mechanism of subsoil sedimentation and surface gas transmission
Then these information
We hope that in the future
It helps to assess more accurately
Ecology and the plan of aquatic engineering
With this whole image
It's 9.50 now
Generally speaking, the speech is about an hour
Is it?
Yes
OK, I should have a little time at the end
So I'll take this time
To share some other interesting things
During the PhD
In addition to the previously mentioned
Smaller aquatic plants
We are also using larger aquatic plants
Like this kind of aquatic plants to do experiments
Then we set the density to be higher
Then the number of more aquatic plants
To explore the structure of the water flow and the problem of gas exchange at a larger scale
I hope that we can discuss
The physical model proposed by the previous small-density experiment
Is it the same
Suitable for larger environments
After all, because our ultimate goal
Is to apply this model
To the real-world environment of rivers and lakes
Because we also know that experiments
Always simplify
The phenomenon of the whole natural world
So if you can make your scale bigger
Then make it closer to the natural world
It means that your model will be more convincing
Yes, of course, we also hope
Is that there can be some limited measurement data
Then compare it with the data we experimented
Then expand the range of the whole model
To the scale of the real field
In addition, we also found
Is that the position of the plant group
In fact, it will also affect the whole
The transmission of geothermal sand and the evolution of the terrain
Like the image on the upper right
The pillar is randomly placed
Then the pillar at the bottom right is regular
Is what we call staggered
This kind of regular placement
Then we compare the two videos
It can be clearly found that
When the pillar is randomly placed
The bottom bed will flow like a wave
It's like a wave
But when the pillar is placed in a regular way
The bottom bed changes
But it doesn't evolve like the wave above
It's just a layer of sand
It's just a continuous downward transmission
Then the other is the video on the left
It shows that the sand particles
Is that it follows
The flow structure produced by the plant in the water
There are different modes of movement
Like some of them
We can see that it is going down along the whole bottom bed
Some of them are what we call saltation
It's a bouncing transmission
Then some of them are directly suspended
Then take it along the water
In fact, these are all very interesting
More basic physical problems
Some scientists are also discussing
Particles
How is it in the fluid
With the flow of different structures
To move
These basic problems
Then during my doctoral class
I was very lucky to participate
In addition to aquatic plants
We also discussed
I just mentioned a question
In addition to discussing plants
Also discuss the flow of water
The impact of another aquatic plant
That is fish
So the origin of the whole plan
Let me introduce you a little bit
The origin of the whole plan
Because of the West Coast of the United States
The current ecology
Is seriously affected by foreign species
That foreign species is Asian carp
Asian carp
Asian carp basically
Midwestern
There is no land
So they react very quickly
Then it will harm
Some local species
So some biologists in the United States
They want to try to use
Natural law
To naturally reduce the reaction of Asian carp
Instead of just going straight
Because now
Basically advocate the so-called
Natural process
On the way
Cooperate with biologists
In the U.S. Geological Survey
Is to put real fish eggs
To our aquatic plants
Then our aquatic plants
This time the aquatic plants are used
We call it Turbulence Tank
It is a
About one meter by one meter
Then we can see
There is an iron grid
Then there is a motor above
Can control the vibration of this grid
Then through this vibration
Different intensity of turbulence
Then we can see
When I know different turbulence
What is the survival rate of these fish eggs
Because we know
The stronger the turbulence
Basically speaking, the film of the fish egg
It is very likely to be destroyed
Basically their hatching rate will be lower
So we do this
Do this experiment
To explore
What is the survival rate
Based on different scales or different intensities
This kind of turbulence
Then provide some biologists
Some insight to do some ecological work
Then we also set different structures
Like a stone
To simulate the flow of different environmental water
Then we
The research here is for
Just hatched
Larvae
Then there is the fish egg that I just mentioned
Then look at
When there is a stone and then there is a stream
When it flows
These larvae
What kind of place do they like to stay
From here
We can clearly see
There are two large parts
One part is at the top
The other part is behind the stone
Mainly because behind the stone
Basically it flows slower
So those larvae
If you stay here
Will be safer
Then basically its survival rate will be higher
If it is higher
The place above
It basically flows straight down
But it is less
It's just above the stone
Because here is basically
We just mentioned
Like the turbulence of Caton-Piscot
In addition to the larvae
We also do adult fish
Do adult fish
Research on the reaction of different flow factors
In the video
We set up a
Just a bigger pillar
Then we can find that most of the time
This fish
He would prefer to stay behind this column
Can be broadcast again
Then we can see
This fish will follow
Is the tail of our pillar
This tail
And then basically
It's like this
It can save its swimming energy
Then
Basically what we are doing here
Are some more preliminary research
In the future
Of course, more experiments are needed
To do further research
Under various flow conditions
Beneficial to the environment of fish
And then
To better predict the ecology of fish
And development
During my Ph.D.
I am more fortunate to participate in these
Quite interesting
Different
Biological-related topics
I think
The time should be almost
So
Thank you
My advisor during my Ph.D.
Then there is my whole
Research group at UIUC
Then basically my funding is from
My boss NSF's plan
Then there is Taiwan and UIUC
Joint fellowship
That's the last
Q&A time
See if you have any questions
Then I am also happy to
Share more
Information to everyone
If you are
Environmental science or even ecology
If you are interested in water resources
You are welcome to contact me
Ok then
That's it
Oh, before everyone
Before asking questions
Please turn on the microphone
Then we applaud again
Thank you for bringing us
Today's wonderful speech
Thank you
Ok
Then welcome everyone to ask questions
You can directly turn on the microphone to ask questions
Or type in the chat
Or there is an icon next to it
Then
Let me ask a question first
I am for
Implement this model
You are a little curious
Just because
After all, every river is different
Or you design an experiment
The size of his tank
Should be
I hope it will be much bigger than you
Implement this
Analytical model
So it will
Like a river
You won't make this thing
Small to
H2O molecule
Then you mentioned in it
You will judge that there are plants here
No plants here
How far is the plant from the water
So I may not catch it
But my guess is
This length scale
It's probably the same as the plant
Is it about the same size?
Basically my scale
It should be a plant group
So it's not just a group
A group of plants
So basically it should be
Because my experiment is basically
Your plant
There must be no way to implement
It's as much as reality
It must be a
Limited situation
But it should be noted that
Because my tank is basically limited in size
So I can think of it as
A scale dump
Physical model
So I'm on both sides here
Basically belong to a
Average scale
So you can think of it
As a plant group
For example
This experiment
You can think of it as a
Very small river
And there are these plants in it
Like I just mentioned
How can I make sure
I'm here
This thing
Can really be applied
In fact, there is still a gap between this
Because
In practice
It must be a simplified model
There are actually a lot of
Empirical parameters
But these parameters
For us experimentalists
This parameter is all inside
It means we
Physical based model
Because basically
Although my river is bigger
But it still follows the same
Fluid mechanics mechanism
But my empirical coefficient may be different
But I can make sure
My model
If it is based on this physics
Then my river will also
Follow this mechanism
So this is what I just mentioned
We hope to be able to do
Larger model
How much is the difference between this
Empirical coefficient
With my small river
Then if we have
Some limited measurements
We can be more clear
The curve of this empirical model
Then these things
Can actually be used as
A numerical simulation
Because basically
We have to do more
There must be no way
So we have to rely on simulation
There must be someone
Challenging
How can you ensure
The result of my simulation
With real experiments
Or the real environment is the same
So at this time
You have to rely on experimental validity
Then give it some useful parameters
Let it do more
Prediction
Correct
I don't know if I answered your question
Basically part of the answer
Answered my second question
My first question is completely answered
My next question is actually
If you want to put your model today
Throw in a simulation
Then for example, I will
Simulate a river
Is there such a plan?
Which one is safer to do experiments?
You have a plan to take data
Then compare
Simulation
My previous group is currently
No
Because my previous group is basically
Mainly focused on aquaculture experiments
But we have
Other schools are talking about cooperation
Some other schools
Their group
Their strong point
Is doing limited survey
Then they may be near the school
There is one
There may be a similar type of river in the campus
Then they may
Use that river as a sample
Then go there to pick up points
Want to compare with our experiment
Then basically
Simulation now
Is already
It's amazing to calculate
Complex
Fluid problem, but it still has a limit
I just talked about it
Completely
Copy the real situation
Especially aquaculture
How do you put
Aquaculture
Implement to your model
So this is why
I just said that we can provide useful parameters
So basically
I just mentioned that aquaculture has two main
One is to reduce flow
So it will provide a drag
Then that drag
I can give it a drag coefficient
Then the other one is that my aquaculture will produce a flow
What about the flow
You can also give it another parameter
Then throw these two parameters
Into my numerical simulation
I can go through
Actually
Build a grid
Build these vegetation
I can do parameterization
To get close results
This is the current
I know numerical model
What they are doing
So they still need
This data we experimented
To give them useful parameters
Then let them do simulation
I understand
I think it's very interesting
Do you have any other questions
I have a question
Yes
Actually I'm curious
What you will do in
Aquaculture
Because you will
You will do numerical simulation in aquaculture
Related things
I should do simulation
Yes
Then your simulation
Actually I have a follow-up
Previous question
You talked about
You are in the system
You will have a
Similar
Basically you see yourself
Average scale
In fact, many simulation methods
Will use multi-scale
You may have different
Dynamics
But you
May look at the problem
I don't know
In aquaculture
Multi-scale simulation
How far
This question is very good
I answer first
What I want to do in aquaculture
Basically I should be in aquaculture
Do simulation
Because there is a good
Calculation computation resources
But I may
Sorry
I may not continue
I should not continue to do experiments
Because they seem to be there
As far as I know, there is no experimental equipment
Yes
As for doing simulation
I'm not sure if I can do aquaculture simulation
I'm still
Because I just uploaded
So I still don't know
Not yet
Future topic
But about you just mentioned
Multi-scale problem
Because basically I
I used to have similar experiences
In fact, doing
Simulation of aquaculture
A very important problem is that I just mentioned
Turbulence model
Because Turbulence is basically very small
So if I want to be precise
To
I want to be precise to simulate this
Turbulence flow
My grid must be thin enough
The result of the physics I came out
Physics
Meaning
But there is a problem
My grid must be very thin
But if I have to do like
Large-scale simulation
I can't have so much resources
Because I want to be very thin and I have to
Really big domain
Then my computation cost is very large
So
They will do some of the parameters I just mentioned
Process
When I have a small AD
How will my AD affect the flow
Then it may affect its drag
It may affect the flow of energy
Then I use this
Parameterization to give
To the large scale model
To do simulation
Then I can skip the small scale simulation
Directly use large scale
Then you just talked about multi-scale
Now there is indeed
Because some people found out
I'll go back to a picture
I mentioned it earlier
I remember there is a picture
Is in
Wait a minute
Find it
This
OK this
We can see
I just mentioned
Most of the rivers
The flow is at the bottom
Because the friction of the bottom bed
This is produced by the gravity
So the flow here is very strong
Now the scientists have found
I just use the parameterization process
To do the whole river
Simulation may have some errors
Because if they
Want to see more detailed things
In the bottom part of the bed, they use large scale
Basically your grid is too thick
The things you see
It must not be thin enough
They are doing multi-scale
They put the bottom bed
The grid is very thin
Then I can solve it
Really solve this
The flow of air
But what about the grid above me
I know their flow is not strong
So they can directly use
Parameterization to transmit
So just do it
To merge
There is indeed such a
Simulation
In fact, this can also be applied to the atmosphere
Because if you want to do the boundary layer
Is that I am far away
The atmosphere on the surface
Basically they are doing
Large AD Simulation
So they are not solving
They are also a parameterization process
Then it's not really solving
Very close to the surface
But if they want to see
For example, these urban buildings
The shape of these currents
They may put
The grid inside is very thin
Then rely on parameters
To transmit this information from the bottom bed
From the bottom to the top
I don't know if I have answered your question
But this question is very good
It is indeed the current scientists
Especially
People doing application math
What are you doing
Because they are good at doing some
Network grid
Network grid information
There is no problem
I don't know if anyone else has any questions
If there is no problem
I am the host of today's speech
Let's talk a little bit
Is in the chat part
You can see that I just put it up
Join members
Then there is also tracking our Facebook
Then how to get today's
Participate in this talk badge
Method of some links
Then at the same time
There is also a proof of participation
The keyword used today is also typed on it
That is valid within two hours
Ok, before we finish
Please turn on the microphone
Warm applause again
Thank you for bringing us today's wonderful speech
Thank you for your participation
Welcome everyone
If you have other questions
You can contact me by email
I am very happy to share with you
My research
Thank you
Ok, now I put that