Thank you very much to the host and thank you very much to the audience for coming today to enjoy the light, and then I am Bo Xuan, and then I am going to talk about the topic here, although there are several English words here, but I think maybe if you are not doing economics, maybe these words, each word guess out what it means, but together do not know what it means, so I will slowly explain that is anyway, the editor will slowly know what I am doing.
What am I doing? Let's start by explaining the topic. First of all, what we are doing is games, so this is the game. I want to use a few minutes to briefly introduce what the theory of the game is, which is a more scientific introduction.
First of all, what is a game? In fact, when you see the game, you may think of online games, table tennis, scissor-paper, or something like that.
In fact, these are all included in this range. For us, the game is actually a mathematical way to describe a strategic environment where we are interacting with people.
As I just said, it actually contains a lot of different situations, such as describing what we eat in our daily life, and we don't know what to eat, so we use scissor-paper to decide. This can also be described, or more complicated, such as a game of Go, which may not be able to play all day.
In fact, it can also be described in such a game theory. It is very comprehensive, but basically it can be divided into two categories in our game. First of all, the first category is Normal Form. I'm not sure what Chinese should be called. Maybe it's called formal expression, but I'll just call it Normal Form.
In the Normal Form, all the players involved in the game all make a move at the same time. It's like scissor-paper. So if you don't know what I'm talking about, you can imagine the environment of scissor-paper. Everyone makes a move at the same time.
The other situation is what I'm going to talk about today, which is Extensive Form. All players make a move at the same time. It's like Go. Everyone makes a move, and then I make a move, and then someone else makes a move. Basically, the game can be divided into these two categories.
Now I'm going to introduce the basic mathematical definition of these two categories. The following two videos are a bit dry. If you have any questions, you can ask me right away if you don't understand the mathematical symbols. First of all, let's look at Normal Form, which is the situation where everyone makes a move at the same time. In this situation, we can actually use three things in mathematics to define it.
First of all, we need to have a collection to say how many players there are now. For example, if two people are playing scissor-paper with me and Gao Xian, then this N is 1 and 2. 1 is me, 2 is Gao Xian.
Next, we need to describe how many moves each person can make. So at this time, for each player i, I will use si to express the number of moves he can make. For example, in scissor-paper, everyone has three moves.
Next, we collect all the people who can make a move into an array. For example, if there are N people, I will collect them into A1 to AN. Then we call it a strategy combination.
Next, the third thing is that I know what strategy combinations there are, and I know how many people are playing. Next, I have to decide who wins and who loses. In this case, we need to use a function to express it. At this time, we call it a payoff function.
So for each player i, this UI is actually a combination of moves from everyone to how many rewards you can get. For example, in scissor-paper, we are playing with Gao Xian. If I make scissors and he makes paper, I win. So in this strategy combination, what I get is 1 and what Gao Xian gets is 0.
It's like this. You can use these three elements to express a strategy environment where you make a move at the same time.
In math, we want to predict what kind of result people will play in this situation. The mathematical prediction we proposed is basically that the most likely result to be played should be the most stable result. At this time, we use a concept called balance to say what is the most likely result.
The concept of balance is actually that it is defined on a strategy combination. We will say that a certain strategy combination is a balance, which means that for each player, if I know what he does, I am not willing to change the move.
So in this case, it means that this is a balance. So if it is expressed mathematically, we say that a strategy combination A is a simple strategy balance, which means that for each player, he actually uses this A-I, which means that it is a move used by players other than I.
So in this case, it means that player I uses this A-I, which is actually better than any other move for his revenge. If this is true for each player, then we say that this is a simple strategy balance.
I want to stop for a few seconds, do you have any questions? If not, I will continue to talk about another part.
OK, then I will continue.
What we have just finished talking about is Normal Form. Next, we will talk about Extensive Form, which is the situation where everyone takes turns to make moves.
So at this time, you think that it is actually very similar to the previous Normal Form in terms of mathematical structure. It is the same as having a combination to describe how many players there are. In addition, we also need a combination to describe the moves that everyone can make.
But now everyone takes turns to make moves, so now there are three things left to describe. The first is who does what in what place.
So this means that we have to describe all possible situations, and then in this case, who does what and what he can do.
There are several different mathematical expressions, but here I use a more common mathematical expression to describe what I just said.
First of all, when talking about these notations, if you think there are a lot of mathematical symbols, you can imagine that this is a game of Go. Now N is 1 and 2, that is, there are black stones and white stones.
Then S is all possible places, so if it is a 19x19 chessboard, there are 361 possible points.
The next first one is that we are describing all possible situations, which is actually all the chess pieces that are still in progress.
That is, you may play half of the chess pieces or the chess pieces that have been played. We use a set called H, which actually represents history.
This combination describes all possible situations, that is, half of the chess pieces, etc. I collect them all in this combination.
So this combination is actually very large, and then each element in this combination actually means that the previous experience has been put in order.
For example, the first step of the black stone line is in Tianyuan, which is an element in the history, and now the white stone has put down another hand.
These things will be collected in this history.
There is a relatively small set Z in this history set, and we call it Terminal History.
So this is all the chess pieces that have been played, and I put them in this set.
Because by the time our revenge is based on this set.
The second thing we have to decide is who is doing what in what situation.
First of all, who is it?
That is to say, it is actually a function P, and then this function is from all possible chess pieces that have not been played.
In the chess piece, it is printed to the player's collection, which means that this move should be the turn of the black chess or the white chess.
So this is P, this function is helping us.
Then the third thing is what.
That is, in every situation, I know that this person is now the turn of the black chess.
What actions can be done?
Then I will use Row as a Correspondence to describe.
What he printed here is a piece of paper from the history set to a possible action set.
It means that this description says what I can do now.
Then how do we decide who wins and who loses?
It is the same as using our familiar UI to show.
Like this thing, it is a function from a final outcome Z to a ten-digit line.
For example, if it is in Go, I look at the chess pieces I play.
If someone's D is bigger, who wins?
This is how we describe the game.
Then in this case, we have the same theoretical prediction.
Then our theoretical prediction here is actually using a concept.
It is also balanced, but it is actually called perfectly balanced.
Then in this case, it is everyone's strategy.
It is actually in every situation where you can move.
This means that it is from each H, and then it is the turn of the player I to do the action.
Printed to say that you can do the action here.
So a strategy is equal to telling me that every time it's my turn to move, what action do I want to do?
When I know what everyone's strategy is, I say that a strategy set is perfectly balanced.
It means that it is balanced in every history.
In this case, this is a little bit more balanced than the previous mathematical concept.
I know very well that the first few minutes are actually very boring.
Because it is actually just defining math.
But it may become more interesting later.
Because I started talking about some more real-world games.
I just want to stop here for a few seconds.
I want to make sure that the audience has any questions.
If there is no problem, then I will continue.
What I just said is actually a 10-minute version of Crash Course.
The next thing I want to talk about is Behavioral Game Theory.
In other words, we think about whether this game predicts people's behavior well or not.
Basically, we are thinking about whether it is balanced to predict people's behavior well.
This is the most important question in Behavioral Game Theory.
At this time, we can consider a game first.
This is called a mystery game.
This game is actually a game proposed by Keynes in the 1930s.
At this time, you can imagine that there was a mystery game.
Imagine that there are six bonus points left in the final of the mystery game.
Then they will publish the photos of the six bonus points on the newspaper.
At this time, in order to increase the exposure of everyone, the newspaper held a lottery.
The lottery is to see the photos of the six bonus points.
Please choose who will be the most popular person in this lottery.
Who is the most popular person to vote for?
At this time, if you are participating in the lottery,
you are actually thinking about something in your head.
It's not about which bonus point is the most handsome or beautiful.
What you are thinking about is how others will think which one is the most handsome or beautiful.
So this means that you are not thinking about what he absolutely thinks,
but at the same time you are thinking about what others think.
At the same time, when you think so, others will also think that you will think so about me.
Should I also think about it based on this matter?
How should others think about me?
So this is what Keynes described as the stock market.
When everyone is buying and selling stocks,
they don't really care about how good this company is,
but what they care about is how others evaluate these companies.
If I can make money, if others evaluate this company well,
should I consider doing business at this time?
Something like this.
Next, I'm going to talk about a game version.
So the audience can play this game with me later.
Let's imagine that there are 11 people in this chat room.
So imagine that we play this game together.
N is equal to 11.
The process of this game is that everyone chooses an integer from 0 to 100 at the same time.
The winner of this game is the person who chooses the number closest to the average of two-thirds of all people.
The person with the closest number is the winner of this game.
Although I can't see everyone,
but if you are interested, you can take a pen and paper.
I'll give you a few seconds to think about it.
If we play this game together here,
what number would you like to choose?
Anyway, let's think about it a little bit.
Then I'll talk about what the theoretical prediction will be.
Okay, I think everyone should have thought about it.
Let me talk about it now.
Anyway, let's think about it first.
How do you think about this game?
How many numbers did you choose?
Let's take a look at what the theoretical prediction will predict.
In this case,
the theoretical prediction will make a very extreme prediction.
It predicts that the balance of this game is that all players should choose 0.
This will be a balance.
Think about it.
If I go to check, this thing is a balance.
It means I'm going to check.
Suppose I know that everyone else chooses 0,
what should I choose?
Suppose I don't choose 0 today.
If I change to a number x,
In this case, the average of all types will be x divided by 11,
and then multiplied by 2.
The person who is closest to this number will win.
Obviously, in this case,
0 will be closer to my target number than x.
So it means that if I choose any number,
it will only make me lose.
So it means that I have to choose 0.
If you go through some mathematical checks,
you will find that this balance is actually the only balance in this game.
So this is basically a very extreme theoretical prediction.
Let's take a look at how everyone actually plays.
This is the first person to do this experiment in 1995.
Then he found this.
I think it's quite a change.
It's a picture of the whole behavior game theory.
This is the first experimental data just described.
Then you can see that this is the actual distribution of data.
Then he found that in this case,
no one chose theoretical prediction.
This means that the theoretical prediction of 0
is not a very good model for explaining data.
You can also see that there are some particularly prominent points here.
For example, there are 33 and 22 here,
which are some particularly prominent numbers.
This experimental data has been constantly replicated since 1995.
It has been constantly replicated all over the world.
This is a very, very stable result.
You can see that basically no one will choose 0 anywhere.
Then you can see that a lot of people choose 50, 33, 22, or 10.
So he wanted to say that this balance
may not be a good description of the situation of such data.
So because of this data,
we inspired another model to take over to explain behavior.
This model is called Level K.
The Level K model actually assumes that everyone
can only think of a certain number,
just a few layers.
This model assumes that everyone can think of different levels.
The beginning of everything is the level 0 people.
Level 0 people mean that
he was stupid when he saw this game.
He didn't even know what number I should choose in this game.
So this model assumes that
these people pick a random number from 0 to 100.
Anyway, it's completely unstrategic.
He just picked one at random.
What about Level 1 people?
He would like to say OK.
He assumes that other people are all Level 0.
So today he wants to respond in the most appropriate way.
Other players are all Level 0 people.
At this time, he will calculate OK.
In this case,
if other people are all Level 0,
then my expected value is average.
The expected value of the number I chose for other people should be 50.
So I want to choose 2 out of 50,
which is the number 33.
Next,
Level 2 people will assume that
other people are all Level 1.
So other people will choose 33.
Then I have to choose 2 out of 33,
which is 22.
So it goes on and on.
Because of this,
the Level K model can basically explain
the information that appears here.
Here you can see that
a lot of people are at a lower density.
They may be Level 0 Uniform.
Then you can see that
there is a peak here,
which means that
a lot of people may be Level 1.
Then there is a large density near 22.
They may be people who want to be Level 2.
So...
Excuse me.
But why...
For example, I am a Level N person.
Why do I have to assume that
everyone is exactly the same
as Level 1?
Can't I assume that there is no distribution?
Oh, that's a very good question.
Because this is another thing that
we are going to deal with in this article.
We will talk about it soon.
But thank you.
This is just a simple introduction
to the whole process of file development.
This is the first version of the model.
But next,
with this model,
although it is mentioned by Yan Yong just now,
this model actually
makes some very strong assumptions.
For example, people who choose N times
assume that everyone chooses N-1.
But at least this model
can actually explain a lot of
strategic behavior in the case of Normal Form.
But if you go back again,
imagine that at the beginning,
in the case of Eccentric Form,
there is no model
that is similar to
Hierarchical Thinking.
Our goal in this paper
is to propose
a concept of the same solution
on Eccentric Form,
which is also a model
of layered thinking.
This is probably my introduction.
In addition to Yan Yong's question,
I will answer it right away.
Do other listeners have any questions?
If not,
I will continue.
Next, let's talk about
our model.
Let's imagine
why the
Level K model
is directly linked to
the Eccentric Form.
At this time,
the Level K model
defines the situation
where everyone makes a move at the same time.
In other words, the original Level K model
does not consider
the past behavior of others
and should update my own
thoughts on others.
It did not build it
into this model.
That is to say,
when you face a situation
where you make a move at the same time,
this model can be used.
But when you face a situation
where others make a move in turn,
the Level K model
predicts how smart
you should be.
The next logical question
is that we can look at
this simple example.
Let me use this tree
to briefly explain and then
respond to some definitions of
the Eccentric Form Game.
Basically, we have a
H that defines all the chess pieces.
H here actually describes the
whole tree.
Here, each top point
tells us where each decision
is made.
The P function tells me
who is in charge of
each top point.
Let's assume that
Gao Xian and I are playing this game.
Gao Xian is the second player,
and I am the first player.
Sorry, the host has been cued by me.
But it doesn't matter.
If Gao Xian is a person
who can think of four layers,
he will think that
Bo Xian can think of three layers.
If Bo Xian can think of
one or two layers,
he will choose A
at the beginning.
If Bo Xian can think of three layers,
he will choose B.
If Bo Xian can think of
four layers,
he will think that
Bo Xian must think of three layers.
So in this situation,
he will definitely choose B.
Then I will definitely
go to the right branch.
But if you find out
that Bo Xian chose A,
then this situation
is a
incompatible situation
in terms of
how many layers
you want to think of.
This means that
I think Bo Xian wants to think of three layers,
so I must be on the right side.
But today it happened on the left side.
This is a problem that
may occur if you
look at it carefully.
If you look at
this incompatibility,
you will find that there are actually two problems.
The first one is what Yan Yong just mentioned.
All players
assume that others are one level less than him.
This means that
Gao Xian thinks of four layers,
but he does not think of other possibilities.
Bo Xian may not be so smart.
He may not only think of three layers,
he may only think of two layers or one layer.
So this is a problem with the original model.
So he can't be directly
integrated into the game.
Another problem is
when you see the actions of others,
you should update
your evaluation of others.
For example, in this game,
if Gao Xian sees
the left side,
then he should immediately notice
that Bo Xian is definitely not thinking of three layers.
But this behavior
is not built
in the original static model.
So these two things
are the two points
that our model wants to break through.
At the same time, we have to deal with these two problems.
Next,
let's talk about our model.
First of all,
this is a place that Yan Yong mentioned.
How do we deal with the first point?
The first point is
the Cognitive Hierarchy Approach.
After these two words came out,
they finally put the whole
topic together.
This Cognitive Hierarchy Approach
is a
advanced version of the Level K model.
It was introduced after 9 years
of Level K.
The operation process of this model is as follows.
Every player
will have a level
at the beginning.
Then everyone
draws this level independently
from the probability distribution.
At this time,
Level K players no longer assume
that everyone is just Level K-1.
He assumes that everyone
may be Level 0, may be Level 1,
or may be from O to
Level K-1.
So these are all possible.
Next,
Level K players
may mistakenly think that everyone
is from Level 0 to Level K-1.
However,
their evaluation of others is not so wrong.
That is,
their evaluation is at least
correct.
For those who are less than
my level,
their relative proportion
is correct.
Next,
from a mathematical point of view,
we can use
Mu ij to express this thing.
Mu is
a probability density.
This is
the evaluation of
Player i and Player j.
The K on the top
means that
Level K player i's evaluation of Player j.
At this time,
L is the probability
of Player j being L.
If L is
greater than or equal to K,
it means that
others can think at least the same level as me
or be smarter than me.
In this model,
if you are a Level K player,
you will feel that
you are smarter than me.
At this time, I put 0 as the probability density.
But if L is strictly
less than K,
the probability density
is the same as
the real probability distribution.
The only difference is that
I have re-normalized it.
It is re-normalized by
Level 0 to Level K-1.
At this time,
these players are not so smart
in our model.
It is possible that
everyone is smart.
It assumes that
others think less than you,
but their ideas
are not so wrong.
It is because
the overall distribution of others is correct.
At this time,
players have truncated rational expectations.
You can observe
that when we
do a direct exercise,
when K is infinitely large,
you can see that
in this expression,
the ratio will be 1,
because the probability distribution
is 1.
This means that
you can have
fully rational expectations.
But if you
only think about K,
you only have a partial
evaluation of other people's ideas.
If you have
some questions
about K,
we can discuss later.
But this article
is like this.
It is an extension of Level K.
We can
deal with the first problem,
that is,
every player's
idea of ​​Level is a fixed point.
Next,
we will deal with how to update the message.
At this time,
we assume that
every history shot
will update its
after-effects probability,
and then use Bayes' law
to update the after-effects probability.
This means that
I can keep updating my
evaluation of others,
and then I use
other people's past behavior
to update my evaluation.
When you make this assumption,
you will immediately face
a problem,
that is, if the
after-effects probability is
0,
then the after-effects probability
will not be well-defined.
In fact,
there are many articles
dealing with
0 after-effects probability.
However,
there is no such problem
in this model.
The reason is
that no matter
what level you are,
you will have a certain chance
to think that the other person is
level 0.
When it comes to doing things,
people at level 0 will choose
at will.
In every
history, you will think
that this thing is possible,
because at least there is a level 0,
he will choose there.
That is to say,
my after-effects probability
is well-defined.
All players
simply respond
to my belief
correctly.
If you can understand
this part,
basically you have understood
our model.
To review a little more,
let's go back to the example
just now.
At this time,
let's take a look at what
our model is doing.
We use this vector
to show
his evaluation of me.
Because he thinks I may be level 0,
level 1, level 2, level 3.
Four elements are enough
to express this probability density.
So today,
when the model sees
that I chose A at the beginning,
let's compare
the three models
he gave us.
He assumes
that all players
can think of A as four elements,
but he thinks B must be three elements.
So anyway,
he only puts the probability density at level 3.
Because of this,
you can immediately see
the incompatibility problem.
Now let's take a look
at what he will give me
if we use the 2004 model.
At this time,
we can see
that the 2004 model
is also a static model.
Therefore,
his evaluation of others will not be updated.
He always thinks that others
work with truncated rational expectation.
So his evaluation afterwards
is always assuming
that others are level 0 to level 3.
So his denominator is 0 plus 3.
Then his denominator
is just 0, 1, 2, 3.
So this is just starting
from the real distribution.
Assuming that others
only have the possibility of 0 to 3.
Next,
let's talk about
the possibility of his evaluation
in our model.
First of all,
when the high-level player
sees that I chose A,
he will start to think
why I chose A.
He will think
that there are several possibilities.
The first one is
that Boxuan is actually a level 0
and he is fooling around.
So if he is level 0,
I have half a chance to choose left
and half a chance to choose right.
So if I am level 0,
I have half a chance to choose left.
The other possibility is that
Boxuan may be level 1 or level 2.
So all the possibilities
appear on the left are put in the denominator,
which is one-half of P0 plus P1 plus P2.
The above is
what Bayes' law tells us.
We can observe the after-effects probability.
We know that
under this sub-game,
the high-level player can immediately
rule out the possibility that Boxuan is level 3.
Because if he is level 3,
I will definitely be in another sub-game.
But now I'm here.
This means that
when I calculate the after-effects probability,
I will completely kill him.
This is basically the illustration
of Bayes' law.
You can pause for a moment.
If you have any questions,
I just saw a question in the chat room.
Let me take a look.
Oh,
here is
Thank you
Yi Ouyang.
He asked a question.
What assumption did we make
on the probability density?
We actually assumed
that each PK is greater than 0.
This assumption is
without loss of generality.
Thank you.
But here we assume that
there is full support.
OK.
Then
I will continue.
Thank you very much for the question.
Next,
this is a bit technical.
But let me introduce a little bit.
Under this model setting,
what general rules
do we have?
First of all,
under any extensible game,
let's say there are many people today.
Let's say it's me and Gao Xian today.
Then add a mysterious player X.
Let's say there are three people playing.
This theorem tells us that
if there are more than two people today,
the after-effects probability
in each place
is actually a
joint probability
of each player.
This theorem tells us that
no matter where you are,
the joint probability of your after-effects
will be
independent of each player.
This also means that
what others did,
like what X did,
will not affect my evaluation of Gao Xian.
What Gao Xian did
will not affect my evaluation of X.
Then the second theorem,
in fact, we can see
that when this game
becomes longer and longer,
I will have more evidence
to know which level
I am.
So next,
I think the other person
has fewer and fewer
possibilities.
This means that when the history
becomes longer,
my support will be smaller and smaller.
The third one is
that
we think that
there is a model solution
under this model.
Because you can see that
when K becomes infinitely large,
people have fully rational expectations.
In this situation,
people will naturally ask
whether our model
will choose to be balanced
when K becomes infinitely large.
The answer is not necessarily.
In other words,
if K does not choose to be balanced,
it has nothing to do with logic.
In other words,
we can find an example
that K will choose to be balanced,
and we can also find an example
that K will never choose to be balanced.
So this is a more general definition.
This is a more technical result.
But I just listed it here.
I won't say much.
The above is actually
more like a pure mathematical model
in my eyes.
There are many different ideas
about science.
But at least in my opinion,
if a model is a good model,
it can be
detected
or denied
by actual data.
In the current situation,
what we have found
is actually a mathematical solution,
and it is a bit
too general.
So we can't find
any more
falsifiable theoretical predictions.
So next,
in order to get some predictions
that we can test in practice,
let's consider
the following very specific decision situation.
OK, let's consider
the following game.
There are two people here.
Let's change someone today.
Let's play with Yan Yong.
OK, let's play the game.
Today's game is
take turns.
At the beginning,
you can imagine it as an investment game.
We are going to raise a...
For example,
you can say watermelon, pumpkin,
or electronic chicken.
But at the beginning, the size is one unit.
Then every day,
we take turns to feed it,
water it, or invest.
Every day,
everyone can do two actions.
Either I decide to take,
I want to take this chicken,
or I want to harvest this pumpkin.
If I decide to harvest,
the person who decides to harvest
can divide it into a larger part,
and the person who is harvested
can take a smaller part.
At the same time,
you have another option every day.
I can invest C dollars
into this.
For example, you water this pumpkin
and let it grow today.
Or you decide to take this electronic chicken.
Then this game is over.
According to the distribution we said,
divide this thing.
But if you decide to invest,
this is actually a
strategic risk.
It's a strategic risk action.
Because
if you choose to invest,
you have an advantage that
you can make this thing bigger.
But your disadvantage is
that the next day it's someone else's turn to decide.
You have to decide to take
or continue to invest.
So if you think
if someone else wants to invest,
you may think that I will invest today.
But if you think you want to take today,
if you think you want to take tomorrow,
you may think you want to take today.
Because if someone else takes it,
someone else will get a bigger part tomorrow,
and you will get a smaller part.
So there is a trade-off here.
But this is just a big concept of the game.
There will be a more detailed introduction later.
This game is actually called
the centripetal game.
Before I introduce the centripetal game,
I will respond to
Yi Ouyang's question.
Yes, this is
common knowledge.
Everyone knows the distribution of odds.
Thank you for your question.
I will continue to talk about the centripetal game.
Why is this thing called
centripetal game?
If you draw it as a tree map,
it looks like a centripetal game.
It's just because of this.
The view of this tree map is like this.
At the beginning,
Player 1 does things.
If he decides to take it at the beginning,
he takes 1 and others take 0.
But on the first day,
he can also decide to pass.
If he passes,
this thing becomes C,
which increases the unit of C.
So if it's Player 2's turn on the second day,
Player 1 can only take C.
Player 2 can take 1 plus C.
Player 2 can decide to pass or take.
If Player 2 decides to pass,
it's my turn on the third day.
So you can imagine that
if I take this on the third day,
my odds become 1 plus 2C.
Then others
can only take 2C.
So in this case,
let's assume that
we have a total of 2S days.
So everyone can do S actions.
This is just a
technical assumption.
Let's assume that
every increase of C
is between 1 to 1.
This assumption
is not a very strict assumption.
We just make this thing
become an interesting question.
You can imagine that
if C is too big,
everyone will keep passing.
So it's not interesting.
If C is too small,
everyone will
just take it.
It's too trivial.
So we consider
a more interesting range.
In these assumptions,
we can see
how everyone
will play this game.
Here is a balanced prediction.
Everyone
has to take
as long as he can do actions.
So we can go back and check
the definition of balance.
That is to say,
everyone has to do the best actions
in every history.
So let's go back one by one.
Let's look at the last day.
It's the second person's turn.
He can decide
whether to take or pass.
If I take,
I can take 1 plus 2S-1
times C.
But if I decide to pass,
I am 2SC.
In this case,
for the last day,
player 2 wants to
take.
It's more profitable to take.
So if we go back
to the last day,
if player 1 knows
that player 2 will take the next day,
after the same calculation,
player 1 will think it's better to take.
If it's player 2's turn
on the second day,
player 2 will also think it's better to take.
We can see that
the perfect balance
predicts an extreme result.
No matter how long the game is,
no matter how big C is,
between 1 to 1.3,
player 2 will always take.
So no matter how long the game is,
it won't continue.
Let's think about this.
Excuse me.
My question is
that you said
you wanted to do an experiment.
When you finished
the theory part,
I wanted to ask
if you wrote a Monte Carlo
to see how it would look like.
For example,
how many people play,
how many Cs,
what would the face space look like?
Your question is really good.
You are a worm in my stomach.
This is something that will appear
after a few videos.
Sorry.
Sorry, everyone.
My worm is talking again.
I'm familiar with him,
so he knows what I'm going to say.
So I just want to introduce
the game environment.
Next, let's see
why we choose Centipede Game.
First of all,
this...
Sorry, I just laughed.
The interesting thing about
the centipede game is
that it has been experimented for 30 years.
Then we thought
we should find an environment
where the existing theory is not good,
so that there is room for new theory development.
Let's take a look now.
For those who are
unfamiliar with this experiment,
I would like to explain a little bit
what the data of this experiment will look like.
Let's say we are now
not good at math. Let's say we only have 10 people.
If there are 10 people,
let's do the experiment.
The experimenter will randomly
pair two people and pair two people.
So there are five teams here.
So after each team starts playing this game,
my observation
is that a team of players will have an observation value,
which is the day
they decided
to take it.
So this is the observation value,
which is my terminal period.
Our balanced prediction
is a degenerate distribution,
that is, all the probability densities
will be placed on the first day.
But in fact,
in 1992,
this was the first experiment
my boss did,
he found that only 1% of people
would choose to be balanced.
This means that balancing in this situation
is not a good prediction.
In fact, it should be a pretty bad prediction.
The first reason is
that the actual behavior
is very, very far
from the existing balanced theory.
So people may think that
our theory has room to play.
At the same time,
we are dealing with this environment.
In fact, there is a purpose that is one more than two times.
Because in the past 30 years,
this is a no-fail game.
In fact, it has been repeated
many times.
But there are two possible
methods in the experiment.
One is to use the extensive form,
that is, I ask everyone once
whether you want to take it or pass it today.
The other is to ask other people
if you know that other people want to pass it,
do you want to take it or pass it?
So this is what I ask one after another.
But the same experiment,
you can also ask another question.
My other approach is
I directly ask
how many days do you want to take
and I ask another person
how many days do you want to take.
So these two things,
many people are arguing
whether these two questions
are still under debate.
So because of this,
we are going to talk about
theoretical prediction.
It is not only testable,
but we also want to solve
a big debate
in the method theory of
experimental economics.
This is why we choose martial arts.
Next, before I start talking about
my theoretical prediction,
I will briefly explain
what these two methods look like.
This example is a six-legged centipede.
There are two people,
so there are six stages here.
So in Extensive Form,
you can look at the above picture.
I just simply ask the first person
if you want to take it or pass it,
and then I ask the second person
if you want to take it or pass it.
At the same time,
I can also ask him
how many decisions
do you want to make
when you decide to take it.
Take the first time means
I want to take it on the first day.
Take the second time means
I want to pass it on the first day,
and I want to take it on the second day.
The second option is
I want to take it on the third day.
The third option means
I want to take it on the fifth day
or I want to pass it on forever.
So for both players,
they have four choices.
So these two methods
have balanced predictions.
Theoretically,
no matter what form you use
to play this game,
you have to take it on the first day.
So under these two methods,
theoretical prediction
is the same as
Degenerate Distribution.
All probability densities are placed on the first day.
But our model predicts
that the results of these two methods
will be different.
The following is
our article
on the most difficult to prove theorem.
The following is the theorem.
For any centripetal game,
you can see that
in our current centripetal game,
there are two parameters that can determine
the centripetal game.
The first is c,
which is how much weight
this centripetal can increase
every time.
The second is s,
which is how many feet this centripetal has.
The theorem is for any c and s.
It is a theorem for any
prior to the level.
it is a theorem for any
Now, let's say I do an experiment today.
I randomized
my method of doing the experiment.
I randomized that some people
I use NormalFoam to play.
Some people use ExtensiveFoam.
The result I get is
that under NormalFoam,
I can find a probability density function
or calculate the cumulative probability density function.
Then I can also find out the cumulative probability density function
under ExtensiveFoam.
Then the next theoretical prediction is
that the cumulative probability density function
under NormalFoam
will be First-Order Stochastically Dominate.
This is the cumulative probability density
under ExtensiveFoam.
This theorem can be introduced first.
What is FOSD?
I thought about it before the speech.
It seems to be showing me a good example.
If you don't like it,
you can leave a message again.
Everyone says that
In the exam.
The scans of this year are harder.
Or simpler than last year.
You can also make a comparison.
What is the difference?
The first order esperiential
is faster this year.
First Order Stochastically Dominate
I believe this theorem shows
I'm looking at the top, front,
middle, back, bottom.
If my top score is 70 last year,
I will be 80 this year.
If my front score is 65 last year,
I will be 70 this year.
So it's more than every score.
In fact, it is the corresponding score
for each PR value.
If this year's score is higher than last year's,
then this year's score is relatively simple.
In the sense of FOSD.
So if you change it to
cumulative probability density,
it will look like this.
If the red line is FOSD,
the blue line means that
the red line will always be pressed
under the blue line.
Or the red line will be
on the right side of the blue line.
The next question is
what our theoretical prediction
will look like in this situation.
Here is a simple example.
If you have four corners,
your possible terminal node
is the first, second,
third, fourth day,
or the last day,
so it's the fifth day.
So there are five possibilities.
The blue one is
the result of our dynamic CH prediction.
The red line is
the result of our
theoretical prediction.
The red line is
the result of our
theoretical prediction.
The red line is
the result of our
theoretical prediction.
No matter where you play,
no matter what your C and S look like,
you will always see this relationship.
The blue line is on the red line.
So today,
no matter what your
Distribution of Levels looks like,
what you move is just the absolute position
of the blue line and the red line.
But relatively speaking,
the blue line will always be
on the red line.
So this is our theoretical prediction.
Let's say that
each player is playing with
Extensive Form Game,
it will be more balanced.
In a sense,
they will decide to take earlier.
So here I want to
talk a little bit about
why this thing is
testable.
Because when I'm doing an experiment today,
I'm in the same group of collectors,
I'm going to randomize,
some people can play with Normal Form,
this blue line
and the red line
are directly what we theoretically
see in the data.
So when we see this next,
we have a lot of
statistical tools to say
whether the blue line is
significantly different from the red line.
And we can see that
the two of them are FOSD different.
So this is why
our experiment results are testable.
Then the second thing is
why this theoretical prediction
is very good for experimentalists.
It is also a stress test for us.
Because
this theory, although it has a lot of parameters
in it at the beginning,
but in the end our statement is parameter-free,
that is, it is not related to any function,
not related to any parameter.
So the only requirement is
that I do randomization
in the same group of collectors.
This means that as an experimenter,
you can pick a C and S at will.
So at this time you can say
that I want 10 legs for my martial arts,
I want 20 legs,
and I want to pick 0.5 for my C,
so I can pick 0.7 and 0.8 at a time.
In these cases,
the only change is
the shape of blue and red,
but the relative position is still
always here,
the blue line is always on the red line.
So it means that for the experimenter,
he has a lot of freedom.
And again, because it is
all right,
it means that I do this experiment
in Taiwan, or in Europe,
or in the United States,
he has to see this.
So it means that our theory provides
a very strong theoretical prediction.
Although it is very, very,
that is to say,
if you do it wrong in any way,
there is no way to present our results,
it may deny our theory.
But in other words,
if I do this experiment,
it means that our theory
is a very, very big support.
So this is
this is
we have different statements in paper,
but this is a more generalized
version of a statement.
Then,
because I think the time is almost up,
so I might just summarize it a little bit.
Then we will leave some time for Q&A.
If you have any questions,
we can meet again,
we can talk a little bit after five minutes.
In conclusion,
what did we do with this model?
The most important message is that
when you see the behavior of others in the past,
it actually tells you
where the progress of the game is now.
It also tells you
how many layers it can think of.
This message is actually hidden
in other people's past behavior.
Then if we say
we apply any static model directly,
whether it is level K or CH model,
it will actually find that
our ideas and the behavior we see
may be inconsistent.
So at this time,
we use the new model we provide
to solve this incompatibility problem.
For those
who do CS computing here,
we can think about
the question that may come to mind
is whether this thing is easy to solve.
In fact, my response is
that our model is
a very easy thing for the computer.
The reason is
that its code can actually
be rewritten with a for loop.
That is to say,
people at each level
actually use the same method to do things.
When I solve this model,
I first think about people at level 1.
Suppose everyone is level 0.
Then I will solve what is the best thing to do at level 1.
Then people at level 2
will look at what level 0 and level 1 are doing.
Then I will explain what these people are doing.
Then I update my belief.
Then I choose what is the best behavior
Next, people at level 3
assume that others are level 1, level 0, level 1, level 2.
Then do the same thing.
So it is actually a recursive definition method.
It is very easy to solve in math.
It is very easy to calculate on the computer.
But relative to the balanced model,
it is actually solving a fixed point problem.
Because everyone must
respond to each other at the same time.
So at this time,
it's like you're solving several equations.
you may not have chosen the right conditions at the beginning.
But in our model,
it is the only one.
And it exists.
And it is very easy to solve.
So these are some good properties.
The other part of the article
is a very strong
theory prediction
that can be denied in practice.
That is to say,
we assume that in a group of the same number,
you use the extension function to play
or the normal function to play
, we will find that
all the players
should take it earlier
in the sense of FOSD.
In the sense of FOSD.
This is true for any sense of beginning.
And it is true in any place.
So this is a very strong assumption.
So when this assumption
can be proven,
it means that
it is a great support for our theory.
At the end,
some future prospects
can be extended.
The first one is the experiment.
Now I am thinking with my teacher
and Wang Daoyi from NTU.
How do we set up an experiment
to verify our strong prediction?
The next theory is
at least the second point.
The theory is the second episode
I am writing now.
It's about the same model.
In the second article,
I can briefly talk about it,
but I can't talk much because I don't have much time.
The first thing to think about
is that
in this game,
you will have
incomplete information.
It's like playing Dezopuk.
All the information
is the two hand cards
on your hand
and the card on the table.
But you don't know
what the player's hand card is.
So in general,
we can only predict
what the player's hand card
will look like
when he or she decides to play.
But
in our theory today,
when someone else is going to play
or decide to fold,
can you update
if the other player is a good match?
If the other player
just randomly plays,
you may know that
you don't have to care about his hand card.
This should be a level 0.
This theory already has
a building in it, but it's not very tractable.
So now I'm writing
a new theory
to discuss this matter.
In two months,
I'm going to use this
second bullet point to test my candidates.
Then there are other applications.
Our theory
is a very general setting.
It can be applied to a lot of places.
For example, social learning.
This may be something like
you've never been to a restaurant
and you're not sure
if the restaurant is good or bad.
All you see is
a group of people queuing up.
At this time,
the general theory may be
that I only use the behavior of others
to update whether this restaurant is good or not.
But it's very likely
that if you see this restaurant
queueing up every time,
but you go to see the medicine,
many people say it's not ideal.
At this time,
you have to update your belief
that those people in line
may be level 0 people.
This means that their behavior
is not too much
in line.
It's not really
how delicious this thing is.
If our model is applied
to social learning,
a similar situation may occur.
Then you can also apply it to
political science, such as voting.
For example, if you vote for a candidate,
it's like playing a game with a voter.
The candidate keeps raising his ID,
and the voter decides
whether to vote for him or another person.
So it's very likely that
after he raises his ID,
you update that this candidate
may be a level 0 candidate.
Then there may be
the case of negotiation.
In any game where you have to take turns
to make a move,
our theory actually applies.
Thank you very much for your participation today.
You can e-mail me.
If you have any questions,
you can contact me.
This article is actually finished.
It's already pre-printed.
If you want to see the draft,
you can find it on my website.
I will also share this video with you.
I will also put it on the website,
so you can go and see it.
Next, because this speech
is recorded,
you can also find it on Project Tyra.
Thank you very much.
Okay.
Now it should be better.
I'll say it again.
Thank you very much
for Boxuan's speech,
especially for your detailed explanation
to help me understand
your theoretical model.
I think because we just
opened some Q&A answers
in the process,
because it's still being recorded,
we can open a few more questions.
I think the Q&A time
is divided into two parts.
The first part is to keep recording.
The second part, I will turn off the recording
and we will save time.
So now in the process of recording,
I don't know if there are any questions
that the audience wants to ask.
You can look at the microphone yourself.
Someone just asked
in the message area,
did you say In-N-Out hamburger?
I said yes.
My answer is yes.
I also want to ask a question.
I want to brush up on my sense of presence.
I actually think
because you mentioned a lot of
detailed explanations,
so it really helped me.
I actually have a question.
You just mentioned the number guessing game.
In fact, in the number guessing game,
I feel that its essence
is a bit like
there is no competition between players.
In the later martial arts game,
what I mean by no competition
is that I just have to
work hard to guess the correct number.
In fact, in the later martial arts game,
there is competition.
And I have to guess
that you don't want to
win in this round,
but you are still
greedy enough.
So I think there seems to be
some fundamental differences
between these two games.
So I'm not sure
if this is a question
of clarification.
But in fact,
thank you very much for your question.
There are some differences
between these two games.
First of all,
because it is a no-attack round 6 move,
and then it is a number guessing game,
it is a move at the same time.
Secondly,
in fact,
because when you are
a move at the same time,
how do you say
In the end, the winner is
the one who is closest to the winner.
So in a way,
the one who is closest to the winner wins.
But his problem is that
his payoff does not grow
because of what you do.
If you win, you win. If you lose, you lose.
But in the martial arts game,
if you two go together,
you two decide to
say that we go together for 10 days
and then start playing this game,
it is true that in a way,
he will cheat and say that
I decided to take the lead first.
So it is true that
his thinking may be different
in two games.
But thank you very much for your question.
Yes, because it feels like the previous
number guessing game
because its answer is fixed.
The martial arts game
is not fixed.
It follows another person at any time.
So I don't know if these two differences
will affect your model settings.
In fact, it is not very likely
because our model is set in a very general situation.
Speaking of this solution,
if you are interested,
you can type in the comment area
and swipe a row.
It doesn't matter if you are shy.
We can also talk about
what number you chose after the recording.
I am quite curious.
Yes, but you can see that
it is 25.
Good.
It's pretty good.
Then you can choose the number 20.
50.
OK.
Anyway, everyone can choose.
If you are shy, you can talk about it later.
I have a question.
First of all, Xu Youzhen chose 25.
It's not me.
The problem is that
you make an assumption.
This assumption is that
those who participate in this game
will make the most rational
and best choice.
The real limitation is that
he is not smart enough.
Or we say that his thinking depth is limited.
But like Gao Xian said,
how do you know that
when you really want to implement
this experiment to a group of people,
there will be no bad guys.
Or he deliberately
does not follow the rules.
Or he had an accident at home yesterday,
so his choice of behavior is very strange.
Something like that.
Will this thing be an interesting probe?
Can you take the experiment
you want to implement
to reverse it?
If I measured it today,
I can prove that
this group of people may have
had an accident at home.
Thank you very much for your question.
It sounds a bit noisy,
but it's actually a very serious question.
The first is that
our theory
does not say
that he may be a
setting defect
or a model feature.
Our only limitation is that
he can't choose
the degree of that place.
It's not because he made a mistake,
but because his brain can't think so much.
In other cases,
some people deliberately
continue to pass on in martial arts.
It is very likely that
he is a level 0 person in our model.
But of course,
there is another type of people
who like to pass on.
So his decision-making behavior
is to pass on wherever he meets.
Our model is actually
more like a method theory.
Of course, it can be extended
to say that I can add
other crazy types of people
into it.
Our model is also used
to simply rewrite
how many types there are.
Our model is more like
what mistakes they made.
In fact, I can talk about
the fact that
some people are thinking about this in
experimental economics.
For example,
we have a game
called the dictator game.
Let's say I play a game with you today.
I have 100 yuan to share.
I decide how much I want to share with you.
You have nothing to say.
I'll give you as much money as you want.
We can use this to
measure other people's preferences.
For example,
how much other people's preferences
are fair to society.
We can use
other environments
to measure
how much
other people's preferences
are fair to society.
Or
there is another game
called the final match.
This game is very similar.
The first person decides
how much money I want to give you.
The second person decides
whether to accept this offer or not.
If he doesn't want it,
everyone won't take it.
If he accepts it,
he will use this method.
We can also use
how much money he will give to others
and whether others will accept it
to see what he thinks of others.
In fact,
at least in the final match,
there are other games
that try to detect
other people's preferences
in addition to strategic thinking.
That's all for now.
Thank you for your questions.
Do you have any other questions?
Or we can
stop recording and chat later.
Does anyone
have any questions
before the recording ends?
Can I ask a question?
Sure.
Hello, I am
Huang Feiyang from Jianqiao University.
I am a neurosurgeon.
I have two questions.
The first one
is more like your extension.
Because it seems that
your model depends on
assuming that
this person knows
his level very clearly.
Is there a possibility that
he is not sure of his level
in terms of distribution?
It sounds like this.
Because I feel that
in fact, the detector
may not be sure where he is.
This is the first question.
The second question is more technical.
In fact,
your prediction is that
extensive games
will be found earlier
than normal game.
I want to ask
how do you prove FOSD in practice?
Because even if you are poor,
you can only guess
that he may be close to FOSD.
Because if you can't find the antithesis,
it doesn't mean he doesn't exist.
So how much in practice
will let you
be sure that
your inference is correct?
Both questions
are very good.
Thank you very much for your question.
Let's do it one by one.
First,
the technical point is that
I totally agree with you.
After all,
this is the first
method in Extensible.
So I think
this is totally feasible.
In fact,
what I know is that
some people's methods
in normal game
are more like this.
Although everyone
has a different level.
It may be different
in every game.
But everyone has a capacity.
No matter how smart I am,
I still play to a certain extent.
But based on different games
and different people
and different opponents,
I have different beliefs.
In this case,
the level I may show is different.
This is another kind of extension.
But as you just mentioned,
I'm not sure
what my level is today.
In the process of playing the game,
you will learn several things at the same time.
First, you will learn
how smart you are.
Second, how smart others are.
Third, if there is incomplete information,
what does the incomplete information
of others look like?
If so,
you may learn a lot
under your model setting.
But I think it's totally feasible.
Thank you for your first question.
Next, let's talk about the second question.
The second question is about the experiment.
I think what you said
is right.
We can only say that
given the FOSD relationship,
we can only say that
although FOSD is possible.
how to say
any arena
The makeup of our team
the makeup of our team
But the meme
A rough case
a rough case
We try our best to pick some extreme cases
If in these cases
It all shows
At least we see that in fact
Because the blue line and the red line are two CDFs
This is a result that can be directly observed in practice
So if we say
In all kinds of extreme situations
We all see the blue line and the red line
If there is such a relationship
Then maybe we can only say
We only meet a necessary condition
But this does not mean that it is a sufficient condition
I think what you said is something like this
It's true that we're just
If we pick a C or S
It's just to verify that the necessary conditions are met
The sufficient conditions may not be right
But what we can do
The best thing we can do in practice is
It's like trying to deny our model
If we say that we have no way to deny it
Maybe it can be said that our model is right
But how right is it
It does take more and more
How do you explain
Because after all, in many cases
When you verify the model
You are just verifying the prediction that it can be tested
So in this case
You are based on the model
Some of the results found
Let me see if it will meet this thing
It's like verifying its necessary conditions
If this thing is wrong, the model will be counterproductive
But I think the questions you ask are very good
I'm not sure if my answer is good
I'm very sorry
Thank you very much for your question
I don't know if I can answer you
Yes, thank you
Thank you very much
If the answer is not good, you can talk to me later
Thank you, thank you for your question
Thank you Boxuan
I'll turn off the recording right away
Before turning off the recording
Do you want to do the last clarification
For
Maybe there will be potential viewers in the future
Will watch your video
So do you want to do the final interpretation
Or concluding remark
I think it seems
Thank you for giving me this opportunity
But I think I seem to have talked about it
Because mainly
I think I have talked about it
Yes yes yes
But thank you
If there are future viewers who want to watch
Thank you very much
Thank you very much for watching
No no no
Thank you Boxuan, I'll turn off the recording now