Thank you for the introduction, and thank you to the audience.
I don't know how everyone is doing in the different time zones,
but I believe it's Sunday,
and it's almost noon.
Thank you.
I hope you can give me some feedback later.
Let me start by saying that what I'm going to share today
is probably not the level of a seminar,
because it's a research project under development.
The rest of it is still ongoing,
so what I'm going to share with you later will be a preliminary version.
In addition, because it's still under development,
my email will be announced later,
or this video will be released on YouTube, right?
It will be released on YouTube,
so you are welcome to contact me.
But what I'm sharing today hasn't been published yet.
The last one is about to be published,
so that's fine.
So please don't quote it first.
But welcome to give me some advice.
Okay, let's share my screen now.
I'm going to share my screen with you today.
What I'm going to share with you today
is what I've been doing all along,
which is a cross-cultural textbook.
Can you all see it?
This is a design and study of a Chinese textbook
with cross-cultural communication as its direction.
First of all, I want to share these two sentences with you.
One is what Hafiz said.
He said that if we don't have conflicts in this communication,
frankly, it's hard for us to wake up to some things,
and it's hard for us to figure out some things about our own culture.
In addition, this is Mr. Gu Baili.
He was also one of the instructors in my doctoral class.
He said that when we do language learning and teaching today,
we shouldn't say language and culture.
Many of our courses are now called language and culture.
He said that we shouldn't say that.
Why?
Because in fact, language and culture cannot be separated.
So he said that language should be in the culture.
So he thinks that culture is bigger.
Language is just a little bit of a cultural expression.
So he thinks that the expression of language and culture is not in a language system.
In fact, it extends to the actual common purpose of language.
Next, I want to share with you why I did this research.
It started about 20 years ago.
When I was very young, I translated this book.
It is also the first academic paper to study the students of the Chinese Language Center in Taiwan.
The cultural adaptation of these foreign students after they came to Taiwan.
At that time, this scholar was Sister Grace Boyce.
She was a professor of social studies.
She was also a nun.
She was very concerned about the adaptation of these foreign students at the time.
So she did a lot of research.
This research was done very well.
She also won a prize at that time.
So she published it.
I was very honored to be able to translate this book and this paper.
When I finished translating this paper,
it gave me a great personal shock and inspiration.
It turned out that cultural adaptation is such a difficult thing.
At the end of this report,
she gave a lot of suggestions on how to help foreign students adapt to their mother tongue.
Of course, it includes the suggestions of the residents themselves.
How to be mentally prepared.
How to change your attitude.
How to integrate this culture before and after.
But she also gave some suggestions to the language center and teachers.
This was a very fresh thing for me at the time.
She said that the language center also needs to pay attention to the special needs of foreign students.
We need to help them improve their self-level and culture.
And those who are mentally prepared may be in a target country.
Of course, it was in Taiwan at the time.
There may be some cultural resurgence.
She thinks that language teachers should also be fully prepared.
Because they are often the first foreign students to come into close contact with their mother tongue.
So she should become a very rich resource to help these foreign students.
So that they can successfully achieve a local cultural adaptation and public communication.
The biggest inspiration that this book gave me was that language teachers are not just teaching languages.
What she wants to help is cultural adaptation and help her students communicate properly.
So I think that language teachers probably also need some ability to cross the cultural ocean.
To be able to do a good job of native teaching.
This is my opening.
Next, we will continue to share my research motivation and background.
First of all, in our foreign language learning, we will learn from first language to second language.
Or the second second language.
Some people will say this is language 3.
What we often notice is the distance between our mother tongue and our target language.
For example, the Romanian language may be very close.
The Romanian language itself may be very close.
For example, if a French person wants to learn Chinese, the language distance is very far.
We often use this standard to measure language learning.
And measure the difficulty of language learning.
But in fact, we often ignore that the real purpose of language learning is to communicate.
In fact, every language contains the culture behind it.
Is the distance from L1 to L2 equal to the distance of the target language culture?
In fact, sometimes it is not.
So the difficulty of language is not equal to the distance of culture.
For example, maybe learning a similar German and English.
If we are a person with a mother tongue.
Maybe on the cultural distance.
We have not done a deep analysis of this.
Maybe we are on the cultural understanding of German countries.
In fact, it may be more difficult than, for example, the target language of American English.
In recent years, I have been paying a lot of attention to the part of cross-cultural learning.
Therefore, language learning should pay attention to deep learning.
That is, to be able to understand the culture of the target language.
In order to achieve the purpose of proper communication.
So this is also a motivation for me to write.
Next, among the Chinese textbooks mainly in Taiwan.
We see that most of them are still learning in the original.
Among them are some spiritual cultural points.
In fact, I feel that the Chinese textbooks in the United States are almost the same.
But they may have some textbooks.
For example, the IC textbook will particularly emphasize the so-called cultural highlight part.
In addition, we often say that the cultural class in the center of the original cultural class.
It is also often noticed that a professor of old culture.
Including, for example, the study of calligraphy that everyone often sees.
Or it is based on a variety of precepts.
There will be some related activities of wrapping zongzi.
In addition, there is also the so-called information culture of this textbook.
For example, the information of the goal and the country.
Including local people, history, geography.
For example, the Center for International Studies will hold a course on Taiwan today.
Discuss some of Taiwan's news or social phenomena.
For example, this kind of textbook is very familiar to everyone.
Today's Taiwan is probably one of these informational cultural textbooks.
In recent years, there have also been some textbooks with a cross-cultural understanding as the orientation.
For example, this is the teacher of our university.
This is the Taiwan comic book.
Taiwan comic book has a way of writing.
It is a kind of cultural contrast.
For example, the theme is sports.
What is the sport that Taiwanese people like?
What is the sport that Americans like?
What is your participation in sports?
It makes a cross-cultural comparison and explanation.
However, the textbooks written specifically for this kind of behavior culture in cross-cultural communication are still very lacking.
So we see that many of our Chinese students may come to Taiwan.
He still has no way.
Even if his language ability is very high, there is still no way to achieve a purpose of physical communication.
So this set of textbooks, I hope that the starting point of textbooks that can be developed is like this.
It can help learners to have early awareness and understanding.
It may face a cross-cultural difficulty caused by cultural differences.
And reduce the anxiety and confusion in real communication.
In the end, it reaches the goal of being able to communicate with native speakers.
In other words, it is a two-way good communication.
In other words, foreign students can communicate with native speakers at ease based on their own understanding of cultural differences.
At the same time, his own speech can also make native speakers feel at ease and not be offended.
Let's take a quick look at this part of the theory.
First is Helmer Lee.
Helmer Lee was probably the first to bring the theory of cultural courses to language learning.
That's what we just talked about.
In fact, Chinese language learning and Chinese culture learning should include these three elements.
The textbook I made today emphasizes this third element, behavior culture.
Next, we just have to talk about ICC, Intercultural Communication Competence.
Intercultural Communication Competence.
We will probably start with Byron.
Byron's ICC model.
Let's take a quick look at it.
This is an indicator that we wrote on the textbook.
Byron thinks that in terms of cross-cultural recognition, knowledge and behavior,
the five indicators of cross-cultural communication competence are attitude, knowledge, cultural interpretation,
cultural discovery, interaction, and cultural self-awareness.
The key point of Byron's cross-cultural communication competence is not only the ability of a cross-culturalist to express his goal-oriented culture,
but also to make his own culture and goal-oriented culture a link, a comparison,
and become an observer with independent thinking ability.
In fact, he emphasizes a kind of two-way understanding.
Next, we have Fatini's ICC model.
I think everyone is familiar with it.
This is an indicator of cross-cultural communication competence.
It includes several aspects, including human relations, communication, collaboration, and cooperation.
In addition, there are four other components, such as attitudes.
I will briefly talk about them.
These are the key points of cross-cultural communication competence.
Next, we will talk about the third-space theory, which has been valued more and more in recent years.
The third-space theory originates from the theory of Homi Bhabha, an Egyptian scholar.
It has been extended to our cross-cultural teaching.
The concept of the third space is different from the concept of intermediate language.
Intermediate language is a transition process between one language and two languages.
The third space in culture is to create a space of compromise between culture and goal.
It is a dynamic part, but it emphasizes a kind of two-way understanding and observation.
Professor Wu Yongyi also mentioned that learners learn two languages not only to acquire a tool for communication,
but also to improve their cognitive and thinking ability.
Recently, Dr. Zhang Xin also brought the third-space theory to the approach of cross-cultural teaching.
Finally, we will talk about the five C's of the American Foreign Language Teaching Association.
The five C's are the most important indicators of successful foreign language learning.
I especially like this picture.
There are different importance and different aspects in the five C's.
This picture puts the five C's of communication at the center.
Communication consists of three aspects.
Communication is realized by the input and output of four kinds of learning.
Finally, the four C's are closely integrated into the communication ability of language learning.
Let's take a quick look at the relevant parts of cross-cultural teaching.
The first is the interpersonal communication in communication.
It refers to being able to freely communicate with people under the basis of understanding the context.
Sometimes people don't understand the context,
but because they don't understand the context, they can't interact with people in a positive way.
The next is the understanding and interpretation.
Understanding and interpretation are usually placed in language teaching,
but I believe that many foreign language teachers are particularly impressed by this.
Many languages ​​are not equivalent to the meaning of the text.
For example, you are so beautiful today.
Then you say that your eyes and nose are beautiful.
In fact, they understand the meaning of the word,
but they don't understand the meaning of the word in the context.
The real meaning is humility.
Next, after understanding,
learners should be able to confidently demonstrate it,
say it, or write it.
The next is the 3P in culture, which we are very familiar with.
We can compare this with Hamelin,
and there are some similarities.
But in fact, in the 5Cs of Apple,
it does not refer to the behavioral culture mentioned by Hamelin.
But it may be shown in other 5Cs.
The next is the connection,
which is to expand one's connection to the world and the target language through the learning of a foreign language.
The next is the comparison.
Comparison is, of course, in our language learning,
including language comparison, including cultural comparison.
The last is Communities,
which is to be able to create a bilingual community activity,
or to be able to enter Communities when entering a target language country.
What I want to emphasize is that many of our foreign students,
for example, they are always in a language center,
or they are friends with foreign students.
In fact, it is to encourage them to enter the target language Communities.
Finally, I would like to quickly say that
in fact, this Hamelin,
his cultural learning indicators,
for me, gave me a lot of inspiration in my writing and teaching.
He said how to train yourself,
including a comment event,
a cultural fairy tale,
and how to investigate in a role-play way,
as well as the discussion of the values of the target language language culture,
cultural understanding and learning,
as well as the list of cultural elements.
Next, I will briefly introduce the theory of the background of cross-culturalization to you.
Then we will enter the concept of the description of my entire textbook.
First of all, based on all the cross-culturalization just mentioned,
the ability to communicate,
and the purpose of reaching a cross-culturalization,
we will find that the cross-culturalization comes from two things.
The first is that you have to feel comfortable.
Language learning has to feel comfortable.
The second is that people with goals and countries should feel comfortable and not be offended.
So, when I was doing a data collection,
I noticed this kind of data collection.
Let's take a look.
In fact, the whole framework of communication includes so many elements.
But in general,
the purpose of language learning is to achieve proper communication.
in fact, we will probably pay more attention to this part of the current textbook.
But the part of the blue frame, the part of the non-language part,
and some cultural parts,
the cultural parts of Behavioral,
are actually less written for it.
Next, let's take a look.
So, when I was doing the demand analysis,
it was different from the general textbook in terms of data collection.
The collection of my textbook
will collect a lot of real context and scenes of cross-culturalization.
So, I started to do a lot of interviews,
and I did an in-depth interview with foreign students who came to Taiwan,
and their contacts,
including their Chinese teachers and general teachers.
Why?
Because during my interview,
I visited foreign students first.
Foreign students think that Chinese teachers are their biggest source of language,
or the best resource for all kinds of cultural adaptation.
It is also a clear object in their mind.
We found that foreign students think that Chinese teachers and general teachers,
many of our foreign students do not come to Taiwan to learn Chinese,
they may be international students.
So, the teachers they come into contact with are not the Chinese teachers who understand different student cultures very well,
but the teachers of general science.
The teachers of general science may not come into contact with a large number of foreign students,
so they often have some communication barriers.
So, in fact, there is a big difference between teachers and students.
Then there are their roommates,
Taiwanese roommates,
and some foreign students,
they are technical families.
So, this is where my main scenario comes from.
Next, I would like to quickly share with you my interview with this cross-border group,
including these three.
I am one of the technical families.
This is a resource that you rarely come into contact with,
a source of barrier to cultural communication.
Let me share with you.
This is a technical family's interview question.
At the time of my interview, the epidemic broke out in Taiwan.
So it's probably all online.
At that time, it was usually a family of two or three groups.
Sometimes it was a family of one or two groups,
depending on the time.
In fact, when these families interviewed,
they contributed some very rich cases of getting along.
And you will find that they often have a lot of common problems,
some common problems.
So this is the question I asked them.
Before the interview,
I had already read a lot of articles about the barriers to Chinese culture
by foreign students.
So when I was leading,
I would actually put these,
when discussing,
when discussing something that is not rich enough,
I would also give them some hints
to see if they really,
really encountered this kind of communication difficulty.
That's also a kind of correction.
So let's take a look.
My question is probably from the technical family itself,
his feelings.
And then there's his observation.
And then there's the reaction of foreign students to him.
We interviewed a total of 10 families.
A lot of people have even more than 10 years of experience.
They have hosted dozens of foreign students.
And then they became long-term good friends.
It's very rare for them to share this kind of experience.
It's very different from what the Chinese teacher said.
They are actually more living.
In addition, I will also ask them the last question.
When we asked the Chinese teacher this question,
of course,
what do you think can be put in the textbook?
Chinese teachers are professional,
so their sharing is in place.
But I later found that the technical family's sharing is very interesting.
It's not quite the same as what our Chinese professor thinks.
They think,
how come I don't know this,
I don't know that.
Didn't your teacher teach you?
So I later put some of the things they shared
into the case I'm going to share today.
Okay, so that's probably one of my ways of interviewing.
Next, in my interview,
a preliminary analysis,
we found some very special things.
The first is that in fact,
foreign students have a great difference in the difficulty of cross-cultural communication,
including different countries and different geographical locations.
For example,
European and American students complain that Taiwan is very hot.
Southeast Asian students complain that Taiwan is very cold.
That also includes the issue of race.
For example,
the same issue is the issue of Chinese students in the United States,
and the issue of non-Chinese white people,
and the issue of people with skin color.
The cultural barriers they encounter are very, very different.
Of course, it also includes the issue of religion.
For example,
students with a Christian background
find it very difficult to find the real food,
and find it very difficult.
There is also the issue of gender.
For example,
male students who are white
are often worshipped as idols,
or black male students
are often asked some very impolite questions
in the south-central region,
and even asked to touch their hair.
Then there is the age difference.
Foreign students of different ages
also have a great difference in their feelings.
So after my interview,
I actually have two ideas.
The first is that
our textbook should show the issue of universality,
and also the issue of racial discrimination.
So my textbook today
is mainly for students with a North American background.
Next,
this is an analysis of the source of the entire article.
So behind it,
there is our highest indicator,
which is the ability to communicate.
Next,
I have already found some documents.
You probably know
the difficulties of cultural adaptation.
Next is our interview.
It is actually mainly to collect a context,
so that our textbooks are more consistent.
This is a real context.
Next,
this set of communication of miniaturized textbooks,
the design of miniaturized textbooks,
is a starting point for the students themselves.
I originally planned to shoot this set of textbooks in Taiwan.
Then,
I would present it in a video format.
Unfortunately,
before I came to the United States,
the epidemic in Taiwan broke out.
So this film was not able to be shot.
Later,
I changed this kind of textbook
to use a large number of pictures to present.
So I hope it is a video textbook.
Next,
it is mainly for miniaturized communication.
It is not just a set of textbooks.
So it is probably suitable for A2 or above.
If you are a second-year student in the United States,
you will have some simple Chinese grammar,
and then you will have a certain vocabulary ability.
Even if he has some vocabulary ability,
he will not be able to achieve it.
He will also be familiar with the description of the vocabulary we provide.
He can learn it by reading it.
Next,
it is suitable for soldiers who will stay in Taiwan.
He will stay in Taiwan for a long time.
He is not a tourist,
or even a short-term primary school student.
Primary school students are very limited in contact with the local area.
He may stay in Taiwan for more than half a year.
In addition,
I hope it is a set suitable for self-study.
I think language textbooks
need a professional language teacher.
A good textbook teaching method.
But I think culture,
based on a certain level of language,
can actually continue.
Next,
let's talk about this quickly.
This is the assessment we may do later.
Actually,
I haven't done this part yet.
Let's skip it.
I'm afraid we don't have enough time.
Let's take a look now.
The design of my entire course structure.
What we will see later is not a video.
It will be text and pictures.
Next,
we will provide some interactive questions.
The main thing is to promote the cultivation of his cultural ability,
including some cultural comparisons and cultural insights.
We will ask him in different ways.
We will also tell him
why it is like this.
What is the culture behind him?
This part is an analysis of a cultural point.
I wrote this part in English.
This part is about understanding,
not learning the language itself.
So we need to let the students know it,
and know why.
Most students will say,
teacher, are you full?
We all say that
it's good to be taught by a language teacher.
But why do I say, teacher, are you full?
Why do you have to say hello and eat?
If he knows,
he will feel more warm.
At the end,
there will be some discussion and suggestions.
If you really feel uncomfortable,
how do I express it to him?
Next,
let's take a look.
I collected these cultural points.
Actually, I received a lot of these points.
But I basically only made four lessons.
Two lessons are related to the class.
One is the interaction with the teacher.
The other is the cultural conflict in the classroom.
The second is the general life,
including visiting friends and staying in the dormitory.
But this dormitory is not a general dormitory.
For example,
Americans and Americans live in the same dormitory.
Frankly speaking, there is no problem.
It's amazing that the bathroom looks different,
the bed is harder,
these things.
In fact, there is no communication problem.
But if he lives outside,
especially with Taiwanese roommates,
this conflict is very big.
What we are going to share later is
the class of visiting friends.
I'm sorry,
my screen is very blurry.
In fact,
his speech should appear after the point.
The picture will be better.
In order to overcome this,
I can't make it into a video.
So I tried my best to find some pictures that look very blurry.
This is the person in the picture.
We are going to visit this person and his grandmother.
Let's take a look at the development of our course.
Jian Ting is Wenjie's good friend in Taiwan.
This weekend,
Jian Ting invites Wenjie to visit his grandmother.
Please note that
in our language course,
we will call grandma,
grandma.
We won't call grandma.
In fact,
our course is designed to target Taiwan as a country.
So I believe everyone can understand.
In Taiwan,
the opportunity to call grandma is much more than to call grandma.
So I deliberately put grandma.
Why?
Because this is also what I received.
A student in the south.
He learned Chinese very well.
But he found that there are many people who don't speak Mandarin in the south.
So when he learned Chinese,
he went to the southeast.
He couldn't order food in the night market.
He didn't understand Mandarin.
So it caused a cultural problem.
So I put him in front of grandma.
Then make a simple explanation.
Then let's take a look.
He said,
Hello, nice to meet you.
I am Li Wenjie.
What is your name?
We see that the language teacher is very good.
He wants to use honorifics.
But he asked grandma,
what is your name?
Grandma was very suspicious.
Why would anyone ask my name?
I am Lin Meizhu.
Then he said,
you can call me grandma like Jian Ting.
Then Wenjie said,
okay, grandma, hello.
Let's take a look.
This cultural point,
everyone should feel it.
He said,
please put on slippers.
oh, I forgot.
I have to take off my shoes.
My socks are broken.
I'm so sorry.
Then Jian Ting said,
it doesn't matter.
Grandma, this is a gift for you.
Open it and take a look.
I hope you like it.
As a result,
grandma said,
thank you, you're welcome.
Put the gift next to it.
Please drink hot tea.
Wenjie can't stand it, right?
It's so hot.
Can you give me a cup of iced tea?
Jian Ting said, okay.
Then next,
grandma asked Jian Ting,
you tell Jian Ting,
you help me ask Wenjie.
Does he have a girlfriend?
Grandma wants to introduce him.
What did Wenjie say?
Grandma, I understand Chinese.
You can talk to me directly.
Thank you,
but I like to find a girlfriend myself.
I don't know what you think of this class.
I think if there are a lot of Chinese teachers on site,
you should have seen
how many cultural points there are.
Let's take a look.
This is what's next.
After we provide the text and vocabulary,
we're going to take the second step.
We're going to have an interactive stimulus.
So let's look at this first.
Hello, nice to meet you.
I'm Li Wenjie.
What's your name?
This is actually...
It's hard for us to tell students.
We're interacting in Chinese class, right?
What's my name?
What's your name?
But in real life,
when we visit our grandparents in the countryside,
we don't seem to be able to ask them
what their names are.
Right?
So here,
we have the first question.
Do you think Wenjie is a good greeting?
This is the first point.
Let him have a cultural awareness.
So we let him choose.
He thinks it's good.
That's what all teachers do, right?
Next,
it might be a little weird.
He can't ask his grandparents' names directly.
Next,
of course,
we'll tell him that
it's not convenient for us to ask his name directly.
We usually stop here.
Don't ask your grandparents' names.
But students will find it strange.
Why can I ask,
but he can't?
So,
we need to look further.
We need to know what we want to know.
That's how we can reach a deeper understanding.
So we use the English term
for the greeting culture.
Actually,
in Chinese,
the greeting culture of the Chinese
is an ancient culture.
It's impolite to ask his name directly.
Especially the elders.
So you can ask your grandparents' names directly.
But the elders can't.
They can't.
So they might say,
or whatever.
That's how it usually goes.
We can only ask his name.
Next,
let's look at the second one.
He said,
you can call me grandma like Jianting.
This grandma is kind.
Wenjie said,
okay,
grandma,
hello.
We see that their elders call them grandma.
It's a very intimate thing.
But for an American student,
I'm afraid he'll feel very uncomfortable.
So we ask him,
if someone asks you to call someone you just met,
this granny,
in the American language,
granny is really just your grandma.
It could also be a good friend.
But you have to be familiar.
You can't meet an old lady on the road and call her granny.
So we ask him how he feels.
Take care of his feelings.
I think it's good.
Very intimate.
Or I think it's strange.
But we have to bring out this cultural point.
Why?
Taiwanese people don't call names.
In the United States,
from old to young,
you can call names.
No matter how important it is,
you can call their names.
But we often use family names.
Here's another explanation.
How do you call people?
And then here,
you can do a simple cultural practice.
A simple cultural practice.
In fact, this is because there is no video.
If it's a video,
you should say,
this person,
what do you call him?
What do you call him?
Something like that.
Okay.
Let's move on.
This is just a point of communication.
In fact,
in this painting,
in order to achieve a real woman,
I didn't make these cultural points a distinction.
What is behavioral culture?
What is information culture?
That is,
based on the scene.
Based on the scene of a visit.
So what he brought here
is an information culture.
In Taiwan,
it's almost like changing shoes.
Of course,
we also need to achieve a sense of humor
and a sense of
a sense of humor
and a sense of realism.
Right?
In the United States,
you really don't have to compromise.
I'm afraid this kind of embarrassment will happen.
So,
to increase their understanding.
Okay.
So,
let's start with his own problem.
His own culture.
Do you compromise when you go home?
Do you compromise when you visit a friend's house?
Next,
if you are asked to go out,
how do you feel?
And then,
can you not compromise?
Especially if
your socks just have a hole.
Can you?
How to communicate properly.
Next,
let's tell him why
compromise in Taiwan.
In fact,
it's not just Taiwan.
Most countries compromise.
And then,
let him judge.
This,
this feeling,
the point where you feel uncomfortable,
can it be reflected?
But in fact,
the result is probably
that you can't help but compromise.
Okay,
so this is an English explanation.
next.
Okay,
this is the culture of giving gifts.
our culture is the culture of giving gifts.
Okay,
Americans say,
oh,
I prepared it for you.
Please open it and take a look.
Okay,
but grandma is an old-fashioned person,
right?
He's embarrassed to open it in public.
Okay,
so he said,
thank you,
you're welcome.
I didn't open it.
Okay,
next,
let's see.
This is also a foreign student
who reflects
the culture of giving gifts in Taiwan.
Taiwanese also reflect
the culture of giving gifts to foreign students.
What's behind it?
This,
foreign students think
Taiwanese are generous.
There are a lot of gifts
for him,
very valuable.
Taiwanese think
foreign students
are very stingy.
I gave him such an expensive gift.
How can he give me
such a worthless gift?
Okay,
as you can see,
this is not a matter of generosity,
but a matter of cultural difference.
So,
let's take a quick look here.
Okay,
uh,
he may have a way.
Okay,
ask him,
why do you think
the goal of this country's grandma is
that she doesn't open it,
she just puts it next to it?
Okay,
and then,
it creates a cultural contrast.
Here we talk about
the Chinese culture
as a sign of sincerity
to give gifts.
But,
in the United States,
he may really be
a kind person.
Uh,
what did you do?
even,
uh,
give a bouquet,
which is a very good gift.
His main expression
is the part of that friendship.
So,
it will cause a political difference
between the two sides
in giving gifts.
It caused a misunderstanding,
uh,
caused a kind of,
a misunderstanding in this understanding.
Okay,
next,
we will talk about
some details
in the Chinese culture
of giving gifts.
Then,
this cultural point
will lead to
the culture of giving gifts.
Okay,
I want to
finish it as soon as possible.
Uh,
next,
like,
for example,
drinking iced tea,
this kind of thing,
do you really have to be patient
to completely ignore
your own culture?
In fact,
not necessarily.
For example,
drinking water,
you really don't want to drink hot water.
Uh,
you can actually say,
you don't want to drink cold water.
Okay,
okay,
next,
this is a,
I am,
uh,
I have collected all of these,
these,
uh,
it should be said that
I did not collect this
in the academic paper,
but when I did this,
I was later in,
uh,
a U.S. election,
when I handed this out,
there was a student
who was almost
saying that
really,
when I was in Taiwan,
I encountered
a point that
was very special.
This is really,
this is,
he,
especially the two
foreign students
who shared it,
they shared it very vividly,
they were very unhappy
and very angry that
he was obviously
good at English,
he was good at Chinese,
he just didn't talk to me,
he just wanted to talk to me
through that person.
Okay,
let's take a look at
these,
these will all
have some explanations
why
Chinese is indirectly
transmitted.
Is it rude?
Or is it
bullying you?
Maybe not,
maybe sometimes
it's about
respect for that person,
respect for the person who introduced him,
maybe sometimes
he's just
shy.
Okay,
then I think
we'll start
with the
textbook sharing
here.
Okay,
then later,
I put these
four courses
in the
University of
the United States
as a
working method
for
this
Chinese learner,
and then
to a
certain
level of Chinese,
and then
this
feedback is
very good,
very good.
Some of them
have been to Taiwan,
and even
those who have been to
Taiwan,
I personally
interviewed them
again,
they felt
that
in place,
so
I was
very confident
in
writing
this
textbook,
so
I can
probably
continue to
write
this
textbook.
Okay,
then I
will
move on
to the
next
discussion
topic,
which
is,
uh,
does
cross-cultural
teaching
require
nationalization
design?
Because
C1 to
C2
are
not
equal,
right?
Okay,
next,
cross-cultural
teaching
design.
Thank you,
Dai Ping.
It's really
very interesting.
I don't
know
if
anyone
at the
scene
has any
questions
for the
audience?
Yes,
or
do you have
any suggestions?
I believe
if there are
Chinese
teachers
or
learners
at the
scene,
they
can
share
their
thoughts
and
experiences
with
the
audience.
I
think
it's
very
important
to
share
your
thoughts
and
experiences
with
the
audience.
I
think
it's
very
important
to
share
your
thoughts
and
experiences
with
the
audience.
I
think
it's
very
important
to
share
your
thoughts
and
experiences
with
the
audience.
Thank
you.
My
next
question
is
about
Internet
connections.
Yes, but I think this paper mainly focuses on the feelings of the local people, the goal and the country.
We usually collect the feelings of our second language learners.
Yes, but in fact, this will produce a big blind spot.
That is, he does not know that his own language behavior is causing the other party's discomfort.
Oh, okay.
Yes, so what I received this time was, for example, the technical family and their roommates.
In addition to the foreign students, in fact, their feedback is very, very rich.
At this moment, I did not see the complaints part.
In fact, I have a lot of complaints.
For example, he blamed his American roommates for not turning off the lights and air conditioning.
But in fact, I know that this is because of the overall difference in life.
In the United States, everyone really does not turn off the lights and air conditioning.
He is not particularly wasteful.
Yes, so there are some differences in the environment behind him that cause such a difference.
But it will cause a barrier to cultural communication.
For example, American students will be labeled as wasteful or something.
Because in the United States, there is really no need to turn off the lights and air conditioning.
For example, they must turn on the air conditioning in winter.
Otherwise, it will freeze, right?
Yes, yes.
And in the end, just adjust the temperature.
It's not particularly a waste of electricity.
Yes, it's like this.
So it's because the environment in Taiwan itself is different, so it's incomprehensible.
Yes, but if you let American students know,
he can at least have a chance to explain that if he forgets, it's because of me.
In this case, it's not easy to create a barrier to communication.
Or it's a kind of stereotype.
Okay, thank you.
Thank you.
I think your research has discussed many aspects of cultural communication.
I was thinking about this.
Because there are many aspects of culture that are difficult to explain directly.
For example, we have L1 and L2 transfer.
You can say which is positive transfer and which is negative transfer.
You can compare and see which is which.
Because culture is also a different distance, a different understanding.
I don't know if there is...
Because I feel like I'm learning another culture.
And I feel like there are a lot of...
From the most basic, face-to-face, to visit someone.
You have a lot of interactions that don't seem to go well.
Yes, and then I think, wow, how can I finish learning like this?
And then I think, is there...
I don't know if this is practical or useful.
For example, C1, Cultural 1 transfer.
Is there a place where they can say, this is actually...
Increase awareness.
I think your question will increase a lot of intercultural awareness.
But I don't know if it will help them.
Oh, this is...
I don't know.
Which ones are similar and which ones are really different?
Yes, you see, language ability is very good at measuring, right?
And the test knows where you are.
OPI does it and you know where the language ability is.
But cultural ability is really hard to measure.
And language ability is not equal to cultural ability.
We see some people.
His Chinese is not very good, but he is very good at communicating.
But his communication is very solid, right?
That may be a kind of self-awareness.
Or his own attitude.
He himself has a respect for the goal language culture.
Like and his open heart.
So in fact, I think this part of cultural learning.
His variability is greater.
Really big.
And there are a lot of points to learn.
So that's why I think.
I also want to ask everyone to share.
Do you think cultural learning is suitable for self-learning?
Plus the combination of the media now.
He is very diverse.
Then it's okay.
Then the length is not the same.
We are online teaching materials.
We don't need to be limited by time.
So I am completely based on the situation.
Where should this situation go?
Where is it?
What are the points of this situation?
Let it happen naturally.
Then there is the description of the whole situation.
I am very grateful to my audience.
My situation is actually from their narrative.
Of course, you have to sort it out more smoothly.
More interesting.
Something like that.
So I am talking about myself.
I am talking about the direction of writing a new textbook.
Is this really helpful?
The purpose of communication.
I can understand you.
Do you think this textbook direction is reasonable?
I think you wrote that.
Because you want to use the way of the film.
Because I think this intercultural experience.
Communication failure.
Such an experience.
I think it is an experiential learning.
But because of this.
I think it is a good experience.
Experiential learning.
Because if you are not experienced.
It is difficult to understand.
This is very common.
Or specific cases.
Sometimes you feel.
This is really like this.
If it is really a different culture.
So I think if you use a film.
You can see some.
You can't say it with blood or photos.
Because you have written.
Facial expression.
You can't feel these.
For example, pauses.
Feedback to pauses.
That is very important.
That is invisible.
That is really.
Verbal.
That is the most difficult.
It must rely on the film.
I received a lot of.
Internet celebrities in Taiwan.
Their films are very interesting.
But they must be their own feelings.
Take it as a film.
It is more like a gradual progress.
Or some behind the scenes.
Excitement.
It means that everyone is watching very lively.
Of course, I also learned some things.
But you see it.
It is very suitable for self-study.
I think it is very suitable for self-study.
Because they have to have that.
If there is no environment.
No real contact with the locals.
No way to understand.
This is a communication.
This is a communication failure.
I think you have collected information.
For example, his technical family.
Some of his contacts.
Some information.
I think it is very important.
Because I think in terms of language learning.
In addition to learning to communicate with the locals.
Locals.
They also have a culture difference.
They also have a cultural competence.
They also have a culture competence.
They have to know.
How to interact with those
Thai language learners in the cultural field.
I do n't know what to do
How to accept
How to train
And get to know
What is appropriate
How to train
Thai
I think that's very difficult
I received that
I still can't think of a good
expression
It's hard to explain
Because silence has all kinds of situations
Thank you
This is very difficult
I think you see, my world is still a
Relatively easy
Some cultural backgrounds that are easier to understand
Right
Ok
Time is almost up
Is there anyone else
Who has anything to say
This is my email
So if you have any
Experience or comments
If you want to talk to me
Write to me
Thank you
If there are no questions
I want to thank you for this wonderful speech
I think your textbook is very interesting
I think it's very useful
For
For international students
Who come to Taiwan
So I'm looking forward to their use
You said this summer
They will start using this textbook
Or if you have students who want to come to Taiwan
You can recommend it to me
I can also share this textbook with him
And then by the way, ask him to give me some feedback
Please contact
Free learning opportunities
Ok
If anyone wants to provide funding
To help us make a video
Probably not
I think
If you hear any information
I will definitely share it with you
I think this is a very meaningful textbook
Thank you for spending so much time
It's very interesting
Actually, I thought I could shoot when I came to the United States
I want to say
You can always make it look like
But I gave up
Because it's really hard to be exactly the same
Then just don't
Just don't
Just have to shoot in place
Yes
So I'm looking forward to the next development
If there is
For example, when you finish writing
Because you are still
I don't plan to finish writing
Because it's just a few lessons
Yes, just a few lessons
Then slowly expand
That's it
Thank you
Your follow-up
Please keep in touch
Ok
Thank you
Thank you all
Goodbye