Hello everyone, I am Jason, and I am the host of Taira Talk. Welcome everyone to Taira Talk on April 19th.
The speaker we invited today is Dr. Zhan Yaojia.
He is currently a PhD candidate at UC Irvine.
His main work is in telecommunications and network information information theory.
He used to study and work at NTU Electronics and Telecommunications.
He is now a PhD student at UC Irvine, and will study abroad under the auspices of the Ministry of Education.
The topic of his talk today is
The impact of information technology on wireless network transmission.
Let's give the speaker a round of applause.
Let's give the floor to Yaojia.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
Okay, let's get started.
In fact, this is channel information.
Channel information refers to wireless transmission.
If I know in advance that the transmission is good or bad,
or if I can even quantify it,
I can make some configurations in advance in the transmission section.
This will further improve the efficiency of my transmission.
But if today's information is not so accurate,
what impact will it have on my transmission efficiency?
I hope I can get to this point.
I know some people today,
and they may all have a background in telecommunications.
But most of them are not our peers,
so I'll see how much I can say.
Okay, good.
Today I will mainly talk about these three parts.
The first part is that I will first review
how we do information transmission
when we are in the so-called traffic jam.
Of course, we have some basic restrictions.
For example, I hope that the higher the efficiency of my transmission,
the faster the speed,
but at the same time I can't let the transmission go wrong.
So what should I do?
In fact, in 1948,
Claude Shannon had already answered this question.
He had some good results,
which we will introduce.
The second part is that I will briefly introduce
some simple networks,
such as broadcast networks,
such as interference networks,
and interference channels.
They have some current solutions
for this kind of transmission problem,
and some problems have been solved,
and some problems have not been solved.
Then, in the absence of a solution,
how do I deal with it?
How do I get around with it?
The last part is actually more like my research.
If today I don't know
how these channels and links in the middle
are,
the detailed information
will not have any fundamental impact on my transmission.
That's the first part.
In fact, basically,
when we communicate,
the channels are always noisy,
they are always affected or interfered with by the transmission.
It's the same with wired communication,
and it's the same with wireless communication,
and the environment of wireless communication is more complicated.
Because of the so-called multipath effect,
the signal is distorted.
In addition to noise,
there is also distortion,
which means that at certain moments,
at certain times,
the intensity of my signal is actually very low.
Let's not discuss this complicated situation today.
Let's continue to discuss the above situation.
That is, in wired communication,
the signal is affected by noise.
When I receive this information,
it is inevitable that there will be errors,
and the information will be wrongly decrypted.
Common models,
common models for analysis,
include...
Wait a minute.
Common models for analysis,
there are the following two.
The first one is AWGN channel,
Additive Wide Gaussian Noise channel.
Basically, what it says is that
I input x1, x2 to xn.
The output I receive is y1, y2 to yn.
The output is what I send,
plus a random variable with a common distribution.
This random variable is a mutation.
But in fact, this problem is still very complicated.
We have made the problem so simple.
In fact, it is still very complicated.
So we will further consider
a simpler binary symmetric channel.
It only says that
the input today is x1 to xn.
At the receiving end,
we receive y1 to yn.
Then we limit x1.
Every x, every y,
is only 0 or 1.
What about the middle channel?
How does the middle channel
change these x and x?
For example, after sending in x1,
suppose it is 0,
then it has a certain probability
that p is converted to 1.
If it is converted to 1 today,
then this y1 is 1.
If it has not changed today,
then it is still 0.
Now the question is,
now the question is,
if I really use this,
suppose our channel is simplified like this,
only 0 or 1 can be fed in.
But there is a certain probability
that some input will be flipped,
will be changed.
How do I do the transmission?
How do I do the message transmission?
One way is
to send 0 or 1 directly.
Then I don't do any coding at all.
In this case,
the error rate is p.
Because it has given another x1,
its probability of being flipped is p.
So the error rate is p.
Is there a better way?
Of course there is.
We do some basic protection devices,
protection architecture.
For example, when I want to send 0,
I send it three times.
When I want to send 1,
When I receive it,
we use the so-called multi-digit method.
The basic high-speed data can be calculated,
the error rate will be relatively low.
It probably looks like this.
But at the same time,
in order to send a bit,
I used three channels.
So my data rate,
that is, the speed of my data transmission
will be reduced.
Of course,
if I increase my repeated times,
it will definitely reduce my error rate.
But what is the price?
The price is that my data rate will be reduced.
And when my channel frequency increases,
its data rate will drop to 0.
In fact, this is not the result I want.
Because in order to protect it,
I send it so many times.
As a result, my data rate became low.
Then my question is,
is it possible to maintain the data rate at the same time?
For example, the data rate is not 0.
Reduce the error rate?
Then, this is a disaster question.
This is a problem that everyone can immediately think of.
But the first contribution is that
I will further analyze this problem.
The first one is
to further disassemble the question itself.
In the first part,
we add some conditions.
The first part is that we do not limit
coding or decoding.
For x,
I did not do any calculations for x.
For y,
I did not do any calculations for y.
There is no problem with computing complexity.
No matter if it is NP-complete.
If I have a super-powerful computer,
it can be instantly calculated.
Then, we do not limit the usage of channels.
Then,
further think about data.
These data bits can actually be borrowed from a table.
This table is on the right.
It sends these bits,
sends these data.
In fact, what did I send?
Which message did I send?
From 1 to M.
So,
the nature of this problem is to say,
for example,
I want to send the 10th message.
How do I design
this method of transmission
so that it can be correctly resolved
at the receiving end?
Then,
next is the rate.
The definition of rate,
as I just said,
is that
in the case of so many channels,
the usage of n channels,
how many bits did you send?
OK, there are M bits here.
So, in fact,
you can use log12 as your M to represent it.
So, there are a total of log12 bits.
So, you can get a basic,
this is the basic,
this is the level that high-level math can get.
That is, M can actually be written as 2nR square.
n is the usage of the channel.
Then,
R is the transmission speed.
Okay,
so, in fact, we will get used to it in the future.
We are used to using this 2nR square
to represent the number of messages.
Then,
it also tells you that
I want to make the error rate as small as possible.
It can only be said that
at the receiving end,
I sent a message
at the transmission end.
At the receiving end,
I will design a decoder.
The fan of the decoder is to guess.
So,
guess which message was sent.
I want to,
so this error means
this is my message.
For example, if I send the 10th message,
you may guess the 10,000th message.
That is, an error has occurred.
Then, we want to make the probability of this event
as small as possible.
But,
I must be,
for example,
the event is set,
10 to the 10th square,
10 to the 100th square,
and so on,
this kind of probability.
Okay,
so,
now,
these restrictions
are converted
into a transmission structure like this.
So,
there is a message in the lower left corner.
So many.
Then,
I can,
for example,
I want to send so many bits.
In fact,
I am sending a certain message.
Then,
it actually says,
OK,
I should pass this message
through a certain method.
For example,
check the table.
We build a
code book,
code book.
Each message corresponds
to a set of code words.
Then,
I use the way of checking the table
to make the message
into a code word.
Then,
send it to this channel.
Some bits are crooked.
Then,
received crooked.
Some of the crooked bits
may be flipped.
Then,
we use the decoder.
When the decoder is set,
I know,
everyone knows what the code book looks like.
Then,
we can decode
the message
we really want.
OK,
so,
now the question becomes,
can we design
such a coding scheme?
What is the coding scheme?
It is the code mode.
Code structure.
What is the code structure?
It includes
the code book.
The encoder is the same as the book.
It is just a table.
And,
my decoder,
my code book requires
whether it can
be its
code rate,
its transmission speed,
whether it is
not zero,
or not a very small value.
And,
my decoding error,
it can be controlled
at a very small value.
OK,
so,
this is,
now,
we have formulated
the problem structure
like this.
We have
the encoder,
the decoder.
Then,
our goal is to
pass this message
to the other end.
Then,
here,
I want this mhat,
that is,
the received end
guess the m,
guess the message,
the less chance of error,
the better.
Or,
it is in a certain,
the chance of error
is in a certain value
below,
OK.
Then,
this answer,
I can,
so,
I just,
I have already exploded,
that is,
this is actually possible,
can be done.
Otherwise,
I can't go on,
right?
I can't go on.
Then,
it is,
then,
it is with,
this is Shannon's
contribution
in 1948,
which is
one of his most
famous contributions.
Then,
then,
he,
he made
a set of
coding schemes
including what codebook
plus the
processor.
And then,
but this m maybe
big
let my error rate,
that is my
effect,
that is,
the error can be
pulled to what I want
that,
that is,
the level of
minus 100
quadrature.
But,
if you are
uh,
if you shoot
too quickly
that legendary speed
today,
too fast,
too high,
that
problem came.
If you
today,
then
uh,
the problem
on the project
came,
because
there may
be
you for all
N,
for all
uh,
no matter
you look for
all possible
ways,
you can't
let my
error rate
be able to
drop to
the level
you want
.
For example,
if you
start to
drop to
10-100
quadrature,
10-6
10-7
quadrature,
you will find
that
you can't
find it,
no matter
how much
you use,
you can't
find this
coding
method.
OK,
so this is
that,
this is called
Noisy Channel
Coding Theorem,
and then
we put this
in our
code,
and then
there are
any questions
you can
ask,
because
in fact,
I should be,
yes,
it should be
like the
host said,
it's really
quite mathematical
here,
and then
uh,
I used to
do is
more engineering
problems,
and then
turn to
more theoretical
problems,
in fact,
it was a
long time
ago,
so it's
completely different,
it takes some
time to
switch,
OK,
so here
is a magical
number,
which is
called
Channel Capacity,
and then
it is
like this,
this thing,
what is
this thing?
This thing
actually,
uh,
there is also
a mathematical
definition,
it is,
uh,
seems to be
very complicated,
which is
the so-called
Entropy,
if you are
reading physics,
you will know
what is called
Entropy,
if you are reading
chemistry,
you know
what is
Entropy,
it basically
measures
how messy
a system
is,
but the
Entropy here
is not the
same as
that side,
the Entropy
definition here
is that
oh,
if today,
in fact,
the probability
is so much,
p of x,
uh,
px of e,
then multiply by log,
there is also
uh,
p of x,
1,
so much,
and then
zero,
zero in,
the calculated value
is the Entropy
of x,
the Entropy
of random variables
of x.
Okay,
so what it means
is actually
the uncertainty
of x,
and then
the uncertainty
of random variables
of x.
Before you do the experiment,
you don't know
how much it is,
but after you do the experiment,
OK,
how many bits
do you need
to represent
the result of the experiment?
OK,
that is to say,
uh,
how many,
it means that
you have,
uh,
yeah,
that's about it,
and then
it's actually
listed on the
internet,
it's
19 equations
for
the
Entropy
of information.
OK,
so we have this thing,
we have this,
after its interpretation,
the Entropy
is,
uh,
the uncertainty
of x,
in terms of bits,
or we need to know
the number of x,
we need to know
the number of bits.
So,
let's see
what this thing is,
I of x,
divided by y,
it,
uh,
its name is
Mutual Information.
It,
from the second
interpretation,
we can see that
it's actually
the uncertainty of x
divided by,
after giving y,
how much uncertainty
does x have left?
OK,
so what does it mean?
It's actually,
if you know,
uh,
in the case of y,
you know in the case of y,
how many bits
do you actually have,
uh,
you,
you can know
how many bits x is.
So,
to a certain extent,
this is actually
what we want,
in terms of intuitive meaning,
it's actually,
uh,
how many bits x is.
So,
what Mutual Information
actually gives me is,
uh,
x is,
in the case of giving y,
I know
how many things x has.
I know x's,
what x's value is,
in terms of bits,
like this.
OK,
so,
uh,
so intuitively speaking,
this seems to be
what we want,
but
in fact,
this proof is
very,
very difficult.
And then,
because of this proof,
there's a new field called
telecommunications,
telecommunications engineering,
there's a new field called
news theory.
So,
so this proof,
in fact,
in our field,
the proof is divided into two parts.
The first part is the so-called
converse part.
It proves that,
OK,
my code,
my transmission speed is greater than c,
it's impossible.
The second part is the
achievability part,
which is
achievability is
achievable,
that kind of part.
So,
it only says,
uh,
I,
I actually have to find a
way to make
this code
pass,
pass with such a high speed,
OK.
Of course,
in the process of passing,
we have to,
uh,
we,
but we have to specify my
error rate first,
for example,
10 to the minus 100 times,
and then,
we have to find
such a coding scheme,
and then,
of course,
nk is any nk,
it may take
a while,
OK.
OK,
then,
sorry,
can I ask a question?
Yes, please.
This is,
uh,
because I don't understand
it at all,
so,
uh,
this is,
I want,
can you give an example?
For example,
suppose I know,
suppose I have a
method of passing,
then,
I,
after I get y,
I'm totally sure
how much x is,
then,
what would i be?
Would i be 0?
OK,
if you know,
for example,
like this,
uh,
if you say you know,
after you get x,
you totally know
how much x is,
right?
So,
my question is,
you have an ideal channel,
yes,
no noise at all,
then,
after you get y,
you totally know
how much x is,
yes,
then,
in the following,
probability should be 0,
right?
No,
no,
so,
the x itself,
it's,
OK,
it means,
if you use this way,
I can,
I can answer you like this,
like,
if you know y,
then,
you know x,
suppose it's a channel
with no noise,
x is actually,
you know y,
you know x,
so,
you know the uncertainty of x,
after you know y,
the uncertainty of x is 0,
so,
this one is 0,
this mutual information,
mutual information
is equal to
x's,
like,
you can think about
how many bits x has,
for example,
if you use this formula
to measure,
for example,
the way you code is
using,
for example,
50% chance is 1,
50% chance is 0,
then,
in this way,
if you can,
you put this,
this,
for example,
you take this data
to calculate
h of x,
the answer will be 1,
OK,
what does it mean?
What does it mean?
So,
p is 1 in 2,
right?
p is 1,
OK,
2 is 1,
then,
log is 1 in 2,
1 in 1 in 2 is 1,
this value is 1,
so,
there are two 1 in 2,
right?
OK,
so,
adding up is 1,
OK,
so,
this value,
i,
this mutual information,
mutual information is 1,
what does it mean?
It means that
my transmission speed
can be 1,
1 bit per channel use,
OK,
so,
channel capacity will be 1,
right,
OK,
and you can easily
prove this thing,
why?
Because the channel is noise,
so,
no matter what you send,
it will receive,
it should be said that
what I received
is exactly the same as what I send,
right?
Then it means that
there is no channel,
I will directly go to
take my,
I know this,
OK,
this base case,
I understand now,
OK,
right,
then,
I should give a,
I actually wrote an example
in my lecture,
but I forgot to say,
I want to clarify,
that is,
the example just now
is not to say,
how to say,
in the case of noiseless,
mutual information
is always 1,
the example just now
is 1,
OK,
this is related to
your encoding method,
right?
Right,
OK,
so,
in my X,
for example,
if today
my X
is 10%,
for example,
like,
another example,
suppose my X,
encoding method
100% is 1,
0% is
0,
that means
everything I send
is all 1,
right?
Right,
right,
that's right,
this is another extreme example,
then,
in this case,
you can figure out that
entropy is actually 0,
right,
because 1 times
so you didn't
send any information
out,
right,
that's right,
then this
is 0,
so,
so that means,
OK,
you want to
say,
OK,
so,
the next thing
we have to ask is,
how do I
get to this thing?
Because I'm
always at this thing,
actually,
because,
how do I get to this thing?
He said,
I can use
such a fast speed
to code,
to pass information.
So,
how do I actually do this thing?
I'm trying to use
some examples
to talk about this.
Because his,
let's see,
let's see if
I can finish
in a short time,
to make it clear,
like this.
OK,
so,
what is the current goal?
I'm going to find a codebook.
And then,
his,
the speed of coding
is,
or his speed of transmission
is very close to
his dc.
And then,
there is a decoder.
He is a decoder.
OK,
so he's looking for these two things.
Let's assume
my input is,
this is 0,
input,
x,
x1 is
0.5 when it is equal to 1,
0.5 when it is equal to 0.
And then,
the channel,
this channel,
the probability of flipping is 0.1.
That is,
if I enter 0 here,
10% of the probability
will be turned into 1,
90% of the probability,
90% of the probability
will still remain the same,
like this.
OK,
so,
in fact,
how do they think about this problem?
He actually wants to say,
OK,
then I just randomly generate
that,
I have a random number generator,
I just randomly generate
0 and 1,
a total of n.
Then,
I use this,
these points mean that
there is a set of results.
Then,
I use this big circle
to represent
all possible situations.
So,
these points
are actually
just a few,
just a few examples.
OK,
according to the rule of large numbers,
I use
the probability
XR,
its probability of
1 is 0.5,
the probability of 0
is also 0.5.
So,
what does it mean?
I can find some,
OK,
for example,
this red dot,
I can find some codes,
it is about 50%
of the composition,
about half is 1,
half is,
the other half is 0,
like the red code
is like this.
The green code is also like this,
that is,
the front half is 1,
the back half is 0,
like this green one
is the same,
the front half is 0,
the back half is 1,
OK,
the rule of large numbers
tells us that
I randomly generate
a set of code words,
it will fall into
this blue set,
we call this
typical set,
it will fall into this set,
the probability of it is 1.
Why?
For example,
like this,
for example,
all of them are
1.
OK,
if today,
although,
all of them are 1.
OK,
then,
this situation
is very unlikely to happen,
right?
Right?
According to the rule of large numbers,
it,
you have to generate all of it,
you have to throw the copper plate,
throw it 10,000 times in a row,
it's all positive,
basically 0.
If all of them
are all 0,
there is a chance of the opposite,
it's all close to 0.
So,
only in,
so,
this thing
will not fall into
this blue area,
this blue area
is the collection of all
that,
54% is 1,
54% is 0,
all the sequences,
all of that,
the code word,
like this.
OK,
if I choose a red code word today,
and then take it,
let it pass,
what will happen to me?
What is this channel
actually doing?
Is to take these
101010,
and then,
I go,
when passing through the channel,
these 10 will be
the most random flip,
some may not change,
some may flip.
That,
there is about 10%,
about 10% of the,
10% of the bit
may be flipped,
90% of the chance will not,
90% of the bit
will not be flipped,
because this is
a channel feature.
OK,
what does it mean
in math?
In fact,
I am the original thing,
plus a sequence,
that is,
I just add
component y,
and then,
what is this zn?
This zn is actually
10% is 1,
90% is 0.
OK,
and then,
that,
that is also very likely,
that is also,
according to the rule of thumb,
this is also very likely,
this is very likely
to happen,
and the probability of happening
is very close to 1.
OK,
what will happen?
What will happen?
It will be found that
my red,
after going through
my own disturbance,
it may be
this red,
in the small circle,
any of the red points.
OK,
then we put
this kind of thing,
every point is actually
a sequence,
n,
the length is n sequence,
0, 1 sequence.
That,
specifically,
which,
which is flipped,
in fact,
we do not know,
we put it all
in here.
That,
I pass
the situation,
I received the y,
uh,
what is it,
like this,
and then,
what is it,
it is 101010
plus that,
all possible,
all,
uh,
the probability of occurrence is very high,
the result of the disturbance,
for example,
there are
the first 10% is 1,
the rest is 0,
then we put it
in this,
this collection.
Then,
this,
then,
this red dot is,
for example,
plus,
the first 10% is 1,
the rest is 0,
the result,
like this.
OK,
the same,
the same thing,
that,
these things are all very likely to happen,
because according to the law of magnitude,
that,
the same truth,
we can,
what,
uh,
we can see that,
OK,
in fact,
uh,
you just said that the small circle,
in fact,
in the red circle,
the red circle,
it itself also has that,
that,
it itself is channel output,
that is,
its so-called typical set.
We can figure out that,
OK,
Y actually has 51%,
50% is 0,
then we collect those,
half is 1,
half is 0,
those sequences,
we collect them in here.
Then,
we put these green dots,
this green dot,
these four green dots,
through this way of passing,
we can receive these,
uh,
for example,
the green dot on the far left,
what it receives is,
it may be,
this green small circle inside,
the top one,
what it receives is this,
the right one,
the bottom one,
is the one at the bottom.
OK.
Good.
Then,
I'm going to design this decoder.
Of course,
you can observe that,
if the dots I choose today,
are very few,
for example,
I only choose these five dots,
then in fact,
after it is printed,
I see on the Y,
that they may not
overlap,
that they may not overlap,
they are all independent,
they are all disjoint.
So,
what does it mean?
As long as its red dot
appears in the red area,
we can see that
Ah,
it wears this.
The green on the left,
if it's sent here,
the green on the left,
We tell directly that
it wears this?
OK.
Therefore,
we can design the decoder.
Then,
I am going to see
I am going to design the decoder.
Then,
I'm going to see
this Y,
or the Sequence
that is received by me
or security
into this compound.
If it's in this set,
if it's in this set,
I will decode the Y
into the corresponding X.
For example,
if Y is in red,
I will decode it into red.
If Y is in the upper left corner,
I will decode it into the upper left corner.
OK.
This is the most mathematical part.
This is the most mathematical part
of the whole decoding.
We can calculate
how many
OK.
I should say like this.
This is the design of the decoder.
I just said that
if they don't overlap
these small groups
or circles,
then
I can successfully decode
and there is no error, right?
Or the error rate
I can say that
I have no error.
But if today
there is a little
allow a little overlap,
then we can
let the error rate
control the threshold
that we want
10 to the negative 6th square
10 to the negative 100th square.
OK.
Today
Now the problem is that
OK.
We can't choose too many
these points.
For example, we just chose 5 points.
It has made this
red inside
so many crowded
small circles.
If we choose
a few more,
then these small circles
will actually overlap.
As long as there is a large
large-scale overlap
the error rate
and the error rate
is still very high.
OK.
We try to avoid
this situation.
So how do we see it?
Let's see
OK.
in this blue circle
how many
code words are in it.
Then we put this
blue circle
called TX
like this.
OK.
TX
Then we use a bar
to represent its
absolute value
to represent its number.
Then you can calculate
its number
is actually about
X
is the entropy of X.
Then its detailed introduction
is
is actually very simple.
You just think about
how do I
if I randomly generate code words
how do I get
the red one?
Then the probability of it being calculated
is about this much.
This is high school math
can be calculated.
Then
through the conversion of high school math
put this
TX
on the square
you can calculate
OK.
It actually draws
a red circle
the probability of a red circle
is 2 to the negative n
X
negative
OK.
But
the probability of a blue circle
is 1.
So
if you collect
all these points
the probability of it being added
will be 1.
So
roughly
in this circle
there are so many
so many
red circles
OK.
So
now
my goal is
to not to
let these
rising circles overlap
so
that
I can
can
let these two
come in
which is
h of
entropy of y
minus entropy of y given x
so
by definition
this thing
my R
is
less than
or equal to
the mutual information
of x and y
like this
OK.
Of course we can
improve
but it's just
a loose statement
we can
improve
to prove
that
this
way of
decoding
can be
as small as
we want
OK.
So
is this
the most mathematical part
of the whole talk
and
then
I don't know
if there is any
question
here
OK.
.
OK