Welcome everyone to today's TerraTalk.
Today is January 8th.
We are very happy to have Zhang Han with us today.
He is currently serving at the University of Taiwan.
His PhD is at the University of Massachusetts Amherst.
He later entered a biotech industry in Boston.
He then went on to study at Boston University's School of Medicine.
In 2021, he returned to the University of Taiwan
to work as an assistant professor at the Faculty of Medicine.
We are very happy to have him with us today.
As part of Terra's tradition, we would like to invite everyone to turn on their microphones and welcome our speaker.
Please welcome our speaker, Mr. Zhang Han.
You may now share your screen.
Hello everyone, my name is Zhang Han.
As mentioned earlier, I graduated from Boston University in 2016.
After that, I worked at a startup company in Boston.
I returned to the University of Taiwan to work as an assistant professor in 2021.
At the beginning of this talk, I mentioned that I had a duty to report on my research every year.
I have always kept this in mind.
After returning to Taiwan, I rarely go online because I can't get up.
So I would like to make a contribution.
I'm not fully awake today, but I would like to chat with everyone.
My main goal is to share my research with everyone.
If you have any questions about my return to Taiwan, please feel free to ask.
My research is called AI Image Analysis.
My research is based on Google Image.
After returning to Taiwan, I have been working on other projects.
I have been working on other projects.
I'm going to end the recording now.