Recording has started.
Okay, thank you for the introduction, Ya-Hui.
And thank you all for coming to listen to my PhD thesis
or my research,
my research over the past few years.
Yes, I'm Gao Xian, Lin Gao Xian.
And I'm currently at the University of Belize
taking my PhD class.
And the topic I'm going to share with you today
is Occult Research in Parental Burnout,
Theory and Application.
It's a cultural research on parental burnout.
Okay, when I give a speech on this topic,
I usually ask my audience,
we can imagine,
or some of us may already have some youthful experience.
What do you think it would feel like to be a parent?
We'll probably spend some time,
probably a few seconds,
or even a minute,
to think about,
if you were a parent,
what kind of feeling would you usually feel?
Most of the audience,
or most parents,
would probably feel,
like it's shown in this picture,
we would feel that
parenthood is a place full of happiness,
full of excitement,
full of satisfaction.
When we see our kids, we think they're so cute.
We think they're very innocent,
very innocent.
But in the past few years,
when we were in our IQ test,
when we were actually interacting with our parents,
we started to realize that
some parents don't feel
that they have this kind of positive feeling.
Some parents would tell us that
they felt
they were filled with a strong sense of bondage,
as if they were crushed
by the role of being a parent.
They even told us that
they felt they couldn't do anything for their kids.
They could only do what they had to do.
They couldn't do anything else.
Some parents even felt
that they couldn't bear
the role of being a parent anymore.
Some parents even told us that
they felt they were no longer
the good parents they used to be.
In fact, this kind of testimony
or this kind of report
is too diverse.
We hear too often
that our parents report this kind of experience.
As researchers,
we really want to understand
why they have this kind of feeling.
So we started to try to define
what kind of phenomenon this is.
So, over the past few years,
our team has defined a new feeling
or a new symptom.
We call it a parental burnout
or a new concept of parental burnout.
This concept includes
the various symptoms
we just talked about,
including the feeling of
being in a parental role
or a sense of distance
between you and your kids.
It's an emotional distancing.
So, you can only do
what you have to do for them
and you can't do anything
for them emotionally.
You may even feel
that you are burdened
with the sense of responsibility
of being a parent.
Or you may even feel
that you have a different feeling
from the past.
It's a contrasting experience.
We know that
if there is a parental burnout,
if parental burnout
really exists
as our researchers say,
we may be curious
about the importance
of parental burnout.
Why do we need to care about it?
I can tell you
that in our past research,
we found that
parental burnout
has a serious impact
on our parents
and our kids.
It affects their mental and physical health.
For example,
we found that
parental burnout
strongly affects our parents.
Especially the parents
with parental burnout.
They are more likely
to want to escape
their current life
and their family life.
This kind of ideation
has a strong effect
on their suicide.
It's a very important
cause of mental and physical health.
On the other hand,
we often see that
parents with parental burnout
tend to be violent
to their kids
or ignore the needs
of their kids
and misbehave.
It's not surprising
that if our parents
have parental burnout,
their kids often have
depression
or anxiety
in their mental and physical health.
This is a very important issue.
As we mentioned,
it may affect
our parents
or our next generation's
mental and physical health.
On the other hand,
we wonder
who
has parental burnout
or this kind of feeling.
In our past research,
we collected
the data of parents in different countries.
We tried to estimate
which country
or which country's parents
are more likely
to have parental burnout.
We found something
very important.
We found that
in different parts of the world,
the prevalence rate
of parental burnout
is very different.
Especially in Western countries,
their parental burnout
is more likely
to happen
in Western countries.
Or they may have
parental burnout.
To be more specific,
this ratio
is even more than five times.
For example,
the picture on the left
is the prevalence rate
of parental burnout
we have estimated.
I don't know if you can see
my mouse.
Basically,
in this picture,
the darker the color,
it means
the more likely
the parental burnout is.
We can see that
in North America
or in European countries,
even in Russia,
the prevalence rate
of parental burnout is the highest.
Compared to non-Western countries,
the prevalence rate
of parental burnout
is basically lower.
In fact, the highest
may even be up to 8%.
Parents may be
suffering
from parental burnout
or mental illness.
Next,
we may want to
ask
why
parents in Western countries
or their parents
may suffer from parental burnout
so easily.
Are there any shared reasons
in these regions
that can help us understand
why they may suffer
from parental burnout?
To answer this question,
we conducted
a series of research.
We did a cultural research
to find out
what cultural factors
are shared by parents in Western countries
to make them
more likely to suffer from parental burnout.
Before we start
our research,
we may be curious about
what a cultural research
should do.
Obviously,
culture includes many concepts.
It includes ideas,
beliefs,
behaviors,
and traditions.
These things
are all part of our culture.
How can we
conduct a research
on such a complex issue?
Fortunately,
some research has shown us
that different cultures
have certain ways
to distinguish different cultural characteristics.
We call this
a pre-existing
theoretical framework.
As researchers,
if we are curious
about the cultural factors
that can explain
why parents
suffer from parental burnout,
we may be able to
use the theory structure
of cultural differences
in the past
to explain
whether these cultural factors
can predict
parental burnout.
This is a very intuitive
and simple research.
On the other hand,
we can imagine
that parental burnout
is a very specific phenomenon.
It occurs in
our parental environment.
We may doubt
that if we use
the general theoretical framework
to explain
parental burnout,
we may ignore
the important
cultural concept of parental burnout.
It may be that
we can predict
that parental burnout
is a very important concept
and we ignore it.
In order to make up
for this phenomenon,
in addition to using
a very simple
or straightforward
research trend like TopDown,
the bottom-up approach
is that we don't hold
any research assumptions.
We directly ask a research question
and collect data.
We directly
let our theoretical framework
appear in our data.
This research method
is very important.
We have to use this method
to explore
what kind of phenomenon
can help us understand
the cross-cultural difference
of parental burnout.
So, based on this point of view,
we basically use
these two sets of different
research trends.
We designed
six series of research.
In the first part,
we want to explore
the research question just mentioned.
Why is it that
the parents
with what kind of
shared causes
are more likely to
be affected by
parental burnout?
In addition to using
the TopDown Research Approach
to find these cultural causes,
we also want to understand
why these cultural causes
and these seemingly far-reaching concepts
can be connected
to the bottom-up approach
of parental burnout.
We want to explore
the mechanism
in the system.
We also use
the bottom-up approach
to find other cultural causes
and other possible explanations
as to why these cultural causes
can predict
the theoretical mechanism
of parental burnout.
We researchers
don't just want to
confine ourselves
in an academic ivory tower.
We also hope to provide
a theoretical framework
for our research
and the phenomena we create.
We also hope that
if it can help
our parents
when they are
at work,
or when they are
interacting with their parents,
we can help them.
So, for our theoretical framework,
we also try to
come up with a practical framework.
We try to find
if my theoretical framework
can help us find
some protective factors
that can protect our parents.
Okay.
Let's start
with my first series of research.
We use the top-down approach
to understand
the cultural differences
in parental burnout.
As I mentioned,
culture includes
many different concepts.
It includes ideas,
beliefs,
values,
and many other concepts.
Fortunately,
there are some
well-known
and robust
theoretical frameworks
that can help us
understand
the cultural differences
in different countries.
One of the most well-known
is Hofstede's Six Cultural Concepts.
It includes
the six factors.
Among the six factors,
we see
that individualism
or collativism
is a cultural concept.
It refers to
if a country
pays special attention to
individualism,
a cultural concept,
it will rely on
people who are close to it
rather than
other people.
It is a cultural value
that is prevalent in Western countries.
We can imagine
that
based on such a cultural structure,
we can imagine
that if Western countries
are prone to parental burnout,
will the
cultural value
that is prevalent in Western countries
explain
the cultural differences
in parental burnout?
In order to validate
our assumptions,
we collected
more than 10,000 parental data
across 42 countries.
We tried to explain
and answer
our research assumptions.
We basically
did a feedback analysis.
We can see
that when we control
various social demographic factors,
that is,
after the population changes,
we can see that
among the six cultural values,
only individualism
is particularly prevalent
in Western countries.
The cultural value
can predict
the prevalence of parental burnout
and its severity.
However,
we also talked about
the fact that
culture
has different aspects.
Individualism
is simply a Western value.
It also has
different aspects.
Some people
focus on themselves
because they want to improve themselves
and make better progress.
But why do some people
believe in individualism?
Maybe it's because
they don't believe in others
and don't care about others.
So we can imagine
that even if individualism
is a very
macro
or abstract concept,
it actually has different aspects
to explain
the cultural value.
So we have to use
a more detailed cultural structure
to explain
what aspects
of individualism
can explain
the cultural value.
So we try to use
a different model.
In this model,
we can see that
individualism,
which is a country
that emphasizes individualism,
individual individuals,
may have
different aspects.
For example,
they may want to
cultivate themselves
or they may
want to enjoy themselves more.
They may not care about others
or
they may not
do anything
that benefits others.
Or they may not
follow their traditions
or others.
We use
a more detailed
theoretical structure
to see
which aspect
of individualism
can explain
the cultural value.
In order to explain this,
in order to answer
our research questions,
we gathered
more than 600 parents in Poland.
We tried to use
the same research method
to run a return analysis.
We can see that
basically,
after we control
all the population changes,
in all the 10 cultural values,
only individualism
emphasizes personal achievement
and personal ownership
and power.
It doesn't want to
do anything that benefits others.
It can explain
more of our family values.
At this time,
we can think about
how to use
a more detailed theoretical structure.
We can see that
in this abstract cultural value,
in this cultural value of individualism,
some more detailed aspects,
achievement, power,
and less cultural value
that benefits others,
it can predict our family values.
Now, we can think about
what kind of people
will show
this value trend.
Now,
you can think about
what kind of people
will have this value trend.
In fact, in past research,
it has been told to us
that
those who need to be perfect
and focus on making mistakes
are the perfect individuals.
It's easy for them to show
that they enjoy achievement,
power,
and less perfection
and become perfect individuals.
It's easy for them to show
this kind of value trend.
So, we can imagine
from the research just now,
we can see that
in different aspects of individualism,
perfectionism may be
a very important factor
to predict our family values.
We can also infer that
perhaps in the family environment,
the parents who emphasize perfectionism
are particularly likely to be affected by family ties.
But we may be curious
that the emphasis on perfectionism
in the family environment
is actually similar to
our personality.
It's a feeling
that we may feel
in the family
with our family ties.
These two concepts
are very different.
Why are they connected?
So, we can think about
the mechanism
of perfectionism.
We want to know
what kind of internal mechanism
can explain these two very different concepts.
So, let's think again.
In our family environment
or in the environment where we raise children,
what kind of situation is it?
It's actually a very dynamic
and chaotic situation.
Sometimes, children may cry.
But when they cry,
there is no special reason.
At this time, if our parents
may naturally
express their negative emotions,
we can imagine
that the dynamic environment of this family
will gradually become a vicious cycle.
There will be more and more negative emotions in it.
At this time, if we want to solve
such a negative cycle quickly,
we may have to adopt
some highly efficient
emotional adjustment strategies.
Our parents may adopt
such an emotional control.
They must control their negative emotions
and not show it to their children.
This kind of emotional adjustment.
We can also imagine that
especially those parents
who particularly emphasize that they need to be perfect,
they will particularly want to adopt
such an emotional adjustment
to control each other's emotions.
So, we can assume
why our parenting professionalism
emphasizes perfectionism
in the family environment.
It is related to parenting.
Maybe it's because such a characteristic
will make it easier for our parents
to control their emotions
and not show it to their children.
This kind of suppression
or expressive suppression
is an emotional adjustment strategy.
In order to solve this problem,
in order to respond to
such a research hypothesis,
we have collected
more than 400 parents in Poland.
We can see that
the more our parents emphasize
that they want to be perfect,
the easier it will be for them
to adopt such an emotional adjustment strategy
to further affect
their children.
So, in conclusion,
we can see that
using the top-down research approach,
using the existing cultural structure,
we can see that
in the West,
Western parents
are particularly prone to
the influence of parental suppression.
This is especially related to their personalism.
More specifically,
it is related to their perfectionism.
So, why is such a cultural value
related to parental suppression?
Maybe it's because
such a cultural value
allows them to use more emotional control
and more suppression.
That's why
such a personalist effect is produced.
As I mentioned at the beginning,
in fact, culture
includes different levels.
We should not only use
the top-down research approach.
We should also use
the approach that is closer to the parents' environment.
We should visit our parents.
We should keep a fixed research question.
We should collect our data
and not make any research assumptions.
We should directly see
if there are any neglected changes
that can actually help us understand
the cultural difference of parental suppression.
So, with this in mind,
we also carried out our third research,
a bottom-up research approach.
We try to take such a research strategy
to see if there are any differences
in parental culture
or if there are any cultural factors
that are particularly prevalent in the West
that can explain parental parental suppression.
Okay.
In order to answer this question,
as we just said,
we have to immediately
raise a research question
and collect the data
without making any research assumptions.
So, the question we raise here
might be,
what is the culture of parenting in Western countries?
What characteristics
can describe Western parenting culture?
To answer this question,
we might be able to directly think about
what kind of parenting culture
and how to collect such data.
We can imagine that
in fact, in different parenting cultures,
there will be a very specific model performance.
We can imagine that some parents
may fantasize that
what kind of good parents
they imagine in their mind.
The good parents in their mind
may be able to show
the characteristics of different parenting cultures.
So, we directly ask the parents.
We directly visit
the thousands of mothers and fathers
across 37 different countries.
We ask them,
in your mind,
if you can only use five characteristics
to describe the good...
model father and model mother in your mind,
how would you describe their characteristics?
I will pause for about a minute.
Although there are only five of us,
we can imagine that
if you are a parent,
you are already a parent,
or you are not a parent yet,
you can imagine
that if we want to describe a model parent,
you only use five characteristics to describe them,
how would you describe them?
Yes, I will pause for a minute.
If you have any questions at this time,
you can also ask.
Okay.
You may already have some ideas in your mind.
I will tell you what we saw in our research.
We found that
in Western countries,
they do have a very special pattern.
Their good parents...
They do have a fixed idea
about good parents.
We did find that,
especially in some Western countries
that speak English,
including the United States,
Canada,
Australia,
the UK,
and European countries,
and even Russia,
and some countries that speak French,
they particularly emphasize
that when they describe those model parents,
they emphasize
that they need to show love,
that they need to show patience,
that they need to pay attention,
that they need to listen to their children.
These are different characteristics.
What do these characteristics show?
They show that
in these different Western cultures,
what they emphasize is
to show positive emotions
and to control negative emotions.
This is a characteristic.
In the past, research has shown
that this type of education
is actually a so-called positive education.
Positive education refers to
showing positive emotions
and controlling negative emotions.
So, from this research,
we can see that
using this pattern approach,
we can see that Western education
emphasizes emotional performance.
This emotional performance
is to show positive emotions
and control negative emotions.
At this time,
we may want to ask a question.
Why does such a
seemingly beautiful thing
show positive emotions
and control negative emotions?
This kind of education strategy
may be related to
the parent-child relationship.
So, after our research,
we further asked
if there is a mechanism
to explain this.
We can imagine that
positive parenting
or showing positive emotions
and controlling negative emotions
is a form of emotional performance.
When our parents
have this model image of their parents,
what do they need to do?
Basically,
they feel that
in the process of raising children,
they need to control themselves
and achieve this emotional performance strategy.
They need to tell themselves
that they need to show positive emotions
and control negative emotions.
To a certain extent,
it is an emotional performance strategy.
When an emotional performance strategy occurs,
when there is such an emotional performance strategy,
our parents may have to act.
When they are not happy,
when they have a lot of negative emotions,
they have to try to
put a smile on their face
in front of their children.
They have to make their appearance
in line with this emotional performance strategy.
On the other hand,
some parents may
try to use different methods
to make themselves
look unhappy
from the moment
to find some happy feelings.
Whether it is
simply controlling your appearance
or simply changing
your inner feelings,
these different emotions
are actually a kind of acting
to a certain extent.
They are all trying to
show and perform
a positive education strategy
in front of our children.
We can also easily imagine
that this set of emotional labor
or emotional performance
is actually very demanding.
We have to constantly monitor
whether our emotions
really fit
this set of emotional adjustment strategies.
So it requires us to put in effort
and put in our
cognitive ability.
Of course, as time goes by,
the more effort you put in,
the more pressure you may feel.
It's not that surprising
that some parents
may have burnout.
So this is a theoretical framework
that we came up with.
Why does positive parenting
have something to do
with the fact
that our children are in this situation?
We need to figure out
how we can do this.
We collected 347
parents' data.
We looked at
whether the theoretical framework
we came up with is true.
We saw that
the more parents
understand our environment,
the more they adopt
positive parenting strategies.
Positive parenting
emotional performance strategies.
The more they adopt
surface acting
or deep acting
emotional performance
emotional adjustment strategies,
the more cognitive resources
these parents use
to make it easier for them
to be affected by burnout.
We also saw in our statistical analysis
that this model
is a great way to explain
the data in our data.
It's a great way to explain
the results of our data.
Okay.
Basically,
based on all the research
we've done so far,
from a top-down research approach,
we can see that
this cultural strategy,
this cultural value
of individualism
and this cultural value
of perfectionism
will allow our parents
to use a lot of
emotional adjustment
to further predict their burnout.
From a bottom-up approach,
we can see that
if we want to describe
Western culture,
positive parenting,
especially their emotional
they have to
show a lot of positive emotions.
They have to control their emotions.
Positive parenting
will make our parents
have to act emotionally
in front of their children
to explain their burnout.
Combining these two aspects of research,
we can see
why this culture
will make parents
more likely to be affected by burnout.
To a certain extent,
it's because
they've adopted
very powerful emotional adjustment.
They've adopted a lot of
willful emotions
in front of their children
or they've adopted
a powerful emotional adjustment
to act in front of their children.
At this time,
as we said at the beginning,
as researchers,
we don't just want to stay
in the theoretical framework.
We also hope that
the theoretical framework
will be helpful
to our parents
and will be helpful
to our food environment.
So, for our theoretical framework,
we also try to find
ways to protect our children.
We try to think from another perspective
on how to help our parents.
First of all, we just mentioned
why Western culture
will make parents
more likely to be affected by burnout.
It's because they've adopted
more powerful
emotional adjustment strategies.
At this time, we want to say
if we can stop this thing,
we can prevent our parents
from adopting so many
negative emotional adjustments,
will our parents be protected?
From another perspective,
if our parents
can control their emotions
more efficiently and intelligently,
will their risk of
child abuse
be lower?
Based on this study,
we did our first study.
We did our first study.
We want to see
if our parents
really have a better ability
to control their emotions,
will their risk of child abuse
be lower?
Based on this study,
we measured
the emotional intelligence of parents,
which is their ability to
identify,
to express,
to understand,
and to adjust
and use their emotions.
We want to see
if this ability
is related to
child abuse.
We collected data from different countries.
We collected data from Belgium.
We found that
regardless of which measurement
we used,
if our parents
can use their emotions
more intelligently,
their risk of child abuse
will be lower.
Our emotional intelligence
can predict the risk of
child abuse
for our parents.
Indeed,
if our parents have better emotional intelligence,
we can protect them
from the risk of child abuse.
However,
as we mentioned,
we can see from the definition
that emotional intelligence
can include...
We just mentioned
that it's related to
identification,
expression,
understanding,
and using emotions.
It can be someone else's emotions
or our own emotions.
It can also be
intrapersonal
or interpersonal.
Intrapersonal
refers to a person
who can
identify,
express,
understand,
and adjust
their own emotions.
It can also be intrapersonal.
It can identify,
express,
or understand
other people's emotions.
We want to ask
if emotional intelligence
can be classified
as intrapersonal
or interpersonal,
will it have the same effect
on child abuse?
First of all,
we collected...
We used
a different set of data.
We collected data
on parents
and children.
We found that
if we only focus
on
parents
who have
better emotional intelligence,
their child abuse,
regardless of the country,
we can see that
this set of abilities
can greatly reduce
the chance of child abuse.
However,
if we only focus on
controlling,
understanding,
and identifying other people's emotions,
this intrapersonal competence
affects our child abuse
not only in proportion,
but also in proportion.
We can see that
it basically predicts
the effect of child abuse.
In other words,
from a humanistic perspective,
in a humanistic language,
it basically means
understanding other people's emotions
or using other people's emotions
to do something related to others.
This kind of emotional intelligence
will put parents
in danger.
So we came to a conclusion.
Interpersonal emotional intelligence
not only has less positive effects,
it may even
put parents
in more danger of child abuse.
So,
based on this study,
to a certain extent,
we can say that
if we can
help parents
to control their emotions
and understand their emotions better,
their child abuse will be less.
However,
based on the second study,
we actually need to
further refine this study.
Basically,
only when parents
are controlling
their own emotions,
their child abuse will be reduced.
If we control other people's emotions,
they may be more
affected by child abuse.
So, in fact,
doing research is a bit like this.
We will always look at
different aspects more carefully.
We may get different results.
This is the first
study conclusion we got.
It actually brings
a very important conclusion.
If parents
have better emotional intelligence,
their child abuse
will be less.
In fact, the good news is
that in our past studies,
we have seen that
as long as we spend
15 hours,
we can teach
an individual
how to learn
and control our emotions
or how to
identify our emotions
in a good way.
From another perspective,
we also care about
individual's own ability
and emotional intelligence.
In fact, we are also curious
if we can start from
the interaction between people
and the interaction between people
to find some
protective factors
that can help parents.
In fact, this perspective
also comes from
the research we just started.
We see that
the individual's
individualism
actually puts parents
at risk of child abuse.
We just mentioned
what individualism is.
Individualism refers to
a person who is very focused on
relying on himself.
He is less dependent on other people's help.
This kind of ability
and this kind of cultural value.
In fact, from another perspective,
if our parents
can rely on others better,
if they can get
the resources from others better,
that is, if they have better
social support,
the chances of child abuse
will be less.
So we also proposed this assumption.
If parents have better
social support,
the chances of child abuse
will be lower.
So to answer this question,
we collected data from
different countries,
whether they are
individualist countries
or non-individualist countries.
We collected data from Turkey.
We collected data from Peru.
We collected data from Poland and Belgium.
We collected data from
any country.
We can see that
in the results of the return analysis,
we controlled all
the data on population changes.
We found that
our parents' social support
is indeed one of the most important
protective measures
to protect our parents
from child abuse.
So from this result,
we actually learned
another thing.
In fact, as long as we can
let our parents understand
that when they are
taking care of their children,
when they are interacting
with their children,
they are not alone.
In fact, if they can
get resources from their environment,
our parents can
avoid the risk of
being abducted
and abducted.
So basically, this is a very important
second protective factor that we saw.
At the end, I want to sum up
the different studies
I talked about today
to make a conclusion.
In fact, through these six
series of studies,
what information did we get?
The first message we got was
that Western culture
does put parents
at risk of child abduction.
We saw from the top-down approach
that Western individualism,
especially their perfectionism,
will make parents
take more suppression,
emotional adjustment.
On the other hand,
we can see from the bottom-up
research approach
that what can show
Western parenting
is positive education,
especially positive emotions,
controlling each other's emotions,
such a positive parenting strategy.
It will make our parents
feel like they have to
act in front of their children,
especially in terms of emotions.
No matter what kind of emotional adjustment,
suppression or emotional labor,
they are all very powerful.
These powerful emotional adjustments
will naturally make parents
more likely to be affected
by child abduction.
Through this theoretical framework,
we also try to understand
another thing.
Indeed, Western culture
will make our parents
more likely to be affected by child abduction,
but our environment...
But from another perspective,
if we can teach our parents
how to better interact
with their emotions,
or if we can find ways
to get more social support
from our parents,
it can actually protect our parents
from being affected by child abduction.
These are the two most important
take-home messages
in my speech today.
Today, I basically
summarized my research
over the past two years
in a very quick overview.
I listed the eight articles
that we published in the past,
which is the main
take-home message I reported today.
You can see that
our lab and I
put our past articles
on our lab website.
If you are interested
in learning more about the details,
especially in today's speech,
I didn't...
I didn't go into the details of statistics
or analysis.
If you are interested
in the details,
you can read these articles
directly.
Okay.
In the end,
we have to talk about
some guidelines in all our research.
As I said in my speech today,
it's like I'm the only one
doing all this research.
But it's not like that.
All the research
is a joint effort
for all of us.
So, I have to say thank you.
First of all,
of course, my two professors
and my long-term
partners.
The most important thing is
that we have hundreds of
researchers all over the world.
We are also
doing research on
the concept of parent-child bondage
and trying to find ways
to help our parents.
So, we have to thank
all the partners
and researchers
who have worked together.
Lastly,
as we have been talking about
in the research,
some parents
are already very bondage.
They may have
been affected by parent-child bondage.
But they still
spend their precious time
to help us fill in
these questions
or help us complete our research.
So, we have to thank
our parents
especially parents
from different countries
who have done so much for us.
Okay.
So, this is a quick overview
of my presentation today.
It took me about 45 minutes in total.
So, I have about
10 to 15 minutes left.
If you have any questions,
we can discuss them together.
Thank you, Ya Hui.
Thank you, Gao Xian.
On behalf of the audience,
I would like to say thank you to Gao Xian
for bringing a very comprehensive
and rich presentation.
If I were not a student
doing research in this field,
I would be able to
understand the essence of this topic
in your 45-minute presentation.
So, thank you, Gao Xian.
At this stage,
I would like to pause the recording
and we can start
Q&A and various discussions.