Welcome everyone to TARA Talk, which will be held on Feb. 19, 2022, which is already Feb. 20 in Taiwan.
Today's speaker is Cai Wei, whose theme is Process Optimization and Economic Assessment for Reducing Carbon Emissions by Converting CO2 to Dimethyl Ether with Renewable Hydrogen.
Cai Wei is a Ph.D. student majoring in chemical engineering at NTU. He began his research on carbon dioxide when he was in his junior year of chemical engineering at NTU.
At the time, his main research was on how to capture carbon dioxide from a power plant to gas.
After graduating, he worked in the industry for a few years before joining NTU's Ph.D. program in chemical engineering.
He majored in program system engineering, chemical engineering, program design, and program optimization.
Cai Wei furthered his research at NTU's Ph.D. program.
At NTU, he mainly studied how to convert carbon dioxide into a high-quality chemical product or fuel.
After graduating from NTU's Ph.D. program, he worked as a chemical engineering design engineer.
He learned the difference between academic papers and practical applications.
He hopes that his research can consider more practical applications.
His research usually includes the economic assessment of the process and the practical aspects of process control design.
Now, let's welcome Cai Wei to share her research.
Hello, everyone. Can you hear me?
Hello, everyone. I'm Cai Wei Wu.
Thank you for your introduction, Bo Ting.
Thank you, Project Taira, for giving me the opportunity to share my research with my friends and audience from afar.
Hello, everyone. I'm Cai Wei Wu.
I majored in chemical engineering at NTU's Ph.D. program.
I majored in chemical engineering.
Today, I'm going to share my research on converting carbon dioxide into a high-quality chemical product or fuel.
I'm going to share my research with my friends and audience from afar.
I'm going to share my research on converting carbon dioxide into a high-quality chemical product or fuel.
First, let's look at D1R.
D1R converts CO2 and hydrogen into a one-step reaction.
D3R converts CO2 and hydrogen into a one-step reaction.