Hello everyone, welcome to TARA Talk. TARA is a friendly venue for young researchers in Taiwan, and we hold a TARA Talk every weekend throughout the year.
Its presentation format and content are very free and diverse, and we hope that everyone can come here to share the results based on their different career stages.
It does not necessarily need to be complete, but as long as you want to discuss or practice your speech, you are welcome to sign up.
What you see on the screen now is our next speech presentation.
If there are some students who are still in school, we have two very interesting speeches.
The first is to tell everyone at the end of July that if you have not yet reached that stage, you are a PhD candidate, how to have a successful PhD career as a junior.
On the 30th of July, the next week is actually another one, after you finish the PhD candidate, the senior PhD student behind it, how do you have some mindset to let you experience the speech of your graduation defense process.
You can scan the QR code for the complete list, and you can tell everyone after the speech, or there is also a post on the chat.
At the same time, we have also issued the NFT. After the speech, we will also tell everyone that if you are interested in receiving it, how to receive it.
Now I'm going to start introducing today's speaker. Our speaker is Wu Yanrong. The topic of his speech is the English version, and the Chinese version is the application of machine learning in space science.
The background he told us is that after graduating from the physics department of the University of Chenggong in 2017, he went to the space science lab in Berkeley, UC Berkeley to do postdocs, and then he could not leave.
Let's start the speech now.
If you have any comments or questions, you can also interrupt me in the speech at any time and ask questions.
The speech I prepared this week is about the application of machine learning in space science. I will talk about some of the attempts we have made, and then I will talk about some of the parts that we have failed.
Currently, I am an assistant researcher at the Berkeley branch of the University of California, Berkeley Space Science Lab.
This is the outline of my speech today. I will mainly spend some time talking about the geospatial environment, that is, the geospatial environment, and how we get data in the geospatial environment.
Next, I will introduce how we use the Principle Components Analysis.
Principle Components Analysis is the result of this kind of analysis method.
This analysis method is mainly used to find some feature patterns from all of our 2D images to find some spatial patterns.
The third theme is related to the neural network. We try to use the so-called long-short-term memory architecture.
We want to find some of our very popular neural network architecture from our space data.
Finally, I would like to introduce some of the parts that we have failed.
The first thing we want to do is to integrate two satellite observations using the neural network architecture.
The second thing we want to do is to integrate two satellite observations using the neural network architecture.
The third thing we want to do is to integrate two satellite observations using the neural network architecture.
The first thing we want to do is to integrate two satellite observations using the neural network architecture.
The second thing we want to do is to integrate two satellite observations using the neural network architecture.
In addition to the recurrent neural network architecture, we also use the long-short-term memory architecture.