Okay, I'll start now.
I was scared.
So what I'm going to talk about today is
I'm going to describe fluid mechanics,
but I'm going to use quantum mechanics
to describe fluid mechanics.
Before I start, I'm going to talk about
why fluid mechanics,
usually the Navier-Stokes equation or Euler equation,
is very non-linear.
How could it be related to this linear equation?
In fact, this is not a discovery.
As early as 1926,
Magnum had already discovered
that these two equations are closely related.
I usually think like this.
The Euler equation,
the physics behind it is like this.
It has a few postulates.
The first one is that there is inertia.
That is to say, if the particle has no force,
the speed is just following the speed of the particle.
So the speed of the fluid is
the speed of the vector.
But in fact, there is an inner force in the fluid,
which is the pressure.
And Euler's assumption is that
this is a conservative field,
so it is already a gradient of function.
And finally, this gradient of function,
which is the pressure force,
is the only constraint.
In fact, it is an incompressible flow.
And these assumptions are combined
to write the incompressible Euler equation.
And the most difficult part in this equation
is actually the inertia part.
Because it has a non-linear effect in the equation.
That is, U dot gradient U.
When you say P-lemming,
I also want to use these non-linear equations.
Yes, just like dust.
Do you know why?
If I have the first equation on the right,
will it be very simple?
It can be said to be simple or not simple.
It is not so direct.
It is also a non-linear method.
It is a Berger's equation.
If you want to simulate,
you can just throw a lot of particles
and let it fly.
But in the end, you have to predict
what the final density is.
In fact, it can be clearly written down.
Especially when it is Euler,
it can be clearly written down.
In fact, there are some interesting phenomena.
It is not very direct.
And those are all non-linear phenomena.
It looks like a very simple physics.
But in fact, because it is non-linear,
it just runs out of phenomena.
Many non-linear phenomena,
such as shock wave and reflection wave,
will appear.
Yes, it's a simple version,
but it's not so direct.
This non-linear phenomenon
can be written in different ways.
Like Lagrange and Helmholtz.
A lot of people
write Euler's equation in the same way.
But the non-linear phenomenon
is always there.
It's all because of the law of inertia.
But in fact, there is a linear equation.
Schrodinger's equation
is built into the law of inertia.
for complex value wave function
is written like this.
I will throw away the potential term.
This looks like a heat equation.
Yes, the mathematical convention
is that delta is the Laplacian.
It's usually a gradient equation.
It looks like a heat equation,
but there is an i.
h bar is a function
in my entire talk.
But this Schrodinger's equation
shouldn't be regarded as a heat equation.
It's actually a wave equation.
And it's a dispersive wave equation.
It has a dispersion phenomenon.
That is, different waves
travel at different speeds.
If I look at the group velocity
of this wave,
you can see the dispersion relation.
The group velocity is actually
equal to the wave number.
The wave number
is usually measured by
the IC time of the E2 wave.
It will show
the wave number
and
the point is that
the wave number and the
wave number of the wave
are actually all
measured by the group velocity.
The wave number itself is
the group velocity.
So you will get a
velocity-advected-by-velocity phenomenon.
That is, it only has
an internal
flying phenomenon.
Because the speed is written as
So based on this variable
change, you can see that
the original non-linear things
may become linear, or the linear
may become non-linear.
After the Schrodinger equation
is logged, what you get
will be this
functional phenomenon.
This was actually done by
Madelung in 1926.
In 1925, Schrodinger
just wrote the Schrodinger equation.
The next year, Madelung said
amplitude squared
is the density of the fluid.
That can be regarded as the probability
density of the particle.
Then you
treat the whole system as a fluid.
The speed of the fluid is
gradient of theta, which is
the group velocity.
If you do this,
you bring these things in
and separate the actual area.
Then it will be a
If you have seen fluid,
you will find that
this is the compressible Euler equation.
The first method is
conservation of mass.
The second is conservation of momentum.
The only difference between
compressible and classical fluid
is the bone potential.
In the end, this is also the key
to evolving into bone mechanics.
But this
won't appear later.
Because you can know
I will add a
compressible Euler equation
to make it incompressible.
In that case,
the density will become constant
and the bone potential will disappear.
So we don't have to worry about it later.
What I just said
is that these two
actually have a point of view.
The first one is
the continuity equation.
q is the density.
So this is
the quality conservation.
So when you say h bar equals 0,
it's completely true.
h bar equals 0.
If your h bar equals 0,
it looks very similar.
But the
fluid velocity
h bar equals 0,
the flow velocity disappears.
Unless your theta
is infinitely large.
Look at the third line.
The fluid velocity is u times h bar times the gradient.
If your h bar equals 0,
your theta will...
You can make h bar very small.
It will become
semi-classic continuity.
It will become very close to the fluid velocity.
But you can't measure it directly.
Just treat it as a variable.
I only have u and theta left.
Under this new variable,
I already have
q bar, q bar,
h bar equals 0.
But this implies that your theta
must be an infinite positive function.
So...
Just treat it as...
Let's say...
Okay, that's it.
So my
overview is...
At the beginning,
I just simulated
to show you the simulation result.
And then...
Next, I want to talk about
a theory that is
more advanced than the variable variation.
It's called Geometric Clutch Variables.
I don't know how much I can talk about it.
For the dynamics part,
I will talk about the result.
But
there may be some parts in the middle.
I will try to talk about it.
If you have any questions,
please feel free to ask.
I will use some
more complicated math.
And then...
We published a paper
called Schrodinger's Smoke.
It's about cat when smoke.
It's about
doing some
utility simulation.
So if you google
Schrodinger's Smoke, you will see our paper.
We use
Madelung's idea.
We want to
treat fluid density...
Instead of using
density and velocity.
We use the complex value
wave function.
And then use Madelung's variable variation.
And this fluid velocity
actually has this...
You can write gradient theta
as the square on the right.
If you
write it like this,
you will find that
minus i gradient is
the momentum operator.
So it just evaluates the momentum operator.
But
the point is
even though it looks great,
but velocity is just
a function of function.
It means that you don't have any vorticity.
When you take
velocity and curl,
look at the angular momentum,
you will find that it's zero.
Your velocity
can only be this kind of potential flow.
Or this kind of
no vortex fluid.
It's not interesting.
To solve this problem,
we consider
two components Schrodinger equation.
You can think of this
as spin half particle.
Or you can think of it as
two components.
Its Schrodinger equation is still the same.
It's component wise.
It's still the same
one component Schrodinger equation.
The variable variation
is the density of the fluid.
It's still the same.
Amplitude squared.
But in this case,
it's the sum of
the density of two channels.
And
for velocity,
it's the same as the momentum operator.
If you write this down,
it will become
the velocity of two components.
But
it's a linear combination.
It depends on their density.
In this case,
you don't have to worry about curl.
It can
describe
more interesting
fluid states.
So we use one component
and two components
to describe the fluid.
Now,
to describe the fluid,
we need to describe incompressible fluid.
We already have the inertial motion.
To describe
incompressible fluid,
we add a potential term
to make it correspond to the velocity.
It's the divergence tree.
It's like the Euler equation.
When you add the pressure,
the fluid becomes incompressible fluid.
Then we
use the constraint Schrodinger equation
to describe the incompressible Schrodinger equation.
The solution is
the incompressible Schrodinger flow.
Then
it's the same as
other incompressible flow.
As long as you have
continuity equation,
that is, the quality is constant,
and
it's incompressible fluid.
The volume will not change over time.
The density
will not change
over time.
Initially, if density is constant,
it will always be constant.
My question is
you
turn it into
a two-component
vector.
Are you a two-component?
If
the screen is zero,
there will be no velocity.
If you have two components,
you need at least two components.
What is the implication?
How do you turn it into a one-component?
Actually,
at the beginning,
nComponent
and twoComponent.
After that,
twoComponent
is enough.
The meaning of enough
is
in
the middle,
at the end,
there is a question.
Can you find
a two-component wave function
that matches
the velocity?
Then I found that two-component
did a good job.
It means that it can be done
suddenly.
Is it a two-component?
Three-component.
Do you mean domain?
Is it a fluid domain?
Is it a fluid space?
Yes.
Two-component or three-component?
Sorry.
There are four variables
on your right hand side.
Each size is different.
On the left hand side,
there are two
or three variables.
If there are two variables,
there is a redundancy on the right hand side.
Do you know
what is redundancy?
You mean
four components
are like four-component,
but there are only three-component
to be described.
Yes, there is redundancy.
Then...
Let me think about it.
Is it a symmetry?
What?
Yes, it is.
It is a bit complicated.
There is a symmetry.
It means
when you write the velocity field
like this,
in the end,
we will do an unshrinkable flow.
The unshrinkable flow is just
that the velocity field drops a little bit.
All the velocity fields
can be projected.
All the radians of pressure
can be shrinked.
After this,
this space
will only be dominated by
one particle.
Given curl of u,
we can only decide how much u is.
The curl of u
will be mapped to
the two-component
wave function
corresponding to the spin vector
or block vector.
There is a gauge symmetry
which is the variable
of the unshrinkable area.
It will be
corresponding to the same velocity field.
In the end,
you will see a big
redundant degree of freedom.
So on the right,
the overall phase
of quantum mechanics
is not important.
Is it physical or...
It's the same.
It just matches
the velocity field.
In the velocity field,
we need to do pressure projection.
The redundancy.
In the end, it will match.
Yes.
In the velocity field,
we need to remove
some redundancy
to describe the
unshrinkable flow.
It's the phase shift
in Schrodinger's equation.
Why can you use
both domain and three-dimensional?
This is...
Actually,
domain can be done
in higher dimensions.
This is because...
I don't know how to explain.
It's...
Simply put,
vorticity is a two-form.
Only that thing
is used
to describe the flow.
It's...
If I say
the speed of unshrinkable flow
is equal to
the vorticity.
It's a two-form.
In the end,
you only need
a map.
At most, you only need
So, vorticity is a two-form.
Yes.
If it's in the other direction,
it won't shrink.
It's not important.
It can shrink.
Yes.
You can see
in the end.
Now, let's say it's just a metronome.
Will you talk about turbulence?
I won't talk about turbulence.
But I will talk about
the dynamics of a normal vortex.
This is incompressible Schrödinger's flow.
Then we...
The mathematical simulation
is very simple.
You just need to
make a circle and
solve the linear Schrödinger's equation.
It corresponds to
your field.
It's like a simulation
of inertia motion.
Then you apply potential force
to make the field
become divergence-free.
Then we started to do some simulations.
In the end, we found
that it was
very successful
in simulating
vortex dynamics.
What is vortex?
I just said curl of velocity.
That thing is called vorticity.
In the real fluid,
it only appears
from the boundary.
It appears from the boundary.
When it forms,
it's already low-dimensional.
It's two-dimensional geometry.
That's vortex sheet.
Vortex sheet is not stable.
It will quickly curl into
vortex filaments.
It will become a vortex structure.
That structure will become very stable.
We see a lot of vortex in our daily lives.
That's what we call
vortex filaments.
Are those two real photos?
Yes, they are.
They are not photoshopped.
They look like real photos.
The color is very bright.
You need to add a filter.
Yes, I need to add a filter.
This is a real video.
But vortex filaments
are hard to simulate
with a normal
fluid software.
Because
these vortex motions
are very sensitive
to the
vortex thickness.
If the vortex becomes thicker,
it will become slower.
If it becomes thinner, it will become faster.
So if you really want to...
And the whole fluid is
the whole fluid motion
is dominated by
these
one-dimensional filaments.
So if you want to calculate the whole fluid
qualitatively correct,
you need to use a very high
resolution fluid to solve
those vortex.
Otherwise, the thickness will be misinterpreted.
The whole
vortex dynamics
will be qualitatively wrong.
So you either need
a very expensive grid,
or you need to use some very complicated methods
to describe those vortex dynamics
using some real curves.
Then you can do those simple reconnections.
But if you use Schrodinger's
equation...
Let me talk about
the difficulties first.
You can see from some benchmark tests.
There is a phenomenon called leapfrogging vortex rings.
If you put two vortex rings
in front and back,
the vortex rings will be sucked
to the front.
This is a real video.
They will be exchanged.
Then you will see...
Will the people on the line see
the same thing?
Anyway,
two vortex rings will leapfrog.
But if you use
a general
mathematical method
to solve Euler's equation or Navier-Stokes equation,
even if you use a very advanced method,
but if you are in a very rough grid,
the two vortex rings will merge together very quickly.
Then you won't see that leapfrogging phenomenon.
Now we are solving...
We just
introduced incompressible Schrodinger flow.
It has the same resolution size.
You can see that
it can do this.
It can reproduce
this observed phenomenon.
Then...
Let me ask a question.
You just said
that it can reproduce this phenomenon.
It means that
you can see it like this.
But if you change it to a parameter,
it can really
change to
the gas you just saw.
Yes.
Because there are some parameters in it.
So if you want to do
further parameter
tuning,
of course you can match it.
It's actually very simple.
Just two rings.
It has a certain vortex.
When the ring is small enough,
its final dynamics is dominated by
the dynamics of the vortex filaments.
That thing is
mathematically...
Even Schrodinger, you can push it out.
Under that progressive behavior,
it's the same.
It's...
You can push it out.
Then the two rings will jump like this.
Yes.
This system is very robust.
If you put the two rings together,
it will jump.
It will jump according to
the evolution distance.
So we just put it anywhere and it will jump.
Another phenomenon is also a very simple setup.
It means that you put two vortex rings
on each other.
But there is an angle.
Then they will recombine.
Then it will separate from the other two directions.
This is a real experiment.
You can see the two rings.
It's like this.
Then it separates.
If you use a normal
LTI
software,
it's hard to simulate this thing.
It really needs very high accuracy.
This is the same as
our method.
You can find this phenomenon
on a very thick network.
Then
I just said that
when simulating LTI,
its grid resolution
dominates a large part.
So you can see that
using some traditional methods
to look at
the node.
Then you will find that at different resolutions,
the result is the same.
So using our method
on a very thick network, it's close to the end.
It can simulate
some other interesting phenomena.
It can be used
in computer graphics.
For example, you can simulate a jet.
You can simulate an obstacle.
The vortex behind.
Then you can simulate
a moving obstacle.
This video looks good when it looks smooth.
Then there's
another
moving obstacle.
Because
in this kind of vortex dynamics,
if it can be calculated accurately,
you can see
a more realistic vortex
phenomenon.
This is really important
in computer graphics.
These are two
water-absorbing boxes.
It's called secondary small ring shoot-off.
What I'm doing here is
putting two
pieces of ink
on top of each other.
It will also
have a problem.
What is network complexity?
Network complexity is
that
my computation grid
how many
pieces each side has to cut.
So usually
usually
you have to
cut 256
times 256 times 256.
Or 512 times 512.
You often need
a very large memory
to eat.
Or you need to use cluster to compute.
This is 64 times
64 times 64.
Then you introduce it in these grids.
Yes.
What is relative?
You can't say it's relative.
How big is the thing in the middle?
Oh.
It's relative.
Just look at this picture.
It's
64 times 64 times 64.
If you put it on the computer
you can see
that
the gray part at the bottom is the network.
You can see the grid.
That's the real
network on the
computation of Lisan.
So the length of the command
is actually normalized.
Yes.
It has a physical size
which is 1m x 1m x 1m.
And
it has a resolution which is dimensionless.
It's 1 out of 64.
Then you put it on that position.
It becomes the smallest length in the world.
At this length
we simulate the Lisan version
of this grid.
Theoretically
at this length
when it's dimensionless
it will be
limited to the real
continuous world.
And this picture
is when I'm at 64 times 64 times 64
it's very close.
But in the traditional method
you need a higher resolution.
Why did you choose this picture?
This is the community.
It's a little perverted.
You can actually add gravity.
It's a little bit
when the density is different.
That's because
there are two components.
You can play a trick.
For example, when the potential of two components
is a little different
you can make some effects.
Because of the gravity
the gravity of the air
is pushed up.
And this is bar.
H bar
has a unit
which is meter square
meter square divided by second.
And
so
I usually
make it dimensionless.
So according to my real
density
it's 1 meter by 1 meter by 1 meter.
There is a
characteristic length
which is 1 meter.
And then you start to get rid of these variables.
Based on experience.
Planck constant
has nothing to do with the real Planck constant.
My final analysis will say
you don't have to get close to 0.
That is to say
H bar can be very large.
The phenomenon you just saw
is the result when H bar is very large.
Finally, we did a mathematical analysis
and found that
when H bar is very large
the result of Perturb
is the difference between it and the Euler equation
the effect
is only in the
vortex
and other places it will be very fast
to the Euler equation.
There is this kind of
argument.
In this case, you will find that
when H bar is very large,
it will get the vortex
dominated Euler equation.
Then you will find
that
I will talk about this later.
I don't know what I'm talking about.
But
H bar
when it is very small
it will become exactly the Euler equation.
You just saw
when H bar is very large
I can simulate some phenomena
and it is matched.
I can see the phenomenon in the vortex.
It is the same as the vortex.
If H bar is very small
it will be the same.
It will be the same.
It can detect the Euler equation
on a very large network.
Yes, if H bar is too small
I think H bar is a bit
too large.
Yes.
In fact, it is H bar
that you have to choose.
H bar will correspond to
your
If you know the super fluid
there is an H bar inside.
That thing will cause the vortex
quantization.
That is, every vortex unit
can be quantized into H bar units.
In that case
you will see that
H bar is very small
you have to have the same strength
of vortex to detect
a lot of small vortices.
You can take the real fluid as
vortex becomes
a continuum.
That is, vortex can be any
number or size.
It can be taken as H bar is infinitely small
and there are a lot of vortices.
But when H bar is large
it still has some thicker vortices.
Those vortex dynamics
are similar to the vortex dynamics
in the fluid.
What is the advantage of simulation?
Is it because
we don't know what linear is?
Or does it have some special properties?
There are two
advantages.
One is
that the method
becomes simpler.
You don't have to worry about
how to idealize.
Because that thing is quite difficult.
You just need to idealize the linear system.
In Numerical Method
it becomes
an extreme simplification.
The other is
that even if I simulate
in a very advanced way
those non-linear OEVs
still can't simulate those phenomena.
In our method
I can simulate those phenomena
in a very early stage.
Especially on those
thin vortex dynamics.
These are the two advantages.
Someone asked
what is the physics of H bar?
Isn't it a high-level question?
The physics of H bar
in this fluid world
can be regarded as a parameter.
It will be connected to
for example
in this animation
you can see
a small amount of
in the end
the vortex will
cascade to a very low level
and look like turbulence.
But because of H bar
it will
go to a certain level and won't continue to fall.
That is the vortex concentration.
Now that you mentioned it
you don't assume
that it will cascade.
Will it?
No.
It will still cascade.
In the original fluid
the vortex will cascade.
H bar means
that at a certain level
H bar will dominate
and the fluid will disappear
at that level.
The vortex will not continue to cascade.
It will become diffusion and disappear.
It will eat up the energy.
So when we look at
turbulence
if H bar
is getting smaller and smaller
it will cause
turbulence.
It will look like turbulence.
Without H bar
in theory
it will develop into
this is still an open problem
how is turbulence born.
A typical situation is that
it will continue to cascade from H bar
and then dominate into a spectrum
of different
things.
So you mean
if H bar is too large
you won't be able to see turbulence.
Because
it hasn't produced a new vortex yet
so it will dissipate.
I remember
in Sandwich
the cascading and reverse cascading
were very good.
We haven't done
that side yet.
We want to
use
a very large network
with high resolution
and then put
some random
velocity
and random wave function
and then use our method
to look at its energy spectrum
and then compare
the turbulence.
But we haven't done that yet.
But usually
if you want to see
if this thing can model
turbulence
you have to look at
the energy spectrum first.
I think
cascading versus reverse cascading
is the most important thing.
Is there a way?
Yes.
One.
But there are still other ways.
So you mean
we don't need
theory.
I think reverse cascading
is better.
Yes.
We also
have
simulation on the left
and real video on the right.
This is what we often show to others
that
we can use our very simple algorithm
to do some
simulation of turbulence.
This is the first part of the remark.
It means
it breaks through our traditional
imaginary fluid calculus
what the usual framework looks like.
Usually we will
figure out how to simulate turbulence.
But this framework
doesn't have this problem.
Especially in Vortex Dynamics
we can
simulate those phenomena.
Usually we think
we need to solve Euler's equation
or Navier-Stokes equation.
We need to be very advanced
and have a very fine network
to simulate those phenomena.
There is also
an interesting
insight on math.
This is
incompressible Schrodinger flow equation.
It looks like this.
Schrodinger equation
restricted on
a divergence-free constraint.
This divergence-free constraint
can be translated into
wave function and
Laplacian.
The spatial derivative of the whole equation
is Laplacian.
This is a very special
part of Schrodinger.
You often need to talk about
U dot grad U.
You use a lot of mathematical structures.
You often talk about 2-dimensional or 3-dimensional.
Or
you have to be on a manifold.
Laplacian can be set
on a very low space.
You can have a graph
or a point cloud.
You don't even need to use a dimensional concept.
In that world,
you can still discuss similar flow phenomena.
This is a surface,
so it's still a manifold.
Then we have this rabbit
and its graph.
A triangular graph.
You can get the graph.
That information is the only thing you need to know.
You can solve the
Schrodinger equation.
You can easily
use the same complexity
to model the graph
in this general space.
That was
my first part.
Next, I'm going to talk about
the
wave function
and
the
encoded information.
This is called
Clutch Variables.
We developed
this theory
to connect the Schrodinger equation
to the classical field.
We have a side project
to use this to do
some
vortex visualization.
Okay.
Notation means
that we often
use vector field
to represent the speed.
On the right,
there are many arrows in a fish tank.
Alternatively,
you can consider its
covector,
or throw the index down.
Or it will
become...
You can imagine
that the arrow
is replaced by
some hyperplane.
This is called
Differential Form.
Differential Form
means that
it can be evaluated
along some curves.
If it is a one-form,
it means that
it can be evaluated
along the curve.
This is called
Circulation.
It is usually visualized
as a hyperplane.
When you see
many hyperplanes,
the curve is
proportional to
the density
of these hyperplanes.
The density
of the banana
is the value of the curve.
So we often use
this one-form.
There is also
a abstract concept called
Pullback.
If you have two spaces
and you have a map
from the space on the left to the space on the right,
if there is a Differential Form
on the right,
you can pull it back
into the Differential Form
of the space on the left.
The definition is that
if there is a Differential Form
on the right,
you map it to the right
and evaluate it to the right.
The symbol is defined as
f star alpha.
If you don't use this symbol,
you often write
the rightmost space.
We often write
Pullback.
Pullback
has some beautiful
definitions.
But that's only
a very detailed introduction.
So I won't talk about it here.
Pullback
has something called
Exterior Derivative Commute.
If you write it in a normal language,
it will be very difficult to see.
So we like to use
this
coordinate-free
notation.
There is a special pullback
in the stream.
Consider that the map
is a flow map.
When the stream is flowing,
the map is from
the space of time 0
to the space of time t.
In this way,
you can naturally
generate the map
and
the physical quantity
in the world of time t
can be pulled back to the space of time 0.
That thing is called
Lagrangian Coordinate.
The physical quantity
in the Lagrangian Coordinate.
We often like to discuss
the division of time
in the Lagrangian Coordinate.
That division is called
Lead Derivative.
If the physical quantity
changes with time,
it will become
the generalized
material derivative.
I often say that
this physical quantity is just
carried away by the stream.
It means that
after it is pulled back
to the Lagrangian Coordinate,
the world will not change.
Do you understand?
It doesn't matter.
The Euler equation
is written as
in terms of velocity one form.
That is to say,
the one form of velocity
is the hyperplane
covector
that I just visualized.
It is purely a vector.
There is a
derivative of some function
on the right.
We often call that
an exact form.
The exact form
means that
the velocity form
is divergence-free.
The vorticity equation
is purely a vector.
The vorticity
is a two-form.
Vorticity is a two-form.
Vorticity
is a quantity.
It is not a vector.
It is a quantity
that is to be measured
on a two-dimensional curve.
We often say vorticity flux.
In fact,
what we can measure
is the concept of flux
that is to be measured
on a two-dimensional curve.
Then,
if you see a curve
that flows
at any given time,
you can pull it back
to its zero-time state
and put the evaluated
vorticity flux
back to the original space.
You will find that it changes at any time.
That is, vorticity is purely a vector.
You want to ask...
The meaning of vector
is not that
it has a
zero-time state.
You can ask again.
The meaning of vector
is not that
it has a zero-time state.
There is still a
velocity field in the fluid.
It is u.
The relationship between u and eta
and the velocity one-form
is that
eta is the velocity
flat.
It is the co-vector.
It is the dual vector.
Then,
the physical quantity
is directly
purely a vector
in this velocity field.
It changes at any time.
You see that
L sub u
depends on
the velocity.
Then, eta
u depends on eta.
So, it is a nonlinear function.
The vorticity
equation is the same.
In fact, vorticity
must be equal to d of eta
or d of u
flat. So, omega
is coupled with velocity.
In this case,
vorticity is
purely a vector
in this equation.
When they are coupled together,
it increases.
What are the benefits?
I am just talking about
the benefits.
There is no benefit or
disadvantage.
It is just a different formulation.
Since the time of Euler,
we have been talking about
purely a vector.
This term is not invented by me.
So, there is no disadvantage.
I am just saying
that
I am just saying that
the definition of purely a vector is
the force derivative.
It is just a general material derivative.
It is just a quantity of u dot grad.
I can imagine
writing a general
derivative.
What is the general derivative?
u dot grad.
The u dot grad
you mentioned
is used for zero-form.
Few people talk about
how to generalize
one-form, two-form, or other tensors.
In this case,
people can only write
a basis for those tensors.
For those
previous functions,
they become a zero-form function.
You can do
a partial division of time
plus u dot grad.
But often the right-hand side won't do that.
It should be taken care of.
It should not be a function.
It should be a tensor.
It contains those things.
So,
sometimes people are surprised
that the vorticity should not be written as
zero on the right-hand side.
So, I added an equation here.
We often see vorticity as a vector.
Or three components
with some
basis.
Then we find that the right-hand side is not zero.
Then it is regarded as a vortex stretching term.
People often say that
the difference between two-form and three-form is
that sometimes there is
a vortex stretching term.
It's just because
it's a co-dimension.
When it's different,
it should be a tensor,
but it's a vector.
When it's a purely vector,
there is a difference.
Then,
I want to emphasize that
I only use the above notation.
I only use the simple notation
to represent
what I need to use.
The first one is notation.
Now I can talk about
clebsch representation.
Clebsch is
from 1850s.
You may have heard of
Clebsch-Gordan coefficient.
But most people may not know
quantum mechanics.
Who is the boss?
Clebsch.
They seem to be from the same era.
But they
are not used
to describe quantum mechanics.
They want to describe
SU.
That was in
the mid-19th century.
So people think
Clebsch is a modernist.
No, he is from
the mid-19th century.
But some of his work
is in quantum mechanics.
Before Clebsch,
people only discussed
potential flow.
At first, people didn't know
what to do with quantum mechanics.
People didn't know curl operator.
And there were no planes at that time.
People were most concerned about
the problem of quantum mechanics.
So
it was all about
potential flow.
In that case,
velocity one form is
d of some function.
Velocity vector field is
the gradient of some function.
This is potential.
But there was no vorticity.
So Clebsch wrote a paper
in Camp-Holt's
first invention of
vorticity.
He immediately thought
potential flow should be generalized.
Otherwise,
the vorticity will be destroyed.
So he considered
two other potentials.
One is lambda and the other is mu.
He wrote velocity one form
as lambda d mu plus d phi.
And
lambda d mu
is generalized.
It will have vorticity.
This was very popular
at that time.
You can see it in thermodynamics.
It's not
closed.
It's
TDS.
At that time,
it's easy to see
lambda d mu as a consideration.
It's natural.
At that time,
d phi can be used as
potential flow.
Lambda d mu is not necessarily
divergence-free.
As long as phi is good enough.
If so,
I will look at
the vorticity two form.
It's just lambda wedge d mu.
Phi is not important.
But
it's like this.
Any lambda mu
can be solved
by
the fact that
eta needs to be divergence-free.
This is
Helmholtz's
decomposition theorem.
Any
three-dimensional field
can be divided into
divergence-free part and curl-free part.
This is Helmholtz's decomposition theorem.
Is this the only part?
No.
It's not well-defined.
Potential flow is not well-defined.
Phi can be any parameter.
D phi is well-defined.
The left part is well-defined.
It's not well-defined or not well-defined.
It can be represented by
this equation.
Phi is not defined as
d inverse of eta.
It's not well-defined.
I only consider
the velocity field.
It's the form of d of some function.
Then we discuss how to
describe the function.
I want to have more potential.
Three potentials.
I deliberately put this form
as curl-free.
It's not
orthogonal splitting.
I don't claim this is
a splitting.
It's not unique splitting.
It's not like this.
You can also discuss
what the gauge symmetry is.
It can be short form lambda mu phi.
It corresponds to the left side.
There are a lot.
It should be easy to see.
Omega looks like this.
It means
you will see later
it's the area form of
lambda mu plane.
It's like gradient mu.
Gradient lambda cross gradient mu.
It's a small area.
If you want to use
vector potential,
can you use it?
Yes.
If you want to use
vector potential,
omega corresponds to
magnetic field or curvature.
I will use it later.
Then
So
capstructure
is described as
three potentials.
You can ask
what the three potentials
satisfy.
Then you will find
those functions are purely reflected.
Then phi
lambda mu is purely reflected.
is chosen at
each time point.
Eta is divergence free and
for all time.
This is capstructure.
But it's
not that famous.
Then
There are still
some works on it.
For example, Marston
found capstructure
representation can make
the fluid
described as Hamiltonian system.
Hamiltonian system is
a generalized coordinate
and the momentum corresponding to it.
There will be a position and momentum
relationship.
But this is the infinite version.
Because fluid has infinite freedom.
Then
lambda and mu
correspond to
position and momentum.
Then
there are some beautiful mathematical structures.
However,
people think it's too artificial.
It's not practical.
The main reason is
there are a lot of fluid
and a lot of momentum
can't be written as lambda and mu plus phi.
Then
it doesn't mean
it can't be...
It doesn't mean
some capstructure can be designed in a strange way.
It is topologically
separated.
For example, if your eta is written as
lambda and mu plus phi.
Then there is a quantity called helicity.
It is the
velocity
and velocity
are integrated.
Then
its total points
will be equal to
the average
of the vortex line in the fluid.
It's like
that
if you have two vortex filaments
and there is a linking,
then the helicity is not linked.
Then
it can use points to describe.
But if
eta is written as lambda and mu plus phi,
you can easily prove that
its total helicity is linked.
Then it will cause
a lot of velocity
that helicity can't be linked.
It is topologically
unable to be described
as a capstructure.
And if it is possible,
it is difficult to find
lambda and mu.
And even if you find it, it is not unique.
Just like what you just found.
Does it have the same thing as trace-734?
Yes.
Trace-734.
If it is a higher-dimensional fluid,
for example, a 5D fluid,
it has a slightly higher helicity.
Yes.
Does it have this effect?
For example, a 2D fluid,
no one will discuss its helicity.
Then 3D, 5D, 7D,
no, 4D fluid,
you can still discuss
its helicity in 3D.
It will be purely a link
with the fluid.
It can be grouped into 3D.
It is a 3D form.
It is purely a link.
Then if it is
a 3D fluid,
it is a closed space.
It should be like this.
Then a 5D fluid,
it corresponds to trace-734.
It depends on how high your helicity is,
you can write a lot of
concert content.
With trace-734.
Then because of these difficulties,
some people want to write
Clutch Representation.
So they invented a thing called
Multi-Component Clutch Variable.
Lambda and mu,
I made a lot of small ones,
and then add them together,
and then defi.
Defi is the same as
pressure projection.
But this is actually
a new insight.
Because it is trivial.
You can write it
in 3D.
Velocity 1 force
is also very trivial.
This is exactly Clutch Representation.
Multi-Component Clutch Representation.
So you don't have
more new insights than Lagrangian.
But there is
an interesting paper in
1980s.
At that time,
it used another
new
generalized Clutch Variable method.
You put the lambda and mu,
which is
the key term.
You put lambda and mu together
as a map.
It's from the floating domain to R2.
Then omega equals
lambda times mu,
it means
the area of the two-dimensional space
is pulled back by the map.
It means
the variable is changed.
You can think of it as
you put the S,
which is the lambda and mu
together.
R2 vector value
function.
From 3D to 2D.
On the left,
you can draw any 2D curve.
Then you can discuss
the vorticity flux on it.
Its value is equal to the area
on the right.
How long did I spend?
8 minutes.
Oh.
OK.
This is a natural generalization.
You can imagine that
you put lambda and mu together.
I don't think of it as R2.
I can think of it as any two-dimensional manifold.
There is a paper that
I put it on the sphere.
Then
the vorticity can still be
the area on the sphere
from the pullback.
You can't actually
put lambda and mu together.
You can only write it as a variable.
Then
you will find that
the helicity is not the same.
So you can find that
most of the three-dimensional flux
can be approximated.
Yes.
The dimension is not the same.
This is a continuous map.
SC continuous map.
Then you can discuss its pullback.
There is a tool form on the right.
You can turn the pullback
into a tool form.
Then that tool form
if you just put the area on the right
from the pullback into
vorticity,
it is a
capture representation.
Because the core of the capture representation
is omega equals
lambda which equals
the area from the pullback
into vorticity.
Yes.
I will say syntactic manifold.
There is a
non-degenerate tool form.
Yes.
Syntactic manifold value function.
Then the induced
non-degenerate version of
syntactic structure
is what Marston and others saw.
Yes.
So we think
this approach is
quite interesting.
It turns the space on the right
into a general manifold.
So we find this route.
But this
is just a two-page paper.
I didn't talk much about it.
So we continue to develop this thing.
But it only discusses vorticity.
Velocity can also be
generalized like this.
Velocity is
written as lambda
dmu plus dv.
You can also treat it as
a map size.
Then
it projects
a one-form
back to velocity.
Just like the vorticity
is a two-form.
Its form is xdy plus dz.
OK.
You can imagine what it means.
This is what Clebsch did.
Before Clebsch, people
only looked at the potential flow.
Eta is equal to dv.
You can treat it as
pulling back the one-form dz.
You can treat dz
as a hyperplane field.
This is a hyperplane field.
It's all pointing in the same direction.
A very trivial one-form.
Then you pull it back like this.
What Clebsch did
is that he replaced
this template field
with a richer xdy plus dz
form.
What you see is that
this hyperplane field is lower integrable.
It's not just
the tangent spaces
of a family of surfaces.
It's all separated like this.
This is called contact geometry.
Clebsch representation
means that
I have a size map,
and I send it to this space.
Then I pull these hyperplane fields back
to become the velocity one-form
To describe the flow,
instead of saying
how some one-forms change over time,
he just said how this psi changes over time.
Then this becomes a zero-form.
So it's a little bit easier.
In the case of Clebsch,
remember lambda, mu, and phi.
Actually, only lambda and mu determine the vorticity.
So
there's a natural projection
to project z.
Then
you can say that
the vorticity is just the first two parts.
The pullback area is sent back.
Then we call
the psi velocity clebsch map.
Then S is called
vorticity clebsch map.
The identity after the pullback
is the velocity and vorticity.
Then you will find that
the right one
is xdy plus dz
and the bottom one
is xdy plus dy.
One is the area form,
and the other is the form of Clebsch.
The relationship between the two
is actually quite important.
It's very obvious.
The result is
that the relationship
of theta
is quite important.
It's
d theta equals pi star sigma.
That is to say,
these curves
are just like a velocity field.
A fixed velocity field.
Then the curl
corresponds to the vorticity
in the template velocity field.
The pullback is equal to
the area form in the
two-dimensional space below.
Then
this
is to say
the frame on the right
plus the square on the left
is called
pre-quantum bundle
in another field.
I don't have much time,
so I will
try my best
to
not explain
what each sentence means.
I think it's not bad.
It's not bad?
Anyway, it's already like this.
I just said
that it can be any
syntactic manifold.
The two-dimensional space below me
can also be a sphere,
or a Riemann surface,
or any syntactic manifold.
Any two-dimensional space.
Then
there is actually
a fiber bundle above it.
I add one more.
Each point below me
grows a little bit of freedom.
Then it becomes
a three-dimensional space
in the two-dimensional space below.
There is an operator
called projection.
Go back to the two-dimensional space.
There is a
one-form
in the three-dimensional space.
It's like x, y, and z.
But generally speaking,
I can use any one-form
as long as it meets the following conditions.
Then
there is
a normalization.
Then it will be
a pre-quantum bundle.
This word comes from geometric quantization.
That is to say,
there is a form that
quantum mechanics
generally
quantizes from the classical system.
We usually say
to change momentum
to space.
There are some standard programs.
But generally speaking,
there is not only
x and p in general space.
There is only position and momentum.
It is a general simplex manifold.
How do you discuss it?
Then the classical mechanics above
how to change the quantum system.
It actually lifts this thing here.
There is more
phase factor.
Then the function above is called wave function.
Then there is a
The point is that you need
the high star c.
That c is a connection.
Then you need
the
coverage of that connection
to match the symplectic form
of the manifold below.
That is
key for
the Poisson equation.
Poisson bracket will turn into
b bracket.
The original Hamiltonian equation
will turn into
that
Poisson bracket equation.
That has nothing to do with this.
They will need
a definition called pre-conform bundle.
I just need the same definition here.
So I call it pre-conform bundle.
This is a one form.
Then you can assume that it is the bundle above
the connection.
Connection means
it defines
the manifold below
to another point.
Then the position above the fiber
is called parallel transport.
Then you will see this hyperplane field.
It means
if it intersects
this hyperplane, then it is parallel.
If it intersects,
it means that if I go around
and then I do parallel transport,
it may go to different heights.
That is the definition of bugausable.
If it intersects,
there will be a gap.
The size of the gap is
how much
is the distance
inside.
What is the library?
What I mean is
the phase.
It is
usually
U1.
Wave function is the definition
for every x and p
and every x and p.
I define
its
amplitude.
How many probabilities it has in that place.
Plus a phase factor.
I can have a quantum density,
but I can only have an iterative IP.
Then it can be parallel on this fiber.
Then
what is the difference between
those two variables?
That
is
another variable
is the density.
Because it is
actually
another number.
But
the bundle is a trivial bundle.
It is just cross r.
But this phase
is complicated.
Because it is cross s1.
But in general, it may intersect.
You have to write cross s1.
So you have to write it in bundle language.
So
density is just
a function
of the manifold below.
But if you want to talk about phase,
it can't be well defined.
You have to choose a gauge
because this fiber
is a compact.
In quantum mechanics, it is usually compact.
So how does it decide
the fiber structure
or the
bundle structure?
How do I
choose sigma
or q?
How do you
make a connection
to the fiber
of the bundle?
I read
Wikipedia.
It only talks about
U1 principle bundle
over a syntactic manifold.
I just generalize a little bit here.
I just say that it is a one-dimensional fiber.
So it can be
not necessarily
have U1 structure.
I don't know why.
What I mean is, even if you choose
a manifold, I think your
bundle will be free.
Yes.
I don't know how physicists
usually choose this.
When doing geometric composition,
how to choose?
How to choose?
Sometimes
there is a problem with the existence.
But if there are many different structures,
I don't know.
As long as you have this pre-quantum structure,
you can immediately discuss
the velocity
and vorticity
capture map.
That is, the domain of the fluid
is the bundle above
is called velocity capture map.
It can be used to pull back
the hyperplane field above
which is the velocity.
The area form or syntactic form
is pulled back to the vorticity field.
Like this.
There is a very important
combination.
In fact,
if my right
syntactic manifold
is only two-dimensional,
and my fluid domain is only three-dimensional,
there is an interesting phenomenon.
If I draw an area on the right,
its pre-image
must be a vortex tube.
The definition of a vortex tube is
that it is a three-dimensional area,
but the vorticity flux through
its boundary is zero.
In other words,
the vortex line is like a flat tube.
If you reduce these regions to a point,
you will find that it is
pre-image of point through S.
It will be a vortex line.
In application math,
there is a well-known
level set method.
You can use a level set function
to describe any
combination shape.
You can use an implicit function
to describe it.
S is like this implicit function.
It is not mapped to R2,
but to the general syntactic manifold.
The geometry it describes
is the vortex line.
It is a very natural
vortex line.
It looks complicated,
but if you have
this geometric variable,
it is a level set function.
If you have this level set function,
it is very easy to visualize
these vortex structures.
This motivates
us to have a side project.
Remember that
if you want to have a level set
interpretation,
the syntactic manifold
must have a side project.
But if we choose R2,
we know that there is no helicity,
so it is too boring.
We already know that S2
is a two-page paper
that describes general helicity.
If the domain below is S2,
you have to ask
how to choose
the helicity.
We already know that there is a precondition bundle
called half-vibration.
The Q above is S3.
S3 is the three-dimensional sphere
in the four-dimensional space.
The three-dimensional
surface is also
the three-dimensional.
To understand the structure,
the easiest way is to use
the four-element.
The four-element is
a plus bi
a plus bi is
the negative number.
You can add
cj plus dk
i, j, k are all negative numbers.
There are three negative numbers in the space.
Then
satisfy some multiplication
i square minus 1
j square minus 1
k square minus 1
aj minus k
polymatrix
So you have four
four-element helicity.
The three-dimensional sphere
is to satisfy the normalized.
To satisfy the normalized,
this is used
to describe the three-dimensional rotation.
When do I need to finish?
I want to finish
the second part.
If you want to hear more,
I will continue.
OK.
The three-dimensional rotation is like this.
Any
Q is a unit four-element.
It describes the three-dimensional rotation
like SU2.
Because it is
SU2 space.
Its internal rotation
is that any
three-dimensional quantity to be rotated
is written as
the span of i, j, k.
It is any point on the earth.
It is written as
a four-element helicity.
If you put the left-hand side as Q
and the right-hand side as Q
as a unit four-element,
the result is still a helicity.
Still a three-dimensional helicity.
So there is a R3 divided by R3.
That is
the three-dimensional rotation.
If you put
Q as a phase shift,
which is the
i, t,
t is a number.
You just multiply
cosine something
by i sine something.
You will find that your rotation
is just a rotation along
the North Pole.
That is, the North Pole
is the invariant vector
under this variation.
The Q bar iQ
is called
pi of Q.
pi is projection.
The Q map of S3
is the new location of the North Pole.
This is the map of S3 to S2.
This map is called
half-map.
From R3 to R2,
the fiber direction
is the projection.
All are projected
at the same point.
The fiber
is generated
by the iQ of E2.
The three-dimensional
helicity looks abstract,
but you can visualize it.
You can use stereographic projections
to project the three-dimensional helicity
to R3.
You can project the two-dimensional helicity
to R2, which is the point projection.
You can project S3 to R3.
Almost everything on S3
can be visualized
as R3.
It is a polyhedral variation,
so you can see a lot of angles.
This picture
is...
is all...
I put 1,000 fibers.
The half-fiber
I just mentioned
looks like this.
This is a fiber bundle.
Each fiber
is a
circle of S1.
It is mapped to a point on S2.
The index set
of these fibers
is S2.
It is the location of the point projection.
The rest of the helicity
is the rotation of the point projection.
You can see that S3
is this structure.
Each fiber
is generated by the IT of E2.
Vertical direction
is
the action of multiplying I.
If the IT of E2
can go in this direction,
then
multiplying I by infinitesimally
is going in this direction.
Its helicity space
is a one-form.
We call it Theta.
This is...
You can think of it as...
Because it is a helicity space,
so
the one-form of Theta
is any infinitesimally motion
projected to fiber direction.
That is to say,
multiply I by Q.
This structure
is generated at every point.
Remember that the fibers are interlaced.
So you can see that
this is a no-wear integral.
You can go through it.
This is...
You can open your personal camera.
I printed out the 3D printer.
You can see that it is a no-wear integral.
This is the real...
In S3,
I drew a quaternion
and stereographically projected it to R3.
Then I printed it out
with a 3D printer.
So it became
an S3 3D printer.
A 4D printer.
Actually, it satisfies
a...
This choice just satisfies
the pre-quantum bundle.
This is the pre-quantum structure.
This thing
can be visualized like this.
In S3,
in S3,
there is a fiber direction.
Just like in R3,
there is a Z direction.
Now it becomes a fiber direction in S3.
So you can take that direction
as the Z axis of the world,
which is the direction of gravity.
The vertical space is a platform.
When you walk on that platform,
you are standing still.
The meaning of no-wear integral is
if you want to...
If you want to walk a circle,
if you want to walk a circle back,
you will find that you have to keep climbing up the stairs
to get back to the red dot.
This is the concept of
the zeta and pi star zeta.
In other words,
the zeta is projected
to the fiber direction.
In other words,
if you draw a circle,
or if you draw a curve in S3,
and then you take the zeta value,
in other words,
you will find that
you are walking in that direction,
but you are still in the fiber direction.
So the physical force you produce
is your total work,
which is the work of climbing up the stairs.
The zeta means
if you walk a circle back,
it is not equal to zero.
If you walk to the red dot,
you will find that your progress is not equal to zero.
This is also
produced in S3.
So you will see
this is the famous
impossible stairs.
Most people
know that
this is a visual illusion.
But in R3,
you have to use a visual illusion to understand.
But in S3,
everywhere is like this.
Because the platforms in S3 are all low-end.
So it must be like this.
So you can
put it in S3.
Just now,
there are a lot of abstract things.
And we found that
one of the good examples is
half-vibration.
So if we change the
catch variable to S3
to S2,
the psi of catch
corresponds to S,
which happens to be
the wave function
in our Schrodinger equation.
Then the
velocity is pulled back.
It happens to be the Madelung transform.
In Madelung transform,
we use C2 value wave function.
You have a, b, c, d, i.
You can expand it into four elements.
Remember
we normalized that
because it is an incompressible case.
So psi is
an S3 value function.
It is normalized.
It is a quaternion or C2 vector.
Notice that
when we do phase shift,
what is that?
Oh, no.
This is just a value.
I want to expand
a, b, i, c, d, i
into a, b, i, c, j, d, k.
There are many different ways.
But I deliberately choose this way.
It will cause my left layer
is a complex scalar,
and my right layer
is a quaternion.
Remember
in Madelung transform,
the momentum operator
is evaluated.
You will find that
a quaternion is a deep sine.
It is projected to the i-th direction.
We can see
that i-gradient
is projected to
the i-th direction.
That is exactly
what we did in C2.
It is projected to the fiber direction.
It is a pullback
of the 1-form.
The pullback of the 1-form
is exactly the Clebsch representation.
In S3,
under the pre-quantum structure,
the Clebsch variable
is exactly
the Madelung transform.
Given velocity
form,
there is a vorticity
Clebsch variable.
The vorticity Clebsch variable
is the sidebar i-th side.
That is
the block vector
we learned in quantum mechanics.
The block vector
is the vorticity Clebsch map.
Remember
the vorticity Clebsch map has an amazing function.
It is the level size function of the vortex line.
If you have
wave function,
you can find the block vector.
The block vector
is the area drawn on the sphere.
The pre-image is the vortex.
Vortex
Vortex2
There is an interesting application.
Given velocity field,
you can find the wave function.
You can visualize the vortex
as an implicit function.
I show some results here.
This turns into
a vortex detection
application.
Vortex detection is
how to find
where the vortex is
in a velocity field.
This is a
flow data,
a delta wing.
You can see
some vortex settings
under
the velocity field.
You can
calculate the vorticity
and the threshold.
You can see the vorticity is higher.
Some more complicated
methods are lambda2 method
or cube criteria method.
There are some heuristics.
You can look at the local Jacobian
and calculate the eigenvalue.
Then you can determine
where the vortex is.
These methods are heuristic.
These tubes are not vortex tubes.
We developed
a method to convert
given velocity field
into wave function.
You can find the spin vector
and
the
level set function
for vortex tubes
and vortex pipes.
You can easily
visualize
the vortex structure.
It can reveal
much more information.
These are the real vortex tubes
and not heuristic.
These are some operators.
You can look at the eigenvalue
and see if it is rotating or not.
Most of the
velocities can be approximated.
For example,
the vortex has a linking number
which is 0.
To solve this problem,
we solve a
image processing problem.
It is a
Ginsberg-Landau model.
Usually,
for image processing problems,
I have some parameters
that I want to match.
My parameter is Psi.
I want to find a Psi
that
is close enough
to the
given velocity field.
This is called the fidelity term.
There is a problem.
As I mentioned,
there is a
redundant gauge symmetry.
If
my S
is below the block vector,
I post-compose
an area-preserving differential coefficient.
It is the same as
the vortex.
Vortex is a pull-back area.
The right side is the
mixed
pull-back area.
With this
big redundant gauge
symmetry,
we still want to find
a better one.
So we add
a symmetry breaking term.
For example,
I want to find
the most smooth
solution.
With this solution,
we get a better
optimization problem.
This is fidelity and regularization.
This is usually
the two terms in image processing.
Fidelity and regularization.
These two terms
are the
two directions
of the
re-quantum structure.
If you have a deep Psi,
the other direction
is how fast
you move
in different fibers.
The projection
is how fast
you move
in the two-dimensional
sphere.
You will find that
ds is the horizontal direction
and the re-quantum direction is the speed direction.
I want to see
the fidelity term.
You just need to change a gauge.
I change d to
d-i eta.
As I mentioned earlier,
the re-quantum connection
is at the same speed.
You can pick it up like this.
After picking it up,
this is my new covariant derivative.
this nabla
Psi is projected
on the fiber direction.
Then
the horizontal direction
is the original ds.
What?
It's non-zero.
0 is the redundant gauge symmetry.
That is to say,
if I choose 0,
the problem should be like this.
I find a Psi that is closest to eta.
It's 0.
Oh, right.
How do I choose eta?
The way of optimization
is that I choose eta at the beginning.
Because the larger the selection,
the easier it is to solve.
The ds on the right is good.
When I solve
to the approximate solution,
I reduce epsilon.
At the end,
when epsilon is almost 0,
I trace
to the suboptimal solution.
When epsilon is 0,
it will be traced to
the minimized
Psi star theta.
The fidelity term
will be minimized.
And it's...
Yes, it's...
Is epsilon the size of a cat's tail?
You can say that.
You can see that
there are two directions
Yes.
It's called a Bergers sphere.
The metric of fiber
and not fiber direction
is anisotropic.
The concept is
used in Weibull's theorem
to do collapse.
S3 into S2.
It happens to be used
in different cases.
So,
according to the Pythagoras theorem,
the square box above
is just
its...
It's just
the size of a knob.
It's just anisotropic.
As you mentioned.
Visualize.
Anisotropic norm
is the same as the
anisotropic theorem.
It's called King-Splendor
It's...
Because it's a normalized
psi.
Directly energy.
Deep psi
norm squared.
D is for covariability.
It's like a magnetic field.
At the bottom,
some vortices appear.
You can see it in the diagram.
Then,
those vortices are
my visualized vortices.
And,
those are some particles.
Then,
this is what we learned in the
survey.
Is everyone okay?
We also
did some
biological
biotech calculations.
We asked for some biotech data
to help them
with visualization.
We found
the velocity field
near the bird.
Convert it into wave function,
set it as block vector,
and pre-image of area.
Visualization is better than
using
vorticity thresholding
to get more data.
This is my second part.
I think
we can stop here.
I just want to show you
some mathematical methods.
Then,
that's it.
That's all.
What?
Did I finish my defense?
All of them.
I think there are
some interesting things here.
Coriolis force and
quantum Hall effect.
Quantum Hall effect is
quantum mechanics
plus magnetic field.
Then,
there will be
Lorentz force
and quantum Hall effect.
Then,
we put quantum mechanics
into the
power system.
The Lorentz force
in general is Coriolis force.
So,
I can simulate
the fluid with Coriolis force.
But my method
is not to add
Coriolis force.
Instead, I solve the Schrodinger equation
and add a magnetic field.
The result is like this.
You can see
that it's all counterclockwise.
Then,
I didn't solve
any fluid equation.
I just solve the Schrodinger equation
with magnetic field.
Then,
there are many open problems.
This is just the beginning
of a new framework.
I didn't talk about
whether I can get
new insights
from the open problems
in the Euler equation.
We can't make
a big claim yet.
But this is just the beginning.
Then,
I don't want to
talk about Euler equation.
I want to talk about general flow
or conservation law.
For example, traffic flow.
Those are
general flow.
But it's not just
a simple matter
like quantum mechanics
and a conservative field.
There are some constants
and some
clebsch representations.
Most of them are clebsch representations in MHD.
We can talk about
the quantum mechanics.
That's all.
If you have any questions,
please feel free to ask.
You should be able to hear me.
Do you have any questions
about image?
What?
About what?
Image.
I think so.
But I think
I need to know more
about the problem.
Then,
I will do some benchmarking.
Maybe climate simulation is better.
The weather forecast.
I think data-driven is better.
I know that
in the past,
it's related to
big companies.
For example,
when the stock price
went up,
the stock price
will be affected.
I've seen their
state-of-the-art software.
It's super hard.
They are...
I've seen some good...
I mean...
I've seen some
crappy simulations.
I've heard some talks
that you can do it
in the right way.
Even though
it's not a fluid,
it's a conservation model.
It's a simulation of a tsunami.
It can match
almost exactly.
It's been around
for a long time.
But
it's not a tsunami every day.
So you need to verify.
It matches
with the Japanese tsunami.
Is it a simulation of
a tsunami?
Non-linear.
Because the tsunami's
shadow water wave
is a non-linear system.
It's a simulation of a tsunami.
Yes.
From the physical model
to the mathematical
shadow water equation,
there might be
some errors.
And the terrain
is the input.
In the end,
the real time and height
are the input.
So I think
as long as you...
If you really want to
make a prediction,
you can do it well.
I have a similar question.
I've been thinking about applications.
I've been thinking about
TimeCube.
Do you mean Gensperr?
I've been thinking about it.
I don't know
if
like Xiaoliu
or DFT
want to use
First Person Coaching
as a new material.
Do you know what they are doing?
I don't know.
I want to
compare
what kind of terms
they use.
For example,
I'll talk about
the simplest Gensperr Landau model.
It's not complicated.
DFT.
It's a Gensperr Landau model.
Usually, you see
where is it?
I said this is Gensperr Landau.
Usually,
Gensperr Landau
will say Psi
is not sent to S3 map,
but to D2 or R4 map.
But it's not normalized.
There's a non-linear image
at the end.
It means
if Psi is not equal to E,
it will want to go in the direction of E.
It's a non-normal term.
Of course, it's related to Psi norm.
So it's a non-linear image.
The image will also
appear in
the GP equation.
It's a very popular GP equation.
There are many non-linear
Gensperr models.
It's in the practical
or electric field.
Yes.
If you want to model,
it's very natural
to fill in some symmetry.
You can see
the mathematical meaning of
normalization term.
You often see many models
with multiple terms.
Like 2, 4, 4, 4, 4.
But this is a
projection
or constraint
system.
For example,
the GP equation
is an incompressible
flow.
So
there's a different mathematical meaning.
If it's going in that direction,
I don't know if there's
any new ideas.
If there are no other questions,
thank you again.