My PhD research is mainly in microfluidics for single-cell analysis.
In the content of biology, I mainly focus on cancer research.
Because we generally believe that in cancer, the heterogeneity between cells is stronger.
For example, when we treat cancer, there will always be some antibody cells that can be used for therapy.
So if we can use single-cell analysis to see the different characteristics of each cell,
and find those antibodies to lock them in for treatment,
we believe that it can improve the efficacy of the treatment.
My research is divided into two parts.
The first part is the phenotypic assay, which I will share with you today.
The second part is also what I'm doing now.
Because I haven't published the paper yet, so I haven't put it up here yet.
But the whole direction is like what Jake just introduced.
As a sample preparation chip,
we can extract circulating tumor cells from the patient's blood.
We get gene expression information from the cancer cells in the blood.
This gene expression information can let us know
what kind of drugs we can use to treat these patients to get better results.
For now, to get this gene expression information,
we usually use the whole flow of chips.
In other words, we need to use a knife.
It's more invasive, and the cost will be higher.
Today, I will share with you the phenotypic assay.
In the technology development, I mainly focus on scaling and automation
in the high-throughput single-cell device sphere assays.
First, I will tell you why we want to do this tumor sphere assay.
In fact, the purpose is to study these tumor-initiating cells.
In this process, I will share with you
why we need to scale up this assay and automate this assay.
Next, I will tell you how I enable this thing.
Then, I will use some experiments to show you the functions of my chip.
Finally, I will conclude my presentation today.
OK.
So, our motivation is to study these so-called cancer stem-like cells.
Our recent research shows that
there is a relatively small number of tumor-initiating cells.
They are called cancer stem cells.
Some people think the term cancer stem cells is too strong.
They prefer to call them cancer stem-like cells.
In fact, it is a biological mutation.
They are a group of antibodies
with some stem cell-specific cancer cells.
This tissue group has some characteristics.
The first one is that it has a relatively strong chemoresistance.
It will cause tumor relapse.
In this picture, you can see that this is a primitive tumor.
The yellow one is CSC, cancer stem cell.
The blue ones are normal cancer cells.
If we use traditional cancer treatment,
these ordinary cells can be removed.
So, we can see that the tumor size is reduced in clinical trials.
But what we can't see is this cancer stem cell.
It has a way to stay quiescent
and not be affected by the drug.
After we stop giving drugs,
the tumor relapse occurs.
So, in the research scope of CSC,
we hope to find cancer stem cell-specific therapy.
So, I eliminated it for this CSC.
The rest of these normal CSC,
sorry, these normal cancer cells,
they don't have the ability to self-renew.
So, they proliferate.
In the end, the tumor relapse occurs.
So, this is the first reason why we want to study CSC.
The second reason is that we generally believe that
CSC has a strong migration ability.
In other words, it is easier to metastasize to the secondary tumor.
We know that cancer transfer is the biggest challenge in cancer therapy
and the biggest cause of death.
So, if we can study CSC more,
it will be very helpful in therapy, tracking, and research.
The most traditional way to study CSC is to use surface membrane protein
or intracellular enzymatic markers.
For gene expression or protein expression,
we use different methods, such as full cytometry,
to separate these different types of cells.
Then, we can study these CSC groups.
But the challenge is that
many of our new markers have not been discovered.
So, we hope to use other methods to study these CSC populations.
As a substitute, cell behavior is a common choice.
We observe that CSC can survive in a suspension culture environment
and grow into a single-cell-derived tumor sphere.
In other words, if it is a normal cancer cell,
it cannot be adhered to the substrate environment.
It will produce apoptosis.
But CSC is different.
It can not only survive in a suspension environment,
but also grow into a new tumor sphere.
So, what is the traditional way to do the sphere assay?
The method is to buy a whale plate,
as shown in the picture on the bottom right.
Then, dilute the whale plate to a certain level of cell concentration.
The whale plate contains one cell.
As you can see,
the low-throughput is a distribution of the probability,
or more specifically,
96-whale plate contains 20-30 single-cells.
It is labor-intensive.
Someone may ask,
can I use automatic cell dispensing,
such as flow cytometry,
to ensure that I can put a cell into a whale?
In fact, flow cytometry has a big problem.
Because it is a flow-sorting process,
it will produce a lot of shear stress.
So, what is the impact of cell behavior assay on downstream?
We need to observe if the cell is dead.
If the cell is dead,
it is not caused by the suspension environment.
It is caused by the flow-sorting process.
The shear stress is too high,
and the cell can not bear it.
So, the cell is dead,
not because it is not CSC.
These are the existing technology limitations.
Why do we think automation is important?
As we mentioned,
CSC is a relatively small sub-population.
In the past,
only 1-5% of tumor cells have this sphere formation tendency.
We hope this assay can start with a larger single-cell population.
At least 1,000 single-cells.
Then we can have a reliable statistical power
to make our assay conclusion.
So, we think
to achieve this throughput,
microfluidics is an ideal technology
to make this assay.
So, this is our chip schematics.
We want to develop a chip
with more than 1,000 single-cells.
Because we have a very large throughput,
we also need an automatic image analysis.
Otherwise, we have to read it manually.
It is a very difficult process.
Only in this way,
can we make the whole experiment
smoothly improve on hardware and software.
So, this is our motivation.
I don't know if there is anything I didn't explain clearly.
Or you can go on.
Ok, let's continue.
I want to ask,
why CSC can survive in suspension culture environment?
This is a question.
Did you hear it?
Yes.
The question is,
why CSC can survive in suspension culture environment?
This is a very interesting question.
I will answer it in two ways.
First,
the definition of CSC is
we only inject 10 cells into the mouse.
Can these 10 cells
generate a new tumor on the mouse?
If yes,
we define it as CSC.
The predecessors defined CSC in this way.
Then, they used this traditional conventional assay
to find out
the cell population of tumors
can survive in suspension culture environment.
This is the first way to find it out.
Why?
Our idea is
CSC can survive in suspension culture environment
by moving through the local environment
to the blood vessel.
The blood vessel is a suspension environment.
If these cells
die in the suspension environment,
they can't move to other places.
So, we believe
CSC can survive in the blood vessel
and grow into a tumor in a new local environment.
We simulate this in vivo environment.
This is the first way to find out CSC.
The first way is to verify CSC
and to find out the correlation between CSC and in-vitro experiment.
The second way is to explain the correlation.
We think CSC can mimic in-vivo environment
and survive in suspension culture environment
and grow into a new tumor sphere.
Does this answer your question?
Okay.
I have a related question.
When CSC is transferred in the blood vessel,
is it in the form of a single cell
or a sphere?
This is a very good question.
Most of the cells
are transferred in the form of a single cell.
But in recent years,
the research of circulating tumor cells
found that
there are more ways to transfer tumor cells
in the form of clusters.
A cluster is not a single cell
that grows into a sphere
and is transferred to another place.
Most people believe that
a small number of tumor cells
fall from the original tumor
and can be circulated.
You can imagine that
in a vast ocean,
is it a warship
or an aircraft carrier?
They think that
a cluster is like an aircraft carrier.
It is very powerful
and has a stronger metathesis ability.
But people think that
a cluster fell from the original tumor
and not a single cell
that grows into a sphere
and is transferred.
Do you have an answer?
Yes.
OK.
Are there any other questions?
I don't think so.
You can continue.
I have a question about operation.
If a worker
is holding a pipe and dripping,
can he catch a single cell?
The best theoretical limit
is 20-30%.
You can think of it as
a cell suspension solution.
Let's say that
I know that
there are 10k cells
in this tube.
On average,
there will be
a single cell
in 100mL or 10mL.
How many cells
are there?
There will be a single cell
in 100mL or 10mL.
The best theoretical limit
is 20-30%.
In fact,
the control of cell density
is not ideal
when operating.
So it will be worse than 20-30%.
It is the operating limit.
It will be worse.
But it is almost the same, right?
For example,
is it 10% less
or less than 5%?
If you have good skills,
it can be less than 5%.
If you don't have good skills,
it can be 5% or less.
It is difficult to experiment.
So it's about 15%?
Yes.
So if you have
a 96-well plate,
if you have a 96-well plate,
and you have Taipei
almost 100 times,
and there are only 15 cells,
and you only have 1-5% single cell
that can grow into a sphere,
it's really hard to do.
Yes.
Any other questions?
No.
You can continue.
OK.
I will continue to present.
So the first thing I want to discuss
is how we achieve single cell capture
in a high-throughput manner.
The way we implement
is by microfluidics.
The principle is quite simple.
We capture single cells
by channel blocking.
So you can imagine
this is a
microfluidics microwell
or microchamber.
This is a capture site.
The blue part is the channel.
This is where the water flows.
These are the flowing cells.
When the cells come in,
they block this place.
So the flow basically
stops.
The next cell will go to the next place.
So each well has only one cell.
If we only have
10-20 chambers,
a simple design would be fine.
But in this workbook,
we have to scale a chip
up to tens of thousands.
At this time,
this simple duplication
will cause a significant flow imbalance.
In other words,
if the entire
flow cell
comes in,
it will mostly be upstream or downstream.
The capture rate will be very, very low.
How do I
make the cell
uniformly distributed
on this
array?
The method I use is
circuit modeling.
In fact,
microfluidics is like
a flow circuit.
Each channel
has a flow group.
This flow group is mainly
dominated by the capture site.
Because the flow group is the largest,
and the size is the smallest.
The entrance channel and the exit channel
are relatively small.
But because it is very long,
the build-up resistance is also very large.
You can see that the resistance of the entrance channel
accumulates from 1 to 200.
This is a circuit like this.
Why didn't
the simple duplication work?
Because if we want
a good distribution,
each branch of the
current is the same.
We know that
if the upper short
here is very small,
the lower short here is also very small,
then this thing can happen.
But today,
we put 200
negligible short here.
At this time,
the performance of the current
will be much worse than what we want.
How do we balance the current?
Flow resistance
is actually a function
of channel geometry.
You can see that
circular and rectangular
have different functions.
In short, the longer the channel,
the higher the flow resistance.
The wider the width,
the smaller the flow resistance.
So we use
microfabrication
to make
this very small
geometry.
First, this can achieve
high flow resistance.
Second, 10x10
can block our cancer cell.
Because we generally believe that
the size of the cancer cell
is greater than 10 microns.
I will have related data
to explain this later.
We have overcome
the microwave
flow resistance
we have defined here.
What about the entrance channel and the NC channel?
I use this
microfabrication
to make 100 microns
wider and 100 microns higher
geometry.
So I can make the
entrance channel and the NC channel
flow resistance
smaller than these cancer cells.
In short,
we use this microfabrication
to control our flow resistance.
So we have a
very good flow circuit
to achieve single cell capture.
This shows that
we use three
different sizes of chips
to scale.
From 800 to
chamber chips.
The size is probably on a slice.
You can see
that this is a device
and every
chamber we can capture
a single cell.
This is a microscope image.
Our cancer cell is labeled here
as a green fluorescent dye.
You can see that this array
has a very good single cell capture.
Now we have
achieved high-throughput single cell capture.
How do we
analyze it?
This is a comic.
So
based on many habits,
we need to
automate the readout process.
So how do we do it?
Sorry,
I have a question.
You can see
that almost every
size has a single cell capture.
But my question is
if you drop a sample
from beginning to end,
does every size
have a cell?
Or if you drop a sample,
does every size have a
10% size capture?
And you have to fill it up again and again.
That's a very good question.
So the beauty of MicroFluidics
is that we put
cell suspension into the sample.
We don't need any other
equipment. We use gravity flow.
The cell solution
will gradually flow in.
So the whole operation is done by a single arrangement.
It's not the first time, the second time, the third time.
It's done in one go.
It's like this.
Tens of thousands of single cell capture.
Is that reasonable?
It's reasonable.
I'm just curious.
For example,
how much is the reduction
of human power?
I see.
It becomes only one arrangement.
It's all captured.
That's the reduction we achieved.
So how much is the
filling ratio of this chip?
Is it more than 95%?
Do you mean that several chambers
can really capture a single cell?
Is that the question you wanted to ask?
Because this question
is related to how much time
you need to spend.
So if it's one time,
you can change it to this.
For example, you drop it once.
How much is it?
It looks like it's 100%.
At least it's 100% in my eyes.
This publication is the most beautiful.
OK, this capture rate
is 75%
in our routine.
It can be optimized online.
But we consider
other things.
So we think 75% is a better number.
I'll explain it later.
OK.
And 12,875.
That's a lot.
After a cell
is captured,
this chamber will be
interrupted and nothing will come in.
That's right.
It's a very simple principle.
Do you plan to
compress it
directly
or
do some pre-processing?
For example,
how do you differentiate
different cells?
That's a very good question.
The project we want to commercialize
is
molecular analysis
or phenotypic analysis.
In my other project,
we do sample preparation.
We want to
extract
the mRNA transcript
from single cell
and barcode it.
We can use Illumina
to do whole transcript from sequence.
We can't do
sample preparation
directly from the protocol.
We need to go through
upstream cell enrichment.
This is
very competitive.
There are many vendors
in the commercial space
like startups.
They can provide
downstream information
enhancement.
These startups
can take the blood
and put it in the instrument.
The result is
a tumor sample
after purification.
These tumor samples
have very limited meaning.
If you want to have clinical meaning,
you need to know
the gene expression
and gene mutation.
We want to finish the last mile.
The commercially available
technology is
upstream
GTC purification.
We can do sample preparation
after purification
to the sequencer
or next generation sequencing.
Thank you.
The answer is a bit long.
Any other questions?
No, I can continue.
Okay,
I will continue.
I don't want to
analyze so many chambers.
I want to automate
the process.
I use a biocompatible
cell
with green fluorescence.
We can use
fluorescence
to read out the cell.
We thought it would be easy
However,
after scanning the image,
we found that
the cell expression is different.
They take the blood
with different efficiency.
You can see the picture
with 5 cells and 6 cells.
Some cells are bright and some are dark.
If we use a simple
search holding,
many cells are ignored.
What should we do?
We need to
use algorithms
to make
the readout more reliable.
There are four steps.
First, we do a contrast
enhancement.
We use a
contrast enhancement
for this part.
I will explain why later.
Next, we use K-means clustering
to find the peak
of the intensity.
Finally,
we can extract local maxima
to find the center
of each cell.
These three images
show the readout
of two or more cells.
That's it.
Contrast enhancement
has a tricky part.
The contrast enhancement
is the goal of histogram equalization.
The sample
has a dark background.
After using
the algorithm,
the whole circle is bright.
We can't use it.
We use contrast-limited
adapted histogram equalization.
We can define
each enhancement panel
to be
660 pixels
or other arbitrary
number of pixels
to do the enhancement.
Under this premise,
we know
the size of a single cell
is several pixels.
We can use this information
to locally magnify
the fluorescent signal
of the cell.
Look at the chamber.
We can effectively
suppress
the background noise
to achieve the image analysis.
These are
the results of
the algorithm.
You can see the suspension cell.
We can effectively
locate
each cell.
This is the state of
adherent culture.
We can effectively
identify one cell, two cells
or many cells
to fill the chamber.
Although
this work is
focused on
suspension culture,
the same capture
mechanism can be used
to achieve adherent cell culture.
This is an example.
The algorithm
can also do
size measurement
and sphere size measurement
to determine
the size of a sphere.
These functions
can only be
implemented
on our corpus.
With this technology
and algorithm,
we can do
the device
test.
The first test is
the capture rate
or capture characterization.
In our test,
we optimize
the capture rate
to 76.5%.
First, we limit
the cell loading time
to 15 minutes.
We don't want to
leave the cell
for more than 15 minutes.
If the cell is left for too long,
it will affect the cell's
viability or
the cell's health.
In this 15-minute loading time,
we try four different
results.
No capture,
single cell,
double cell,
or multiple cell.
In the different
cell loading concentration,
the lower the cell
concentration,
the less cells are left.
If we increase
the loading concentration,
the more chambers
are double cell or multiple cell.
In the cell concentration
trade-off,
50k per mL
in single cell
is 76.5%.
In fact,
if we want to push
the capture rate,
we can use
a lower cell concentration
for 30 minutes.
I think we can push
the cell capture rate
to 80 or 90.
Some friends say
there are more than 10k chambers
with 70% of the load.
This is also good.
We think so, too.
So we set the number here.
Why
is there a double cell
or multiple cell
in higher concentration?
In the chamber design,
we must
let the cell block
the cell capture site
so that the cell can't get in.
If the loading concentration
is high,
there is a possibility
that the first cell
may get in
before the first cell
blocks.
It's hard to avoid
two cells
in the same chamber.
But it doesn't matter.
Even if there is a multiple cell
or double cell,
all the data
is extracted
from single cell.
As we mentioned,
the size of the cancer cell
is very important.
We don't want
cells smaller than 10 microns
or other sizes
to get in.
It will skew
or distort
the whole experiment.
As we mentioned,
the cancer cell
is very
strange.
So we must
ensure that
all sizes can be captured.
So we take
the cell line
from the ground
and make it round
or sphere-shaped
to quantify
its size
with the
diameter.
Then we put the same cell line
or cell
in the tube
to measure its size.
The distribution
is next to it.
As you can see,
the distribution is very similar.
Here are four images
showing relatively small cells
about 11 or 12 microns
in diameter.
This is very rare.
One-thousandth cell
has a diameter of 40 microns.
We can effectively
preserve the size.
To sum up,
there are two challenges
to overcome.
The first one is how to
scale up the throughput.
The second challenge is
how to automate
the readout under
engineering innovation.
To scale up
the throughput
using a highly parallel
flow circuit,
we need
a compact
high-density array
to scale up
the image processing.
To scale up
the image processing,
we need to scan
each image
in the device area.
The higher the density,
the smaller the number
of frames needed
for image processing.
These are the two challenges
of engineering innovation
to scale up the throughput.
In terms of automation,
we developed a highly adaptive
algorithm to analyze
the different single cells.
We also used
the function
to analyze the size
of the single cell or sphere.
Is there anything
you want to discuss?
I'm a bit curious
about the fluorescent bag.
Our fluorescent bag
uses CellTracker.
CellTracker
is a live technology.
What does it do?
That's a good question.
As far as I know,
it's a bit like
a metallization product.
If the cell is alive,
it will intake
these bags
to show the color
of the cell.
You may want to know
what the chemical is.
I can send you the link.
I'm curious
how you can make sure
that all the cells
will eat the bag.
I don't know if
there is something
in the sample
that will be eaten by the cell.
Are you worried
about the negative force?
Yes.
In this chip,
the fluorescence
is very dim.
As I said,
some cells may be very weak.
It's very dim.
These two cells
seem to be weaker.
We try our best
to minimize the force
and minimize the negative force.
As we see in this experiment,
we use manual
and brightfield imaging
to verify
that the negative force
is less than 5%,
so we minimize the negative force.
The second is
that we need
commercialization projects
to do molecular analysis.
In this project,
the real cell readout
is from sequencing,
not from fluorescence reading.
So the readout method
is different
with different concerns
and different methods.
I didn't understand
what you said
about commercialization.
What is the readout?
We directly see
how much transcript recovery
is required.
I have another question.
I just calculated
the size of the chip.
For example,
a cell is about 10 microns,
and a grid is
several times the width of the cell.
If you have
about 10,000 grids,
and we think of it as a square,
so the length of the grid is about 100 grids,
then the chip
will be several centimeters
long.
Is that right?
Yes.
That's about it.
My question is
you have a several centimeters
long chip,
and you use a channel
to feed through
all the slides.
How many channels
do you use to feed through
all the slides?
If there is no clock
in the feeding line,
it will be a whole row.
All the slides
will not have feeding.
Is that right?
That's a very good question.
You said
if the channel is broken,
all the slides will be dead.
Yes.
If the channel is broken,
there will be no cells.
This is not a problem
in our experiment.
There are two reasons.
First,
each branch
has 64 or 32 chips.
So
even if one branch doesn't work,
we may lose
some of the cells.
Second,
if the channel is 100 microns long,
it's not easy
to break it or kill it.
So there is no problem.
Thank you.
How do you make the channel?
Can you tell us?
Of course.
We use
microfabrication
to make photolithography.
We use
SUA.
The feature is that
we can make a channel
with a wide range of thickness.
For example,
one micron to several microns.
We can define
the different
channel sizes.
Thank you.
I think
it's a good question.
I think everyone is following.
Thank you.
I have to answer
how to make
suspension culture
based on capture.
We have a
capture scheme.
The chips
are made of PDMS.
How do we make sure
that
it won't stick
to the chip?
We use
a chemical called
Peronic F108.
The feature is that
the two ends
of the chemical
have a
hydrophobic
core.
So what happens
when we load
the F108 to the chip?
The hydrophobic core
will stick to
the PDMS.
The two ends
or the pegs
will expose
the surface of the channel.
When the cell comes in,
it sees that there are many pegs.
Pegs are
a kind of
anti-biofouling material.
If we have
these pegs
on the surface,
the cells won't be able to
stick to the PDMS.
So we can make
suspension cell culture.
In this work,
we show four different
breast cancer cell lines.
You can see
the sphere-forming cell
at the top,
and the anoikis cell at the bottom.
You can see the single cell
at day 7 and 14
started to form
a humerous sphere.
The width of the chamber
is about 100 microns.
So you can see
the humerous sphere is relatively small.
The anoikis cell
has
a debris
or cell
inside the chip.
You can see
that different cell lines
look different.
Some look like balls.
Some look like grapes.
The morphology is slightly different.
Can you go back to the first page?
Sure.
When you make cell culture,
you should release the cell first.
At least don't let it
get stuck in the channel.
Right?
OK.
After completing cell loading,
we will wash the cell
to make sure
there is no cell on the entrance channel.
Then we will flip the chip over.
This is a more detailed
experiment process.
So we flip the chip over
and the cell will fall into the microwave.
You can see
from this image
that this is the capture site.
You flip it over
and it falls to the bottom.
Because of the gravity,
it falls to the bottom.
Then it
grows into a sphere.
Or it may die.
OK.
After flipping the chip over,
you need to provide nutrients,
right?
You need to use the same channel chip
to do this.
That's right.
It's easy to do.
We just take
the in-and-out chips
and put them into CultureMedia.
CultureMedia has more chips.
So it will gradually flow
to the outlet.
We provide nutrients
in stages.
We change
the frequency of Media
once a day.
It's our protocol.
I see.
Thank you.
We use
this technology
to put the cell in.
You can see the sphere size distribution
and the sphere formation rate.
You can see the different cell lines.
It's quite obvious.
It's easy to grow into a sphere.
First, the sphere formation rate
is high.
At the same time,
the size is large.
It's smaller than other cell lines.
The result is
quite consistent.
It proves
the capability
of our technology.
What else
can we do
with this technology?
We can
get the
sphere formation rate
with this technology.
We can see more details
and information.
First, the relationship
between stem cell and
stem cell.
It's controversial.
Some people think
the smaller cell
is related to
stem cell gene.
The lower the stem cell gene,
the smaller the cell.
However,
mitochondria
have more
and larger cell lines.
It increases the size of the cell.
At the same time,
it makes the cell look more
stem-like.
What's going on?
We can
understand stemness
from sphere formation rate.
We have a good algorithm
to analyze
the size of mitochondria.
We can study the impact of
different size groups on sphere formation rate.
You can see
cell size distribution.
We can see
the size of
the single cell
in different cell lines.
We can see
the size of
the single cell
in different cell lines.
We can compare
the size of
inter-cell line.
We can compare
the sphere formation rate
of the first 30%
of mitochondria.
The result is very interesting.
In the experiment of
SOM-159,
we can observe
that the smaller cell size
is larger than
the larger cell
in the sphere formation rate.
However,
in SOM-149 and
T47,
the fourth cell line
has no difference.
We think
in different cell lines
or different pathway regulations,
they may be different.
It also explains
why other people
get different conclusions.
We can't study the correlation
directly from size.
We have to look at
gene regulation
to determine whether it is CSE.
Size is not a reliable
CSE marker.
This is
the conclusion.
Next,
we can check the size
of the sphere in
Day 0, Day 7, and Day 14.
We can see
the growth
in each stage.
We can see
that in each cell line,
some cells
grow very fast in the first week
and not so fast in the second week.
In contrast,
some cells grow very slow
in the first week,
but in the second week,
they grow bigger.
This is
the plot
on the
scattering plot.
If we put
Day 7's sphere diameter
on X,
Day 14's on X,
we can see
that Day 7's
sphere diameter
is basically
1X.
If Day 14's
sphere diameter
is 1X,
Day 14's
sphere diameter
is 1X.
Day 14's
sphere diameter
is 1X.
Day 14's
sphere diameter
is 1X.
Day 14's
sphere diameter
is 1X.
Day 14's
sphere diameter
is 1X.
In the theory of
cancer stem cells,
oncologists believe
that there is
a tumor-stem cell hierarchy,
meaning that
it can't further differentiate
into regular cells.
We believe that
these progenitor cells
are not yet
fully compatible,
so they can also
produce a tumor sphere.
However,
it is not a stem cell,
so it can't
self-renew
after proliferating
several times.
On the other hand,
cancer stem cells
have a quiescent property,
which means
they don't like proliferation.
They may grow slowly at first,
but it doesn't mean
they don't want to.
When I showed this result
to our collaborators,
they were very interested.
In their hypothesis,
although there are
so many sphere-forming cells,
this cell line
is a special cell line
with a lot of progenitor cells
and strong sphere-forming capability.
That's why
the proliferation rate
in the second week
is so much lower.
SOM149 is more
compatible with
oncologists' cancer stem cell model.
It may be quiescent at first,
but it can continue
to proliferate.
Through this technology,
we can see
the proliferation
of single-cell
derived sphere
and
study the
cancer stem cell hierarchy.
This is the second part
of our technology presentation.
To sum up,
the high-throughput single-cell
derived sphere as a chip
can scale from
800 to
more than 10,000 wells.
The capture rate
is now
around 76%.
When capturing the cell,
the representative cell size
per population
is equal to the block.
We can make sure
that we didn't
change the cell
in the cell process.
We didn't scale the result.
We also used
genetic analysis algorithm
to help us
do cell counting
and cell sphere size measurement.
Without these functions,
it is difficult to
quantify the sphere formation rate
and observe the dynamic
of sphere formation.
At the end of the presentation,
I told you
about two different
experimental results.
The first one is
the comparison of cell size
and cell strength.
We don't think
cell size is a good CSE marker.
We think
there are more
gene regulation
that we need to study
in the cell,
not just cell size.
We also showed
the ability to track
the process of sphere formation.
This can help oncologists
to study
tumor stem
and cancer stem cell hierarchy
to help them understand
the details.
This work
was published in
Lab on a Chip last August.
If you are interested,
you can check it out.
Thank you
our lab
for being with me
for an hour.
If you have any questions,
feel free to ask.
I have a question.
Can you go back to the page
before the conclusion?
This page?
Yes.
I have a question.
How do you rule out
the size of the culture well?
It's about 100 microns.
How do you rule out
the size of the chamber?
The speed
is not limited
to the size of the space.
It's the
characteristic of the sphere.
Is the entrance small?
I'm asking
the size of the chamber
is not limited
to the size of the chamber.
The size of the chamber
is not limited
to the size of the chamber.
That's a good question.
The entrance
is set at
50 microns.
We observed
the cell population.
The cell population
is not more than 50.
If a cell
is very powerful,
it will grow fully in the first week.
How do I know
if it will grow slowly
in the first week?
That's a good question.
In fact, we set 100 microns.
From our experience,
very few cells can grow
more than 100 microns.
The reason you can see so much
is because our data is
very large.
We can observe
very few cases
in our data.
If you are really interested,
it's not difficult
to solve this problem.
We can change the chamber size
to 150 microns
to solve the problem.
However,
in the context of work,
the chamber size is a minority.
It's not the focus of our research.
Our focus is to demonstrate
the capability.
So we set 100 microns
as the chamber size.
I have a question.
How do you
quantify
the gene performance
of a single cell?
This is my
other work.
If you are interested
in the gene performance
of a single cell,
you can read
a paper published
in Cell.
It basically
barcodes
each cell
and transcript.
From next-generation sequencing,
we can infer
which cell
this transcript
comes from.
We can quantify
the strength of gene performance
by this way.
The way it captures
messenger RNA is
to put a
poly-T-tail to capture
a poly-A-tail.
So they can hybridize
and barcode.
I have already captured
these cells.
How do you transfer them
to a single-cell RNA-seq
device?
In molecular
analysis,
we use
a bead
as our
mRNA-captured carrier.
This technology
is introduced
by Dropseq.
They introduce
this technology
and license it
to a company.
We buy the product
from the company
and put the bead
into our chip
to capture mRNA.
We take the bead
and do downstream amplification
for gene sequencing.
It sounds like
we will succeed.
We still have a long way to go.
Yes.
We don't have any more questions.
Thank you again
for the wonderful lecture.
Thank you for inviting me.
Thank you.