So after I graduated from university, I think I did an RA, if I remember correctly, at Professor Chen's place, right?
I did it for a year or two
After that, I went to Canada's McMaster to study for my PhD
When I was studying for my PhD, one of the tutors was Dr. Trenner
He was doing a course on music perception and intuition
If you're interested, you can ask him why he chose to do music
or intuition and cognition
I don't know much about intuition, but my impression is that
doing visual psychology takes up a large portion of the work
So why did I decide to do intuition? I think it's interesting
I don't know, it's just my guess
Yongyi has a website, you can go check it out, it's really scary
The publications are as long as ghosts
Other than the publications, there's also awards and media coverage
I think that's really cool
I hope one day I can tell my parents that I'm a journalist
Without further ado, let's welcome Yongyi to share his research with us
I'll turn off my mic so you can hear me
Can you hear me now?
I think it's okay
I'm a little shy
I don't even know if I have to give a score
Today is July 8th, I'm guessing my highest score is 87
I can't go any higher
That's about it
I can predict the results
You have to turn on the audio so you can hear the laughter
I don't think there's any feedback
I think we need feedback
Forget it
It's pretty funny
I'm being encouraged, I'm indeed a person who studies truth psychology
It's different
I'm probably just making things up
I'm not really interested in hearing
There's no deep reason
First of all, I'm very interested in music
I only found out later that most people do visual research
Most people talk about intuition
It's directly implied that it's visual research
I only found out later
If you're doing hearing research
You have to say it's particularly famous for auditory
Otherwise people will get it wrong
It's pretty interesting
I think there are some phenomena in hearing
It's different when it comes to other senses
There are some special problems to deal with
I think that's what makes hearing interesting
It's a special place
Okay, let's get into my presentation
I'm going to start studying how to share my screen
Okay, while you're studying
Let me tell you
Just in case there's feedback
Let me turn off the microphone
If you have anything you want to say
You can type it in
You can also speak
Okay
Let's go
My PhD research topic is
It's very vague
Dynamic Auditory Communication
It's vague
It's about how to change your hearing
In a dynamic situation
How to change your hearing
This includes
For example, you're listening to me now
All my voices change at any time
For example, every time I make a sound
There's a millisecond
And then it disappears
Or listening to music
It's kind of like that
And then
And what I want to share today is
My experiment
From a traditional laboratory
Psychological laboratory
And then do it
More complicated
We think it's closer to the real
Interaction
Under the environment of human interaction
That is
From a small laboratory to a large laboratory
Between each other
There are some research methods
Needs to be adjusted
And then I just want to explain today
Take our research as an example
How do we do this
So my sub-topic is
How do psychologists do research
And there is a step-by-step explanation
Explain
What are the problems we encounter
And then
We think
In our situation
How do we solve it
And then
By the way
Just
Please help everyone
The place is
September
Taiwan's Science and Music Magazine
There will be a
A special special issue of music psychology
And then
I want to put this
Related research
It's a draft
Go over there
As a
A small topic
Just share it
Just as a science book
Share it to readers in Taiwan
Then I didn't write it myself
The experience of doing a science book article
Then if I hope
That is to say
I hope to make today's speech
Into different fields
People interested in science
Can probably
Psychologists
How do we do research
Especially in
In such a special situation
If you think
On the content
Or how to explain
How can it be adjusted better
That is
I hope you can tell me
Then
I will
I'm going to take the exam in two weeks
So thank you very much
If there is any help
OK
it is good
The nonsense should be over
First of all, I want to say
Hearing has many domains
Like for example
You can know if the pitch is high or low
What I want to focus on today is
Focus on time
For hearing
Is a very important thing
In fact, time is for many senses
And the reaction is very important
For hearing
I think it is especially critical
Why
If you record my voice
Then take it to
In the software of the computer
Open it
Look at its radio
Its radio
It looks like
Almost like this
Then you can of course
Decode
That is to say
What is my voice
Then
Our hearing is
We have to put it together
To become a meaningful sentence
Ah
But it's hard for hearing
That is to say
Every message
The time it appears is so short
And
It won't appear again
Ah
Human beings have lived for so long
History
The history of human communication
Before the recorder was invented
We have no chance
Listen again
What happened before
How is it
So human hearing
A big problem
That is to say
We have to be able to catch it quickly
Ah
This message is displayed at any time
And then accurately
Awareness
Feel it accurately
The content of this
Then
And another
More demanding is
That is
We are not just aware of this
And we have to
Make a quick response
For example
When you have a conversation with others
What are you hearing
You will be able to understand immediately
Then immediately
Be able to react
Then this skill
When quarreling
It's particularly important
Because if you slow down
If you slow down
You lost the quarrel
It's very
It's important to speak
Right
So you see
Human beings are like this
No, I'm kidding
That
Not only in conversation
In another situation
For example, you are listening to music
Ah
And for example, you are with
You sing with others
Ah
Sing together
That
I can't just listen to other people's music
Listen to this
I'm going to
Sing my part
Because you are like this
No matter how fast your processing speed is
There must be a time difference inside
That
Ah
So
In fact, in many cases of hearing
We think it is
He keeps
Keep predicting
What's going to happen next
Then let people
Always
Let your intuition
Let your nervous response
Always in a
In a well-prepared situation
Then you can
Precise intuition to this matter
And then
Quickly prepared
To make the next reaction
So I think hearing is on time
Ah
In fact, compared to other sensory domains
Is
More demanding
This is
My task
So I think time is very important to hearing
Ok
If you have any questions
You can interrupt me in the middle
Then if there is no problem
I will continue
Then
By the way because I
Now
I share the screen
So if everyone
If you leave a message in the chat
I should not be able to see it now
So everyone can
Just turn on the microphone
It has nothing to do with me
Ok
Ah
I have a question
Ok
Please say
The
The M-I-N-G-E-R above the waveform
What is that?
Oh, that's just an example I found on the Internet
I don't know what that is
Sorry
Ok
Ok, thank you
It should be a project title
Yes
It looks like this
But I don't know
I haven't searched either
Alright
Maybe it's doing something
Voice
Voice of the computer
Some of the projects handled by the visual
I don't know
Sorry
Then I will talk about it first
In traditional psychology and neuroscience
How do we do this kind of research in the lab
If we want to know
What is the importance of time for hearing
How do we do research
For example
I
I will
Design a series of hearing with a computer
A series of hearing that opens at any time
Then for example
I can
A kind of audio file
I put it
Every note
Bop, bop, bop
All time
Every bop, bop, bop
Between each tone
Its time is fixed
The same length
For example, it's 500 milliseconds
So this way you
It sounds like a decoder
Bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop
Then you can keep going
So this
This is a very regular time
Then you can have a
An irregular time
For example, it's
Between your pain and pain
Can be
For example
Random 250 milliseconds
Between 750 milliseconds
So it might sound like this
Bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop
Just
You don't know at all
You
When will the next pain appear
And then
In this different
Under the circumstances
We can
Require the audience to do some
Intuitive answer
For example, we can make
Some of them have sounds
Most of these sounds
Most of them are exactly the same
There are some sounds
Maybe we'll just make it
It's a little bit higher or a little bit lower
We're on the frequency domain
To make some adjustments
And then the audience
Just
To participate in the experiment
The college student has to listen to that sound
If he hears a higher pitch
He'll press a button
If you hear a lower pitch
Just press a button
It sounds like
Bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop
Bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop
You have to listen to the higher pitch
You have to react
And then the other
Under the circumstances of irregular time
You can also do this kind of manipulation
And then we can go and see
For example
Under the circumstances of regular time
The correct rate of his answer
It's going to be higher
Under the circumstances of irregular time
Then we can
Psychologists usually say
Oh, that's the regular time
It can help you
Have a better sense
Because you're better
Because your accuracy is higher
You can have a more accurate answer
In this case
We can also do some
Neuroscientific measurements
For example, I can measure people's brainwaves
This is a memory map
It's because of the nervous response of the brain
The nervous response of the brain
It's all about the nerve
It's all about the neurotransmitter
To do the reaction
Then we can put those
For example, the ECG map
Or the sensors for measuring muscle position
We'll put it on the scalp
That's because of the nerve response
It's going to be that wave signal
It's going to come out
So we can put it on the surface of the scalp
Record this signal
That's what we call it
The signal of the brainwaves
Then we can do some corresponding analysis
We can see that the brainwaves are
How to capture the regularity of this time
And then for example
Let's do some complicated processing
And then we'll get
Something like this
The answer is
We'll find out, for example
The brainwave
It's going to adjust the speed of its vibration
It's the same as the external stimulus
And then we just have to catch this
In the brain
Imagine the nerve in the brain
It's like a decoder
It's going to be able to accurately capture
How to produce the next second
That's the traditional neuroscience
Or psychologically
We're going to do this
A study of orientation
But this study is actually quite
OK, please go ahead
That's your time
That's the frequency
That cycle
How short can it be
You mean the cycle of my voice
Or the cycle of the brainwaves
The cycle of the voice
And then there's the brainwaves
You're going to adjust it
If it's the same as your external
Does it have a limit
This is a good question
Usually humans can catch the beat
The shortest is the shortest between pain and pain
It's 200 milliseconds
I can't sing so fast
It's about the same speed
More than 200 milliseconds
You probably think
It's almost a continuous sound
That's the slowest
It's the longest between pain and pain
It can be as long as 1,200 milliseconds
1.2 seconds
After that
You'll feel like every sound is independent
You don't think it's a continuous rhythm
You just can't
Know the pattern
What's interesting is that the brainwaves
Can only catch up
Such a speed range
It's slower than this
Or faster than this
There's no way
As for what causes what
I don't know
It's because the brain can't move so fast
Move so slow
To make us instinctively
Can't catch up so fast
Such a slow speed
I don't know
I can only say
This is what we have now
Thank you
Hello
So I'd like to ask
When you do this experiment
Do you have to eliminate
Other noise interference?
That's right
We do this kind of experiment
Because we want to be clean
So we do it in the soundproof room
And then we'll use headphones
That is, we'll use those
More special headphones
Just send the sound
Into the ear
And it's very close
The more inside, the better
And then the sound is transmitted
It's all very clean
I just want to reduce
External interference
That's right
So when you say
The so-called hearing
It means
Human beings
We can really
The sound we hear
Or include that
Include that
The frequency we can't hear
It's also in the hearing
For example, ultrasonic waves or
Very low frequency
That kind
That kind of hearing
That's what you're asking
That is to say
Physical stimulation
Does it stimulate psychological feelings?
That's what we say
Will ask questions like this
Of course
Of course there are people
Study such a question
That is to say
Where is the limit of human hearing?
Then you can see
Where is the limit of frequency?
But this is not me
Today
Is the main part of the discussion
Maybe we'll wait
Discuss again later
Like this
I don't know if it's like this
Or just
You can discuss it casually
No no no
Because of me
I'm more curious
When you say you want to eradicate
That interference
When noise interference
That's how you eradicate that kind
We don't know at all
The kind of interference we hear
For example, like ultrasonic waves
You are in that
What is that called
There is no noise at all
That kind of interference
In that kind of experimental environment
You can't guarantee
He won't be affected by the outside world
OK OK OK
Then I know
Of course we
What we do is
We already know
Human hearing frequency range
It's about 20 Hz to 20,000 Hz
In the frequency range of this Hz
We
In fact, in the experimental environment
Can still measure
In the case of measurement
We will make a comparison
As for ultrasonic waves
We generally think it's human
Physically, you can't hear it
So
So we don't care about his control
So for example
There is an ultrasonic wave in the lab
The sound of the ultrasonic wave
Or that kind of very, very, very high frequency
We don't care
So it's based on an assumption
Those things won't cause
It won't cause too much interference to humans
Yes, it really won't
And the other thing is
In the case of our experiments
We don't say
One condition is to make a trial
Of course we will do hundreds of trials
Thousands of trials
Even if there is an effect
As long as it is with your experiment
The program set by the computer
If it's not related to each other
Then the effect we observe
These external effects
It should be reduced a lot
OK, thank you
Then
Hey, copy it
That is to say
What about this POP process
Of course you can decide for yourself
See if you want to say
To accept the middle question
Or ask at the end
Or open the discussion directly
You can decide
Then but
That is
We
The prediction is that you can
You can talk for about an hour
And then
There will probably be a 20-minute discussion
Ah
That's it
As for you
Cut it in half
Or mixed together
How do you decide
Just decide for yourself
OK OK OK
OK
Let me tell you first
I actually didn't prepare a lot of POP
I only prepared about 18 pages
So
So the topic part will be finished in a moment
If there are some related topics
Sorry, I just didn't know what your question was
If it's related to listening or other music
We can wait until then to discuss
That if it has to do with the topic I'm talking about
Of course we will raise it and discuss it live
Sorry, I just didn't know what your question was
With this
Where is the thing I'm talking about now
OK
Well
But
OK, I will continue
I think the biggest problem in doing research in the lab
Is that
If what we want to know is
How people interact with each other normally
For example, interacting with each other by listening
But in fact, the two kinds of information
Time-regulated and time-unregulated
This kind of experiment
The information I made in my computer
It doesn't exist in the natural world
In the natural world
You won't hear a
Such accurate information like a decoder
A completely random message
You usually hear
A little regular
But it's not that regular
So if I do research like this
What does it do to understand my human
What is the real ability to help
In fact, sometimes it is a bit biased
So
In fact, there is a very interesting paper
It was just published recently
It's called Neuroscience Needs Behavior
If you are interested in
Related philosophy, scientific philosophy
If you are interested
I highly recommend this paper
Then I will use the few pictures in it
To talk about
This research
The limitations of laboratory research
Generally, we want to know
It can be said
For example, the neural pattern of the human brain
What is the relationship between natural behavior
Then you can take the neural pattern
As a
For example, the psychological process
The psychological inner process can also be
This is what we want to know
Then a better designed ideal experiment
That is to say
We can control
We know which part of the psychological process
Or neural response
Corresponding to some of our natural behaviors
We can have one-to-one
Is the correspondence of one-to-one
Or a simpler correspondence
But like the experiment we just did
In fact, the experiment just now
Is the experiment I did
I did it myself
Um, we
I actually designed an experiment
The situation is
Humans are generally
It's not going to happen
Then we are studying his neural response
Although we can know
The relationship between these
But we can't answer directly
What is human nature
We can't answer
Human natural reaction
So what we know is
Some humans
Supernormal ability
It's beyond his usual ability
but
Our main research topics
In fact, there is no direct understanding
This is what I think
Laboratory research
Some big limitations
Especially in other areas
There is such a situation
For example
If you want to manipulate social interaction
You are in a very small laboratory
Basically can't do this
Because our lab
Basically looks like this
Just a person
Sitting in a small space
Because we have to
Like I just said
Must control all external stimuli
So
I often sit alone inside
In a very quiet situation
Interact with the computer
Then at the same time because
Uh, our measuring tool
For example, uh, uh, uh
That side brain wave
The length of the line
He can only sit there
He can't do anything
He can only use two fingers to react
So actually this is also
Very unnatural
Then this is some
Traditional laboratory environment
Some restrictions given
OK
Come here
Everyone agrees that there are actually quite a lot of restrictions
Then I
What I want to say is
Then we
In our laboratory
How do we try to go
Uh, extend to solve
Such a barrier
Uh, what I want to say first is
Music can be a good research tool
It can be a research tool
As a
Uh, to help study human mind activities
And neural reactions
He
Uh, there are some very good ways
For example, I can keep
There is a good experimental situation
For example, today I
For example, look at this A picture on the far left
I can ask the subject
Ask someone to come in
Then I'll give him a beater
I asked him
Press the key of the piano
Then the speed of pressing is exactly the same as the beater
Then this is a
A good control experiment
Then I can put this
The conditions I control are getting more and more relaxed
For example
I can ask
The computer generates a beater
But this beater is
At the speed of your pressing keys
Then he will go
Follow your speed
To change his own rhythm
Or you can say
Let two people play together
Multiple people play
Even in the case of multiple people playing
You and the audience are listening at the same time
That
Moving more and more to the right of the score
That's what we call ecological interaction
Interaction
Ecological validity
That is to say, what you are studying
Is
Can correspond to human
In the case of real life
The more right-handed
That's what we think
More like real life
Because when you play music
You will also have an audience listening
This can be understood
But on the right side of the score
In fact, your experimental control
It's getting worse and worse
So for example
When a group of people play music
If they decide together
To speed up or slow down
What do you want
This is not your experiment
Things that can be decided in advance
The information you get in the end
It will be difficult for you to explain
That music can be a good tool
Just because he can
Get some kind of balance in the middle
For example, when the two of them interact
They may not be random
Play the music they want
I can give him a score
Ask them to play according to the score
And if they have
If they play the wrong note
In fact, we can
From the recording afterwards
To find out about this
So we can know
What did he do wrong
I can also know
What is the correct answer
And we can set
That is to say
What is the rhythm he wants to play
So we still have some control
But even under these conditions
Their activities
Still very
An activity that is very close to human behavior
So we think music
Can be a good tool
To study human interaction
But there is also auditory communication
And it can balance
Experimental control and ecological efficiency
These two big problems
And another advantage of music is
You said music is a good research tool
The reason is
It sounds like it's because he can be
That is, he can have this
From experimental control
To ecological interaction
The whole spectrum
But then you think
What research tool
Um
How to research
Is there no such thing as language?
Language, can you
Yeah, so I think I don't really understand
That's why he's a special
Good research tool
I didn't say he was particularly good
I said he could be a good research tool
OK, good
So I understood this time
What you mean is
He can span the whole spectrum
Language is of course
You can communicate with the computer
Language communication
Or the language between people
Communicate with others
Yes, language is also a good research tool
My language is on
There is a difficulty in neuroscience
Because when you want to talk
Mouth to move
And then actually
It's a bit difficult to measure signals
Of course, this is an externalization
But I think language is also a
It's still a good tool
I understand
I didn't say music is the best
He is one of them
And then
And another advantage of music is
He is a special one
A special activity
But in fact, in each culture
There are music activities
And humans actually spend
Spend a lot of resources
In music activities
A lot of time and resources
So we think
Research on music activities
In fact, it can also be
He is a reflection of a human being
A very basic behavior
With a capability
OK
So
So you say music is a good research tool
It means
For example, you want to measure his brain
How does the brain work
You just play music for them
Is it similar to this
Is this a research method
Play music for them
Or let them
Let them play music
So that means
You can have a
A spectrum
You can go from the far left
Play music for them
I have already designed this music in advance
All the way to the far right
For example, you can
Interact with the music
For example, singing karaoke
Or if there is no music
Two people play music with each other
OK
Everyone has a question
I have a simple question
It's like this
Because it's said here
We may start from here
More and more
About music as a
Research tool
So I want to clarify
A simple question
What we are discussing now is
Sound is a good research tool
Or music is a
A specific
There is a clear subset
In the sound
Or are we discussing
Sound as a research tool
I would say it's music
Because
If I talk about sound
It's just a definition
Because
Because sound
Can you repeat your question?
Yes, so my question is actually
You are talking about music
A good research tool
What kind of sound
Don't you think it's
You want to use it as
The definition of music
Research tool
I understand
Yes
I forgot to say before
In fact, in traditional research
In terms of listening
We will use computer synthesis
That's a very
It's like you pick up the phone
To hear that kind of sound
Or more than that
A lot of noise
These things
We all know
Basic listening
Materials used
But in general
We don't use
That kind of material
And then we
And
In addition
When we study listening
Often we will present
A completely unchanging sound
A complete array
For example, show it for one second
But in the natural world
All the sounds
It's probably the first time
It's gone
It won't have the same stimulus
Repeat repeat
And music
It has another component
That is, it has
More social interaction
It's not just about making sounds
It's not just about making
I'm going to knock on the table today
Make a sound
Instead, people will
According to your voice
And then he has a response
And then he makes a new action
Does that answer the question?
Yes yes
Thank you
OK OK
OK
Everyone's questions are very good
That
In our study
The example is
We want to understand
Play with music
As an example of a model
Is a model of social interaction
How do we measure cooperation
And then we have to understand
Is the relationship between the leader and the follower
And then we have to
What direction to go
To do this research
Ah this photo
Is a photo of our lab
Then I just found
We have a short film before the lab
OK
Show it to everyone
I hope everyone can hear the sound
Uh, there's a two and a half minute introduction
String quartet
Is just as exciting and challenging
Canadian cellist Adrian Fung
And his colleagues are fitted with
Specially designed caps and sensors
You put them in front of your shirt
And wired to monitors
That measure their brain activity and heart rate
Motion capture cameras
Record their movements too
Researchers are studying
How the musicians communicate with each other
During a performance
Without using a single word
How do they use movements
What gestures do the musicians make
That make it possible for them
To communicate with each other
And to communicate with members of the audience
They're all wired up too
To study how they respond
Physically and emotionally
To the performers on stage
What's great about this
Is it affords us the ability
To see how effective we are as communicators
The theatre is state-of-the-art technology
Including a sound system
With incredible acoustics
Here with just a tap on a tablet
I'll make it extremely reverberant in here
Sort of like a cathedral
The room is transformed
A cool feature that serves
A wider, more scientific purpose
One that could help researchers
Design a better hearing aid
For the hearing impaired
So, ratting
Ratting
Background noise is coming out of all the speakers
It's a multi-channel surround mix
And then we can test how well
Does a person with a hearing aid
Comprehend speech
That's presented to them
In an environment like this
Instead of in the quiet room
But for now
Most of the research is focused on music
And its therapeutic powers
Researchers hope their findings
Will uncover how some rhythms
Might help an autistic child
Or why a musical beat
Can improve the gait of a patient
With Parkinson's disease
In order to understand
What's going on in the brain
We need to know how it's done
In typical populations
Once we understand that
And we know that music
Can help people with Parkinson's
Or we know that music has an effect
On children with autism
We can start to understand
The deep reasons for that
We can perfect the therapies
That we give these people
And add to mounting evidence
That music is good medicine
For the brain
Cass Roossey, CBC News, Toronto
Can everyone hear the sound
From the video?
Yes, we can
We are lucky
Our lab
Has built a music room
With the same size
With a stage
And a seat for the audience
And those can be adjusted
So in general
Just like just now
Sorry, I don't know who asked
In general
We can't control a lot of environmental factors
But in this case
We can let a large space
To be controlled
And in this space
We can do some precise measurements
And experiments
So our lab
Can solve the trade-off
Between experimental control
And eco-efficient
A little bit
So this research
Is done in this situation
And you can see
The situation of this bottle
You can see
There is a ball
It is a motion capture marker
We can use the camera
To capture the red light
And we can build
The body movement
And the time
And the location
So when we measure
The image will look like this
It is a 3D image
It is the body movement
It is the shoulder
It is the right arm
And the head
So our research is
Can we use
The easiest index
Like the body movement
To understand
The human interaction
And the leader
And the follower
We want to start
From the easiest
And the simplest
So there are some questions
If we want to do anything
We do something
The body must have a lot of movements
Like playing music
We can start from the simple
For example
If I play the piano
I can study the simple movements
Like the time
The difference between the time
And the person
We can see
The difference between the time
And the person
But there is a big problem
When we do this research
The time of each player
Is affected by the music
And the music
So even if we measure
The result
We can only see
The music
And the performance
We can't measure the actual
Interaction
This is a limitation
Another interesting signal
We can measure
The whole body movement
For example
The body movement
Is not only in the music
But also in the daily conversation
If you measure
The body movement
The index
Is the addition of the whole body movement
For example
If I raise my arm
My body needs to lean back
To balance the center
Otherwise you will fall
Another interesting thing
The music itself
Doesn't require you to move your body
When you talk
But people will naturally do this
So it's not limited to the music
It's not limited to
What you do
What you say
It's something that happens naturally
So it may reflect
A psychological process
We think it can be a good index
So
The first problem is
We decide to measure
The whole signal
Don't just measure the finger
The other problem is
We know what to measure
How do we use
Traditionally
We get this time series signal
We can see the relationship
Between the two signals
We call it cross correlation
A big limitation of cross correlation
Is that it can only tell you
How similar the two signals are
But if today
In the case of interaction
Usually there will be a leader
For example, four people move chairs together
There must be a person shouting slogans
Now 321 everyone moves together
So if we want to know
Social interaction
The direction of social interaction is also important
But cross correlation analysis
Can't tell you the result
The other analysis is
Granger causality
It was originally invented by economists
A mathematical method
It mainly reflects
A time series signal
To what extent
To predict
A time series signal
If it can predict
We can say
The first time series
It can affect time series B
But it doesn't matter
There are many
Methodological disputes
But we have to say
We can measure
How much of the first series
Can predict the second series
We can
Reflect the direction of message transmission
So we think
Granger causality is more than traditional
Related measurement
Is to provide more human
Interaction
So now we know what to measure
Then we know
How to analyze
The third question is what they want to do
We just play music
If so
We just observe
Scientific research
We need to separate
What we are interested in
And what we naturally observe
We need to know
Will it affect our observation
This is to understand
What we are interested in
So on the stage
They will do
This is just a summary
It will have front and back movements
We have to measure this
Then we want it to play
Bach's Hymn
And while playing
We did one thing
It's a little different from normal music
We will randomly point
One of the people as the leader
Usually in the case of music
For example, rock band
The lead singer is usually the leader
Everyone has to follow the speed of the lead singer
Follow the volume of the lead singer
To make adjustments
It's the same in the case of music
Usually the first violin is the leader
But in Bach's Hymn
The advantage of this piece is
The relationship between the leader and the follower
So when we do experiments
We tell them in addition
For example
We only play the violin today
For example, the third row
You are the leader today
You are going to lead the other three people
To play this music
And while we are playing this music
In order to
Close to natural interaction
So they play this music
They have never rehearsed before
This is the first time I saw this score
Then they played for the first time
Then ask them to interact
And we
When we point out who is the leader
We also give him a note
Everyone can only see their own role
If you are the leader, of course you know you are the leader
But if you are a follower
Then you can only know that one of them is the leader
Then I have to try to find
Who is the leader and then I have to follow him
It's a bit like a guessing game
OK
This is the part of our experiment
We experiment on the society
Who is the leader
Who is the follower
Then we hope
If our measurement is effective
It should be able to reflect
We follow the leader
A relationship of such manipulation
It should be able to reflect our experimental manipulation
OK
So the information we get is like this
Their body movements
Then for example, the relationship between the first step of the violin and the second step of the violin
Then according to the measure
That is to say
The first violin
How much to predict the second violin
This body movement
Then in the case of the four-axis
We have 12
The direction of possible message transmission
This is the direction of all message transmission
Then
Through our experimental manipulation
For example, we are in a piece of music
We call the first violin
It says V1 on it
Then
So the direction of these three messages
It will be the relationship between the leader and the follower
The opposite direction is
The relationship between the follower and the leader
Then the rest of the direction
Is the relationship between the follower and the follower
OK
Then I just use English to put it
Leader follower follower
So that means we
Through the manipulation of this experiment
Everyone of us
Interactive relationship between them
Different situations
Then if we are in the next situation
For example, if the second violin is the leader
Then all the colors of these arrows
Will exchange
Is there a problem here?
This is the more complicated part of the experimental manipulation
I want to ask
You just said that
What is the tune of the performance
I don't know about music, but what is it?
That means
Does it already exist in this world?
That's right
We let him find something to do
Will it be like this?
For example, these four people
Someone in particular
I've known this song for a long time
Then it will affect the results of the study
This is a good question
So we are special
Special is that we have confirmed with the musicians
They haven't played these songs
It's the first time
Then these musicians
We are looking for more professional musicians
So they got these songs for the first time
They can start cooperating right away
OK, thank you
This is a good question
This reviewer also asked
Then the next thing is
Get the result of our experiment
The three points on the X-axis are different situations
Then the Y-axis is
The strength of Grand Jack Casualty
The higher the Y-axis
The higher the Y value
The stronger the transmission in this direction
Then this is the result of the experiment
You can see it
You can see it from here
From the leader to the follower
Their information
The amount of transmission is the highest
It's the highest compared to other situations
OK, this is a
The statistics show that
And then we have another one
The manipulation is to say that they are playing
Can you see other people
We found that
This effect is relatively strong
But even if you can't see it
Even if it's just playing music
There is no visual information
You don't know what other people are doing
You see what other people are doing
You still have this effect
OK
This is our main finding of the experiment
Basically it means
The overall action can reflect the direction of information transmission
Then see the other person
Will this
This communication is helpful
OK
This is the first result
The second result is
Sorry, you say
I see your
Non-seeing condition
I can't speak Chinese
Follower
This is the difference between FL and FF
There is a difference in dark gray
Is there any difference in light gray?
No
Oh
This is quite interesting
This means
Leader actually ignores
Not affected by Follower
Relative to the relationship between Follower and Follower
That's what it means
And this is only in non-seeing
Follower and Follower
Need to coordinate with each other
But the leader doesn't need to adapt to Follower
It will look like this
But this is only
In non-seeing
An obvious effect
The experience of non-seeing
Maybe
Make some noise
Make it more difficult
Not to be affected by Follower
Of course this needs to be replicated
This is a small difference
Or did you analyze the interaction?
Did you find it
Sorry
Your
There is no difference between the two white bars
There is a difference between the two dark gray bars
Is there any difference in this difference?
No
I looked at all the interactions
OK
Thank you
You're welcome
We actually replicated this thing
But you just said
The difference between the two dark gray bars
Actually did not appear in the replication
So
We didn't explain too much on paper
What is the reason
Not very clear
But basically it can be found
The body movement can reflect the direction of information transmission
Reflect the direction of information transmission
But I don't think this is very interesting
Because
What does this have to do with playing music?
Just a bunch of people moving around in the studio
Who moves first
Then we
In fact, after they play every song
We ask musicians to use a scale
To evaluate how well you feel
Then
We asked him to evaluate three items
What is the overall quality of the performance?
1 to 5 points
Then the synchronization of time
Is it very synchronized?
Then the difficulty of the cooperation
Is there a difference?
Then we go to them
The amount of Granger Casualty
To do
Then we found
This X axis is
For example, here is very good
The far right is very good
Then the Y axis is
Basically
The overall amount of information exchange
Then we found
In fact, the quality of this performance
With causal density
With the amount of information exchange
The coupling of body movements
Is related
Then there is also some correlation with the synchronization of time
But in my second time
Replication
Only the overall quality of the performance is related
So that is
The amount of information transfer
This body movement
Not only reflects the direction of information transfer
Then the amount of information transfer
It seems to be with the quality of cooperation
Can reflect their quality of cooperation
So that is
Summarize what we learned
That is to say
Learned in a multi-person cooperation environment
Can be observed from the body movement
Direction of information transfer
Then even if this is a
Listening and action-based homework
But can you visually see the other person
It seems to be a very important communication channel
Then the overall action
Information flow
By measuring the body movement
The amount of information activity can reflect the quality of cooperation
Then
In fact, these three points
For everyone
In fact, if you don't do research, you will probably get this result
Then we think the biggest value
That is to say, we actually provide
A very low-threshold research method
As long as you don't have to be in our
Such a laboratory for observation
You can observe in any natural situation
You can use imaging analysis
To observe their
Physical actions between people
You may be able to observe in a natural situation
The group behavior between people
We are just in a better and more precise
Under the control of the laboratory
Prove that this effect should exist
Should be an effective index
Then I think that is
Provided may follow-up researchers
If you want to study complex social behavior
At least
He may now have a tool
I have a question
Sorry
You said
I don't understand the second point
The third point is the second point
I thought the result was
If they are facing each other
So in the absence of
This result is still the same
Still have
But its effect is weaker
Then
There is a main effect
Simple main effect
Leader to follower
In this direction
See each other
Much better than not seeing each other
But
In fact, both sides are still effective
So this is my
The third question is
What is the direction of causal relationship?
For example
This
This communication channel is because of
Communication on music
Caused your body to move like this
Following
Or your body moves like this
Caused the progress of music
Because if
If you can't see your body now
Body sway or follow each other
It means that it is not visual communication at all
Is hearing
Or the essence of music
Caused by
Natural body reaction
Is a real cause
I didn't say it was a cause
I just said it was a reaction
Indicator
I said it was
When we play music
Actually don't need
Body to do this action
But we still do
Then this information seems to reflect
Direction of information transmission
And the quality of its cooperation
So you don't think
It is functional
It's just a indicator
It's just a indicator that you can measure
I'm conservative
I don't know
I can't prove it yet
There are other studies
Some people are
Block the whole person
Then measure their time
The time difference between each other's buttons
It is true that the time difference between the buttons
Will affect
But I think
The conclusion is
My current research
My current results can only say
It can be reflected
Maybe it's just a related indicator
But its function
Is it part of the communication itself
Is it that I want to see other people's body movements
Or part of it
I don't know about this
Because like you said
Even if you can't see it, the body movements have this effect
Understand
I have another question with Zhang Ting
But it's not directly
About your research itself
But we want something very interesting from your research
If we
This Baja
Because you just emphasized
Its four characters are actually relative
What is that called
Responsibility is more average
So you can randomly assign who you are
But if we change it to jazz four beats
That kind of character is very strong
You expect
The effect size will become very strong
Or will they break down
Because they don't know who they are
Suppose you don't assign
I know
This is our experiment 2
Actually we
We also did it
I didn't post it today, but this is experiment 2
In the case of experiment 2
We don't have that kind of jazz four beats
We want them to play
Mozart's music
If you look at the score
All the melodies are in the first minor
The other parts are just beats
But we still do exactly the same
Even if we say the cello is just beat
You still have to lead the cello
To play his music
So this is basically the same as you think
The result is
I go back to the previous slide
This is what I just said
Replication
There are still three lines above
The following three lines are gone
So we are in a task
Is an unbalanced starting point
We do manipulation
Still see the above effects
But he is actually weak overall
Then we measure
That is to say
In the case of bassline
Is the strength of the grunge causality between each other
How much
We found that in the case of playing Mozart's music
The bassline is more uneven
In the case of playing Bach
The bassline is average
This is the effect of this bassline
This effect
It actually shows that this is functional
Because you are in the case of non-sync
When this music itself
When there is no such message
When this music itself has an obvious bias
It's hard for you to have one
For example, in the case of a cello
Without seeing your body
But
When you see
It still produces an effect
It means he is
Link
I suddenly feel like I'm talking about
Because although
But we didn't
But the music itself is also
Actually explained
Then we
I think it's a bit difficult
difficult
I think even if there is such a difference
Just say there is this possibility
But answer the question directly
For example, I tied the musician
Tied to the chair
I can't move
This is a direct manipulation
Do you agree with me
I don't know, I can't figure it out
I have to think about it
That is to say, I can't let you move today
See if the quality of your performance will be reduced
You obviously have a lot of barriers
You can't do that
I'm still thinking
The evidence just now is not enough
He seems to be able to prove
You still find this body
The reaction is related to the cause and effect
Follower
This is related to the leader
But the cause and effect of this relationship does not mean
Music performance
Cause and effect between body sway
So it's not a good evidence
Have you always been like this
I'm a little confused
I'm also confused
When we wrote the paper
In fact, different authors are thinking
Some authors argue directly
Body sway is communication
But
I don't think you have that evidence
I think the evidence is not direct
Then I'll be safe
Then discuss
But I don't know
I think there are two causal relationships
One causal relationship is the body sway of the leader
Causing the body sway of the follower
This is the analysis you are doing now
As long as the bar on your left is higher
It means that this causality exists
But
You finish first
But another causal relationship
Music communication
Causal relationship between body sway
Is body sway
Is the cause of music communication
The first point
About grunge causality
I guess many listeners may know
It is actually argued
Causality is a big problem
Mathematically
It can only say
The amount of information transfer
Is there really a cause?
There must be some other situations
For example, I have to sample
The whole universe
And you have to assume
Anyway, there are some situations
Anyway, it's conservative
Mathematically, I can only say
A predict B
Can't say A cause B
You can say causality
Because it is the difference in time
This message leads to this message
What other factors do you have in body sway
Will lead to this change
There may be a third reason for music
In short, I think
Alternative is limited
Not any possible hypothesis
These alternatives sound
Not very
Not very convincing
So I think even if it's a bit risky
You can still argue
But on the other hand
What you really care about is
Body movement response
Is this message
Is it music communication itself
Does it cause better music quality
Is it a good communication
This sound
But this seems to need other evidence
That's right
I'm conservative
I think you are conservative
My bubble is gone
So everyone is welcome to discuss freely
It doesn't matter
I would like to ask you this experiment
You are talking about this experiment now
For example, how many groups do you want to do
Is a group
Or how many musicians
There is a way to get one
Is relatively unrecognized
For example, the culture of the performer
Or the level of training of the performer
Is less disturbed by this aspect
OK, I think you asked this question very well
I think this is the weakness of this study
Because first of all
We are looking for very high-level musicians
That is, you have to pay a lot of money
The kind of concert to buy a ticket
They will come
Because of the financial restrictions
We found two groups
In terms of statistical methods
We think it's better to say
We are all
We call it within subject comparison
Compare yourself to yourself
That is, in the case of yourself
How much stronger is this effect
So even if
The sample we took
Is very limited, that is, two groups of musicians
A total of eight people
But within each person
Their direction of effect is consistent
Is it possible
I took some very biased samples
For example, these musicians do not represent all humans
It is possible
This is the weakness of this study
How high is this representation
I do not know
I can only say from other current studies
Musicians and normal humans
The representation is actually
It can represent
Ordinary human beings
Other cultures
This is also a matter of representation
It is also said that the representation is still OK
It's just that I don't have direct evidence
Say this effect
Can it represent the effect of all humans
I don't know
Is it conservative
It's okay
I have a question
You ask first, you finish first
It's okay, my next question has nothing to do with this
So you can continue to ask other questions
You mentioned quarreling at the beginning
But quarreling
It doesn't seem to be sung
I want to know
It can also be sung
So I want to ask
The question is
The results are already here
How big do you think it is
How big can it be
Let us predict
Or provide us
Language communication
Knowledge
What kind of implications
If there are some
Weaknesses
Where it can't be inferred
Some research that may need to be supplemented
What will it be
To the part of speech
OK
First of all
About body movements
Most of the research is actually done in the case of speech
But what they do is
In a small lab
Two people
Use relevant methods
That
There are other research around
In fact
Music performance and speech
The psychological process they use
Actually very similar
Then we are equal to
In the case of music, we also observed
This body movement
Of course it's not exactly the same effect
Extend out
But the effect is the same
Effect
Although there is no direct evidence
But I think
This effect should be in speech
It should be exactly the same
This is my guess
Thank you
I have a related question
Can you plug in
Is there a lottery number
Someone said he had a problem
I'm afraid I won't keep plugging in
I asked too many questions
You just said language
In fact, I think
More broadly
Do you think these are all
Is it the phenomenon of hearing?
Or is it actually a wider perception
Or is it a new way of operation
Or is it
Specific to the phenomenon of hearing
For example, the experiment you just started is regularity
Decide
You can anticipate
How to deal with sensory information
Obviously this is also the case in vision
Then there is your current music
The communication of cooperation
Is it really due to the performance of music
Or all the cooperation
All the cooperation
For example, the table you just raised
There are all the same phenomena
Does the sway of the body also affect
Or there are some more general mechanisms
For example, any synchrony
Any synchronicity
Will help communicate
Can you remind me again
What is the first part
I thought it was all examples
The main question is
Do you think this is a domain-specific phenomenon
Specific to the phenomenon of hearing
Or is it a broader
New way of operation
I don't need a standard answer
I'm just curious
Curious about my idea
According to other studies
Actually found
Like this kind of time synchrony
For hearing
It's still a bit different from vision
Like
The sense of rhythm of vision
In fact, it is relative to hearing
Is quite difficult to trigger
The accuracy of his track time
No
It seems that the results are not so high
But someone has succeeded
Someone has succeeded
Vision still has this effect
In fact, it may not be the same
The domain of hearing
Obviously frequency and time
But in vision
It will be space and location
So
Translated, it becomes
Like statistical learning
If there is a fixed pattern
Can't speak Chinese
Repeatedly appear
Your processing will be faster and better
More accurate
Is this a similar phenomenon?
Or there is a specialized
Some
Processing in the brain
Processing in different areas
I think the special process
Because time is one dimension
Although
It is a single direction
But you are always
To the future
That
For example
Visual
This pattern
This pattern is not the same
But it must be future-oriented
Based on your existing knowledge
You keep guessing
What is the future information
And it is online processing
So
I think these details
Let time
For hearing
The requirements become
Different from other senses
Because his information is open at any time
Let me give you an example
Visual phenomenon
Also belongs to
Temporal anticipation
For example
You should know this experiment
Three
Three random sounds
Combination
This is the first time
Language learning
For example, there are nine possible
Tones
These things
Three
Always stuck together
Always a pair
These sentences
Can be combined
But in fact
If you use visual stimulation
Do the same experiment
All the results are the same
This is also a future
Processing from the past and online
Anticipation for the future
Affect your intuition
I know
In each special case
Some cases are replicated
But there are many cases
It's hard to do
For example, the effect of rhythm
Temporal grouping
I know you have done it in the lab
But their citation
In fact, you can see
A lot of people failed
But it doesn't matter
I know I have done that multisensory
I know it's hard
It's super simple
You just need to present four tones
People will know
So you mean
It has a domain-specific part
Extract
Temporal regularity
What do you think
About regularity
What do you think is different
What is the difference between auditory regularity and visual regularity
I think
I think the effect is the same
But maybe in processing
In the very early stage of hearing
Will start to deal with this matter
You will be in
Temporal coding
But visual
You may want to
Where domain
I'm not sure
The later process will deal with
This message
These mechanisms
That's why it's so noisy
For example
I don't know if it will affect auditory
Because of these phenomena
So auditory and visual
Basically there is a difference
Ok
I've been standing for too long
Can I guess
It's over, please say
I read a article before
He said
This is a new one
He said if the stimulation material
The trigger material is used
Language or
Sound is the hearing
Trigger material
That
The subject
The abstract
Will be higher
Later he described this material
And so on
He will use a more abstract and psychological distance
To describe
Relative to visual stimulation material
I don't know this
Processing
Listening to music
Music and language
Are close
Relative to visual stimulation
Because
Take the initiative to do
Prediction
It feels like
My feeling is to be abstract
When it's higher
I will do it
Because if it's very concrete
Isn't it just
Just accept input
You don't have to guess
Or is it like this
I don't know
But
I really don't know
I don't know how to do it
I don't know
I really don't know
Hello
I just said I don't know
Sorry
Okay
Do you have any questions?
Someone is chatting
Okay
Can I ask a question?
Please
I was thinking
If you
When the musicians come
You tell them on purpose
Three of you
Follow and one is leader
Now you are saying
When you are doing it
You give them two leaders and two followers
To see their
Will they fight?
Yes
Actually we did this experiment
Our condition
Is called
Bitch I'm the leader
We
We originally thought
When your leadership assignment
Is a conflict
How do we
Choose a leader
Then
That person becomes the leader
We originally wanted to see this
But the result of the experiment
We found that only when
Everyone can see each other
And everyone is assigned as followers
To solve this conflict
To be able to
At first everyone's coordination was bad
But after a while
Only when everyone is followers
And can see each other
To solve this
In other cases
For example, everyone is the leader
Or can't see each other
They can't solve it
So we call it bitch I'm the leader
Okay
Have you ever tried
Without a leader
For example
If you tell them
One person is the follower
One person is the leader
But no one gets the leader
That's right
We just said
Everyone is the follower
And can see each other
When no one is the leader
And they play
Gradually
Information flow
But only in a quartet
Only in Bach
In Mozart
If it's not balanced
It doesn't work
So we think
If everyone is the follower
Everyone follows Poussin
Follow Poussin
Once they find this conflict
Just follow Poussin
At the same time
After each performance
They have to guess who is the leader
They were forced to choose the other three
Even if they are all followers
You have to guess who
I think they are too good
After the performance
They wrote on the answer sheet
No leader
They were not fooled by us
So this part
The conclusion is not clear
And we avoid
In order to have no leader
In the case of no leader
Or in the case of all leaders
They will conflict at the beginning
Two seconds before the performance
We play the beat
Before the performance
The beat is removed
So they just have to follow the beat
So there will be no problem
Does anyone have any questions?
I have a question
If I understand correctly
You do this experiment with music
Because I hope this experiment can be close to
Social interaction
But in human interaction
For example, there are leaders and followers in group behavior
This often depends on
Personal characteristics
Personality
These things
In music, they have been closely trained
They may be able to express their personality
Their desire
Then follow the music
So they can't react to human society
Personal characteristics affect interaction
Do you think this will affect
Your research results
How to cover this part
I think these questions are too good
I can only say
In this case, this is also a weakness of our research
Because we are looking for a group
We are not
Go out and find two violin
Put them together
In this case, we can
For example, we look for
For example, a very strong first violin
Or a very strong cello
Then look at the relationship between their personalities
Relationship
Then see how they
What effect will this experiment have
I don't know about this, Zhang Yanping can do an experiment
You can come to us
I can only say that this is indeed a weakness of our research
Our research is currently
As a personality effect
We didn't study
We just don't look at it
Answer
I think
In your experiment
You have assigned leadership
Can't you argue
To a certain extent
Do you operate such a personality
Because when a person gets
When this assignment
To a certain extent
That person
Is a strong personality
Of course, people who are not so strong
May not be able to get so much
But in general
That person
Should be taken out
It seems
Right, this must be understood
I don't understand this
That's right
This leader
The operation of the follower is our experiment
I think it is
In a more unnatural situation
Just like the previous question
In general, everyone is
According to the personality
Then we experiment to manipulate
As for the effect of the operation and its original personality
I don't know
Just say we manipulate
It seems to be
In everyone
We still see
Even if I am the leader
I can influence others
The level of predicting others
Higher
Thank you
Do you have any questions?
We designed 10 experiments
To continue, right?
Not bad
Then we have to hang the author
Hang the author
Who will help me run the experiment?
Canada is a bit cold
Caltech is now 100 degrees
Almost hot
It's already 4.24
Then we officially
Come here
If you have any questions
Or want to continue with Andrew
Future interaction
Please remember to fill in the feedback form
You can leave your contact information
To YongYi
Then we will help you get it
Thank you
Especially the comment part
If there is a comment
Welcome
I think
I think it's good
And you turned to Chinese
Everyone is laughing
I was practicing 20 minutes before the speech
I can't speak a word of Chinese
I'm starting to chat now
So if you want to leave
You can leave
Because I
I talked about it in Taiwan University two months ago