Oh, it's started.
Okay, let's start.
Let's give a round of applause.
Wait a minute.
Do I have to share my screen with you?
Yes, you have to share your screen.
I'll turn off my own screen.
Okay.
You have to share your screen.
Let's take a look.
You should be able to choose your screen.
You can choose the one you want to share.
You can share the one you want to share.
Okay.
I'll turn off my screen.
Can everyone see it?
Okay.
The sound is pretty clear.
First of all, thank you, Yen Ping,
for introducing my past experience.
And then,
today, I mainly want to...
From the past to the present,
most of the time, I've been doing
air pollution analysis
and air pollution model
analysis
to understand some air pollution
in the atmosphere
and how it is from
emissions to transmission and then
affects the human body.
I know that in March this year,
you talked about the relationship
between air pollution and
public health.
We are in the same lab,
but what we do
is a little bit different.
It's more about
how to connect air pollution
to public health.
I'm more about
how to understand
air pollution in the atmosphere
and its movement and emissions
or some chemical
reaction mechanism, etc.
So,
I will introduce
three different
tools
to try to
share with you how to use
these tools to understand
how air pollution
is formed and
how it is transmitted.
And then, atmospheric science is not
like other basic sciences
like physics and chemistry.
It's more like application science.
Then,
after combining knowledge
from different fields
of each discipline,
we use these knowledge
to do atmospheric science
or atmospheric pollution analysis.
First of all,
we all know that
if there is no air pollution
in the atmosphere,
we will see
a blue sky.
That's because of
the relationship between
atmospheric dust and light.
So, we will see a blue sky.
But once
there is air pollution activity,
for example,
human or natural combustion,
it will change
the matter in the atmosphere
and change the color of the sky.
So, you can see
the two pictures below.
The one on the left is the forest fire
and the one on the right is
the two explosions
in Mexico.
These two pictures
have similarities
and differences.
The similarities are
the high temperature and high energy
brought by combustion
will bring the pollution group
to about 300 to 400 high altitudes
and then it will be transmitted.
The difference between the two pictures
is that the one on the left
is more grayish.
That means
it is more
organic carbon pollution group.
The one on the right
is more
blackish.
That means it is more
black carbon or elemental carbon
pollution group.
Today, I mainly want to
introduce
the background information
about pollution
and how it is
transmitted
around the world.
Then,
I will also
review the existing
air pollution documents,
tools used,
and some popular
atmospheric science research.
Finally, I will talk about
my research and
what problems Taiwan
is facing
when it comes to
atmospheric pollution.
Can you hear me?
Yes, I can hear you.
But your voice is a bit low.
Is it better now?
Yes, it is clearer now.
When you are
sharing the screen,
can you
see the dialogue window?
No.
You can't see it, right?
I can see it.
If you have any questions,
you can post them on the dialogue window.
Or you can turn on the microphone.
If I see it,
I will talk to you.
Then,
a student
asked two questions.
The first one is
who is Zhang Shiying?
The second question is
what is organic carbon
and what is elemental carbon?
Who is Zhang Shiying?
Our lab
talked about
air pollution and public health
in March.
He is
a Ph.D. graduate
from our lab.
He is doing
atmospheric pollution
in Sonoma Technology.
He is focusing on
integration model
with
original model
and assessing
public health.
He will calculate
how many people die
due to
air pollution.
Organic carbon
and elemental carbon
are
carbon
combined with
air pollution.
It is more like organic carbon.
Elemental carbon
is pure carbon.
You can see
charcoal is
elemental carbon.
These are the two questions.
Next,
we will talk about
air pollutants.
There are three basic ways to classify them.
The first one is
criteria air pollutants.
According to
US EPA,
there are 6 criteria air pollutants.
These 6 criteria air pollutants
must be classified
as standard air pollutants.
They include PM2.5,
PM10,
NOx, SO2,
and Ozone.
The other one is
harmful air pollutants.
These pollutants are
more like organic matter.
For example,
CHPCB,
or
heavy metal,
such as steel,
and so on.
These pollutants are harmful to human body.
Criteria air pollutants
are more harmful to
respiratory system,
circulatory system,
and cardiovascular disease.
These pollutants
will accumulate in
human organs.
The second way to classify them
is based on
physical characteristics.
For example, some air pollutants
are more likely to be harmful
to the air
under high temperature.
These pollutants, such as
SO2 and Ozone,
are similar to these pollutants.
The other one is
more likely to be harmful to
aerosol phase.
For example,
many people think
PM2.5 is a solid particle.
In fact,
PM2.5 not only contains
solid particles,
but also contains
liquid particles,
such as salt and acid,
and so on.
In addition, some pollutants
are in the middle
of these two phases.
These pollutants are
highly volatile compounds,
such as
organic compounds
or nitrate.
Because
their vapor pressure
changes with temperature
and pressure,
they are more likely to be harmful
to the air under different conditions.
The last one is
primary and secondary air pollutants.
Primary means
they are directly released
from the air.
Secondary means
they are released
from the air
through chemical reactions.
Secondary means
they are toxic.
Primary means
they are harmful to the air.
When we
study air pollutants,
we only study
a small amount.
For example,
PM2.5 contains
30 micrograms per cubic meter,
which is meaningless.
But if you add
12 micrograms per cubic meter
in US standards
and 15 micrograms per cubic meter
in Taiwan standards,
you can start
calculating
your health risk
after studying
air pollutants.
So
why do we
study air pollutants?
Because we want to
connect with public health.
For humans,
air pollutants
cause
lung and
cardiovascular diseases.
Secondly,
toxic substances
are released
from the air
and are
absorbed by
rice,
other plants,
vegetables,
and fish.
When humans
eat them,
they accumulate.
For example,
PCV and PCVPH
are toxic substances
that are harmful to humans.
Air pollutants
not only harm humans,
but also affect
the environment.
First,
air pollutants
are reduced
by 150 to
200 kilometers per hour.
As pollutants
are produced,
especially particles,
they will
diffuse or absorb light.
This will reduce
the visible distance.
In sandstorms,
the visible distance is
several meters.
Secondly,
climate change
includes
traditional air pollutants
as well as
new air pollutants,
such as
greenhouse gases.
They absorb
energy and
store it in the earth.
This has a
huge impact on the earth's environment
and climate.
Thirdly,
acid rain
is from nitrate
or sulphate.
Ok,
so
climate change
is a hot topic
especially in the US.
Trump has been denying
this issue.
He signed the Paris Agreement
last year.
Didn't Trump
sign it?
Trump didn't sign it.
But
other countries have signed it.
Only the US
didn't sign it.
Then,
this part
is
for example,
CO2 and ozone
are emitted into the atmosphere.
This causes
global
global average temperature to rise.
However,
it has different effects
in some areas.
The average temperature
is dropping.
In my opinion,
the word
global warming
is too
broad.
It doesn't
accurately describe
what we are facing.
What we are facing
is climate change.
For example,
global warming
in the US
and the
storm in the
US
and the
snow storm
can't be described
in one word.
I think the word
climate change
is more accurate.
It describes
what we are
facing.
The third
is acid rain.
Acid rain
can reduce the
harvest of crops.
Many
ancient buildings
were built by marble.
Acid rain can corrode
these buildings
and affect
the environment.
I've talked about
climate change.
Let's talk about
the source of
greenhouse gases.
The primary source
is the power system.
Whether it's fuel,
gas, or coal,
coal has a big impact on
the environment
because it emits a lot of
oxygen.
Whether it's
forest or industrial
power plants,
it has a big impact
on the environment.
The third is
driving every day.
Especially in LA,
traffic
is a high source of pollution.
Other pollutants
such as natural pollutants,
volcanoes,
and forest fires
are the source of
greenhouse gases.
In the past,
people thought
that the source of
greenhouse gases
is industrial emissions.
However,
in the past 20 years,
the U.S. and Europe
have strictly
controlled
the emission of
traffic and industrial pollutants.
Some pollutants
have decreased.
The next issue
is agricultural emissions.
Taiwan and South Korea
have been facing this issue
for the past 10 years.
China and India
may face this issue later.
When you control
industrial and traffic pollutants,
agricultural pollutants
become important pollutants.
The second is...
Excuse me.
You said agricultural air
pollution.
I didn't hear you.
Hello?
Can you hear me?
Yes.
Can you repeat that?
Did you mean
agricultural air pollution?
Yes.
It's hard to imagine.
Agricultural air pollution.
I'll explain later.
Please be patient.
The second issue
is
after some reactions,
some pollutants
are produced.
We can see...
We can see
after the pollutants
are emitted,
they enter the atmosphere
and are transmitted by the gas plant.
After the gas plant
produces the pollutants,
the pollutants will be
decomposed in areas
such as national parks.
After the pollutants
are decomposed
and enter the ecosystem,
the pollutants will
enter the human body.
The above
are some
basic
air pollution
introduction.
Next, I'll talk about
some simple
secondary chemistry.
This picture
is
secondary inorganic
chemistry.
We can see
SO2 and NO2.
These two are mainly
from industrial pollutants.
Industrial pollutants
are like the
coal, gas, fuel,
and electricity plants.
Transportation pollutants
emit NO2.
For example, the
iron industry
emits SO2 and NO2.
They are the main
emitters of SO2 and NO2.
After some
radical reactions,
they produce
oxygen and nitrogen.
Then,
they turn
SO2 and NO2
into common
particles in the air.
These are common
Ammonia bisulfate,
ammonia sulfate, and ammonia nitrate
account for
30% to 70% of
PM2.5 in the air.
It depends on the region and season.
They are large.
However,
in South America,
industrial pollutants and
transportation pollutants
reduce PM2.5
significantly.
To produce
ammonia-related aerosols,
you need
ammonia.
This is from agriculture.
This is what I said
last night.
After controlling
transportation and industrial pollutants,
agricultural pollutants
contribute significantly.
The U.S. Department of Environment
is thinking about
how to limit
ammonia emissions.
Ammonia emissions are mainly
from fertilizers.
They are thinking
how to control
the use of fertilizers.
They can
gradually reduce
agricultural pollutants
in the air.
I don't know
if that answers
your question.
The second part is
secondary organic chemistry.
Secondary organic chemistry
mainly
comes from
volatile organic compounds.
Transportation pollutants
such as
toluene VOCs,
volatile organic compounds,
and other
biogenic emissions
such as
alpha-pining or
beta-pining VOCs.
These VOCs
have a high
vapor pressure
in their original state.
They don't come
from aerosols.
However, when they react
with ozone, OH,
or nitrate,
they become
more volatile compounds.
These compounds
have higher
volatility and
lower vapor pressure.
They have a chance to
change from gas to solid.
Organic chemistry
is very complicated
in the atmosphere.
Its concentration is relatively low.
In the atmosphere,
there are
hundreds of
species.
In the atmosphere,
we know
very little about
organic chemistry.
Unlike inorganic chemistry,
we know
a lot about
organic chemistry.
However, we know very little about
The above two slides
are about
some basic
experiments in
atmospheric chemistry.
Next, we are going to talk about
the transmission part.
We need to know
how to
transmit
at different scales
from emission
to
spatial distribution.
I will divide it
into three different scales.
The first one is
global transport.
The second one is regional.
The third one is local-urban transport.
Global transport
is from NASA.
It is a
high-altitude
wind speed map.
It is in the range of
300 to 400 mb.
In the northern hemisphere,
we can see that
the red color
represents
higher wind speed,
while the blue color represents
lower wind speed.
Most pollutants
are in the northern hemisphere.
The air pollutants in the southern hemisphere
are low.
The air pollutants are low.
In the northern hemisphere,
most of it
are caused by
the influence of
the heavy wind and
the just-trained.
When we route
into the regional transport,
we can first see
the area in East Asia,
where the two high-pressure systems
are mainly affecting
the region's
transmission.
For example,
the Mongolia high-pressure system
and the Pacific high-pressure system
can be seen in different seasons.
For example,
the Mongolia high-pressure system
is stronger in the winter,
so we see the northeast wind in Taiwan.
In the summer,
the Pacific high-pressure system
is stronger,
so we see the southeast wind.
How does this affect
Taiwan's air pollution?
In the spring and summer,
the Pacific high-pressure system
is stronger,
so we see the southeast wind.
How does this affect
Taiwan's air pollution?
In the northern hemisphere,
the northern hemisphere
is mainly affected
by the just-trained.
The just-trained
has a different
route in winter and summer,
which is mainly
affected by polar vortex.
When the polar vortex is stronger,
it will shift the just-trained
from the north to the south.
So you will see
different sources of pollution
depending on the season.
Sometimes you will even see
sources of pollution in Asia.
In the United States,
the contribution of
US air pollutants
is about 20-30%
from Asia in spring.
Lastly,
the urban
and local transmission
is affected
by the heat wave.
In the metropolitan area,
there is a lack
of vegetation.
In the morning,
the sun shines
and the temperature
in the metropolitan area
is very high.
In the evening,
the air temperature
is down.
On the ground,
the air temperature
on the ground
is up.
them
are like a lid.
The hot air
in the metropolitan area
can't escape
the heat wave,
so many pollutants
are trapped
in the air.
These three
transmission mechanisms
play an important role
in the air quality model.
We use these three
transmission mechanisms
or different scale
transmission
to understand
what kind of
transmission mechanism
will affect
the pollutants
in the air.
These are the
information about
air pollutants
from different
emission sources
to different
transmission scale.
Next,
let's talk about
literature review.
The first tool I want to
talk about is
source approachment
to
the data
in the air.
We use
statistical analysis
to divide it into
different factors
to find
the contribution
of the air
pollutants.
As I said,
the air pollution
is connected
with public health.
We want to reduce
the concentration of pollutants in the air.
The fastest way
to reduce the concentration of pollutants in the air
is to reduce the emission
of different emission sources.
To reduce the emission
of different emission sources
and make different laws
for them,
we need to know their contribution.
Source approachment
is a simple
and easy way
to find the contribution
of different pollutants.
The literature is an example
of
ICP analysis
and
OC analysis.
We have
different elements
and
four years
of sampling time.
When we do
factor analysis,
we get different
factors.
Based on the different factors,
we can see
the characteristics of
organic carbon
and elemental carbon.
Labolution
and
casing.
Based on these,
the first factor
is the
carbon emission factor.
Based on
time series analysis,
we can see
the contribution of
different pollutants
in different years
and different seasons.
We can use
Lagrange's Heisberg model
to infer
the emission source
of
these pollutants.
The second factor
is the dispersion model.
Dispersion model
is a simple model
based on
Gaussian dispersion
concept.
It is
parallel to
the axis of
the wind direction.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
This
dispersion model is
suitable for small area
like tens of kilometers.
It does not
include chemistry.
Most dispersion models
do not include chemistry.
Only a few have simple chemistry.
It is suitable for primary
air pollutants.
It is suitable for
primary air pollutants.
The third factor
is the chemical transport model.
It is based on
Lagrange's Heisberg model.
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
The third factor is
the chemical transport model.
It is based on
the equation
of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
The third factor is
the chemical transport model.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction using
dispersion to
calculate.
The third factor is
the chemical transport model.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
The fourth factor is
the chemical transport model.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
The fourth factor is
the chemical transport model.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
The fifth factor
is the
chemical transport model.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
The sixth factor
is the
chemical transport model.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
The sixth factor
is the
chemical transport model.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation
of the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
the wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
wind direction
using
dispersion to
calculate.
It is based on
the equation of
wind direction
.