Can you see me now?
Ok
Can you see my screen now?
Yes?
Yes, yes, yes
I will turn off my camera
So it will be smoother
Ok
Let me tell you
There are two more people here
One is here
One is over there
The camera may not be able to see
There are three people here
If they have any questions
Don't be surprised if they are real people
Sorry
There were some microphone issues
That's why we are delaying
The topic I am going to talk about
looks a bit
difficult to understand
Functional connectivity and dynamics
and burn organization
In short
The main purpose of my research
is to look at the functional connections
between neural networks
The so-called functional connections
are the neural signals
generated by neurons
during activation
How these neural signals
are transmitted between different brains
This is the main thing
I am going to talk about today
I will divide it into two parts
The first part is introduction
Introduction is a general
background idea
If you are not a neurologist
You need to know something
to make it easier for us to explain
This is one of the main research
The second part is
the current message
It is about a
special project
The last part is all about that project
The first part is
a little bit
scientific
The second part is more about
that research
I have seen
the comments
Some people are just
talking about science
So I want to talk about
what is neuroscience
I have seen
on the internet
Neuroscience is a
comprehensive research
It includes chemistry,
medicine, physiology, medicine
even computer science and engineering
There are a lot of subjects
From the perspective of
modern neuroscience
There are
cells
and neurons
If you
enlarge the scale
There are cognitive science
and behavioral science
Finally, there is transfer medicine
It is to apply the research
in the lab to clinical
If you want to
There are micro scale,
mesoscale and macroscale
The last part is
about the research
The first part is
between neurons
The research topic is
Let me correct
The first part is
about single neurons
The second part is
between neurons
The last part is
The biggest part
is what I have done
At the same time
What I have done
will cover the last part
I will use
a simple sentence
It is about
neural connectivity
You will hear
functional connectivity
It is about
the connectivity
of neurons
There is another point
We want to see
the connection of
human behavior
For example,
their behavior
in clinical
or in cognitive science
I will talk about
functional connectivity later
For example,
some of you
have studied psychology
or cognitive science
You may have heard
some theory
I will give you some examples
The left one is called localization
In short,
scientists study
brain function
or human behavior
They want to
target some function
in a specific area
This is the result
of an FMRI
on the Internet
You can see
the three colored areas
It means that
when the subject is doing something
the neurons in these three areas
are active
This is a more traditional theory
They think
they need to
classify
which brain area
is responsible for which function
The other one is called
distributed brain networks
These two schools
have been fighting for a long time
But recently
because of some new research methods
most people think
this is more like the human brain we expect
In this new school
their focus
is not on studying
a single brain area
Instead,
they focus on
the function between
different brain areas
For example,
this brain area
may send a message
to this area
This area
may send a message
to this area
This area
may send a message
to this area
This is a way
for them to communicate
between neurons
This is a way
for them to communicate
between neurons
This is a way
for them to communicate
between neurons
About
how to study
and measure
functional connectivity
From statistics
from different areas
For example
This is a brain
Let's say
you have 3 regions
1,2,3
The blue, red, and green lines
are the time course
I'm using FMRI
This is the signal change
caused by the activation
of a neuron
FMRI is used as basic
ingredients for cooking
When you get the signal
You can see the relation
between neurons
You can use different machines
I used FMRI for my research
Every functional connectivity
I use FMRI for my research
Time series
If you have 3 regions
The first step is
to extract the signal
You start sending signals
using different methods
to estimate the relation
to 2-3 brain regions
If you use Pairwise Correlation
You will see a lot of values
For example
This represents
the relation between
Ri2 and Ri1
If they are positive
For example, this is about 0.5
This means that this region
and this region are connected
and this region and this region are connected
Don't look at this
It means that you and yourself are connected
But this is not a normal situation
This is because we are calculating
After we get this evidence
We will force the line to 0
This is the way we use
Of course, you shouldn't use Pairwise Correlation
Many people use different methods
For example, Partial Correlation, Mutual Information
There is no specific method
It depends on what you want to see
After that
After we get this evidence
We will be curious
What are we going to do next
After we get this evidence
We will be curious
There are too many signals
So, I am going to report on this data
So we got the evidence
We have two main topics
Now we have two main topics
Dynamic Functional Connectivity
Let me answer a question
Let me tell you
If you have any questions
You can type it into the chat
and I will find time to answer
Or I will tell you to check with the organization
And I will ask you the questions
Because I can't see the chat
So I don't know the questions
If you have any questions, you can ask
Before we talk about graph theory
Do you have any questions?
If not, let's continue
There is a little bit of abstraction
Let me try
Later we can continue to discuss
It's intentional
Describing the relationship between two points
It is a very good tool
If you use graph theory
You can get a lot of different values
Each value represents a specific feature of the network
For example
We'll talk about some different values later
Some values may represent
How well the signal is integrated in the entire brain
Or how well it is integrated in a single system
So there will be some different messages
When you do graph theory
There are two things that are very important
These are the two files you must get
The first one is Node
The other one is Edge
Node is our so-called region of interest
For example, on the right
This is the data obtained by the actual receiver
I have 36
So there are 36 areas of the brain
One point to remember
Each of those 36 types of dots
Each of these 36 types of dots
Every one of those 38 dots
Integration
Segregation
Local Measures
Centrality
ROIs
HOPs
Graph Theory
Dynamic Functional Quantitative
ROIs
Non-stationary
Binary
Pacific Parkinson's Research Center
Biomarker
Prediction
Risking State FMRI
Brain Organization and Dynamic Functional Quantitative
Functional Integration
Segregation
Time-Varying Method
Substantial Nigra
Rigidity
Postural Problem
Motor Symptoms
Substantial Nigra
The patient will be sent to the center of the machine.
Because the magnetic field in the center is more stable.
Then we start scanning.
One thing you need to know is that
MRI has a very loud noise.
So we put earplugs on the patient.
To protect their hearing.
In addition, it is a magnetic field.
So there can't be any metal objects on the body.
For example, keys, wallets, rings, etc.
All have to be taken down.
Including women's underwear can also be brought in.
So we always ask the cleaner to change clothes.
This is the image we got.
In principle, we do this kind of thing.
We will scan two images.
The most basic.
One is called T1 Weighted Imaging.
This is to provide you a structural image.
You can see it clearly.
This image will tell you which one is which.
Gray is gray.
White is white.
The empty space in the middle is water.
There is a spinal cord.
Brain.
These two are eyeballs.
The middle is the air.
This image provides you with very clear structural information.
In addition, we will scan the functional imaging.
We call it Bolt Signal.
It is written here.
This image is physical observation.
If you don't deal with it, you can't see anything.
You can only see the middle is the CSF.
You can't clearly define the brain.
Or gray and white.
So when we analyze,
The most important thing is to analyze this image.
The principle of fMRI is quite complicated.
This is what I have found so far.
I have seen the simplest and most powerful picture.
I can introduce it to you.
When the neural source is active,
It needs oxygen, oxygen and blood.
Now the neural source is active.
The blood vessels near the neural source begin to increase blood flow.
Bring fresh oxygen blood cells to this place.
You will find a lot of fresh blood coming here.
Because oxygen needs to enter the neural source.
Fresh blood will come.
There are a lot of new oxygen here.
When the oxygen-blood-red and oxygen-blood-red interact,
We can generate a signal.
Because fMRI is a strong magnetic field.
We used to learn the Faraday's law.
Because of the change in the magnetic field, it will generate an electric signal.
It will be received by the current.
After a lot of image processing,
You will see this image.
Because of the imbalance of oxygen-blood-red and oxygen-blood-red,
It will generate a signal.
So the picture we just talked about,
The so-called Tom course,
It's this thing.
After we get this thing,
We can start the follow-up analysis.
Of course, the story is not that simple.
Because you can analyze from the signal to the magnetic field.
There are a lot of things to do in the middle.
For example, you have to correct the difference in time.
And then correct the space difference.
Sometimes the brain will move like this.
You can't just take the data and analyze it.
You have to correct these things first.
These things are called preprocessing.
I didn't talk too much today.
The main thing is to let you know that you have to correct the difference in time and space.
We will focus on the latter part.
How do you analyze them?
Wait a minute.
Did you have any questions about any image acquisition?
Can I ask a question?
Do you have any questions on the spot?
Did you get this picture on the spot?
You got this picture when you did it.
Then you turn it like this.
Then you turn it into this picture.
After sending this picture in, it will give you this.
You have to set a few points on the picture.
Then it will find it.
Otherwise, how do you know how many pictures are there?
Okay.
He asked if we get this picture from here to here.
Basically, how do you get there?
Yes.
Because I omitted a lot of things.
So I'm going to talk about it now.
If we process it in our lab, we will get this T1 and BOL signal.
Then we will throw T1 into a software called FreeSurfer.
The purpose is to do so-called cortical postulation.
That's why we get those R1, R2, R3, R4.
We take this T1, which means we label each brain area and give it an ID.
Then we do the pre-processing of the image obtained by the fMRI.
After the pre-processing, we have to put the T1 with the label and the pre-processed fMRI in place.
Because they say that the victim's head won't move too much.
But we still have to put these two images in place to ensure that the area we see on the T1 is the same area on the fMRI.
So this placement is very important.
After we put T1 and fMRI in place, we tell the software that we first define how many RIs you want from T1.
If there are 100, I tell the computer that I want 90.
Then I list all the 90 IDs.
There is a step called Time Course Extraction.
After we put these two IDs in place, I tell the software to extract the time course of the 90 RIs.
For example, the first RI is here.
I extract the time course of this RI.
The second RI is here.
It's like this.
How big is the RI?
It depends on how you do the protocol postulation.
Basically, the resolution of this RI is 1x1x1 mm.
But some areas are bigger.
For example, if you have a prefrontal cortex, it's very big.
But if you have a very small one, the anterior cingulate cortex will be smaller.
So it doesn't necessarily depend on the area of your brain.
So what do you usually decide to look at?
This is a very tricky question.
If you look at this area, you will find that this area has not changed at all.
It's just floating in another area.
Yes.
So now most people tend to use it.
It's a bit like looking at how many brain areas you have when you do postulation.
Usually, at least 90 or more.
I know there are more than 100 in FreeSurfer.
A lot of people take out more than 100 brain areas.
Because they don't know which one they want to look at.
So they just take out all the information about the brain areas.
Some people are very specific.
They have their assumptions.
They think which brain area has a special relationship with which brain area they want to look at.
Then they will have a purpose to choose those brain areas first.
Indeed, at the beginning, when you are writing articles,
the question that often comes back is why you choose these brain areas.
So now, I think it's better to avoid this question.
Plus, you really don't know where the changes are.
So you use all the brain areas.
So is it a problem that you already have?
Or is it a problem that you already have?
Oh, I found that these PhD students have a lot of questions.
In fact, it should be said that we already have different software and different templates.
You will get different brain areas.
In fact, this is a big problem in video editing.
Generally speaking, my answer is that we will have a defined brain area.
For example, you use FreeSurfer.
Then you will definitely know which brain areas you can find in FreeSurfer.
This is a long list.
Then we will say that we want these brain areas in that list.
There is another one called AAL.
This is another template.
This is another software.
If you write an article and say that this is an AAL template.
Then we probably know which brain areas.
In principle, I don't think they are much different.
But there are a lot of people who specialize in the so-called postulation.
They will tell you which different templates will have which different shortcomings.
Then last year, I don't know if you have seen that report.
There was a paper in Nature last year.
There is a Human Connectome Project in the United States.
They scanned thousands of people.
Then they used the data of those thousands of people.
Then at the same time, it also contains different modalities.
For example, there is a functional image of MIT1.
There is also T2 or Proton Density Modeling.
There are many different images.
They put all the modalities together.
Use all these modalities to build another template.
My impression is that there are more than 100 brain areas than we currently know.
It seems to be more than 200.
So how do you define your brain area?
It's a bit tricky.
At present, we can only say which template you use.
Or if you use which software.
We probably know what your so-called brain areas are.
Is there any other questions?
For example, if the area is large or small,
you can set it to large or small.
For example, if the signal is very strong when you are small,
but when you are large,
you have to remove the signal.
Yes, there is.
This is what I don't believe.
For example, there are some things in the brain area
where the signal is very, very bad.
Because it just intersects with the air.
In fact, you can see it in this image.
You can see that there is still a brain area here.
This is the prefrontal cortex.
But it's already close to the sinus, the air area.
In T1, it looks okay.
But in FMR, you can see that it's super bad.
Half of the frontal area is gone.
For example, in the frontal area,
there are some very small areas, such as the frontal pole.
That area is very small.
And it's close to the air.
So the signal under FMR is super bad.
Usually, I don't look at that area.
If your signal is already bad,
and you find out that it's mutating,
what do you say?
Is it really caused by the difference in the vital signs of the nervous system?
Or is it because your own signal is bad?
So my approach is to put those too small areas
or in those areas where the signal is unclear.
I don't want those areas.
Which areas are often unclear when you draw like this?
Frontal
The closest to the frontal area
is the frontal area.
Because it's too close to the air.
There will be a so-called partial volume effect.
If you look at this picture,
the signal is bad in the front area.
And there's an area near here called the orbital frontal cortex.
It's close to the nasal cavity.
There's a lot of air there, so the signal is bad.
And the other area is the temporal pole.
It's at the tip of the temporal area.
And there's the inferior temporal cortex.
It's at the bottom of the temporal area.
Because it's close to the skull base.
So in those areas,
if I actually see the whole data sharing,
and find that there's an important change in the location,
I'll be a little hesitant.
And then I'll go back and see if my image blurring is good or not.
And then I'll decide whether to believe it or not.
Okay, anything else?
Okay, let's move on.
Okay, this is a little bit...
You have to be patient.
Because this is a little bit complicated.
This is the background I was talking about earlier.
The background for this experiment.
Now I'm going to talk about how to use it for this experiment.
And then you'll see...
First of all, I'm going to talk about dynamic functional connectivity.
I use sliding window.
This blue is the so-called fMRI timecord.
That's what we've been talking about.
When you're doing a sliding window,
the most important thing,
the first step is to define your so-called window length.
Which is how big your window is.
I'm using 20 time points here.
That is to say, I only need...
I only have the first 20 time points.
And then I'll do correlation.
I'm using Pearson's correlation here.
And then I'll get a matrix.
And this matrix represents...
I have 54 ROI here.
It represents the relationship between these 54 ROI.
And then I'm going to move my window forward.
Just one time point.
And do the same thing and you'll get the second matrix.
Wait a minute.
How long is a time point usually?
Oh, it depends on your MRI scan parameters.
We have two seconds here.
And then you just keep doing the same thing.
Until you've used up all the fMRI timecords.
I have a total of 221 window correlation matrices here.
And then the next very important thing is...
I've got so many matrices.
But not all of them are the same.
So how am I going to report their variability?
So we've calculated seven...
I call them network features.
According to these matrices,
I'm going to calculate some numbers.
And each number represents variability.
For example, the first one.
I call it network variation.
The first one is very simple.
In fact, we want to see the overall variability.
So let's just take the first one and the second one.
Take all the numbers in the matrix and subtract them.
And then do the same thing for each of the 221 matrices.
On average.
So the number we get is a bit like...
On average, the variability of your entire brain's connectivity.
And then the second one is called network power.
This is actually very simple.
It's mainly about adding up all the connectivity values.
On average.
And the purpose of this is to get...
It's a bit like...
On average, the strength of your connectivity.
And then these are very similar from C to G and A.
But the difference is...
A is measuring all the numbers in the whole brain.
All the elements in this matrix.
But C to G is for a specific connection.
For example, this is called Inter-Hemisphere Connection.
We only calculate the connection between the opposite brain areas.
And then this is Cross-Hemisphere.
And then this is Within-Hemisphere.
It's on the same side.
And then we divide it into the left and the right.
So you can see that the mathematics is actually quite similar.
It's just that when we calculate C to G.
The value we get is...
For example, when we calculate C, we take the right-angled line.
Because the right-angled line represents the connectivity from left to right.
And then...
This is how the sliding window runs.
What about the other graph theory?
I made it a little fancier here.
I have a little bit of a graph theory.
Combine the two sliding windows together.
So in the front, you'll find that it's exactly the same as the sliding window.
It's all the same until this step.
The difference is that after I got this matrix.
I didn't just add or subtract it.
Do some processing to calculate the so-called network feature.
But I first apply a threshold.
Above a certain threshold.
I think these connections are real connections.
There's no miscommunication under this threshold.
And then I'm going to throw this threshold edge.
There's something called Brain Connectivity Toolbox.
This is a free download on the Internet.
It's a graph theory.
After I throw it into the graph theory.
I'll get two global features in each window.
And a local measure.
In fact, you can get more.
I'm just using these three for now.
The so-called global measure is.
One subject will have one number.
The local measure is.
It depends on how many RRIs it has.
How many numbers will there be?
And then I'm going to have 221 sets.
Then there are three numbers in each window.
This is a bit complicated.
But in a nutshell.
It's a different way.
I got a lot of different numbers.
Or so-called network features.
Then the point is to look at the patient.
What's the difference between normal control and normal control?
And then the next one.
Okay.
Actually, this is a little bit.
Is there a problem?
It's okay. I'm going to ask this one.
Now you have it.
You can keep talking.
Don't talk to me.
Okay.
It's okay.
After the analysis of the RRIs.
We got the so-called numbers.
These are the ones.
When we use the sliding window.
We'll get the power of the network variation.
And then the specific connections I just mentioned.
This is inter-hemisphere.
And then this is cross-hemisphere.
And in the same brain.
In the same brain.
And then there's the left and the right.
The so-called flexibility.
It's actually what we're going to do.
The number of correlations.
The number of correlations between the two windows.
Two minus.
And then on average.
So these are the numbers in the sliding window.
If the number is higher.
It means that his connectivity is more dynamic.
The more mutable, the bigger.
And then dynamic graphical approach.
That's what we just talked about.
Combined graph theory and sliding window.
It's the same global feature.
I have two.
One is called global efficiency.
One is called modularity.
It's a little hard to explain here.
I'll try to explain it.
I can't explain it.
If it's not clear.
Maybe you need to check that.
I'll show you a paper later.
There may be a complete one in there.
There's a complete math.
It's easier to understand.
In short, global efficiency.
The way it's calculated.
The shortest distance between these two points.
Make them equal.
Do the math first.
And then on average.
This global efficiency represents.
The information of the entire neural network.
In the whole brain.
How well is it integrated?
So it's also an indicator of integration.
Modularity is just the opposite.
It's an indicator of segregation.
Modularity is actually.
Under this network.
Will this network be.
Will it be divided into several different.
Small networks.
It's an indicator of segregation.
This means.
If the modularity value is higher.
It means.
Its signal.
In a single system.
It's better to be integrated.
These two points are the opposite.
Integration and segregation.
Another local measure.
Betweenness centrality.
In short.
You calculate this brain.
Brain area.
This RRI.
How important is it in the entire neural network?
That is to say.
How many.
The shortest path.
Through this brain.
This brain area.
This RRI.
If this number is higher.
It means.
This brain area is more important.
It could be.
The hubs we just talked about.
With these numbers.
The first thing we do.
Is to see.
What's the difference between the patient and the PD patient?
And the other is.
These values.
Do a forward return with the clinical indicator.
See what happens.
Then.
Next.
it is good.
I want to test the bed.
I'm here.
This is the result.
I can tell you.
If it's just a two-sample t-test.
I can't see any difference.
Between patients and normal people.
Those.
There is no difference at all.
But we do.
Simple.
When it's Pearson's correlation.
You can find out.
This is.
Sliding window.
The result of dynamic connectivity.
You can find out.
Let's look at the above two.
It's the age.
With the network power.
And.
I put a small picture.
You can know which one it is.
Connection.
Inter-Hermitian connectivity.
It's related.
But I can tell you first.
I think this is actually more like.
Normal human aging.
Will be produced.
Because I.
I see this on Parkinson's disease patients.
But I also see it on normal people.
So this.
We won't do so much discussion for the time being.
And then.
But.
This is more interesting.
This is that.
Postural instability.
Get disorder.
It's their balance.
Physical coordination.
That number.
With.
Enter.
On the right.
This.
This is the right.
Dynamic functional connectivity.
It's related to them.
That is to say.
The more serious the patient.
His right connectivity.
More.
Uh.
Stiff.
Can't.
Uh.
Change.
And then.
This is the dose of the drug.
It's the same.
When the dose of the drug.
When the higher.
They are also.
With.
Like.
They are.
Uh.
Crossing two brains.
This connectivity is also more rigid.
You can find.
In this way.
If based on these two.
If the relationship.
We can roughly think.
Uh.
Parkinson's disease.
The patient.
Their.
Uh.
The.
Yeah.
Uh.
This is.
Paras.
Uh.
In the way.
It is.
Paras.
Uh.
Yeah.
Paras.
Uh.
Compensator effect.
Bye bye.