Hi, everyone. We're going to have the fourth Q&A session this year.
We're honored to have Zhang Yanping here to talk about positive emotions and human relations.
Zhang Yanping is a Ph.D. candidate at UNC-Chapel Hill.
He has been studying at UNC-Chapel Hill since 2013.
Prior to that, he obtained a Ph.D. and a master's degree in psychology at NTU.
His research focuses on positive psychology, positive emotion, gratitude, self-transcendent emotion, well-being, cultural psychology, and moral psychology.
His research includes emotional communication, interpersonal dynamics, Taiwanese indigenous psychology, prosocial behavior, political participation, and moral judgment.
As you can see, Zhang Yanping's research focuses on social psychology and social participation.
Today, he's going to talk about emotional and interpersonal dynamics.
Let's welcome him.
Thank you, everyone.
First, I'd like to say I'm sorry.
I thought I'd be here next week.
So the content I'm going to talk about today is a little different from what I wrote for Zhang Yanping.
Wait a minute. I'll close the door.
I was going to prepare a more general content next week.
I'm going to talk about a lot of projects that I've done before.
I'm not going to go into too much detail, but I'm going to put them all together and talk about a big direction and what to do next.
But I got the time wrong.
So I didn't prepare that.
So what I'm going to talk about today is one of the projects I was going to cover.
But I'm going to talk about this project.
The bad thing is that I'm going to talk about it in more detail.
So if you have any technical questions, you can just ask.
The good thing is that I'm not going to talk about the studies I shared last spring.
So if you've heard of it, you won't repeat it.
This is the first one. I'm sorry. I got the time wrong.
The second one.
The second one is when I was talking about my research interests.
It sounds like a lot of answers.
It sounds like independent things.
But in fact, it's like this.
Imagine.
I'm actually interested in how people communicate and understand each other.
What the other person wants to do.
Who is the other person?
What is the other person thinking?
Wait a minute.
In this process of interpersonal communication,
In the past, people have been pointing out a lot.
That is to say, our speech and communication.
In fact, non-verbal communication is a big part of it.
And it's not just a big part.
In fact, it's a relatively large part.
Compared to verbal communication.
For example, if I say hello to everyone today.
Thank you very much for coming to my speech.
But from start to finish.
Then you must find it strange.
But in fact, that's a constant behavior.
I didn't even move.
You can just say that my hands are stiff.
But in fact, it's not.
Just that little action.
The whole process of communication has changed.
What I'm interested in is non-verbal communication.
Non-verbal communication is largely related to emotions.
If I'm angry, I'll just crack my teeth.
Even if I haven't hit you yet.
I also crack my teeth.
I don't know if you've seen that.
There is a very famous photo of an Olympic gold medalist.
He once won a silver medal.
I don't remember his name.
Very famous recently.
Then his mouth is on one side of his mouth.
Because he's very ungrateful.
That's actually a content performance.
Will it affect
If you're talking to your partner.
It's like this.
A very ungrateful look.
There's going to be a problem with communication.
So what I'm interested in is
Emotions in non-verbal communication.
How does this have anything to do with moral psychology?
Because it's simple.
Because if I'm talking to my partner today.
Then show a very ungrateful look.
There will be a fight later.
There will be a fight.
It's about morality.
It's about who's right and who's wrong.
Why do you think I shouldn't do this?
Why should I listen to you?
But I give you this ungrateful look.
You think this is morally wrong.
Where do you see this signal from?
Then next.
For example, I walked on the street.
Then there was a street friend.
He showed me some emotional non-verbal communication signals.
But then it will affect my judgment of his situation.
For example, this guy deserves it.
He didn't work hard to get there.
Or do I think he must have been bullied.
So this society is not fair.
So I have to help him.
So moral behavior or moral judgment
And the next moral behavior
It's all in this kind of interpersonal communication.
It's all in this kind of interaction.
So it's actually a line that keeps pulling down.
And then finally.
I'm very interested in culture.
Because that's what we're going to talk about today.
Culture greatly affects how we understand others.
Like this.
We'll talk about culture later.
I won't talk about it now.
Anyway, you can imagine it.
Then I started.
Because I have two screens.
So if you leave a message, I can see it.
It won't affect my PowerPoint.
So if you have any questions, you can leave a message.
You can also speak directly through the microphone.
It doesn't matter.
So I should be able to see it.
Okay, let's get started.
First of all, thank you all for coming to listen to me today.
And it's under such late notice.
So.
I was interrupted just now.
Thank you all.
In order to express my gratitude to everyone.
This is what I used in my dissertation proposal defense.
So it's funny.
Maybe it's weird here.
That's what I said at the time.
In order to express my gratitude to everyone.
Please let me kiss your feet.
Okay.
This behavior.
Especially in Taiwan.
It's very bizarre.
Why would you do this?
But in India.
I don't know if you know.
In India.
Kissing someone's feet is the highest expression.
Respect.
And gratitude.
Grateful for the help of these people.
And cultivation.
And incense.
So this behavior is usually for.
This.
It's usually for the elders.
Or this monk.
This monk.
It's what the monks do.
Of course, it's not limited to these people.
But it's usually like this.
This behavior looks very bizarre.
But in fact, in this part of the world.
This is what everyone does.
And don't forget.
This is not a small island in the Pacific Ocean.
Then there are only a few hundred people.
This is India.
There are hundreds of millions of people in India.
Very, very many.
So it's not a.
So it's actually not a.
Very rare event.
But we don't know about these events.
I don't know.
So for us.
Grateful is to express gratitude.
Just say thank you.
Hug.
But.
This thing.
In the example just now.
It shows that.
This is often not the case.
Before we start.
Before analyzing culture.
Let's talk about why.
So why do we need to study gratitude?
Because.
We know that gratitude is a positive emotion.
I'm going to talk about gratitude today.
Gratitude is a positive emotion.
When we feel grateful.
We feel very happy.
Warm.
So he.
Psychologically.
Comfortable.
And the study also shows.
Feel positive emotion.
Will make us.
There are many benefits of mental health.
Come again.
In addition to mental health.
Physical health.
The study also shows that.
When feeling positive emotion.
All kinds of positive emotions.
Physical health will be better.
Not to mention gratitude.
Because gratitude is usually between people.
I thank a person.
Then a person is good to me.
He gives me social support.
So I feel grateful.
Then I might return it later.
So give him social support.
The study found that.
Social support.
For this.
Mortality rate.
Will it hang anyway?
Will people die?
This prediction.
Very high.
How high is it?
Higher than smoking.
Then.
Let me see if I can.
Find this information for everyone.
Take a quick look.
This is a big one in the past.
This review paper.
Then he found that.
Everyone can see me now.
This powerpoint is affiliation.
Or the one just now.
I can see it.
Affiliation, right?
Very good.
This is.
In the past, this study is.
He did it like this.
Everyone can see this.
There are a lot of bars here.
This bar.
Is these items on the left.
For mortality risk.
Prediction.
This effect size.
If you don't know what effect size is.
Don't care about it.
The longer the prediction, the stronger the prediction.
The less noise.
The top.
This pile.
Is a variety of different ways to measure social support.
Then social support.
Or good quality.
High quality social relationship.
For the mortality rate.
The prediction is very high.
If you have good quality.
These.
Quality relationship.
Then.
The mortality rate is relatively low.
Prediction is stronger than smoking.
And this smoking is not what.
Pick two a day.
What is it?
Less than 15.
Everyone can see here.
So this is a crazy pile.
You.
A crazy pile.
You are not necessarily.
Not necessarily dead.
It will be faster than those who do not have social support.
Social support is so important.
Then there are below.
But.
Aren't they consistent?
You have an error bar.
What is it called?
They are not consistent.
Your social relationship.
After adding the error bar.
Within one sigma.
Consistent with smoking.
I can accept.
You said alcohol consumption.
But I don't think smoking is good.
Smoking is right.
This is not wrong.
This is true.
And this.
You can see this.
The size of the error bar.
In fact, it has a lot to do with the method of measurement.
Because if you are today.
Especially when you.
If you ask about this smoking.
Then you pick a few.
This can be counted one by one.
But how to measure the relationship quality.
Is a very tricky question.
So it will have three different categories.
Then there are several categories.
The error bar is super big.
Because it is obvious.
The way of measuring is not very good.
It's not accurate.
But generally the idea is.
Social support.
At least.
At least it is with.
Smoking.
Can't be distinguished.
Just like this.
Like you don't have friends.
It's like you smoke every day.
Yeah, that's fine.
It's not bigger.
But at least it can't.
Not lower.
And then alcohol.
In this place.
Alcohol is a little lower.
But it.
It is still lower than social support.
Then there is the flu vaccine.
The flu vaccine is even lower.
Physical activity is here.
It's lower.
Then.
Okay, that's it.
These are the more important ones.
So.
What is the point?
The point is that social support.
It is for.
Mortality risk.
The prediction is so strong.
So we.
I want to have a good relationship.
In the end.
Wait a minute.
I see someone.
Oh.
Is the edge wrong?
Okay.
The edge is not wrong.
The edge needs help.
Need help.
But we just want to talk about this.
That is to say.
There is no social support.
In fact, it is a very.
A serious problem.
So it's not just about teenagers.
Teenage smoking is not good.
It's just that teenagers are excluded.
He might die faster.
Anyway, think about it.
This is actually quite reasonable.
This smoking.
You still have smoking.
But.
People who are excluded.
It's easy to commit suicide in the end.
So this is really a serious problem.
Okay, finally.
This past research has been considered.
It's not research.
This is a philosopher.
Many philosophers.
Maybe not many.
But there are a few important philosophers.
They believe that.
Gratitude is a very important emotion.
Because it brings people together.
He.
It is the foundation of our modern society.
Just social exchange.
Or this.
Rational exchange is not enough.
So it's a bit like a lubricant.
That's why we need to study gratitude.
But the problem is.
Just like the example we just saw.
We're not really sure.
How to express gratitude.
Or what to do with gratitude.
Because the cultural difference is so big.
So in this project.
I'm going to do this.
The question is.
Cultural variation in good expressions.
Different cultures.
How to express.
Express gratitude.
And then.
Especially I will focus on.
The difference between the United States and Taiwan.
I will explain later.
Why the United States and Taiwan.
Except.
Of course there are some theoretical reasons.
I will explain later.
Another one is because.
I'm in the United States.
So it's easy for me to get American samples.
Then I have connections in Taiwan.
So I get connections in Taiwan.
This is a.
This is a practical reason.
I'll talk about this first.
The theoretical reason.
I'll talk about it later.
OK.
Then it officially started.
We've already spent half an hour.
It's really funny.
Anyway.
OK.
So what is gratitude?
Gratitude.
This emotion.
We just.
Define it a little bit.
It's a kind of.
When we receive help from others.
Or goodwill.
When goodwill.
Will feel a kind of.
Positive.
Happy.
Joyful.
Warm.
This feeling.
This emotion.
We.
We call this feeling gratitude.
Or say.
It's usually not wrong.
As for whether.
Only this feeling is called gratitude.
We don't care about it now.
Don't care about it now.
In this place.
Gratitude has several characteristics.
Compared with other positive emotions.
The first one is.
It's usually.
In interpersonal relationships.
Produced.
Someone helped me.
Give me a gift.
Or.
Say something nice to me.
Give me.
Just.
Do something for me.
Teach me something I don't know.
I feel very grateful.
This is different from.
Other positive emotions.
But I'm happy today.
I don't need anyone else.
I feel great.
This is positive emotion.
This is joy.
But this is not grateful.
You won't because.
I'm happy.
Feel grateful.
Usually not.
We can discuss later.
If you are happy.
Feel grateful.
Why is that?
I think this question is very interesting.
But basically.
Gratefulness.
Its characteristics are.
Produced directly from interpersonal relationships.
Usually.
In addition.
It will have.
Results in interpersonal relationships.
Or effect.
We receive a person.
Gratefulness.
We usually.
Repay.
Or at least say thank you.
This thank you.
Not in the air.
Say it to another person.
So.
Gratefulness is a very interpersonal.
Emotion.
Relative to.
Other positive emotions.
So.
This is.
Later.
There is a.
Because of these phenomena.
There is a theory.
Called.
Find.
Remind.
And.
Find.
Theory.
This theory says so.
He said.
Gratefulness.
The reason why people.
Have this emotion.
Is because.
Gratefulness.
It's like this.
Think about it.
It's like a light bulb.
We usually wear a light bulb.
Then.
When.
Someone is nice to me.
I think this person.
This person is a good.
Social partner.
This.
I deserve to continue.
With him.
This light will be like this.
Will light up.
Then remind me.
This guy is a good guy.
This is gratefulness.
The thing that lights up.
Is gratefulness.
So he.
Help us.
Find.
Good.
Social partners.
And.
If.
Next time.
I meet this person.
My light bulb.
Will be like this.
Will light up again.
Remind me.
This guy was nice to me last time.
So.
I should repay him now.
Or.
I should pay attention to this person.
Next.
Make good friends with him.
So.
Can build social partners.
This social relationship.
So.
He helped me.
Find.
And.
Remind me.
Put the two of us together.
That.
We all know.
It's easy to die.
But if there is.
Cooperation.
It's easier to live.
Especially.
Good.
With good.
Partners.
Cooperate together.
Then.
OK.
Oh.
OK .
OK.
suite
Oh.
Okay.
So.
This is.
he is very famous in recent research.
If you're interested in it, we can talk about it later.
But this is a concept.
This is collective culture.
Everybody image of this dimensions are different.
So what's the result.
The result is.
If in to personalistic culture change.
We all think about change the role of society already and social norm.
It's easy.
It's allowed.
Let them do it.
But in extremism.
Especially in extreme extremism.
It's very difficult.
Let me give you an example.
You're in Japan.
If you want to quit the black society, you have to cut your finger, right?
You have to.
This is very serious.
There will be very serious consequences.
And usually the result is that you won't quit.
Otherwise you will die.
So you actually didn't quit.
Or you really cut a finger.
Then your whole life changed.
Ok.
Then we put the culture into the emotion.
What's the result?
The result is.
In the left side of the personalistic culture.
It's easy to see.
Everybody's emotional expression is a lot of big body movements.
Then easy to see.
And I say it is easy to see.
It's literally easy to see.
You push that person far away.
Then you see that person is far away.
He is saying hello to you and waving his hand.
It's literally easy to see.
But.
If it is.
This collective culture.
Everyone's expression is relatively small.
That is, he may smile at you.
Even the teeth did not show.
So if you are two meters away.
You just.
This face is.
It looks like a flat one.
Won't move.
So why is that?
Because.
Back to that American.
The example of panic.
Everyone is really two meters away.
You can't see.
Then you express.
Express.
Sour.
But if it is.
If you.
On the right.
In Taiwan or Japan.
You have a very special.
Fixed social position.
You don't even need to express.
You know what you want to do.
Others know what you want to do.
You also know what others know what you want to do.
So why do you have to use emotions to communicate?
No need.
The most is to do a little adjustment.
Then you just smile.
A smile is probably enough.
So the result is.
In addition to people.
There are different ways of expression.
We will also.
There are different ways of understanding other people's expressions.
In fact, this is.
This.
The other side of the board.
I don't need to explain.
It's easy to understand.
As a result, we call this thing.
Emotional culture.
Every culture.
Or every group of people.
Because of their.
The structure of interpersonal relationships.
The structure of their natural relationships.
Form a set.
A unique way of expression and understanding emotions.
It's called emotional culture.
Emotional culture.
Good.
So.
So we.
In this.
In my research.
In fact, what we are going to study is.
The difference in emotional culture.
Then I will.
I will.
Select the United States and Taiwan.
The reason is.
I just told you.
The United States is a country with a very high percentage of individualism.
So he is.
One of the dimensions.
Taiwan.
Although not the highest.
But also.
Among the three highest.
One of them.
South Korea.
South Korea, Japan, Taiwan.
One of them.
Then.
So.
Select these two countries.
He is.
This kind of.
This is called.
Select these two countries.
Can increase us.
In fact, after the increase.
This finding.
This.
Generalizability.
Interpretability.
It can also be used at a lower cost.
Because we put.
This is equal to.
This contrast.
Pull to the maximum.
We use the lowest cost.
See this effect.
Good.
The next question is.
If you go to identify.
These two countries.
Then these two countries.
When expressing gratitude.
What kind of behavior will be used?
That has just been said.
Individualism.
This kind of panic country.
They will form.
Is big.
In theory.
They have to form big.
Because big will be effective.
Emotional expression.
And.
Generally.
More.
Expressive.
Or more.
Observable.
This.
Emotional expression.
In the past.
For gratitude.
In the United States.
At the same time.
Oh.
When people feel grateful.
In addition to saying thank you.
This seems.
There is no cultural difference.
In addition.
Americans will.
Very inclined to.
Body contact.
Including.
Hug.
Handshake.
Including kiss.
Including high five.
Or slap.
And so on.
In the past.
I found that.
If you are grateful.
Ask him what he wants to do.
He will.
Come out.
That's because it's.
Body.
Body interaction.
He has bodily contact.
So he will.
In relation to.
Just say thank you.
Or.
Say thank you.
This.
Is the sound.
Sound.
This.
Communicate.
Channel.
But if you add bodily contact.
There will be one more.
The channel.
So.
It's not easy.
Oh.
Is.
This is.
This.
This is why.
A lot of emotional.
Reason.
So.
Assuming that it will become here.
The United States is relative to Taiwan.
Because of its cultural factors.
So.
When they express their gratitude.
There should be more.
Body.
Behavior.
Conversely.
In fact, it is more special.
Not the other way around.
But on the other hand.
I think this is more special.
Is.
So what is Taiwan going to do?
To express.
In this study.
We put forward a.
Called.
The other.
Question together.
I am now reading.
There is a question.
You read it out.
Because we record.
Or do you let me read it out.
You read it out.
OK, I read it out.
page change.
I understand now.
Because of them.
This question is like this.
Is it because they are a panic-type country?
So raise extreme individualism.
Or because of the original
People who want to panic.
It was originally an individualistic feature.
So I want to panic.
OK, this one.
I think it's a very good question.
I'll answer it later.
Because this is not actually.
This is actually not this project.
The question to be discussed.
Right.
In this project.
They are a
Individualistic culture.
In fact, it is a given.
Then this given.
There is also a lot of data knowledge.
So I don't want to discuss it now.
Why did it become like this?
So I don't want to answer the question now.
But we'll talk about it later.
Discussion time.
Let's talk about this question.
What happened to the culture?
I think this question is very interesting.
Can I do this?
OK, back to Taiwan.
How do you express your gratitude to Taiwan?
We found one.
We went to
Translate some books.
Then I found an act.
Called self-improvement.
English translated into self-improvement.
But this is very strange.
But his Chinese is actually called self-improvement.
Or self-cultivation.
In fact, it is self-cultivation.
Or
Self-cultivation.
Such a thing.
The definition is like this.
Basically, if you are
A good student.
Study hard.
If it's a good kid.
You have to respect your parents.
Because these are your social responsibility.
And social role.
Why is this behavior
A possible way to express gratitude?
Because
Big brother.
Why is it
A possible way to express gratitude?
Because we said before.
Gratitude.
The existence of this emotion.
Because it can help
Promote interpersonal relations.
Then in a
Interpersonal relations.
The structure is already stable.
And it's almost a spoken place.
How do you promote interpersonal relations?
You can't.
You are not expected to build a new relationship.
Or destroy a new relationship.
Or destroy an old relationship.
So what you can do is maintenance.
This is to let the relationship.
In three.
What can be done is to do maintenance.
Or do buy.
No more buy.
No more
Initiate or what.
So this
Buy.
Can do is to put your
Position well.
Because past research has found that.
In this.
I actually.
In our society.
If you put
Own.
This role.
Do it well.
Or when your responsibility is done.
Others will see it.
The result that others can see is that he will come.
Willing to invest in your relationship with you.
And then.
Put your original
This bonding.
Or bond.
Think it's important.
So self-cultivation can actually help.
Relationship.
Stability.
And maintenance.
In our culture.
Give you an example.
This is a big brother.
What am I going to say?
The window on his head.
Why tie a window in that place?
Because this is his job.
This is his job.
His job.
He's playing.
Most people can say.
I must win.
That's because I'm a player.
I just want to win.
I'm cool.
This is not good.
But everyone has.
If there is.
For.
I think everyone is from Taiwan.
So what does it mean to win?
Is.
There should be a little feeling.
That is to say.
Usually we are talking about winning.
I am determined to win.
When you do this thing well.
Usually this thing is our responsibility.
Then we.
For the society.
Or for us.
The surrounding social face.
Including parents.
Or the teacher.
The mayor.
There is a sense of responsibility.
So I'm going to do this thing.
Give him a hard time.
Not just.
It's cool to win.
This is also.
At the same time.
This is what the big brother said.
He said.
I remember in a place.
He will work hard to play.
Because of fans.
Because of the coach.
Because of teammates.
Not just.
Because it's cool to win.
So he is not.
So he is a grateful expression.
But his result.
On the other hand.
He wants to do his job well.
And then.
This is our data.
I can talk a little bit first.
That is to say.
Indeed.
There are victims.
When he feels grateful.
He will.
I will show up to work.
Hard every day.
During practice.
I don't know.
Is this person an athlete?
Or what?
Because he wrote.
Not very sure.
But you can see.
When you feel grateful.
People really want to.
Do your job well.
So the assumption is.
The assumption is.
When grateful.
In the United States.
For Americans.
They would like to.
Use physical contact.
To express gratitude.
In Taiwan.
There will be more.
Want this.
Self-improvement impulse.
Is there a problem here?
Because I'm going to talk about the experiment later.
Very fast.
Very short.
Later.
3.
2.
1.
No good.
We continue.
Good.
There is a problem.
Please say.
You can speak into the microphone.
If this is easier.
Can you hear me?
Yes, I can hear you.
In fact, it's good to speak into the microphone.
Because then we can record the voice directly.
Don't have to repeat.
There are others next to you.
Sorry.
I want to ask.
That self-contact.
With that.
Self-improvement.
These two.
Outcome.
There is no conflict.
Not two.
Conflict.
Things.
That.
Why.
It's possible.
In fact, it will.
Two outcomes.
Is it mixed together?
Oh.
It's possible.
What you say is not confident.
Wait a minute.
What are you not confident about?
You say.
He wants to have a physical contact.
You can also want.
Self-improvement.
Or.
There is a kind of behavior.
He is self-improvement at the same time.
Self-contact.
For example.
You say.
When you say Americans.
They are more.
Feel.
When there is a sense of gratitude.
That.
Taiwanese.
When he feels grateful.
He wants.
Self-improvement.
That.
But.
Physical contact.
With self-improvement.
These two.
There is no conflict.
So is it possible.
In fact, Americans.
When they are grateful.
In addition to wanting physical contact.
I also want self-improvement.
Or.
Taiwanese.
Feel.
When grateful.
Want self-improvement.
Then.
But at the same time.
I also want to do physical contact.
Hey.
Okay.
I think.
I think it's possible.
Both behaviors.
Are motivated.
Right.
Okay.
But why do I think.
So.
Let's talk about it.
Physical contact.
In.
Americans will be higher.
Because.
Physical contact.
Is a big move.
It is often used in.
Initiate.
New relationship.
Because you want.
From.
Originally.
Far.
Social distance.
Become.
Literally.
You can meet this person.
But this.
Relationship.
Change.
In a.
Relationship.
Is in the culture of painting.
In fact, it is not easy to happen.
Not even.
Not allowed.
Like you said.
Thank you very much for your teacher.
Then you go.
Kiss him.
This.
Isn't it weird?
But.
In.
Physical contact.
Is fluid.
Can.
Be allowed to change.
The place.
The relationship between Zhenjing and the teacher.
Maybe it can be allowed.
So I.
These two behaviors.
Is.
When I assume.
Independent assumption.
That is to say.
Not a.
But a.
Do you know what I mean?
It's not a blow.
That is to say.
If your enemy.
The other one will be high.
But I assume the first one.
This.
Physical contact.
Then the United States will be higher than Taiwan.
Then the second is.
Self intimacy.
Taiwan will be higher than the United States.
But it's not a.
Relationship.
Do you know what I'm talking about?
I understand.
Thank you.
it is good.
Oh, by the way.
And then.
I didn't finish this just now.
Self intimacy in the United States.
It's not supposed to be.
I assume it's not very effective.
Relatively ineffective.
Not being used.
The reason is.
Because it's too small.
You're here.
Kill yourself.
Do that.
This behavior is very.
Obviously.
Not very.
Noticeable.
The effect is not dirty.
Especially in.
People don't pay attention to others.
What are you doing.
When.
So this effect is not dirty.
This is not very.
There is no.
Function.
It's not functional.
Check these two.
Two assumptions.
Oh, by the way.
We chose these two assumptions.
Is deliberately.
One high.
Another low.
Another high.
This low.
Make that contrast.
So it is.
Strategically selected.
it is good.
What about study1?
We'll ask the recipient.
Write some first.
He was helped.
Very happy.
Very grateful experience.
And then.
Ask him to do one.
No relevant.
Task.
In this task.
Please write something casually.
He usually.
In everyday life.
Will be used to express gratitude.
He can write one to seven.
He wrote it himself.
See how many he wants to write.
At least one.
At most seven.
But this is with the previous.
The experience of writing is not related.
Come again.
We asked him to go back.
Uh.
The previous writing experience.
And then in front of the camera.
Record a passage.
With.
He felt.
Let him feel grateful.
This person.
Express his gratitude.
And.
That instruction is to say.
Let him.
It's like interacting with this person.
The same.
And then this movie.
It looks like this.
Like this.
So.
Zha Yong said this movie.
If I broadcast it.
There will be a very serious lag.
So I put this.
This.
The website is pasted in the dialogue window.
Then everyone went to click on it.
Separately.
Tell me after watching.
It should be.
Sorry.
I made a mistake. I didn't cut this video.
You only need to watch 1 minute and a half.
1 minute should be enough.
There's nothing after that.
He doesn't know what to say.
Sorry.
I made a mistake.
You only need to watch 1 minute and a half.
1 minute should be enough.
He doesn't know what to say.
This is an example.
After all, he insists that his self-improvement is needed.
Or when he has no one to support him, he argues withkh his facial expression.
Self-improvement is a nonsense.
This is the data we have collected.
Next, we will ask some research assistants to grade these videos.
If this video has hug or bodily contact, this video will get 1 point.
Lastly, if this video has hug or bodily contact, this video will get 1 point.
If this video has reciprocity, this video will get 1 point.
So we are going to compare the presence and absence of these videos.
It's a Logistic Multi-Level Linear Model.
In this video, we have written 1-7 different ways of expression.
Based on these, we can classify the body contact, self-improvement, reciprocity.
There are two of them are self-improvement, and three of them are body contact.
My self-improvement is 1 out of 3, so it's 33%.
My body contact is 50%, because it's 50% of my expression toolbox.
Do you understand?
So we can classify the data in this way.
In this task, we have self-improvement, body contact, and reciprocity.
We use uTest to analyze the data.
You don't need to care about the test, it's just an analysis of the data.
Let's see the result.
In this result, there is a bar.
This bar is the video data.
The box above is the task data.
Do you know what p-value is?
If you don't know, just say you don't know.
3, 2, 1
Ok, everyone knows.
Let's say everyone knows what p-value is.
In the body contact, the blue bar is America, and the red bar is Taiwan.
I don't like the red bar is Taiwan, but I didn't think about it when I chose the color.
The Americans also don't know why I don't like the red bar.
Anyway, it's red.
As you can see, the body contact is higher than Taiwan in general touch.
You can't see the error bar here, but it's higher.
The hug is also high.
In the writing data, the Americans also mentioned more body contact-related methods.
But this one is close, p-value is 0.055.
Let's look at self-improvement.
The results of self-improvement are also close, but now the direction is all the opposite.
Taiwan is better at self-improvement than the U.S.
I don't know how they do it, but at least they say they do it well.
There are more videos explaining that self-improvement is a way of expression.
In the writing data, the Americans also mentioned more self-improvement-related methods.
Finally, there is no noticeable difference in reciprocity or reciprocating kindness.
Even though the blue bar is higher, but there is no noticeable difference.
The results support our assumption.
Taiwan is better at self-improvement than the U.S.
The U.S. uses more body contact.
There is no noticeable difference in reciprocity.
The background information of the victim is not important.
The only thing I want to talk about is this.
In this study,
Taiwan is in NTSU, National Taiwan Sport University.
The victim is in NTSU, and the U.S. is in UNC.
This will cause a problem.
I don't know if you can see my slide.
The U.S. is in the U.S., and the Taiwanese are in Taiwan.
This will cause a problem.
This is because the two groups of people have different cultures, so they have different behaviors and preferences.
Or because they were experimented in different places.
Or because they were experimented in different places, so they have different languages.
If the U.S. people can understand Chinese, they will also behave like Taiwanese.
Or do the same in Taiwan.
This is a confounding.
In Study 2, a methodological change is that we collect information from Taiwanese in the U.S.
We collect information from Taiwanese in the U.N.C.
We use English, so there is no linguistic priming.
We were asked by a reviewer, how do you know this has anything to do with gratitude?
For example, if you ask a Taiwanese, what are you doing right now?
You don't need any background information.
You will see that Taiwanese are more self-improving.
They are self-improving. They are studying and working all day.
The U.S. people will report to the U.N.C. at any time.
The reviewer will ask, how do you know this is not a baseline difference?
How does this have anything to do with gratitude?
Another example, when we are happy, we watch a comedy.
It's funny. We bump into each other.
Look at the NBA players.
One shot, three points.
They bump into each other.
This has nothing to do with gratitude.
I bumped into him.
It's not his fault.
Maybe he passed the ball to me.
Not necessarily.
So body contact doesn't have to happen in gratitude.
There may be other positive emotions.
On the other hand, is self-improvement possible in other positive emotions?
It's possible.
When I feel that I am more powerful, I am more capable.
Am I theoretically more capable of self-improvement?
It's possible.
So self-improvement may not necessarily be gratitude.
It's just a general positivity.
This positivity indicates that I have more resources now to do this.
Another thing we need to control in Study 2 is
another positive emotion.
We need to show that this difference
is not entirely caused by gratitude,
but gratitude has a special effect
on the cultural difference.
So we ask the reader
when a stranger or a close other
feels grateful
or amused
by our positive emotions.
There are 4 conditions.
2x2
4 conditions
The reader will answer 4 times
in different combinations.
The reader will ask
if you want to thank this person
verbally
or touch that person
for whom you feel thankful.
This is body contact.
Repay the person.
This is reciprocity.
Pay you forward means
you are good to me,
I am good to the third person.
Socialize with the person.
This is another thing that was mentioned in Study 1.
He is good to me.
I feel grateful.
Let's go shopping with him tomorrow morning.
In this behavior,
shopping does not really do anything to this person.
But this is a socialization behavior.
Let's play together.
We think this behavior cannot be
because it does not
have a direct benefit to the other person.
So it cannot be reciprocity.
He did not pay you forward because there is no third person.
Will there be touch? I don't know.
It's not verbally thanks.
Verbal thanks means I will thank him.
So he is isolated.
Finally, improve yourself.
This is self-improvement.
So how many questions does the reader answer?
2x2x123456
Answer 24 questions.
Finally,
for each behavior,
for each emotion,
for each relationship,
we ask two different questions.
The first one is
how likely you are
to do this behavior.
This is the likelihood
and preference of their behavior.
The other one is
whether you want to do it or not.
But generally, if someone does it,
do you think this behavior is bizarre?
Can you understand?
This is the second question.
Is it understandable?
OK.
What's the question?
The reader did a lot of rating.
3, 2, 1
Let's assume there is no question.
Let's look at the result.
This analysis is tricky
because we don't compare
the scores of Taiwanese and Americans.
In the past,
I found that
this kind of rating scale
is problematic in cross-cultural research.
Because some people
such as Japanese, Taiwanese,
and South Korean
will deliberately avoid
extreme scores.
For example,
if the score is 1 to 9,
we will cut it off.
If the score is 2 to 8,
No matter what the score is,
we will cut it off.
Why?
Because
if you think about
the world of Tai Chi,
or the so-called
bias thinking,
if I ask you
if you think you are smart,
you might say
you think you are smart,
but are you extremely smart?
You might say no.
Then you might think
there are smart people in the world.
But are you really stupid?
Probably not.
There are probably more stupid people in the world.
So you go down to the bottom,
but you don't see the bottom,
and you go back.
So in such a
extremist culture,
people tend to avoid extreme scores.
Any score is.
So we made a
adjustment here.
We standardize the scores
of Taiwan and the US.
We standardize the scores of Taiwan and the US.
We only keep within cultural variation.
Then we do
the principal component analysis.
No matter what you know,
I don't need to explain.
I will explain how to interpret the result later.
Then we put these six
behaviors
in each culture.
So the scores of each culture
are standardized to 0.
mean to 0, standard deviation to 1.
Then for these six scores, we run the principal component analysis.
Then we found that
these six scores
can form two components.
With these two components,
we can effectively summarize
the variation of these six behaviors.
We named these two components
expression and affiliation.
You will know why later.
But let's talk about how to interpret the result.
As you can see,
there are six behaviors.
The inner circle of the radar
is negative 0.5 to 0.
For example,
if reciprocating kindness is 0,
it has nothing to do with the expression component.
If it is negative,
it is completely negative.
If the component is higher,
the reciprocating kindness will be lower.
The middle circle is 0 to 0.5.
The outer circle is 0.5 to 1.
It's a strong link.
There are six behaviors.
The blue line is the same as the United States.
For the United States,
the expression component
can summarize
some behavior variations.
The most is verbal acknowledgement.
It's almost equal to verbal acknowledgement.
Perfect correlation.
There is also reciprocating kindness.
These three behaviors
can be used on the spot.
Body contact
has a high loading.
For the Americans,
for the Americans,
the use of body contact
is similar to verbal acknowledgement.
Self-improvement is almost zero.
But if you look at the results in Taiwan,
verbal acknowledgement,
reciprocating kindness,
and pay you forward are all outside the circle.
We will use these three behaviors
to express gratitude.
We all know in our lives.
But body contact is now
I remember this point 3.
A very awkward position.
But at the same time,
self-improvement has gone out.
Self-improvement
is similar to
verbal acknowledgement,
pay you forward,
and reciprocating kindness.
We see that
these three behaviors
verbal acknowledgement, pay you forward,
and reciprocating kindness
are not cultural differences.
But
the two behaviors
self-improvement and body contact
are different.
The two behaviors are different.
This component is named
expression
because it is
derived from verbal acknowledgement
and reciprocating kindness.
It is very expressive.
On the other hand,
the second component
is socializing.
It is more interactive.
The two cultures are relatively high.
Interestingly,
if the component 1
is not explained,
it will be pushed here, including socializing.
For both cultures, socializing is pushed here.
We call it affiliation.
But for Americans,
self-improvement is pushed here.
Body contact is negative.
For Taiwanese,
self-improvement is not
under the same category as socializing.
self-improvement is not under the same category as socializing.
But body contact is.
You can imagine.
When do we have contact with others?
Only in a long-term, intimate relationship.
But when can we do self-improvement?
When can we do self-improvement?
When it's time to do it.
So it is expression.
But affiliation-wise,
body contact is the concept.
But in contrast,
What to do is your own business.
But for long-term relationship,
they will do self-improvement.
But it's not in the same context.
Last one.
Excluding asking people in these two cultures,
asking people in these two cultures,
can you understand?
If someone did it,
if someone did it,
It was not very well understood.
The picture you see is the part of understanding.
There is little difference between the two cultures,
Especially the expression,
the Americans and Taiwanese
almost overlap.
This shows that Americans
can understand what self-improvement is.
It can be used to express gratitude.
Taiwan is OK.
But naturally,
it's not that the two cultures can't understand each other.
It's just that their behavior choices are different.
The implication of this is that
the expression of gratitude
The expression of gratitude
is a conscious behavior.
In front of me,
I can think of these options,
and I consciously choose this
because it fits my context
or my culture or cultural context.
or my cultural context.
My options are only some.
Only in my culture.
Let's summarize it.
Verbal acknowledgment,
reciprocal kindness, and paying you forward
are the same in both cultures.
But bodily contact
Bye-bye.
Sky is gone.
In the US,
bodily contact
and these three universal behaviors
are tied together,
but there is no self-improvement.
On the other hand, in Taiwan,
self-improvement is tied,
but bodily contact is not.
What is implication?
We call it universal.
Obviously,
emotions are expressed
in different cultures.
Is there anything
in cross-cultural
that is universal?
In our research,
although the behavior is different,
but the function,
at least gratitude,
is the same.
It is to build or maintain relationships.
Gratitude is used to support
interpersonal relationships.
Just because interpersonal relationships
are in different cultures,
in different structures,
in different ways,
so you have to fit the relational structure
to use different relationships.
So functional universal exists.
If you keep this function
in the second line,
if you make this function
a constant,
then you have to adjust the behavior
to fit the culture.
That's what we want to say.
Thank you.
Any questions?
Let me answer the question.
Is it because the country is
confused, so it develops extreme
individualism, or
is it because the people in the country
have the characteristics of individualism?
I think this question can be divided into
two levels.
The first is that
they are such a country,
so they develop such a culture.
Then you dig up the culture,
it may not be individualism,
it may not be confusion.
So is it the current situation
that affects their culture,
or is it the current culture
that affects their current situation?
Or is it a specific culture,
or is it American culture?
Is it because they are in a
confused environment,
or is it American culture?
Is it a specific case,
or is it a general culture?
Let me make it simple.
It's the United States.
I think both exist in the United States.
The history of the United States
is about immigration.
Immigration to a new continent.
So it's a country
that's in a state of confusion.
In such a natural environment,
as I just argued,
you need to form
a form of individualism
and a way of
living
to create
a new natural environment,
a new continent.
So it looks like
it's possible for
confusion to form individualism.
But at the same time,
why did Mayflower
come to the United States in the first place?
Because of religious reform.
What is religious reform?
It's when churches
form a rigid
social organization.
They want to
connect with God.
Is this religious reform?
No, it's not.
Mayflower is the UK.
But if we
look at new religion reform
it's a form of individualism.
Individualism
forces people to
live in a state of confusion.
That's where the UK came from.
But what I'm talking about
is American culture and natural environment.
If you
dig it up
into an empty X,
what would it be?
If you dig it up into an empty X,
I think both are possible.
Maybe
we need more
evidence to support it.
But at least
in East Asian culture,
I think both
are possible.
A study found that
in places where
there's a flood,
compared to
wheat fields,
it's easier to
form collectivism.
Why?
Because you need to
work with others.
So natural environment
creates culture.
On the other hand,
people who are
used to collectivism
will they
enhance the environment?
I think they will.
It's simple.
You can't
just let it go.
It's been happening in history.
So
I think the UK-UK relationship
is also possible, at least in East Asian culture.
But I can't say
how far it can go.
I've answered this question.
Here's another question.
There's a small question.
Have you seen a similar research
but in European culture?
I'm curious
if European culture is similar to
American or Asian culture.
Some European cultures
are similar.
I've seen
a similar article.
It's from the UK.
The result
is my interpretation.
The UK's gratitude
is stuck
in the American way
and the
collectivism way.
I think the article
is funny.
It's like
all people see white people
as the same race,
but all research is about Americans.
All people see
Western culture as the same race,
but it's all about Americans.
He can't stand it
because he's British.
Fukuyama
talks about
trust between people
as a
social capital.
Social capital is
something that can be fulfilled.
Let me put it this way.
He thinks people's trust
can be fulfilled.
He's a
Japanese-American.
His first name is
Francis.
He's American.
He has a strong Japanese identity.
He thinks
culture should be divided.
He looks at Italy,
Germany,
France, South and North.
He divides them.
His argument is
that
he divides
several different collectivism.
At least he thinks
Italy,
South and
Mexico,
and some South American countries
are collectivism.
I don't know if you have
friends in Mexico.
Their family concept is anti-Semitism.
It's like
East Asian culture.
They also have
honor culture.
If you insult
my family,
I'll kill you.
If you insult my family,
But I have to kill you.
You can see this
in the UK
and Mexico.
That's right.
Fashion Fury is like this.
Everything is for family.
When I was in class,
I told my students
that it's quite special.
You're investigating
a car thief.
You can catch him.
But you can't.
He felt the strong family bond.
So he
stole a car.
That's Fashion Fury.
So
there's
another thing
I want to say.
We didn't
push it
to individualism
and collectivism.
When we talk about
individualism, we're talking about
America.
Collectivism is like
Taiwan, Japan, Korea.
We don't know
whether other countries
can fit
this
dimensionalized
distinction.
So I'm careful
comparing Taiwan and America.
These two specific
entities.
We're not
drawing two dots on a dimension.
But when we draw,
we still follow
the past research.
It's a limitation.
Any other questions?
Hello.
You go first.
The self-improvement
you mentioned earlier.
Is it
a common
professional term?
Or
is it special?
It sounds
like
you're grateful
for the self-improvement.
It sounds like
you want to do
what you want
according to your expectations.
You want to satisfy
your partner's expectations.
But what I do
when I satisfy
my partner's expectations
doesn't mean
I'm improving something.
Do you understand?
I understand.
In this case,
your research still
classified as self-improvement.
But in fact,
it's not improving anything.
It's just satisfying
your partner's expectations.
That's what I mean.
I agree.
From this perspective,
it's still
satisfying your partner's expectations.
It's like reciprocity.
But interestingly,
if we ask
what you expect
from your partner,
you expect
a better
social role.
For example,
if my mom wants me to become
a better student,
or she wants me to repay her.
There's a cultural difference
in expectation.
If you say
you satisfy your partner's expectations,
but we found
cultural differences.
You're just
using the difference
in expectation
to explain.
Otherwise,
the result won't be there.
I think
your question is
interesting and good.
Because it shows
that
on the surface,
there's a cultural difference
in appreciation
and universality.
But
we need to dig deeper.
For example,
you think the expectation is the same,
but the result
is different.
I can accept that.
Do you have an answer?
Yes.
There's an interesting point
about expectation.
I didn't expect that.
I have another question.
You said that
appreciation can help
interpersonal relationships.
Am I right?
Yes.
When you talk about interpersonal relationships,
you need to think about yourself
and your partner.
When I appreciate my partner,
it's just a one-way relationship.
It's not about
how my partner reacts to my appreciation.
If it's not about
how my partner reacts to my appreciation,
it's hard to talk about
the impact of appreciation
on interpersonal relationships.
I only talked about one-way relationship.
I didn't talk about
how my partner reacts to my appreciation.
I can't talk about
how my relationship
with my partner
will improve
after the whole process.
If we need to think about
how to improve
interpersonal relationships,
we need to think about
how to improve
our partner's reaction.
How to design
such a research?
I think
this is a
good question.
I think
this is a good question.
It sounds like
it's a compliment.
I think
it's a good question.
As I said before,
I totally agree with you.
emotion culture
has a set of
ways of expression.
In addition to a group of people
who are used to this way of expression,
at the same time,
a group of people
who can understand
their partner's way of expression
can achieve
their goal.
Otherwise, it's useless.
So,
in this project,
in addition to the difference in expression,
we also assume
the difference in perception.
As you said,
people who receive appreciation
can interpret it
as expected,
and turn this interpretation
into
a friendly signal
to promote the relationship.
We are doing this now.
This should not be
an answer to your question.
I just said I agree.
We are doing this now.
But I understand.
As you said,
when we study
how a person expresses
his appreciation,
it also represents
appreciation.
I can understand.
Thank you.
Okay.
Thank you, everyone.
We are running out of time.
But it was a great talk.
Thank you for your questions.
Thank you again to our speaker,
Zhang Yanping.
Thank you, everyone.
Now, it's my turn to share the screen.
Wait for me.
Now,
can you see
my screen?
Can you?
I can see myself.
So,
you can see Zhang Yanping's website, right?
Can you?
Okay.
If you have any questions,
you can go to this website,
sites.google.com
slash view
slash ypzhang.
This is Zhang Yanping's website.
If you have any questions,
or if you want to collaborate,
you can contact him.
Thank you again, Zhang Yanping.
That's all for today.
Thank you, everyone.
Bye-bye.
Oh, I forgot to tell you.
Next week, it's my turn to talk.
The topic is
quite technical.
Next week, it's cryogenic engineering
in various
advanced experiments.
See you next week.
Bye-bye.