Okay, no problem.
Hello everyone, I'm Dinghao.
I'm a postdoc at Caltech.
The topic I'm going to talk about
is mainly my research on some of my papers.
My research is about
designing an artificial system
and hoping to use that system to detect cell-cell contacts.
My ultimate goal is to use this system
to dissect the entire neural circuit.
Oh, in the field of neuroscience,
the most important answer that everyone wants to know
is how our brain functions,
so that we have all kinds of different emotions
and how reactions to the environment stimulate.
How to stimulate.
But about 100 years ago,
Raymond Kahar had a very elegant study.
And the elegant study proved that
our brain or neural system
is mainly operated by these neurons or other cells
to transmit all kinds of neural messages
and ultimately have a behavior.
This is a very famous neural doctrine.
So a lot of research now
is focused on how different neurons
communicate with each other.
This is a very complicated problem
because our brain is a huge machine.
Like what I'm showing in this picture,
it's a reward circuit.
This actually includes a lot of brain areas,
like the hippocampus, prefrontal cortex,
and the famous basal ganglia,
nucleus, convent, VTA.
These different brain areas connect with each other
and operate and calculate
to achieve a goal.
And another more complicated aspect
is that even in the same brain area,
there are different neurons
that receive different messages.
And after synchronization,
it's transmitted to another brain area.
And the calculation of the other brain area
may be transmitted back.
So these connections are what we...
What we want to answer right now
is the idea of connectome.
We hope that by understanding these connectome,
we can have a blueprint
of how our brain or neural system
is wired.
And then we can use this basic knowledge
to calculate
the changes in the message transmission
of the neural cells
that may lead to different behaviors.
Like this.
But in fact,
in addition to neural cells,
there are many other different cells,
such as glial cells.
Many studies have found that
these glial cells
actually affect the function of our neural neurons.
For example,
like this astrocyte,
the heart-shaped neural cell,
is...
It has been found that it can actually
clean up some of our neurotransmitters
and make it turn over faster.
And it's also found that...
Sorry.
It's found that it can actually transmit some signal
and affect the whole synaptic property.
So the connectome or microcircuit
that we originally thought of
is like this.
In addition to neural cells,
we still need to consider
the function of these neural glial cells
to have a more complete picture
of how our brain functions.
And then I mentioned earlier
that understanding these microcircuits
can help us know how our brain works.
Another point is that
many...
We already know that there are many neurological disorders.
It actually has something to do with
the wiring of the neural circuit.
Like schizophrenia,
phrenia,
or some psychological diseases.
It actually has something to do with it.
If we know how the normal brain works,
we can further study
the causes of these disorders.
I hope to get some answers
to help these patients.
So far,
there are many different tools
that have been developed
to help us understand
how to dissect,
that is, to analyze the entire brain circuit
or neural connection.
Here are some examples that are commonly used.
For example, Serial Electron Microscopy,
which is an electronic microscope.
There is another one called GRASP.
Its full name is
GFP Green Fluorescent Protein Reconstitution
Across Synaptic Partner.
This means that it has a fluorescent protein
that divides engineering into two parts.
I will explain this later.
There is also Tango.
There is another popular tool
called Rabie Virus
to trace neural connection.
These are all great tools,
but they all have different
shortcomings.
For example, Serial EM
is to take a small sample
and cut it into pieces.
Then use EM to take the whole image
and then reconstruct it.
Then look at its very fine-detailed
neural morphology
or the connection of different neural cells.
Usually, a small one-millimeter-cube
size sample
takes about five or six years
to complete its analysis.
It also requires a lot of human power.
So this is not a very efficient method.
Because it is not very efficient,
it can only analyze a small sample of an animal.
If you want to analyze 10 different animals,
different variations,
it may be a bit difficult
or require more time and more manpower.
Another is CRESP, a genetic tool.
It can be used in
mice or
I'm going to talk about Drosophila fruit flies.
It is mainly divided into two parts of this fluorescent protein.
Normally, it emits green light.
After dividing it into two parts,
they will not emit light.
Only when the two parts are very close,
they will be re-combined
like this.
So the two parts themselves do not emit light.
When they are re-combined, they will emit light,
and you can see the green light.
Then it can detect
that two cells are close to each other.
Its disadvantage is that
it...
Sorry.
It can only see where it is in contact with.
It can't make any further modifications
to affect cell poverty.
In addition,
its binding is irreversible.
So there is a concern that
it may affect the connection between the cells.
The dynamic.
Connection to dynamic.
Another system is called Tango.
It mainly has a G-protein couple receptor.
Its feature is that
when it binds its ligand,
it will recruit a protein called arresting.
Arresting comes to activate
its downstream signaling transduction.
Then the engineer added a protease to this protein.
Then this receptor has a transcription factor.
Then there is a sequence in front of it
that will be cut by this protease.
So when the protein is binded,
the protease will cut this part.
Then it will release the intracellular transcription factor
and drive downstream gene excretion.
Its advantage is that
it has these reported proteins,
either fluorescent proteins
or mutant proteins.
You can control some of the features in its cells.
But the disadvantage is that
it is only limited to G-protein couple receptors.
In our neural system,
there are many...
For example, this is a dopamine receptor.
It is a G-protein couple receptor.
But there are many receptors that are just IN channels.
So it can't be used in this place.
In the mammalian,
there is a very popular tool
called re-engineering the RebVirus.
It can monosynaptically trace upstream neurons.
The point that needs to be considered
is that we need to do surgery
to inject this virus into the brain
to express,
to let this virus
to transmit to its Gag cells.
It has cytotoxicity.
So usually the research
can only be completed within a week.
Otherwise, the cells will die.
But another point is that
I just mentioned that it can only be used in the mammalian.
Even so, its efficiency is not very good.
I have tried this tool before.
Different brain regions.
Some brain regions may have special neurons.
It's harder to let the RebVirus
jump to their upstream partner.
So the important purpose of my research
is to generate a system
that can be used on all transgenic animals.
I hope it won't have any toxicity.
So we can safely study
the property and function of these cells.
In addition to tracing the neuron
or the connection between the cells,
we can also manipulate their property.
So my main design here is that
if a cell, not necessarily a neuron,
has a ligand
and the other cells have a corresponding receptor,
when these two cells have contact,
the binding will generate a cell signaling
to the downstream cell.
Then we can either express some fluorescent reporter protein,
or express some gene or mutant that we are interested in.
Or it can be RNAi.
So here, we used a very important
signaling pathway in animals,
Delta protein and Notch protein's signaling pathway.
So let me briefly introduce
the structure of Notch protein.
It has a very long hRSA domain.
Most of it is EGF repeat.
This domain will bind its ligand, Delta,
and when they bind,
the current hypothesis is that
if the ligand is endocytosed,
that is, if it is brought in by the cell membrane,
it will generate a force.
It will open this structure called NRR.
After Notch binds,
there will be two cutting points
that will be cut off by Proteus.
One is S2 and the other is S3.
So the original S2 cutting point
is in the NRR structure.
So it's embedded inside the structure,
and Proteus can't digest the S2 site.
So it won't be cut off
until Delta binds.
After it binds, it opens this structure,
and the S2 site can be cut off.
Next, its transmembrane domain
also has a cutting point called S3.
S3 will also be cut off.
Then its intracellular domain
is a transcription factor.
It can move to the cell membrane
to activate downstream gene expression.
So here we use this logic.
We replace some domains
that will affect the cell's endogenous domain,
like EGF repeat,
it will bind the endogenous Delta ligand.
So we replace it with an antibody here.
Then its intracellular domain
will drive endogenous downstream gene expression.
So we also replace it
with a yeast transcription factor called GAL4.
So our idea is that
our new synthetic receptor
can recognize its own ligand.
I'm using CD19 here.
After it binds,
it uses the NRR domain in the middle
and transmembrane domain.
It will have S2, S3 cleavage.
Then it will release intracellular GAL4.
Then it can drive either GFP
or any gene expression.
It depends on what kind of study we want to do.
We call this whole section track.
It's Transcellular Activation of Transcription.
First, I'll test
whether our designed ligand and receptor can work.
So we use it in the cell line.
Here I show you the control.
Red represents the ligand.
The cell line with or without ligand.
My reporter is GFP.
So when you see the cell with receptor,
it has no GFP
because the co-culture cell has no ligand.
When I change the co-culture cell
to the cell with CD19,
you can see that most of the receptors
and positive cells
start to show GFP.
Here you can see the difference in the amount of GFP.
You can see that the amount of GFP
increases with the co-culture time.
The blue line is the control cell.
The orange line is the test group.
To make sure that they have cell-cell contact,
not because my ligand-positive cell
releases any weird factor
to trigger the downstream gene expression.
So I put the receptor cell
and the ligand-positive cell
in the same play.
But I put less CD19.
So they generate their own colonies.
When they grow up,
only when the two colonies
have direct contact with each other,
the ligand-cell line and the receptor-cell line
will have contact.
This is the receptor-positive colony.
This is the ligand-positive colony.
Only when they have direct contact with each other,
the cells produce green ligand.
The rest are dark.
We use the cell-cell line to prove
that our system can function normally
and detect cell-cell contact.
We hope to use it in the in vivo system.
We use the fruit-gene model.
It is a well-established genetic model.
We have a lot of tools to study it.
The life cycle is relatively short.
The fruit-gene model is about two weeks
from the soft to the mature.
The most important thing is that
the nerve system is similar to the mammalian brain.
We hope to use the nerve system
to imply the mammalian brain.
Let me briefly introduce the central nervous system of Drosophila.
They still have neurons and glia.
Their neurons are not like our brain.
There are a bunch of neurons in the brain.
Their synapses are in the same area.
Drosophila's cell body is mainly
around the edge of the nervous system.
These regions have no synapses or connections.
This is the area where the synapse is located.
Besides neurons, there are many other glia cells.
I will introduce these in more detail later.
One thing to remember is that
most of the things I will talk about later are not neurons.
First, we want to test
whether our system can detect any different cell-cell contact.
Next, we want to see
whether our system can detect
neural-to-neural contact.
Next, we want to see
whether our system can detect
neural-to-neural contact.
First, it's glial-to-neural.
There are different types of glial cells
in ToSoftware.
Different glial cells
have different levels of contact.
For example,
surface glial
is like a protective film.
They don't have much contact
with other types of glial cells.
For example, cortex glial
is protected by
neural soma.
Astrocyte is infiltrated
by synapse.
Different types of astrocyte
have more contact with neural soma.
First,
if a person is in a glial cell,
can we detect neural-to-neural contact?
We display receptor protein
in all neurons.
Next, we display it
in glial cell ligand.
The diagram shows
the lava brain of Drosophila.
There are two parts, the central brain
and the ventral nerve core,
which is like the spinal cord.
If there is no ligand,
Drosophila's background is weak.
Only in other tissues.
When ligand is shown in astrocytes,
many neurons are labeled.
This is because
ligand and receptor are combined
to trigger GFP protein.
This is another driver.
It is called ELAM.
This is an astrocyte-specific gene.
As you can see,
ligand is shown in astrocytes.
Ripple is shown in glial cells.
The pattern is different.
I will zoom in later.
We don't see much GFP expression.
We don't see much ligand expression.
The neurons project the process
to the glial cells.
That's the reason
the neurons show strong GFP expression.
that's the reason the neurons show strong GFP expression.
Now,
this proves
that this tool can work in Drosophila.
Can we use our system
to label astrocytes?
Mainly because
astrocytes has been proven
to control synaptic function.
It can adjust synaptic contact
to remove unused synaptic
It can help synaptic formation
astrocyte is able to help
neurotransmitter
it can control the neurotransmitter release
It can control neuronal activity
In theory, all these studies depict
that astrocytes are homogenous
So now they explore
if you knock down gene function
or mutate gene
all the astrocytes will be affected
Studies can't say
I want to look at this area
to change this part of the astrocyte
to look at the specific function of this part of the astrocyte
So we want to use our system
if we can selectively label
the neurons in the brain
we can selectively label
the astrocytes in the brain
So our idea is
we want to show the ligand in a different way
in the neuron
this neuron innovates this neuron
There are many different astrocytes around here
Maybe only a part of it will go to this place
to control the function of this neuron
We just want to selectively label this astrocyte
and not this astrocyte
So we want to show the receptor in all the astrocytes
and show the ligand in different neurons
and selectively label the sub-population of the astrocytes
I hope we can study the astrocyte function more precisely after the improvement
So the first thing I use is
the same brain of the fruit fly
The first choice is the mushroom body neuron
There are about 600 mushroom body neurons called K-on cells in the brain
The reason why people are interested in mushroom body
is because it is an important structure of alphanumeric learning and memory
So here we show you a control
If there is no ligand in the K-on cells
then we see very few alphanumeric cells
The purple here is the glial cell marker
So I just want to tell you
After we label these cells, it will actually be a glial cell
So when I show the ligand in the mushroom body
We can see that we label the astrocytes around it
So the red here is the mushroom body
We can see that these astrocytes
This is a single-plane confocal image
So we can see that these astrocytes are really
how to say
next to the ligand positive neuron process
They have intermingled to each other
It's surrounded by the ligand positive cell
We want to further test our system
how robust our system is
So we want to use fewer cells
So there were about 600 mushroom body neurons
Now there are only 21 alphanumeric neurons
The alphanumeric neuron is the cell body
It's at the tip of the head
It will project a very long axon
to the Drosophila lava brain
This area is called the antenna lobe
It's a bit like our mammalian sleeves
They will receive the olfactory sensory input
The first thing we see here is the control
Without ligand, the antenna lobe is very clean
When the ligand is shown in the olfactory sensory neuron axon terminal
We can label these astrocytes
that infiltrate the antenna lobe region
We want to narrow it down further
to four cells
Here we use a PDF neuron
It's a very important circadian pacemaker
If you remember, this year's Nobel Peace Prize
was about the function of the PDF neuron
There are only four PDF neurons in the lava brain
in each hemisphere
They only have a very thin axon
and project to the dorsal part of the brain
We want to see if our system can detect
such a small connection between the astrocyte and the axon
Contact
Here I show you the control
I forgot to mention
The PDF neurons I use
are not only in the central brain
but also in the ventral nerve core
These are the PDF positive neurons
I also look at the ventral nerve core
Here we can see that the control is very clean
If a ligand is present in the PDF neuron
We can label the astrocytes
that make contact with the PDF neuron
Here I show you a few different samples
We can see that our system is very consistent
We can see consistent labeling in different animals
The next question we want to ask is
Can our system let us understand
compared to the previous study
what's the new thing that we can know by our system
The previous study showed that
the astrocyte in the ventral nerve core
the distribution is very stereotypical
Different astrocytes
are located in different locations
They are located in different locations
They are located in a fixed area
For example, the red astrocyte
is in the dorsal lateral part of the ventral nerve core
It only innovates the dorsal lateral part
It only labels the lateral part of the ventral nerve core
The yellow one is in the dorsal midline
It labels the dorsal midline part of the ventral nerve core
The astrocyte in the ventral part
labels the ventral midline part of the ventral nerve core
This study shows that
the astrocyte is boring
It doesn't change much
The ventral nerve core is a very stereotypical structure
It's a different repeat of the neural mirror
It's a repeated circuit
I don't know if the central brain has a more complex system
I use LIGAND to represent the Ophiatory Sensor Neuron
We want to know if the astrocyte near the ventral nerve
has a different distribution
We have the induction
We divide the ventral nerve into 8 different areas
I want to see where the astrocyte is
I found that the cell body of the astrocyte
is mainly in the medial part
the medial sector and the ventral lateral sector
This is more in line with the previous research
where is the astrocyte near the ventral nerve
They also know that it is mainly in these two parts
But further research on the distribution of different individuals
I found that the astrocyte infiltration is different
In the brain, the astrocyte is mainly located in the lateral part
The astrocyte is mainly in the medial part
The two areas are only one astrocyte
But in this area, I have labeled three different astrocytes
In conclusion, in the central brain of Drosophila
it is not as stereotypical as the ventral nerve core
it has more diversity or change
We hope that in the future
we can use our system to manipulate the astrocyte properties
and see if the population of the astrocyte
will affect any special function
or it actually needs a larger population
to manipulate the neural signaling path
In addition, I only study the astrocyte
In the future, we hope to expand our tool
In addition to the astrocyte glial cell
we can study other different glial cells
such as cortex glial
It is wrapped outside the cell neurons
Its function is probably very different from the astrocyte
We hope to do further research in the future
In the next part, I want to focus on neural-to-neural
We use the same design
to test whether it can be used in
tracing neural-to-neural connection
We mainly focus on Drosophila's olfactory system
I mentioned the olfactory sensor neuron
Why do we want to use this system?
Because the connectome here has been studied very thoroughly
It can be used in DSN or EM
So we know that
if we express the ligand on a certain type of neuron
it may be connected to some different neurons
So we can know if our system
has only labeled some new things
or if it has missed some different things
to test whether our system is perfect
So in the antenna lobe
the olfactory sensor neuron we just mentioned
will project its axon to the antenna lobe
Different olfactory sensor neurons
will only show one olfactory receptor
These olfactory sensor neurons
will only innovate to a certain
antenna lobe called gomulus
It will be connected to a certain type of projection neuron
The projection neuron is green
It will pass the olfactory sensor input
to the olfactory system
like the mushroom body
In addition to the projection neuron
the antenna lobe has another type of neuron
called local interneuron
It is a GABAergic inhibitor neuron
It will innovate the entire antenna lobe
to be a bridge between different gomulus
In the LABA central nervous system
if there is no ligand
we can see that the background is very weak
There is no other labeling
But if I put the ligand in the olfactory sensor neuron
we can see that
we can label a few downstream neurons
There are some markers
These neurons are GABAergic neurons
It means that they are local interneurons
But in this case
we don't see the main projection neurons
being labeled
So
In the current design
The track system
is not yet
How to say
optimized
to detect
neural neural contact
So
We missed a lot
We want to say that there will be labels
Maybe
labeled neurons
So in the future
we may need to make further improvements
to improve our system
to make use of the new neural circuits
There are some new promising results
Hope to share with you soon
I think that's it
Thank you
Hello
How this is
Hi
Hello
Can you hear me?
Yes
I see a question
Can we use it on humans?
At the moment, we can't
Because we can't
Because my system is mainly used on
transgenic animals
So I don't know if CRISPR
will develop to what level
Will it be able to generate transgenic humans?
If it doesn't work
then we probably
can't use it
And
But the advantage of this tool is
we can use it on different animals
If CRISPR is so successful
then it can be very convenient
to use it on transgenic
like a fish
or other non-genetic
For example
I saw a dolphin
It has a very special behavior
It draws a beautiful picture to attract the opposite sex
I think its neural circuit is really amazing
I want to study it
If we use my tool
and add CRISPR
I think it can be used on different animals
That is to say
But
We still need to improve
to make my system more promising
more robust
And
I don't know if there are any other questions
Hello
I have a question
It's a simple question
Do you experiment with mice?
Is it a mouse?
Or a bird?
You just said a mouse
Do you experiment with a bird?
Yes
Is it alive?
The experiments on behavior are all alive
But in the end we need to sacrifice them
and study the changes in their brains
or something
Is it still alive?
Is it conscious?
Or is it dead?
Just take out its brain
and see what happens
Both
Now we have a postdoc
He is using
He is making a miniature microscope
Let me see if I can
Sorry, can you hear me?
Yes
Our house was on fire
and I was kicked out
What happened?
Anyway, I was kicked out
and now I'm back
There is no internet out there
It's ok
You just said
Yuqing
Yuqing, right?
Yes
He asked
Do you experiment with a mouse?
Is it alive?
The experiments on behavior are all alive
We have a postdoc
who made a small microscope
and put it on their heads
We hope that
we can see
and add some
photoreceptors
and they can see
the neural activity
We want to use these two things
to see the brain of a living animal
how a living animal
lives
Most of the cases are
after we do the research
even after the behavior
we will sacrifice the mouse
and then see
whether our modifications
have changed
How do I get my video out?
I feel like you said
you made the microscope very small
and then put it on your head
and look at it
I feel like it's amazing
There is a company
that specializes in
selling this device
selling a super small microscope
but it still has some
disadvantages
like it can't adjust
focus
it can only observe
the surface
of the brain
Isn't that supposed to be
on the head?
Do you have that
I can't remember his name
Let me think
KALTECH
Ni Yuli
Did you talk to him?
because they now
do non-invasive
and they want to
the firing pattern
but they want to
do it on people
because you can't
and I was thinking
I don't know if you talked about this
I posted a question
because
if you do it like this
either
Guoying's head
has to be very transparent
or you have to
put something on the rat's bone
but I don't think it's possible on people
yeah
because
my system
has two things
you have to etopic express
two ligand and receptor
and reporter, three
yeah
if you can't
do something like
transgenic animal or
other virus
there's nothing you can do
and human brain
has limitations
but
I mentioned
I don't know if you're here
and
CRISPR
is very popular
it can
make it easier
for us
to change
different animal
genetic profile
you can do transgenic animal
so
using
CRISPR
we should have more opportunities
to test on different
animals
like rabies virus
this
tool is very good
there's a lot of paper
published
but the problem is
we can't use
on birds
because
birds can't get rabies
that's rabies virus
so
this tool
because it's transgenic
if CRISPR looks promising
we can use it
on different animals
like I mentioned
I saw
dolphin
not dolphin
puffer fish
dolphin
it has
a very strange
behavior
it will draw
on the sand
very
symmetric pattern
to attract
it will feel
amazing
if I have a chance
I want to study
animal brain
really?
why?
I don't know
but the pattern
it draws
is like
wheat field
very big
like this
for its size
it's big
so I think
it's interesting
ok
but for humans
because it's transgenic
the tool we can use
is functional MRI
but
it can't be that good
so I'm
thinking
how to
understand
our
animal brain
I was thinking
if you change
LIGAND to
some
magnetic field
or electrical field
you can use
MRI
to locate it
but the resolution
is not high enough
it looks like a piece
here and there
so it's useless
yes
I remember
I saw
a speech
he was using
X-ray
to look at
the structure
of the brain
he
he chose
very small
X-ray is very traditional
so I think
they want to say
if they use X-ray
to dissect the brain
the resolution will be good
maybe in the future
it can be used
in human
or large animals
ok
like this
but
I don't know
how much
it can be
maybe in the future
maybe
I think
there's a big gap
animal model
can help a lot
but animal model
and human
there's a gap
both sides
don't know how to cross
there's no bridge
yes
maybe
the closest
is
primate
yes
I think
especially in my department
it's very obvious
if it's primate
it's
obvious
like
aggression
mating behavior
or even
hierarchy
but if it's higher
like stroke
primate
it's very close
but if it's
social, complicated social behavior
like
psychology
people do jealousy
this thing
I've heard people say
that
they do love
on mice
and they say
it's not just mating, it's love
and I think
how do you know what love is
it hurts
yes
so
I was thinking
this system
the limit
but
on human
there's still
human
brain function
limitation
yes
but
human
can't do research
yes
but I think it's cool
I think your
resolution is really high
it's quite
quite big
I don't know where the people in the front sit
but I feel it's quite amazing
and
it increases a lot
you can see very detailed things
actually
because it's mainly
social contact
so it depends on
we can test
its sensitivity
what minimal
area you need
to detect
to see the difference
so
yes
it depends on
how much
you can touch
and your
concentration
is it high enough
to see
downstream
but you can
adjust it
my main work
is to adjust
this tool
so it can be used
on
neural circuits
and
yes
don't
I'm the only one talking
do you have questions?
YuQing
asked a question
I don't know
is Jenny still here?
I'm here
YuQing is here
Jenny
there's another one
I think
in the future
maybe
after more information
this is the basic
maybe in the future
we still need
telekinesis
or computer simulation
to understand
brain function
now
I can only provide a tool
or a blueprint
an established
blueprint
in the future
as I mentioned
we can adjust
the level
of cell poverty
to be more selective
to do research
do you have questions?
please
there's a medicine
called LSD
is it
I think
I don't know
if it's related
after taking the medicine
does the brain
how
is it related
to the research
after taking it
LSD is
like
hallucination
it's like
I don't know
it's mainly
related to
I'm not sure
what's it called
it's like
in the same place
I forgot the word
what's it called
it's in the
circuit
so
it's like
reward circuit
mainly in that part
like
that area
the brain area
it's related to
reward
and addiction
it's related
talking about
reward system
I'm not a
biopsychologist
but
reward system is very popular
you might have mentioned
but I missed it
besides addiction
it's also
like
many psychological diseases
autism
or
they have
abnormal
repetitive behaviors
they keep doing it
and they'll
what
like OCD
they said
it's because of their reward system
so when they do
these behaviors
their reward system will keep firing
and it's abnormal
you don't need
to do it
they're doing
imaging research
right
so like
I mentioned
we're
researching
connectome
the other purpose is
we have a normal
reference
then we can
look into
schizophrenia
it's related to
brain problems
related
diseases
what's the difference
like schizophrenia
there's a theory
excitatory and inhibitory
balance
there's a difference
is there less connection
or
synaptic strength
less
I think our department has many
researchers who like your research
because our department
our department's
biopsychology and
clinical psychology are quite similar
clinical psychology is
doing schizophrenia
they push people in
all kinds of patients
but
I remember
there's a talk
about functional MRI
right
it's about ADHD
I remember
it's about imaging
they're doing
function structure
MRI used to do
too big or too small
which side is thick
which side is thin
they're doing
firing pattern
it's called functional
right
I remember
it's 7.25
any questions
if not
3, 2, 1
thank you
sorry
we'll continue
any ideas
ok
thank you
I don't know which one
the blue one
fire station