This is also a similar picture.
This is the radius,
and this is the brightness distribution picture.
So you find that this HSC, H-band
is the mirror infrared light,
so it's very new.
Its distribution is wider,
and its distribution is more concentrated.
Concentrated in a closer radius.
So it tells you that
these dusts are more compact,
concentrated in the center of the galaxy.
And the stars are running around.
What does this tell you?
It tells you that these SMGs
should be major mergers.
As I said before,
it's two stars colliding.
When the two stars collide,
these stars are running around.
Because when the two stars collide,
the stars
can basically be regarded as collision.
They don't...
They only have gravity for each other.
Because the two stars
don't collide.
Because the universe is very wide.
Very wide.
And the stars...
Imagine they're colliding one by one.
But there's a collision
with a collision on the left,
and a collision on the right.
Then you push each other.
But most collisions
just pass each other.
They don't collide with each other.
Because the space of the universe is very large,
and the frequency of the stars is very small.
So the stars
basically don't collide with each other.
So they run around in space.
It's like this.
They only have gravity
for each other.
But DOS doesn't.
DOS actually comes from...
At first, it comes from gas.
Gas...
When the two stars collide,
the gas will collide with each other.
Then they will lose their kinetic energy.
OK.
And after the gas loses kinetic energy,
they will...
fall to the center of the star
because of gravity.
Because of gravity,
they will fall into the gravitational well of the core.
And after the gas reaches the core,
they will form new stars.
New stars.
They will produce star formation.
After star formation,
as I said at the beginning,
after star formation,
they will have supernova,
and then they will produce some gravity,
and then they will produce these dusts.
OK.
So that's why these dusts are gathered in the middle.
So basically, this paper tells you
what SMG is.
But what this paper doesn't have is
that it only has DOS and STAR components.
It doesn't have
gas components.
That is, you have to observe through
the plane of the molecule or the plane of the atom.
Because this part is still being developed.
We're still waiting for ALMA
to build more instruments
so that we can get this part of the observation.
This is also the focus of SMG
for the next few years.
After you have this component,
you can draw it on the map.
Then you can compare
the behavior of STAR, DOS, and gas.
You can learn more about their dynamics.
OK.
That's all I want to say.
I'm going to briefly introduce
what this field is for,
and then talk about my little project.
And then the last few slides
talk about what ALMA can do in the future.
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you, Xu Liyan.
I've been talking for two hours.
Do you have any questions?
Yes, two hours.
Do we have enough time?
You can ask a few more questions.
Do you have any questions?
I'm not in a hurry.
No, I...
No problem. We can record for five hours.
No, no, no.
I have a question.
I'm more interested in engineering technology.
You mentioned that
some measurements are slower.
For example, SMA is slower than ALMA.
Specifically,
in terms of engineering or technology,
which link
makes it slower?
Basically, it's...
Let me talk about my understanding
of astronomical telescope first.
Then you help me see if it's right or wrong.
As far as I know,
the antenna
receives radio signals.
No matter what kind of wavelength it is,
it's basically an electromagnetic wave.
It receives electromagnetic wave signals
and processes them
through the computer.
For example,
it combines signals from different regions
to make some visualizations.
My understanding of astronomical telescope
is like this.
I don't know if it's wrong.
Hello?
Am I disconnected?
I'm disconnected.
Julian, did you mute yourself?
Hello?
Can you hear me?
Yes, I can hear you.
I just disconnected.
Okay, continue.
So where did you hear it just now?
You said the antenna
receives all electromagnetic wave signals.
It receives electromagnetic wave signals
and then
a large part of it
is processed by the computer
after receiving electromagnetic wave signals.
It combines signals from different regions
to make visualizations.
If my understanding is correct,
when you say
an astronomical telescope
is slower than another,
which part is slower?
Basically,
SMA only has 8 dashes.
ELMA has more than 60 dashes.
That's basically it.
So it's like
more dashes
at the same time?
It's called
collecting area.
So...
I'm still online.
I can see you.
It's basically
collecting area.
It has more than 60 dashes.
I can hear you.
SMA only has 8 dashes.
But SMA can't add more dashes.
Yeah.
To put it simply,
it can observe
a larger area.
So you have more dashes in total.
So effectively,
you collect
more electromagnetic waves.
I see.
That's it.
SMA
has been doing some upgrades.
It can't add
more dashes,
but it can collect
more electromagnetic waves.
What does that mean?
It means
how much electromagnetic waves
a telescope can collect.
Now,
a telescope
can collect
32...
32 GHz
of electromagnetic waves.
On the other hand,
ALMA is not that big.
ALMA is only 8 GHz.
Yeah.
But SMA can only
make up for it.
It doesn't add more dashes,
but it can increase
the frequency of each individual dash.
So it can collect
more electromagnetic waves
at the same time.
Yeah.
But it's not enough.
So...
Is there anything else?
He's not here.
His signal
seems to be lagging.
No.
I'm here.
Is there
Jenny?
Is there anything else?
Is Jenny here?
She hasn't asked a question.
If possible,
I'd like to ask another question.
At the beginning,
you mentioned astronomy
and cosmology.
What's the difference?
Astronomy is about the universe.
It's hard to define.
Basically,
I think
astronomy and cosmology
can be seen as
two different areas
with overlapping.
But they are not the same
or completely different.
They overlap.
I can explain it this way.
For example,
if someone studies
the distribution of dark matter
in the universe,
to understand the evolution of the universe
to understand the distribution
of dark matter in the universe
and to influence
dark matter...
Have you heard of dark matter?
The distribution of dark matter
affects the formation of the galaxy.
The formation of the galaxy.
This is basically cosmology.
But it's also astronomy.
Because it's related to the evolution of the galaxy.
As long as it's related to the evolution of the galaxy,
it's related to our observations of the galaxy.
If you use a microscope
or a sub-millimeter or a radio,
you have to use astronomy to observe.
This is astronomy.
Cosmology is also astronomy.
But some things
are purely cosmology.
For example,
pure cosmology
is basically physics.
For example,
the study of the explosion theory.
I just...
For example,
the study of the early universe.
The explosion theory is
the early universe to the Big Bang.
After that,
there was a period of very crazy expansion.
This part
is very theoretical.
It's hard for us
to actually observe.
It's all physical models.
You have to understand very deep theoretical physics.
This kind of thing
I will classify it
as pure physics.
Basically, it's cosmology,
but not astronomy.
You can say that.
The other part is astronomy,
but not cosmology.
It's a good example. For example,
some people study small stars,
study comets,
or study
very basic star formation.
But it's not my kind of star formation.
It's a star formation one by one.
It studies stars,
such as small stars and comets.
It studies these things
at a close distance.
It's not like
when I study galaxies,
I will talk about redshifts.
If you study solar systems,
small stars and comets,
you won't use the concept of redshifts.
Because they are too close to us.
I just said that redshifts are mainly...
Of course, there are many kinds of redshifts.
They will use Doppler redshifts,
because they have Doppler redshifts as soon as they move.
Cosmological redshifts,
because the universe is expanding,
they will observe this effect.
If you study
very close stars,
study comet formation,
they won't use cosmological redshifts.
They will observe that any
blue and redshifts are Doppler effects.
Basically, when you study these things,
you don't need to consider
the evolution of our universe.
You don't need to consider
whether there is dark energy
or dark matter.
So,
these things will be classified as pure astronomy.
They don't have cosmological redshifts.
I feel a little bit
like that.
Basically, this is what I want to say.
Because people in this field
will have a better feeling.
Okay, thank you.
Because
the time is a bit late,
we will end here today.
Okay, thank you.
Can you still hear me?
I know I can hear you.
I'm just a little bit laggy.
Okay, let's thank Xu Liyan again.
Okay, thank you.
Okay, that's it. See you next week.
Okay, bye bye.
Bye bye.
Translated by Hua Chenyu English Subs