Okay
Oh
F
Oh, I forgot
Share
Share screen
Wow
Okay
Okay, so the topic I'm going to talk about today
is
Dark Matter Super CDMS
which is what I'm doing right now
and the Super Conductive Future
of Particle Physics
which is
what I'm doing right now
Okay, next page
The topic I'm going to talk about today
will be divided into two parts
The first part is
the physical part
I'm going to talk about Dark Matter
which is mainly
focused on
the direct detection
part of the experiment
What is its physics?
What is the current
state of the field?
What is everyone's goal? What are the difficulties?
How to do this experiment? How to measure this thing?
It should be more reliable
and more interesting
The second part will be my own work
which is quite R&D
People who are interested in
technology may be more interested
But it should be very related
Okay
My screen is a bit laggy
First of all, because we have already
introduced it before
What is
the basic example
of a
model and a theoretical basis
So I'm going to talk about it very quickly
So basically
Can you see my mouse?
Can you see it?
There are many basic examples
We think these basic examples
are the basic materials
we know
in the universe
But
because of some reasons
we think there are still things in the universe
that we don't know
We can't use this model to explain
But anyway, this is called Standard Model
It is the best description
If you are
interested in this
You can look it up on Wikipedia
There are six quarks
three leptons
neutrinos
and X
Okay
The point I want to talk about today
will focus on
the ones you can see on the screen
The red one is a mole
The blue one is a neutrino
Basically, this is
the most important example for us
Because honestly, in life
the most important thing is
the things you are interested in
the things you breathe
and the things that make up you
These are the only two
Okay
Then
Sorry, there are electrons
These are the three
There is another important one
The white ghost
It is called light
It sounds very mysterious
like a laser gun
So
these things
exchange light like baseball
and they will
reach the energy balance
Basically, the heat balance
After reaching the heat balance
everything will have a black hole
Okay
This is very important
Because my family often ask me
Is dark matter a black hole?
Actually, it is not
You will know why
It is very vague
This is the universe we usually see
When we look at it
the whole universe is black
Then you will say
Why do we think
everything is the matter we know
and it will exchange light
like a baseball
This is actually
the universe we see
with a good instrument
Like this
The whole universe is basically bright
The different colors
are basically the same as the black hole
It corresponds to different temperatures
Okay
You see the brightest one in the middle
It is the galactic plane
There are many planets
and a lot of energy
So there will be a lot of energy
Okay
My mouse
Okay, you see the back
This part is very red
The energy here is very low
It only has a foreground
It only has a background
The background is the whole background of the universe
It is very cold
It is only 3 degrees K
But basically it has a temperature
So we can still see it
Okay
This picture is basically
filled with colors
How can we say there is any dark matter
that we don't know
Let me see the next page
Because there was a very wise man
He said
Vader was seduced by
The dark side of the force
The force is what gives Jedi his power
It's an energy field
created by all living things
It surrounds us
It permits us
It binds the galaxy together
It sounds very confusing
I don't know what he is talking about
So I will focus on it
The dark side of the force
Behind the galaxy together
This sentence is probably
from 1976
So you can imagine
this is the era when we started to
be interested in dark matter
This statement is correct
We started to be interested in dark matter
Okay
Actually
What did Obeah Kenobi mean by this?
This means
There's a picture here
The brightest place is
the center of our galaxy
Then the horizontal axis
is the distance from the center of the galaxy to the outside
The vertical axis is
the particle
in that position
The speed of rotation around the center of the galaxy
Then you can see
the yellow data
The yellow data is
the stars over there
Okay, like the sun
So we can see those stars
are moving
Then we can see
the center of the yellow data
is the galaxy
That is
the size of the galaxy
300 years ago
Then we found
we can keep looking out
according to the
dark radiation
We can see the infrared
Then we can see
the blue hyperfine structure
The blue dot
is the light source
of the moon
You can keep pushing
to the outside
the position of 50,000 light years
It can be connected
This is what we know
the size of a galaxy
Okay
Then we can see
the speed of
the particles
we see
We can
There is a point
According to the theory of relativity
It is basically Newton's law
According to
the traditional law we know
We can guess
We just see the speed
the speed of rotation
around the orbit
So we get
the following line
Okay
But actually
we observe
the speed of rotation is the line above
Okay
So
you will find
the speed of rotation
is the speed of the line above
The actual weight of the orbit
is much more than
what we can see
Okay
So we really can't see it
In the 1980s
That's because
our instrumentation is not good enough
We can't see anything
Okay
So there were some
disputes about dark matter
Then
in the 1980s and 1990s
we started to know
that everything we can see is almost right
So we started to think
whether the particles we know
can meet this nature
The answer is yes
There are three kinds of particles
called neutrons
They do have this nature
But the neutrons we know
This is the point
Some people think we don't know neutrons
The neutrons we already know
basically
have something to do
with the particles
we already know
Because particles and neutrons
have something to do with the ratio
When they change,
they will use it
So according to all the stars we observed
Those stars are all neutrons
We can infer
how many neutrons there are
Can it
cover
our missing mass budget
The answer is that it can't exceed 6%
It can't exceed 6%
Okay
So basically we think
it might be new physics
The answer is that it shouldn't, right?
Because the quality you see
is a virtual line
So if I have more
missing mass
I think it will fit the original data
So when you plot the upper line
How do you know
when you have more missing mass?
Let me write a book
Is it easier to plot like this?
Let's say the middle part is symmetric
We can think of it as the middle part
Oh
It's the
transverse speed
Yes
Oh no
It's the speed of rotation
So you can see
The real speed
is a few hundred
kilometers per second
So it's really slow
So basically
it's a neutron
It doesn't have to be close to the speed of light
Okay
This number is a bit important
Actually Darkmatter
has a lot of clues
I won't say it's evidence
So there are a lot of clues
This clue is actually
the most suspicious
It has a lot of reasons not to think like this
But Darkmatter has a lot of other
clues
If you are interested, you can ask
But basically this is the most important to us
Okay
Anyway
We need to have additional
quality to generate additional benefits
Or somehow
your theory needs to generate additional benefits
to explain this question
Do you have any questions for Darkmatter?
Okay
Then I'll jump straight to
This is an interesting article
I've seen recently
And I think
you should know better than me
Okay
You should know who this is
Yeah
This is the latest
CERN Courier
article
It's
I magnified the point
But I still have a citation
So I magnified the citation
It says
Let's see where to start
Okay
Let's see
It
It should be here
It says
EPR pair
referred to
referred to ER Einstein Rosenbridge
and one part that connects the two parts of
the black hole geometry
This idea is
brought by many theorists
in particular
in the context of ADS-CFT
correspondence
Okay
Let's look back
The point is
The problem with this theory is
I think it's motivated by
what I just said
So it can work
in galaxy scale
But the problem is
it can't
or it's not good enough
in phenomenology
to work
to estimate
larger scale
For example,
what I just said is a galaxy
and it will have
a modified gravity effect
But the problem is
we have another observation
that if there are two galaxies
and these two galaxies
all have a
dark matter
and they contrast
we can see the interaction
of two matter-like things
dark matter and non-dark matter
This kind of local
and dynamic behavior
is not a good way to explain
What it's doing now is
if it's a whole universe
in the early universe
it will have a modified CMB
which is cosmic background radiation
Can it work?
Okay
I actually made up another part
How would
emergent gravity affect
the physics?
Someone asked me
There are many different explanations
such as extra dimension
EREPR
or modified gravity
Modified Newtonian Dynamics
It's a standard name
But why do we want to do dark matter?
I think the reason is simple
because dark matter can be done
Even if you
don't think it's a good
theory
But it's important
to prove it
That's why we're doing this
I would say it's hard to do
But someone is thinking
For example, microgravity
or some light experiments
Well
Jingjie
I think you know better than me
So I don't know much
Can there be special
kind of
That's what he meant
Right?
So I just imagined
If there is an extra dimension
Contact
Then your
3 plus 1
will be equal to
the size of
the contact white space
So if you
make it bigger or smaller
it's more likely to be
stronger than outside
But it's related to
the size of
the compactified dimension
Right?
If the size is not
a constant
or here is this big
Then it means that in different places
the size will be different
I think it's possible
Jingjie, I don't know
how they do it
But the point is
That's what he said
Then
I think I'll just jump back
from here
Where did I talk about?
OK
Actually, the more interesting thing is
that
if anyone is interested in
other kinds of
prediction
Right?
There are all kinds of observations
So
we just talked about
the missing mass
So
what you see now
is our Milky Way
This is what we think is the Milky Way
The Milky Way we see
Then next to it, I help you zoom in
That's our solar system
Then we go around the sun
So the Earth is in the third one
OK
Why is this important?
Because we do experiments on the Earth
So you know why it's important
The picture in the upper left corner
is to say that this is not a special phenomenon
That is to say
only our Milky Way Galaxy has
Because a lot of people thought
you would observe this
Is it because we are in the Milky Way?
So we are in the Milky Way
The Milky Way is not in the center
It's on the side
And then you have to correct it
It's like you've been going around
A constant change
OK
Is there a problem with this experiment?
But this thing
is basically a
A whole observation
in the 1970s
completely broken
Vera Rubin
This person later won the Presidential Prize
He observed a lot of galaxies
There are such phenomena
So what you see in the upper left corner
is what I said
The speed of the rotation
It's really flat
But if you
r² gm² is equal to r²mv²
In fact, it should be
Is it the opposite of once r?
It will keep going down
Equals once
v² will be the opposite of r
So we really think
What should the universe look like?
It should look like this
It's a little bit laggy
There is a halo
Something like a light cloud
OK, so this thing is called Dark Matter Halo
And then we're in that
So we've been constantly
in Dark Matter Halo
Movement is being soaked in
It feels like you're being soaked in
I have a question
That is to say
How big is the curve?
How big is the scale?
The effect will come out slowly
Because you're looking at a galaxy scale
For example, the scale of the solar system
Or the scale of the galaxy
It will have a similar curve
When you draw it out
Is it the same?
I forgot to put that thing
This is very interesting
You can ask a question
How long does it take for us to go around the sun?
One year, right?
How long does it take for us to go around the galaxy?
OK, basically
There's no life
Can feel the difference
So you can imagine
We are in a
In the center of the galaxy
The origin of the coordinate
Around the sun
Local rotation
Can you?
So basically in this Dark Matter Halo
We are actually in a fixed position
In that very local place
Keep turning
So what do you get in the end?
You will get
If you measure the local
The speed of the Halo
I mean
Dark Matter
Wait a minute
You just asked about the speed of the planet
OK
Let me tell you
The earth itself
The speed of rotation around the sun
This measurement
OK
So actually someone found something very interesting
It should be proposed
A very interesting concept
Because we are
Compared to our life
And the time scale we use
We are in the Dark Matter Halo
The solar system is basically fixed in the Dark Matter Halo
You see that point is not moving
Your whole life will not change
A pixel on the earth
But the earth has been around
So it means
Our solar system is sitting in a
Constant Dark Matter Week
A Dark Matter Wind
Keep moving in the same direction
Then we have half a year
It's clockwise
Half a year is counterclockwise
This is called Dark Matter Annual Modulation
It can be a
Probing Dark Matter
As a particle
A very important phenomenon
About ten years ago
Someone planned to test it
And then there was no way
To reproduce the experiment
Do you know this?
In addition to
The scale of the solar system
It's a little bit bigger
But smaller than the galaxy
See
Because there are a lot of stars in the galaxy
Is a lot of
Constellations
I don't know
Because usually we
We are
Anyway, everyone is talking about
What clues are there in Dark Matter
Just use a few scales
Galaxy
It's a bunch of galaxies
It's called Megastructure
And then there's the whole universe
There are about four
Will there be a star group in the middle?
I don't know
Next one
But
I have the doll above
That is
So
Then we think it's weird
Since we are sitting on the whole earth
Including ourselves
Do you feel like you're being blown by the wind?
Have you been hit all the time?
Is there a ghost behind you?
No
So a very popular theory
Is
We are all surrounded by
Dark Matter
OK
It's like we're all surrounded by air
But they basically don't
Pass their momentum to us
It won't interact with us
OK
This is smaller than air
Because air is actually
I don't feel the interaction
Dark Matter's basic theory is that
The next two are the substances we already know
And then they interact with each other
In the form of throwing balls
So they can pass
Momentum energy
That's what we know
And then it's all dark matter
But Dark Matter has no way to catch the ball
Just stand there and watch
Of course
But it has gravity
Right
So we put one over there
A gravity pole
It's the only thing that can interact with us
It's pulling us
So we can
Basically, this is the only thing we can
See the reason for the rotational curve
OK
Right, because it has a gravitational interaction with us
Can this be
Localized?
Let's say we have a
Dark Matter density
Let's say it's 0.5
Will it enhance
The gravitational interaction between the substances?
How do we interact with each other?
Oh, yeah, that's what I just said
Microgravity
This thing is very interesting
You either measure a very large scale
Why?
Because you can have a very large group of Dark Matter
You can measure a lot of pull
This approach will become
There is a kind of
What is it called?
Lensing
In fact, we can use
Baryonic Matter to do
But a lot of people are doing
There is a galaxy far away
Then
He also has a Dark Matter Halo
And then there's something behind him
So we can see what's behind him
Then we can see
The effect of this galaxy's lensing
Can we go
So this lens
How heavy is it?
Then we can see how bright this lens is
So we can guess
How heavy it is
I don't know why I'm doing astronomy
I don't know how to talk about Baryonic Matter
Standard Model of Matter
How heavy it is
This is a way
There are a lot of these measurements
Measurement and
Is it in line with the SNOKER?
In line with
But it's a mass
Because if you measure it like this, it's a mass, right?
Because you're looking at a very far
A very far galaxy as a mirror
And then there's another group of people
What they're doing now is
That's what you said
Can I do it on Earth?
For example, I'm on the table
I know how heavy this apple is
How heavy that banana is
But if there's Dark Matter in the middle
How much should he change
The problem with this is that you can put
All experiments are controlled very accurately
But their signal is very small
Because things are very light
So it's hard to do
If you do this
Will be a completely different
For Theory
But this is
This is more like what you're talking about
We know this
Oh yeah
So
The problem here is
How big is your sensitivity
You have to compare
Because if we measure big G now
It should all be observed from the sky
Just look at the big
I don't know
What are they doing now
But someone is doing it
This is actually a very interesting experiment for me
But I think it's been five or ten years
Should be very
Test performance
There will be no
I have a question
Oh, this is a
A completely different idea
There is that you want to talk about
Just talk about manufacturing
That LHC wants to do this
I'll talk about it later
Theoretically, right?
It's just a
If it's a pile of matter and then there's mass
Yes, it can be theoretically
But I don't think it's measured
Because your weight is very small
So it's hard to measure
So now the big difference is
Of course, there's more mass
But I'm not sure
No one knows what it is
But
What you can imagine is that you can modify
You originally used to do the assumption
That is, if Newton's law is right
That is, there is less matter
Or Newton's law
Or relativism is not so right
Then you have to modify that
Anyway, either case
You have to think of a theory
What we're doing is to treat it as
Particle
Yes, it's a particle
And then the only thing it does is
Okay, this is what I'm talking about
So he's standing there
And then he doesn't do anything, does he?
So our assumption now is that
Dark matter doesn't interact
This sentence is right
If you talk to astronomers
In all of our roles
Dark matter will never work with you
What are you doing?
OK
But what is our hope?
Our hope is
Next page
It's a very, very, very
Small chance
It's actually going to be with us
This red
I don't know if it's straight or neutral
Anyway, it's with our normal matter
Interaction
But what are its conditions?
Its condition is to be small
So rare that it's seen as
Consistent with non-interacting
In all previous experiments
That is to say
You want this opportunity to be small
Um
In all previous experiments
It looks like it doesn't work
But you'll think
It's already so small
Why do you have to assume it
There are other reasons
Because we are
Directly start
Directly
Um
We have a lot of other examples
The theory of physics
He predicted that there would be new examples
OK
It's not just what we know now
Then these new examples
With
Even their bigger and more complete
In theory, we know that part
The interaction is very weak
Um
Weak to all the other
It looks like it's
No interaction
But it's not completely non-interactive
This is the point
And then it's more important
That value
Is what we should be able to measure
As long as we design a
Dedicated experiment
Um
Because
In fact, we can't measure it
It's not that it doesn't interact
But we don't have a very sensitive way to measure it
So we always thought it was completely non-interactive
But in fact it is not
Then if we measure it today
In what we think it should interact with us
This sensitive detector
There is still no interaction
Then we can rule out the old theory
Which we did many times
I'll talk about it later
What is the current situation
The current situation is
The earth is over there
Red is our experiment
We cover it on the earth
Then we are in the dark matter
So as the center of the coordinate
Dark matter has been hitting us
Then we hope that many
One will hit our detector
And then hit the detector
The situation is actually quite serious
It's like you hit the ball
Come in and out
Then he put a little bit
The kinetic energy is passed to the detector
Then we have to measure this little kinetic energy
Ok
This is what we have to do
How do we actually do it
Ok, let's start slowly
That is to say our project
This is not our project
But I want to talk about it first
The two most popular methods on the earth
Then I want to
In our work
Why do we think this is better
This is the first method
It's called Time Projection Chamber
The red line is dark matter
Dark matter comes in many times
There was one time he hit the bucket
Detector material in the basket
Then like hitting the ball
Then go out
Then he passed the energy to the line like a caterpillar
What is that line
Inside the bucket
Is our so-called
Target Matter
Usually I don't know what matter is
Anyway, it's Target Matter
Then he passed a little energy
This kind of material
The atomic box of this element
Then the atomic box
After recoiling some energy
Pass this energy to him
The electrons on the track
The electrons will move
Then it will drop
Then it's the yellow line of the caterpillar
OK
Then this flash of light
Will spread out
Will be above and below
PMT
PMT is called Photon Multiplier Tube
Basically it is very sensitive
Light sensor
You can measure that light
Then I just said
He hit it
Then pass the absorbed energy to the electrons and drop it
Then you know that the moon
The light coming out is a fixed color
Is a fixed energy
So you look at the energy of this color
How strong it means
How many electrons are there
Then you can reverse
How much energy did he eat
OK
This is
The first signal
Then the second signal is what I just said
He will have an electron moon
Then the moon of the electron
In addition to this kind of falling
It will have a certain ratio
OK
What about these electrons
He is in this vertical direction
Put a very, very strong power plant
Is that I wrote there
It's probably thousands of volts per centimeter
So one you look at the following picture
One person is so big
The vertical direction of the barrel is probably tens of thousands of volts
He used this very strong power plant
The electron is pulled all the way to the bottom
Just drag it all the way
Drag it all the way to the top
There is a virtual caterpillar above
OK, that virtual caterpillar hit the detector
He has a secondary signal
So there is such a method
Can you
Then because he was pulled up
Speed ​​is a fixed speed
It's probably a fixed speed
Is the electron in
Drifting speed
So you count that
Flash, flash is basically a moment
Just a flash and you'll see
To the speed of the electron
The time difference in the middle
Can you reverse the distance
OK, you know what I mean
Then if you have a row of electrons being drifted
Then the distance to each one is different
You reverse the whole thing and you get a track
Then through this track
You can vary
Roughly
Different
Hit your example
Distinguish whether we already know
The particle hit us
Or his behavior is consistent
We should have expectations for us
This is called Time Projection Chamber
What about his question
OK, let's talk about his advantages
His advantage is
That material is usually
Liquified
What
That
Xenon
Or
Where is it
Argon
It's these two kinds of gas
So it's actually a very heavy element
Then we
What about the elements that we know are heavy
It's a bit like
If you hit a heavy thing today
Hit the air molecules with you
Then the air molecules will get more
Energy or heavy things
It should be heavy
So if you hit it today
Hit a heavier atomic box
Then you can leave more energy
Then we know that the energy is equal to the square of M
The square of the atomic box
So their signal is very big
And they are actually easy to scale up
Why scale up is important
Because basically there is
How many Doppler Meters pass through your detector
How big is it with your detector
How many atomic boxes are there
So if you have a two-time detector
Basically you
The rate of the expected signal should be twice
They are easy to put a lot of
Super high voltage
It sounds crazy
But it's actually easy
Basically
To summarize
State-of-the-art optimization
Of a widely used
Iron geophysics technology
Invented in the 70s
OK
State-of-the-art optimization
This very widely used
What are the benefits
They can scale up very quickly
They know what problems they will encounter
So currently their approach is
The most sensitive
In terms of event rate
OK
The second one
Another one is Solid State Detector
Why is this thing
Let me talk about it
What you see on the picture now
The part I enlarged
That little metal box
Inside the metal box
It's the carton next to it
The blue thing
Is a solid state detector
Its principle is actually the same as
The etheric detector
You go in and hit it
Then give it energy
Energy makes it flash
OK, and then the flash
What about the light
Can it pop out
And then the top and bottom of this picture
That label
It's called TES
TES is
We know the most sensitive detector on Earth
What is it
It's called Transition Edge Sensor
I'll talk about it later
OK
It's very sensitive
And then
In addition to this signal
You can also get another signal
It's a deposit
It's basically heat
It's heat in the crystal
If you think about it
Then the heat will be passed out
But he put the whole box
It's empty
Nothing
So heat can't be passed out
Heat stays inside
OK
The only track that can be passed out
It's the top and bottom
It has two caterpillar wires
It will pass to heat bath
So you can eat all these heat
Then measure the heat
Then you
Correlate these two signals
You can identify
What hit us
Is it a particle we know
Or a particle we don't know
OK
What's the benefit
This kind of solid state detector
Can be operated under cryogenic temperature
For exquisite energy resolution
With ultra-low noise
But
What does it mean
OK
It can have a lot of
Very special phenomena
Our collaborators
In Berkeley
In different laboratories
That is to say
This kind of thing can play a lot of magic
Recoil threshold depends on material property
You can invent
Very exotic material
Then let them eat
This
After hitting the ball
Then how to give it to you
Then you measure
OK
I know that Chicago University is now leading
They are doing CCD
To put it bluntly
The CCD chip in your camera
Take it to Dark Matter
After hitting it, it will leave the electrode
Then walk a small line
Different particles walk that line
The behavior will be different
So you can be very, very
Accurate judgment
What kind of material
What kind of particle
Then there is the superconductor
I will talk a lot about this later
Because we are doing superconductor
It is also a very sensitive material
What is graphene
What is special about graphene
Its conductivity
Is
Not all the same
It's the same in every direction
Like your
Your guide is basically like this
Graphene
It is on the same plane
The conductivity of six directions is zero
Then
It's not zero in the other six directions
Or it is
Six-fold symmetry
It's very interesting
When your particle comes in
If it runs in the direction of that no electrode
Run
It can be as small as possible
I can pull it
I should just say
But there is a place
It's even weirder
It's superfluid
It's very sensitive
Then there is
It's Fermi arc
This is what we did in Caltech
This thing
It's basically in a certain direction
That
It's also zero
You can imagine these things
They are all very super
But the problem is
You are the subject of research
Instead of using it to study other people
So every moment
It's very, very expensive
OK
But why is this thing interesting
I'll tell you later
Its dilemma is
Harder to scale up without meeting new challenges
While maintaining your budget and sensitivity
This is very
You know the biggest experimental background
Is sensitivity
No, it's your budget
OK
So I just finished
Time Projection Chamber
And Solid State Detector
This is a monoplot
It's the whole field
The current state
The arc
Is your assumption
The quality of dark matter
Why do I say assumption
Because no one measured it
If you measure it, you know where it can be drawn
You assume
How heavy is the dark matter that can't be measured
OK
Then you know
How heavy is your dark matter particle
Then you know your dark matter halo
We stand in that halo
How heavy is the dark matter total
So you know
How many
Particle in terms of number
The flux has been flowing through you
Then you can't measure it again
Then you can know that the chance of interaction with me
Can't be greater than how much
So the arc is the chance of interaction
Then every line you see
Is the upper limit of that opportunity
That is
The interaction between dark matter and detector
The chance must be less than that line
If it's higher than that line
We should measure it
This is the logic of the picture
So it actually has two directions
One direction is you
We're going to make the detector bigger and bigger
Like the Time Projection Chamber
Then you can expect more events
If it's going to be measured
So if you can't measure it, you can keep the line down
It means that the higher the sensitivity
You still can't measure
Then the other one is you
You can measure the smaller and smaller
Energy
Then can you know that
Because very light particles hit you
The energy left is very small
Then can you go to the left of this picture
To draw that line
Because you know
You can measure this kind of energy
But you didn't measure it
Then you can put it there
That limit
This part is the solid state
It's right there
This is the main direction of this field
Everyone wants to push down
To make the detector bigger
But if you want to go to the right
If you push left
You need a better detector
That's right
What if you go to the right
Ok
To the right is like this
Why do we want to do a dedicated experiment
To measure dark matter
Because we actually have a very very
Strong machine
We have been using
It's a big magnet
When they built it
In addition to looking for the exposure
They actually want to find
The most important thing I think
I think it's fair to say
The example of superposition theory
It used to be the best for dark matter
The most anticipated thing to happen
Their goal
Basically around TEV
Or sub-TEV
So that's where I put the picture
Then you will ask
Do we want to measure them now
The answer is that LHC has not been able to measure
And it has exceeded
The earliest version
The original superposition theory
That is to say, we have basically
So there are a lot of superposition theories now
It's just looking at its original superposition theory
According to our continuous measurement
They think it's a
Superposition theory should have
What new phenomenon
Look at this thing
So basically
You keep going down
To measure
Superposition theory
Is it wrong?
But he can't measure
It's already weird
If you are interested
You can ask me
So now Susie's
The expectations are probably all on this map
You will be surprised
Because almost all of them are in the places we have entered
So now a lot of new theories
Come out
If it's not a superposition theory
It's another one we've never thought of
The dark side
It's like you know
We can't see it
But it's very, very weak
It interacts with the world we see
But it's a completely stand-alone
Dark world
It can have very light particles
Then we have to have
Very new technology
Go to the left of this picture
So this is our goal
Then you can see above
In the SSD frame
The four lines on the left
That's basically what we experimented with
Four different operations
So we are the most leading in this place
Then we are going to propose the next technology
Push us down again
No, push it to the left
Sorry
So this should be
OK, this is the last page
So the first part everyone has
Any questions?
I know
Dark Matter
It has its own interaction
This is
Ok
This is our most popular theory now
Called
Let's talk about popular
This is a piece of cake
Anyway, everyone is the most
The theory that people are pursuing in the experiment is
It's weakly interacting
Massive particle
Weakly is not in terms of
Interact with us
Interact with anything
Including themselves
So WIMP is very weak
But in fact
It should be said that Dark Matter does not have to be very weak
Like that
The latest paper published by He Shu-yu is SIMP
What is SIMP
Strongly
He can strongly interact with himself
What is the problem with strongly interacting with yourself?
If he can
Strongly interact with himself
It's true
They may have something
They have their own
Or whatever
They can condense into very small objects
This very small object
It will
Run this
What is this called
This kind of super super
This kind of simulation
They run this
Galaxy Evolution
If you let Dark Matter and Dark Matter
Strongly interact
They will condense into very small objects
Very fast
It can't form here
Then
Become our Dark Matter
It will become
Dark Matter Planet
Something like that
I thought it would turn into a planet
As long as there is gravitational force
Because this is related to the time of Evolution
Because your
You know how strong the gravitational force is
It can condense
There is a process
But it can condense very quickly
I think I missed one thing
Astronomers now
Their perception
Is like this
At the beginning of the universe
Things are very
Average distribution in the universe
Some places
A little bit more
Then
Dark Matter is a little bit more over there
They all come together
Then it's Dark Matter Halo
Then this Halo
To produce a local gravity
We already know
Drag it over
Become a current structure
So if this process
Time speed
If there is a change
For example, it condenses very quickly
A very small one
Then it will not be able to form
What we already know
Or the density of the galaxy
In the universe
So I really want to ask the question is
Will Dark Matter be used in the future?
Oh, there is such a theory
and so
Black hole is not a big concept
Because the black hole is just based on gravity
So
Black hole is still very strong
You will find
You can't see
Matter
This is being done
but I
I have no idea
It sounds reasonable
But in fact, someone is doing this
Someone is doing one thing
He can let
Dark Matter is over there
Then he said
Dark Matter and Dark Matter
Even if it doesn't work with us
You will be with yourself
Let's say he will
This is the theory
After he annihilated
He can
It becomes a pair production
What else
But because there are many
And very tight
So even Dark Matter coupled to Standard Model
The chance is small
It will still have
Very high
Event rate
For example, Gamma Gamma
So they are looking at that kind of
A lot of quality
For example, we think our
Our own
The center of the Milky Way is a super-heavy black hole
That
That's a hot spot
It's a lot of time looking over there
And then look over there
Gamma Ray
Whether it's Spectrum or Ray
Is there any
Beyond us
Normal Matter
Then you can say over there
Effectively there is a Dark Matter
Black hole
But this kind of experiment is also difficult to do
Because you know that the black hole itself is a very
Violent environment
So it's equal to
Even if you see a lot of Gamma Ray
You can blame it all on your model
Why didn't you run well
So they have a lot of uncertainty
But there are always people
Because they are so old
You can say it's a pile of Dark Matter
Black hole
And then there's Parallelization
Then it becomes Gamma Gamma
Then
But there is one
In Dark Matter
Self-interaction has a
Upper bound and lower bound
There are several upper bound and lower bound
If it's too weakly interact
It won't form a black hole
Then you have no way
Either
Is to become
A galaxy where the black hole forms
Or
If it's too strong
It will quickly become Dark Planet
Dark Planet
You can expect
If there is a Dark Planet in a certain place
There will be a Dark Galaxy
This thing is done by someone
But it can't be done
Like an experiment called AMS
The earliest
The purpose is to find
Dark World
Can't find it
So it has a bound
So they are now
You can still tune
But
There is a boundary
I think
Dark Matter strongly interacting
Principle will cause
If there is a black hole
The black hole will be colored by various modes
If
Dark Matter strongly interacting
I think only half of the people
There should be Dark Matter
Then you will find
If there is no way to measure
Anyway
Can you find
Yes
This can be done
You said this black radiation
I know what you mean
So what you are talking about now
Black radiation is talking about
Object black radiation
Instead of the whole universe
I don't know
I don't know if it can be done
But it sounds like it can be done
Because I don't know
How to observe
Things in the sky
Yes
That's it
Any questions
Next
Technical
Then
4 minutes
OK
So what are we doing
Didn't I just say we do Solid State Detector
So what you see now is a crystal
OK
This is a crystal we know
Then
What about the two folding lines
Is Incoming Particle
Then knock and run out
Then the small one on the track
That's the electron
We know that Dark Matter will not have
Electric charge
But not electric charge
Because if it has electric charge
It will work with light
So you see that knock
The electron on the side
That must be the particle we know
And it's a charged particle
So we look forward to Dark Matter
What should happen
You can knock the electron in the middle
Oh, yeah, but you look at the size
It's easier to know
So this is a two-scale picture
You know, one is super-invincible
Basically there is no electron
So we basically assume
As long as it knocks the electron
It must not be Dark Matter
So we put a piece of crystal
Over there and let it knock
And then we're going to measure this
This
This energy
What do we know
What kind of crystal do humans grow the most
Do you know
Julia
acid
Of course not
That's what you grow the most
It's not what humans grow the most
The answer is that the crystal that humans grow the most
It's called a fine crystal
How can Taiwanese make a mistake?
It's weird.
And the cost is very low
How to grow very clean
So our approach is to grow
We are
I don't know how to say
Fine crystal
And Germanium
It's the next one
These two are actually very good at growing, so the cost is very low
We can grow very big and very clean
And then after knocking it
Did I just say
The first one I just did as an example
It will leave
This
Ionization will produce light, right?
But the light of ionization
How much is the energy of ionization?
Do you know
It's EV
Right?
If you have a concept of electronics
For example, hydrogen is 13.6 EV
If it's a heavier atom
Because the electrons are placed further
So the pull will be smaller
So it's less than 10
Less than 10 EV
If it
The energy left is really small
If it's less than 10 EV
Can we measure it?
It won't stay
Because it can't even eat the energy of the most basic unit
What will it do
It will become one that keeps shaking
It won't knock things away
It will keep vibrating over there
When it vibrates, it becomes a kind of vacuum
We know that vacuum
It can actually be translated into a very fancy word
It's called Fona, which is actually hot vacuum
We can measure this hot vacuum
Our goal is to measure this hot vacuum
So measuring this hot vacuum
Immediately put our threshold
From EV-ish
Down to mini-EV
Because the basic mode of a vacuum
Is its frequency
Multiplied by Brownian frequency
Is its unit, its energy
It's very small, it's mini-EV
So we immediately
From our detection threshold
From the crystal itself
EV becomes
Our
Can be used to measure
The threshold of this Fona detector
This thing has become
It's not a limit at all
Then we will do another thing
When it has
We give it a very, very strong electric field
Across this crystal
So it has a little bit of
Electrode-eating energy
It will be pulled away violently
Then pulled all the way to the top
Just like the TPC you just saw
So basically we are doing TPC in the crystal
But we are not liquid
We are not solid
So this electron is being pulled all the way
It's not a fluid process
It's crazy to hit people all the way
So it's crazy to hit people
It will produce a bigger signal
More Fona
So it's a bit like an Amplifier process
So we use this method
Can put
Very small amount of signal becomes very large
Now the question is
How do we measure it?
What is this for?
We know that the ultraviolet
It has a change in temperature
Above this temperature, it is normal
Under this temperature, it is ultraviolet
It's basically like a leap
The same process
OK
This is a very simple concept
The picture you see now
Is a very carefully engineered
Material for ultraviolet
So you can see the slope
Otherwise, it looks like a hammer line
If you put your ultraviolet
Just control the temperature
The detector is in that place
It becomes normal as soon as it eats energy
Then the energy is dissipated by the heat
Fall off immediately
Basically it is very sensitive
This is what we are using now
This technology
What is its problem?
Its problem is
If you want to put a lot of
Detectors today
On the surface of your big crystal
You can't
The surface of the detector
There will be no temperature gradient
Right?
You probably have half
It continues to be too hot
Half of it is normal
Then the other half is too cold
It doesn't have any sensitivity
Because it falls in this
It falls in this
This area
It won't produce this signal
For you to measure
But this is really a
I can only say now
Available technology state of art
So we spent a lot of
A lot of energy to use it
Then adjust it to be usable
This principle is like this
it is good
Actually
What will it look like?
You see the picture in the upper right corner
That big piece is ours
Our
That
Wafer, you can say it is a wafer
Actually it is a crystal
It is not a semiconductor
We operate it at 30 mK
So it is electricity
It is a source
It is not a semiconductor
Then its thickness
It's not our super thin
But it has to be 20 inches
We are 3 inches
But it grew a big piece
The thickness is 3 cm
Then we are above
In the way of light
Put this TES
That's a lot of little ones
Then enlarge it
This one next to it
You can see it
It has one, two, three, four
Then there are eight
Like a fan
Then the black at the end of the fan
It is TES itself
But why TES is so small
Because the problem is
TES does not want
It has a large
Temperature gradient
So you have to
TES itself is very small
Then you have to make another
A big piece
Phonon absorber
Put the heat in
Then send it all to a very
Small TES
It is very
So from the side
Pink
The pink part is our crystal
Our wafer
After sucking up
TES
This process is actually very complicated
And the cost is very high
But this is not the most complicated part
The most complicated part is that its signal is still super small
It's so small that we can't
Just measure DC
Isn't there a bias?
The answer is no, we can't measure
So we have to use another one
It's also a very high-tech thing
High-tech
It's expensive, it's called Squid
Squid here
Then Squid
The principle of this thing is that it can be measured to a very, very
Small magnetic field
But the magnetic field is only in
Oscillating field
So you become
We want to put our TES
I circle it up and then connect an AC
Current
Then cross a
Magnetic field
Then the magnetic field will produce a magnetic field
For Squid
But we want to say
Our TES is not heated
Then it becomes useless
We want it to be pulled back to its original temperature
So
There is one next to it
This
The circuit
If today's TES is bigger
The current flowing through it
Will become smaller because the current flowing through the next door
Will become bigger
So its self-current heating will become smaller
But you continue to put it in a
Cooling power
Inside the refrigerator
Its temperature will be pulled down
So this is very complicated
Then couple to Squid
Then go up and use Amplifier to magnify it
So our TES
Looks like this
What you see
The one next to it is the size of a person
You can understand
Middle
This little one by one
Each one is the picture on the right
The lower half of the picture on the right
Six boxes
Is the box you just saw
Then there are 31
So there are 31 times 6, 186 pieces
This crystal
Is in such a big experiment
Then
We call it Tower
It's full of complicated and expensive
Circuit
Then we put it in Canada's
Snow Lab, 2 kilometers underground
If you are interested, you can ask me why
Underground
Then Future
This is a summary
Focus on low mass
Then we
We hope it is very low threshold
There is no way to make single
A small elliptical TES becomes very sensitive
So we want to put that
A lot of puzzles
Connect it into a big piece
Then use a single readout
Let it become a
Pixel, so a pixel is so big
Actually, we only have 12 pixels
It means that the fluctuation is averaged
it is good
What is his problem? His problem is
Obviously our Reconstruct
The location of the collision
The location resolution is very bad
Right?
So I want to speed up
Speed up
Then my projection does not speed up
Then this is
Different electronics need to be frozen at different temperatures
So we still have a super super expensive refrigerator
To control this temperature, then it is very wasteful
it is good
So what are we going to do?
What you see now is a prototype detector
I will talk about it quickly because it is basically
Can't
I don't want to talk about it
You see every dot
It's all a single pixel
OK
What about this pixel?
You can see a line here
This line goes up like this
Then down
Then go up again
Then come down again
Read out all the signals of each dot
it is good
Then it is all single pixel
It is not connected into a pixel
And
It doesn't need cryogenic electronics at all
Its signal can be measured directly
What is the reason?
The reason is that we use superconductors
Superconductors have no resistance
But the superconductor has a resistance
Why?
Because we know our
Charge carrier
It is masked
You are in normal electricity
What is it?
Inside the conductor
It is an effective mask
Because it is in a
Electrode inside the lattice
It is a cooper pair inside the superconductor
It is the same
There is a mask
Then there will be a circuit
So let's measure this circuit
What is the best way to measure the circuit?
You say that good
Then I will scan the whole frequency
Then let's see the speed of its drop
I know its slope
I know how big the circuit is
The smartest way
Is to make an oscillator
You help it with a capacitor
Then it becomes like this
OK
So you have a circuit
Then you can use the incoming energy
The example here is light
But we are copper to phonon
Then break it
Break its cooper pair
It changed its circuit
After changing its circuit
The oscillating frequency of this oscillator
So its oscillating frequency
Here will move
Move away
From the side of this move
We know how much it has been broken
Then we know the cooper pair
So we know
How much energy do we need
So what do you actually see?
You put it on
Network analyzer
You see a lot of peaks standing here
Like a comb
This is not in the time domain
Then the frequency domain
If a pixel is hit
It will move to the side
Then the real device
It's broken again
It looks like this
A cable goes in
It's a waveguide
If you don't hit on
Those resonant frequency
It's basically a one in one out
No problem
But hit on resonant frequency
There will be a very big drop
So it's a waveguide
You can read all the pixels
So basically
On the CDMX crystal you just saw
12 pixels, we can make it 1000
No problem
Summarize
This effect
This is our current status
It sounds easy
We just make a number
Then we have 1000 pixels
There is no problem
What is the problem?
What we do now
Looks like this
Resonance is very small
Resonance is about 2dB
Resonance
But our waveguide
It's very, very bad
20dB drop
Continuous
We can make the waveguide
Looks like this
The waveguide is about minus 5dB
But our
Resonance is only about 1dB
Anyway, it's all super bad
Ok
Then finally talk about what we want to do
That is
We know different superconductors
The binding energy of the cooper pair inside
Different
Then we know again
Uh
What is our phonon energy
So if we choose
Cooper pair binding energy
Greater than
That phonon energy
Phonon hits the cooper pair
It won't absorb, it will spit it back
Because it can't break the smallest unit
So
If we put our waveguide
Made of that kind of material
But our detector is called KIT
Kinetic Inductance Detector
Made of material that can be broken
Our 100% energy will
Absorbed in the pixel
So our resolution
Should be very large
High
That's it
A little over time
Actually, I said R&D, but I didn't say it
Someone over there is talking
I'm sorry
My wife told me to go grocery shopping
Will this be recorded?
Will be recorded
It should be recorded
It doesn't matter
Let's go
Resolution
This question is actually like this
The first one is you want to put your
Resonance Q factor
Because the larger your Q factor
The more dots you have to scan
Otherwise you won't see it
Scan your Q factor
How big
What is the basis? How do you decide that?
Instinctively
Just make the Q factor super big
Because if it's super big, it means
It doesn't have a problem with its own detection resolution
But because you
Knocked into the crystal
Phonon
Phonon will
It's just a shockwave, right?
It has a
You know the shockwave divided by the size of the crystal
It's probably the time it floats to the surface
So its wave shape
There's probably one
There's one
There's one in the frequency
There's a main band
Today you want it to be coupled
To a certain
Resonance
Actually you have to do
Conversion
Convert to
The width of the baseband is
Equal to your bandwidth
So your
Resolution actually depends on
How big your crystal is
So we actually
Don't want it to be big
It can't be too big
Otherwise we will miss the phonon
That's probably
10 to the power of 4
And then we see how many pixels to put
And then between each pixel
In order to keep it out of the way
You have to look at its spacing
How wide
Then add this up and you can push
Your whole
Dynamic range
You have to measure a few points
And then how fast
Of course it has something to do with DAQ
I have a question
You said a
What does it mean
Actually
Waveguide is a very fancy word
But it's actually a wire
The wire is actually waveguide
When you appreciate this thing, you feel that the wire is super powerful
Just good
I go back to that page
This picture
You put the one next to it
The Tai Chi picture is all gone
There's a wire, isn't there
And then there's a bucket here
Each bucket is a pixel
And then that pixel
It's a
LC circuit
You can think of it as
It's a resonator
It's a very, very narrow band
Bandpass
And it's super bandpass
That is to say, when your frequency
Just fall in
That
The frequency
Your signal will not flow from the beginning
To the end
You will flow from the beginning to this side
And then you just turn it all the way down
OK, so
What about this picture
You can think of this picture as
The signal you take out
The signal you put in
So
This line is 1.0
That is to say, there is no hit
When the resonator
How much in, how much out
What I'm talking about now is an ideal situation
But it's not an ideal situation
But when it goes in
The frequency it goes in
It just happens to be from this
It will show up all the way down
So this will go straight
To the bottom
Theoretically, it should be super 5DD
So it will become a number
Basically, that's it
Is this number picture a one-shot
Or does it always have a frequency
Or is it always
You can think of me sending a frequency
And then send a frequency
This is a way to do it
But another way is like this
Is that you send a signal in
And then the signal that comes out
Do a Fourier transform
So you have to send in all the frequencies at once
So the AC next to you
Is to send in all the frequencies
Yes, but it will be slower
It should be said that its resolution is lower
Sorry, it's not slower, it's lower
So we usually
Take the detector
And then do this once
See all the numbers
Where is that one by one
And then we send a lot of
Those tones
Do you know what I mean
So we actually
Just delete a lot of
The bottom of the flat line
So our DAQ will be much faster
But yes, that's probably it
It has its problems
That's it
At least for people
It's a one-shot time for people
I can hear you
I'm Zhang Jianping
You're Zhang Jianping
What else
Are you sleeping
What's the problem
That's it
I think you've been talking about it
It seems that basically everyone is
Mostly from the hardware
To
To change
Have you ever thought about this
In fact, you can
The software part of the statistics
Can do a little help
Because I feel like you're in the front
The chamber
It's a more continuous way
It's a continuous one
But it still has to knock things
But it's more continuous
But when you get to the back
When it becomes the transition edge
It's like
We want to measure a person
How perverted he is
Give him a perverted meter
Assuming continuous
But to see if he's going to kill
It becomes a one-off
Do you know what I'm talking about
Wait a minute
Do you know that speaking will be recorded
It doesn't matter
I'm not talking about it today
Anyway
So your curve will become
This should not be called long linear
But this is the
Line of logistic regression
So in fact
It's a one-off
You spend a continuous line
One or one straight line
In the middle
Then I see you feed him
It's just looking at his results
But actually if you put it
Because your problem now is
My feeling is
Because Dark Matter is a
It's more of a sample study
Because your signal is rare
If I'm not mistaken
There are some
Processing sample
Information
Can increase sensitivity
With the accuracy of the time
Including if you use some
Like bootstrapping
Or use some
Regularization
To
Regularize his signal
It's actually
Bayesian method
You can increase
Artificially increase its accuracy
Although it sounds weird
Because you actually
It's not really seeing anything
No, it's not weird
You know what I want to use
But it doesn't seem to work
Do you know
It can be used
I'm here
Because the question is a bit long
So
I repeat it again
So the problem with the sample
In addition to talking a lot of dirty words in the middle
Because there are not many
His problem is like this
That is to say, we are now doing detector
Then measured
If you don't measure it, you don't measure it
But can we use
Software method
Our
General
Experimental sensitivity
Is that what you mean?
Correct
The answer is yes
And when you have
One or two hundred people doing an experiment
This part will have one hundred people
Do something like this
Ok
Why are we
Now focus on this part
There is actually a very interesting reason
When you start doing dark matter
You will find out
The environment you live in
The air you breathe
The pen you use is super invincible
Very radioactive
OK
So the problem is
We can now
Measure the signal
Then use the software you just said
To correct it
Whether it is correct
His true location
True energy
But we eventually
There will be a problem
We want to be very clear
Confidence level is very high
This is my detector
Radioactivity
Or the real dark matter
Then we
Now found
The most important
To distinguish this
The difference is
Even if it is a neutral particle
As long as it is
The particle we know
The depth of his special detector
It must be lighter than dark matter
why
Because his interaction must be bigger
So he was blocked earlier
So we are very, very
To know exactly
Where is he really hitting
Then we just
Buy a super expensive crystal
Then he is one-half outside
The signal over there
Don't use
It's a waste of money
So we want to be very, very good
Location resolution
The most important thing we are now
The biggest limit is
We have six pixels on one side
What do you want
So our limit is not
The reconstruction of our software
Not good
Your detection is basically
The biggest limitation
Our software
Video
Talk about this
I don't want to talk about the content
You can see the picture
The star next to it hasn't come out yet
The star next to it
The blue part
Is in one of them
Surface detector
The red part is in another
I just said
There are six pixels on one side
So there are twelve
The six pixels are actually arranged
A triangle like this
Plus one in the middle
Then there are two rings on the outside
If there are two rings on the outside
He has measured any signal
We think he is on the surface
We just threw it away
So you didn't see it here
And then in the middle
But there are a lot of triangles
You can see
If that size is six
If it's three inches
The width is actually super wide
So the resolution is super bad
If you want to do this
You either have to dig
To the very edge
Let you go
This thing is
We know the particle
Or we have to find the particle
The confidence level is very low
Or you have to dig a lot
Either way is not the most efficient way
So we have to do this on the hardware
It's the most you're right
It's true that it's true on the software
But it's relative
Change the hardware directly
His effectiveness
Too much difference
But you're right
Do you have any questions?
I just turned off the microphone
So speak slower
I'll ask you again
You just
The new design
Is to use
Six L and C
Then it looks like
You can do 40 on the hardware
Then you just said that
You can't do too high
Then you need to consider
His loss
That is to say, he changed to this
Super early
It's broken
Ok
Good question
The answer is
This is the problem of TES
Not our problem
Why?
Because TES
He just needs to operate near TC
So there is a little bit
Local heat accumulation
Will have a big impact on the function of the detector
But what we want
Turn on kinetic inductance
The more the better
So
TC is 1K, 2K material
We freeze it to 20mK
This way
Our kinetic inductance is very large
And
Thermal fluctuation
There is no impact
So this is one of the advantages of TES
But yes
This is the problem of TES
Any other questions?
If not
Thank you