Let's start recording.
Okay.
Okay, I got it. Thank you.
Let's start.
Hello, everyone. I'm Zhang Yanping.
I'm your host today.
But I'll probably talk for a while
and then I'll be gone.
Because my wife's waist is twisted
to the point where she can't hold the baby.
So...
I'm going to have an emergency meeting later.
So today,
let's welcome Hanxi to share
with us...
He's the only one who has a webcam
so he's Hanxi.
He's going to share
with us about the
law related to
public safety.
Because
Hanxi...
Is Hanxi right?
Yes, that's right.
Okay.
My Chinese isn't very good.
Hanxi used to
study law.
But then he went to the police station
to study...
He studied for a while
in Yang Ming's police station.
Then he came back to study law.
His major is
the law related to
public safety.
Hanxi will share the details with us later.
No problem.
We're happy to have Hanxi here today
because he's probably our first law student.
Also, he's probably our first...
I guess,
pure humanist.
So we're happy that we can finally
expand to a more complete
academic field.
There are people in all fields.
Without further ado,
let's give a round of applause to welcome Hanxi.
I'm the only one in charge of filming.
Because
today's guest is not alone.
Today's guest is not alone.
Let me briefly introduce myself.
I'm a friend of Yuhui.
Let's get to know each other.
Why is my microphone
turned off all of a sudden?
Okay.
Yeah.
It's like
a small roundtable.
It's like a chat.
It's not a formal report.
Since we have the opportunity,
let's get to know each other.
Okay.
I'm not sure
which school you're from.
So let's...
Let me introduce myself.
I'm from UNC.
I'm from Beka.
I'm majoring in social psychology.
Who's next?
Hello.
Hi.
Let me introduce myself first.
I'm from DC.
I'm George Washington.
I'm majoring in mechanical engineering.
I'm majoring in
high-performance computing.
It's related to supercomputers.
I'm doing an internship
in Tennessee.
So you're not in DC.
I'll be back in September.
Cool.
So your name is
Zhuang Ping...
Bi Yue.
Zhuang Bi Yue.
Bi Yue Xuan Hua.
Okay.
Let's switch to Caltech.
We have two people here.
I'm Zhuang Ye You.
I'm working in Caltech
and NASA JPL.
I'm working on dark matter experiments.
I'm Yu Zhe Jing.
You can call me Zhe.
I'm studying in Taiwan University.
I'm working in Caltech.
I used to work in chemical engineering.
I'm working in environmental engineering.
That's cool.
So there's one more person.
He left a comment
in the chat room.
Oh, okay.
He's studying geography.
What field is he studying?
Geography is pretty broad.
It ranges from biology to natural science.
I'm pretty interested in this.
So we're going to
chat with Zhuang.
Physical Geography.
Okay.
You've been to Charleston.
I'm going to start.
I'm going to hand over my video.
Okay.
Hello, everyone.
I'm at Georgetown
studying law.
If you have any questions,
feel free to ask.
You can see my screen.
I think you can hear me.
If you have any questions,
feel free to ask.
I'm happy to share
my research topic with you.
I'm at Georgetown Law School.
It's a big classroom.
The signal here is very good.
I'm preparing this topic
about obesity
and soda tax.
I'm preparing this topic
about obesity
and soda tax.
I'm preparing this topic
about obesity
and soda tax.
I'm happy to share
my research topic
with you.
As for this topic,
as for this topic,
I've seen your research background
and your interest.
You are a Law student,
after my research.
You have a reputation
as an authority
in social science
You have a reputation as an authority
and with the social issue.
I am not sure
If we are too
boring or too hard Louise.
I am not sure
is a good
introduction.
Well
Briefly is a bit
complicated because
Actually I have
been to many schools
and by the way
this is the 5th
University of Charleston
So there are
my field
On the one hand, I was born with a legal background
as you all know
I studied law
and then became a lawyer
I was born with a legal background and trained
I also studied law
and now I am studying law
On the other hand, I have
a different background
from other law students
in my work experience
and medical background
How to say
My first
political work
I put a small picture here
My first political work
was in Seattle
ICHS
International Community Health Service
hospital work
At that time, I was in UW
After graduating from the University of Charleston
I went there to work
This is my first political work
Because I was a lawyer in Taiwan before
I haven't worked in Taiwan
That was my first political work
For a lawyer in Taiwan
I worked in a hospital
I think this is a very surprising thing
Anyway
So that year
to some extent
I got interested in medical law
and then
jumped out
When I returned to Taiwan
I tried to keep it as relevant as possible
So I continued to specialize in medical law
in the field of public health law
So can everyone hear me?
Because I found this
quite strange
I can't hear everyone's voice
We can hear you
Welcome everyone to speak at any time
Otherwise
It's my first time to find this kind of self-talk
It feels strange
You can't see anyone
It's like practicing a speech
I can hear you
Will it be better if I turn it on?
If you don't mind
I feel like I can see your face
Because I'm not wearing clothes right now
So I don't want to see
But other people who are wearing clothes can turn it on
Other people who are wearing clothes can turn it on
If there is an answer, we will turn it on
Okay, no problem, thank you
Can we turn on the video?
Yes, you can turn off the sound
At least there is a video
It feels better to talk to a real person
Okay, thank you
To put it simply
I'm basically a lawyer
I went to Taiwan to study law
But I'm interested in public health law
So I chose this topic
OK, I'm probably
It's 6.20 right now
It's actually quite simple
My presentation is divided into three parts
The first one is introduction
I want to introduce the background of this research
Why did we choose sugar?
Why did we choose soda
And the intervention of public health
The second one
I reported a case study
One of the things I studied was the case of Sodatex
Finally, I hope to leave some time for discussion
About Sodatex
Because Caltech should be in LA
So if there are students from
San Francisco or Berkeley
They are really
Within the scope of the use of Sodatex
Because there is Sodatex in the city
May feel better
But this is a trend
So all cities in the United States
are moving in this direction
So maybe you will have this problem
I have talked to the LA public health officials
So it may not be in the short term
But this proposal has always existed
It is possible
After the discussion
There must be pros and cons
So I will use my time
What is the concept of Sodatex?
Isn't there any in California?
People in California
Are using cities as units
To increase the Sodatex
Most correct names are
more accurate translation is
it is except this Salestex
it is in addition to a SodaTex
it is the at the top
more than now
This trend continues
more and more places
plus tax
When buying fuel
it is more expensive
like buying cigarettes and drinking alcohol
The tax on it has a higher price
Not exactly
extent
not exactly
I don't know if you will talk about it later
I just want to ask
Does the tax cover
hand shake drinks
like bubble milk tea
For now
for bubble milk
This is a good question
Because most of it
in tax
is made
the finished product
But
if it is a
freshly made drink
freshly made juice
It doesn't look like it
But I can
I think it is not included in terms of definition
But I can check again
This is a good question
Especially in Taiwan
If you want to pass
Does this hand shake drink include
I think it is not included in terms of definition
But I can help you confirm this
I can check again
Thank you
We will cut it into three parts
I will do the introduction part first
I want to tell you
Why we choose sugar
Why we choose soda
This is a trend
You may have noticed
But if you use Google
This is what I did yesterday
I went to Google
You can see
Bloomberg
This is from New York
This week
You may have seen this
They are
Nuts Bar
Energy Bar
They
have 45485 pounds of sugar
This is equivalent to
every 5 minutes
all children in the US
Let me check
About
70 million
children
under 18
5 minutes of sugar consumption
Private companies
do this
to promote
their products
They want to promote their products
They have a new product
which is
fruit bar
They call it D-tar
This company is very interesting
I don't know if you have bought their products
If you look at their products
you will see the word healthy
This company
used the word healthy
on the packaging
This company won FDA
FDA música
FDA
Coca-Cola
Singapore
Pepsi
artificial sweeteners
Diet Coke
Coca-Cola
Sparkling Water
Diet Coke
Non-Communicable Diseases
Diabetes
Obesity
Diet Coke
Non-Communicable Diseases
主持人李宗盛