Hello everyone, I'm the host for today, Zhang Yanyong, and we're going to have our 21st Terra Talk.
Today's speaker is Xu Liyan.
Xu Liyan and I have known each other for almost two years.
It's really interesting because we're at Caltech, and Xu Liyan is studying astronomy at Manoa University in Hawaii.
In 2016, we had a year-long visit to Caltech and IPAC.
At that time, we met Xu Liyan.
Xu Liyan happens to be a senior in the Department of Physics at Caltech, but he was studying astronomy at Manoa University in Hawaii.
Did I say that correctly?
I'm from the Department of Physics.
Oh, you're from the Department of Physics.
But you're studying astronomy at Manoa University.
My advisor is from Manoa University.
I see.
It's interesting because he's from Hawaii, and they were surfing.
I was surfing, so we became good friends.
Of course, his main job is still doing astronomy observation research in Hawaii.
After returning from Caltech, in 2017, he recently obtained a Ph.D. degree, so he is a new doctor.
Liyan's research is mainly galaxy observation.
In his doctoral career, he is going to talk to us about this big topic today.
He published 34 papers, but today he will focus on the latest one.
If you are interested in learning more about the previous papers, you can contact him directly.
Without further ado, let's welcome Liyan to give us his speech.
I'll mute myself.
I'd like to remind everyone to mute your microphone when you speak.
Thank you.
You can start.
Okay, I'll start.
If you have any questions, please mute your microphone.
I'm afraid people won't understand.
Oh, sorry.
We forgot something.
We need to clap.
We need to mute our microphone when we clap.
Okay, you can start.
Okay, thank you.
As you can see, my title is Characterizing Faint Sub-millimeter Galaxies with Posture Lensing.
If you don't read astronomy, you can only understand Characterizing, Faint, and Width.
I'll explain what they mean.
In short, I'm studying a galaxy called Sub-millimeter Galaxy.
The wavelength detected by this galaxy is called Sub-millimeter.
Sub-millimeter is shorter than millimeter.
Millimeter is in kilometers.
Traditionally, people use 850 micrometers to study Sub-millimeter Galaxy.
Now I'll explain why I'm studying this galaxy and what I'm studying.
Okay.
Why do we study this galaxy?
It's related to the evolution of the universe.
You can google the history of the universe.
You'll see a similar picture.
The age of the universe is 13.7 billion years.
Maybe you've heard of it.
It started from the Big Bang.
The history of the universe is shown here.
Then there was a period of time called Inflation.
At that time, the temperature of the universe was still very high.
It was all gaseous gas.
Until the temperature dropped to the ground.
The gaseous electrons in the universe were recombined with the gaseous atoms.
They became neutral gas atoms.
From then on, light can start to run freely in the universe.
Before that, any light would be scattered by those gaseous electrons.
From then on, light can run freely in the universe.
At that time, the universe was scattered by those gaseous electrons.
Okay.
But the temperature of the universe was still very high.
So there were a lot of neutral gas atoms in the universe.
After the temperature dropped to the ground.
The temperature of the gaseous atoms dropped to the ground.
The temperature of the universe was still very high.
So there were a lot of neutral gas atoms in the universe.
Before that, there was a period called Dark Age.
Okay.
Basically, in the Big Bang, Inflation, and Cosmic Microwave Background.
During this period, I basically think that this part of history belongs to physicists.
Like the theory of explosion, it's a physicist.
This is very physical.
And Big Bang.
From the beginning of the formation of gravity.
After the first gravity.
This part can be done by astronomers.
Astronomers can do this part.
I said that the temperature of the universe.
Because the universe is constantly expanding.
The temperature slowly drops.
And these gaseous atoms.
It can be further combined into gaseous atoms.
Gaseous atoms.
If it's cold enough.
After gravity collapses.
It will form a star.
Then the star will.
You should have heard of the star.
Just like our sun.
It produces a fusion reaction.
So it will glow.
Then it will produce gas.
Okay.
Then the star will not be one by one.
They are produced in groups.
That is to form the so-called galaxy.
Right.
The galaxy is.
A galaxy is basically.
More than a billion of stars.
Okay.
It is a system of galaxies.
So.
From this time on.
After the galaxy.
It is.
Many galaxies.
In this universe.
More and more galaxies.
Okay.
Then.
We study.
I mean.
This part.
I study the so-called.
Galaxy formation and evolution.
The formation of galaxies.
And evolution.
Then.
An important point is.
My research.
This research.
Is to study.
This universe.
The star formation.
The history of star formation.
This is the so-called.
Cosmic star formation.
Then.
We want to use.
That is to say.
From this.
From the first star to now.
The evolution of this universe.
One of them.
You have to understand the evolution of this universe.
You have to understand.
It must be very important.
How to say.
One of the very important factors.
Is star formation.
Because.
If you.
From the perspective of astronomy.
No matter what you are studying.
No matter you are studying.
The evolution of galaxies.
Galaxy formation and evolution.
Or.
You want to study.
What.
Stars.
For example.
Like our solar system.
Or study.
What.
Mars.
Small stars.
In the universe.
No matter what kind of weather you study.
It must be.
Related to the stars.
Because.
You have the star.
You have the star formation.
After.
After the star formation.
These stars.
Merge together.
Becomes.
Galaxy.
So it's related to the galaxy.
Then.
You.
Star.
Star system.
Like our solar system.
Is.
After the star formation.
Then.
Some dust around this star.
Slowly.
Is formed.
Star.
Then the star.
Just go around the star.
Like the comet.
Small star.
This is also.
So.
You can say.
Astronomy.
No matter what you study.
Ah.
I said astronomy.
If it's.
The kind of physics in cosmology.
It doesn't count.
Astronomy.
Basically.
Whatever you do.
No matter what you do.
It's related to.
Star formation.
So star formation.
History.
Star formation.
So it's a very important.
Ah.
You want to understand.
This universe.
This is a very important thing.
OK.
Then.
So.
I believe I have.
Convinced everyone.
Star formation.
History.
It's a very important thing.
But.
Ah.
Star formation.
History.
Ah.
We.
When we do research.
Found.
This picture on the left.
It's the so-called.
I put star formation.
History.
This thing.
Brighten it.
Then.
This place.
Left.
This axis.
Called.
Star formation.
Great.
Density.
Star formation.
Great.
Is.
Left.
There is a green layer.
Is.
Every year.
His unit is.
Ah.
The quality of the stars.
Out of.
Time.
Then.
His unit basically.
Every year.
You see.
Can produce.
How many solar qualities.
This.
This unit is the solar mass.
Is the solar mass.
So in this part.
Calls.
Star formation.
Great.
So if you are in the volume.
Is.
Star formation.
Great.
Then in the unit volume.
Then.
Don't.
You don't care how he came.
Then he is a huge unit.
Then.
Three times.
So he is this part.
Ah.
Gravitational law.
In the unit volume.
So called.
Star formation.
Great.
Density.
Very early.
Here is the lookback time.
So the more to the right.
Is.
Longer ago.
OK.
Then this lookback time.
Can correspond to the so-called.
Redshift.
Called.
Then this.
Redshift.
What is it?
I'll explain it later.
But you can.
I can tell you now.
Is.
The more to the right.
The earlier.
The.
Universe.
That.
Zero.
This place is now.
OK.
So the time travel.
Is from the right to the left.
Or from the left to the right.
OK.
Then this picture.
Basically.
Is a star formation.
History.
Then you want to.
Measure this picture.
Ah.
You.
We.
Ah.
Will find.
There are two.
Ah.
Basically.
Can be.
Two kinds of observations.
Is very important.
Is.
Ah.
When we used to.
Probably in the 90s.
When.
The end of the 90s.
We have some.
Ah.
Satellite.
It's the space telescope.
We go to measure.
The whole universe.
Background radiation.
That.
There are different.
Wavelength background radiation.
That.
I just mentioned.
The background radiation of the universe microwave.
Is called.
Cosmic Microwave Background.
Is here.
Ah.
Then this.
Is.
Is the intensity of light.
Then.
Horizontal.
Is wavelength.
So this is basically.
Light wave.
That.
CMB is probably a place.
Then we will find.
In this universe.
There are two components.
CMB does not count.
There are two.
Very important components.
One is called.
Cosmic.
Optical Background.
It is visible.
Light.
Background.
Then the other part.
Is called.
Cosmic Infrared Background.
Is infrared background.
Then we found.
These two.
Background.
Their amount.
Is almost.
Almost.
So what does this tell us?
Because in this universe.
Horizontal.
They will send out.
Ah.
Point light.
Visible light.
Or.
Infrared light.
That.
Horizontal.
Direct light.
Basically.
Is this component.
Optical Background.
OK.
But.
In this universe.
Star formation.
OK.
About half.
The other half.
Is not.
We can directly observe.
It is called.
Dusty Star Formation.
What does it mean?
That is.
When you have.
A lot of stars.
In a region.
Then.
A lot of.
New.
Huge stars.
They.
Very soon.
They will age.
And become so-called.
Supernova.
Then.
These.
These huge stars.
They are produced.
A lot of.
Heavy objects.
Then.
They become supernova.
They will explode.
Then.
Those heavy objects.
That is.
Is talked about.
In the space of the universe.
And.
Heavy objects.
For example, carbon.
Metal.
These things.
They will form.
The dust of the star system.
That is.
So-called.
Dust.
That particles.
Is.
Like dust.
Floating.
In space.
That.
Dust.
Will block.
These stars.
Directly.
The light emitted by the star system.
As I said.
It is.
Extraterrestrial light.
Radiation light.
And.
Near-infrared.
That is.
Near-infrared light.
Those dust.
Will absorb.
This part of the light.
Then.
From the perspective of.
The observer on our planet.
That is.
Blocking it.
Blocking that part of the light.
But.
After it is blocked.
The energy is stored.
After it is absorbed.
It will radiate.
These energy.
The energy it absorbs.
Radiate out.
But when it radiates out.
Is.
Absorbed.
So we call.
Dusty star formation.
Or.
Dust.
Hidden star formation.
Or.
Dust obscured star formation.
Anyway.
The meaning is.
These star formation.
Will be.
Dust.
Gave.
Gaved.
This animation is now 이게 siblings of the Rebel Spirit.
The Rebel Spirit is far away from us.
The Rebel Spirit is in the cosmos.
The Cosmological Redshift.
The Cosmological Redshift is the effect of cosmic radiation.
The Cosmological Redshift is the effect of gravity.
The lower shift galaxy is more dusty.
Carbon-2 is a notation used by astronomers.
You can observe the frequency of the plane.
You can observe the genetic movement.
By GPS, campuses are very dark, not easy to measure
molecules and elements
The problem tells the particle wavelength
You can analyze the distribution of the components
to know their dynamics
As an example, this study paper
The green and blue
are basically visible light or near-infrared light
So what they represent is the horizontal part
And the red part is the result of OMAR observation
So the result of OMAR observation is basically dust
Then they found that the horizontal part is a messy piece
That is, they have a wider distribution
And their dust is very compact in the middle
So what they found is that the horizontal part is a messy piece