Ok, welcome everyone to today's Tara Talk. I'm today's host, Zhang Yanyong. We are very honored to be able to invite our speaker today, Lu Yi, which is a very special field. Because most of our Tara Talks are based on material science or science, but today we invited Lu Yi to talk about the topic of material science.
The topic that Lu Yi will talk about is the discussion of copyright in streaming, a comparison of the U.S. and European regimes, understanding streaming and copyright.
Lu Yi is currently a candidate for the doctorate of law at the University of Washington. His main field is the law of intellectual property rights, anti-Thorax and economic analysis.
At the same time, he also served as a legal advisor to the 2H online store during his time at school. He is now in the doctoral class. Before he was in the doctoral class, he was an intern at the U.S. and European law firms in Washington.
He is also very interested in the spirit of entrepreneurs, so he joined the China Entrepreneurship Interaction Association to serve as a counselor.
He regularly holds meetings and talks to promote the spirit of entrepreneurs in Taiwan. Before he came to the United States, he was an intern at the U.S. Department of Justice.
During his time at school, he represented Taiwan in the international business dialogue in Germany and the Harvard-Asia International Relations Conference.
He also has a very handsome photo on my bio. If you are interested, please take a look.
Before he came to the United States, he represented Taiwan in the international business dialogue in Germany and the Harvard-Asia International Relations Conference. He also has a very handsome photo on my bio. If you are interested, please take a look.
If you are interested, please take a look.
The online streaming service we use now is also part of the online streaming service. In fact, the online streaming service has changed a lot of human privacy habits, including YouTube and Hulu.
I think this is all streaming and Netflix. These are all things in streaming. What I want to share with you today is the controversy of streaming in the production industry, especially in the United States and Europe.
This is my outline today. I will share with you briefly. Because today's PowerPoint is shared by me in the seminar at the Department of Justice, so the content may be a bit deep for everyone.
First, if you have any questions, you can interrupt me at any time. Second, because I am thinking about everyone's state, I will not talk so deeply in each session. If you have any more detailed questions, you can ask me in person or leave a message to ask me.
This is the order of my speech today. First, I will tell you why I am doing this research and how I do it. Next, I will start with a little bit of technology.
This technical aspect is not as much data as Li Gong-ge. I will only briefly talk about the background structure of the streaming service. Fourth, I will take some European and American cases related to streaming and compare them.
In the end, I will find that some companies are often neglecting certain things. I hope to make some suggestions. If the audience here is interested in this field in the future, you can listen to it and refer to my thoughts.
There are many online streaming services, including music streaming, video streaming, audio streaming, and news streaming. As everyone knows, there are Amazon, Spotify, Hulu, and Netflix.
This is the background. In addition to doing wireless TV, traditional media is now jumping in to do streaming, such as NBC and ABC.
Next, I will talk about why we should pay attention to streaming. In the lower right corner, there is a name called Cleaning Perkins. This is one of the most famous startups in the U.S. and is dedicated to the so-called network industry or network entrepreneurship.
At the beginning of this year, Cleaning Perkins published a research report. It shows that consumers are using the internet, and companies are investing in it. This is a very interesting intersection.
This shows the perspective of corporate investment. In the past, corporate investment has been invested in traditional media, such as TV or large-screen advertising.
At the end of this year, net investment will exceed the investment of traditional media. What does this show?
It shows that companies are slowly shifting their investment in advertising or marketing budgets from traditional media to the internet. At the end of this year, net investment will exceed the investment of traditional media.
Let's talk about corporate investment first, and then look at it from the perspective of the market.
In 2017, when the market was estimated, this report is from McKinsey, a well-known management company. McKinsey predicts that in terms of consumer consumption, the year-on-year growth rate is still increasing compared to 2014.
If you look at the three numbers, the North American market, North America, Western Europe, and Central Eastern Europe, in 2017, they still accounted for about half of the total number.
This is why I choose to compare the European and American systems. This is from the perspective of per capita consumption. From the perspective of the company, the investment is slowly increasing, and the per capita consumption is increasing.
The market is still concentrated in the North American and European markets. This is one of the main reasons why I want to research. I will focus on the US and European markets.
Next, I will talk about my core research. First is the structure. The structure of streaming is mainly divided into three parts. The first part is the aggregation on the far left.
The aggregation means that if the structure of streaming is used as a metaphor for television, it only changes the signal of streaming from wireless or wired to the Internet.
To put it simply, the structure of the background is actually divided into three parts. The first part is aggregation. Aggregation is to create content from television or major media companies.
These streaming will collect these signals and put them on the cloud. I think everyone has heard of the storage format on the cloud, which is called MP4.
MP4 compresses the storage process, allowing the original wireless or wired signal to become a cloud storage format. MP4 allows the streaming to be relatively stable.
MP4 is also a technology standard that has always been in the spotlight. Maybe in a few years, it will no longer be MP4. It may be faster and more fluid. Of course, there are many reasons why the Internet media will lag.
The storage format is one of them. MP4 becomes a very important part of the entire structure of streaming in the second stage of storage. After storage, it is sent.
In fact, in the part of the delivery, it will also be converted from the storage format to the delivery format. I won't go into detail about the delivery format. If you are interested, you can check on the Internet what HLS is, what MPEG-DASH is, and what Smooth Streaming is.
Basically, it is converted from the storage format to the delivery format. There is a thing called Streaming Endpoint in the middle. Streaming Endpoint is a bit like a Chinese book concept.
It means that when it is converted from storage to delivery, Streaming Endpoint allows consumers to watch these videos without lagging. This is the main structure of streaming. I converted the original signal into a storage format and then sent it out.
In the process, it is smooth, but there is a storage in the middle and the so-called gathering process. The question will appear at the very beginning, which is gathering. Why is gathering a common problem in streaming?
Let's go back to the paper itself.
Sorry, let me interrupt. There is a question about this page. The feature of streaming is that it can store the data in the cloud and then have a distribution. You mentioned today that you want to focus on areas, such as the United States and Europe.
But if today you can imagine that someone is in Asia and he can somehow use VPN to watch Netflix data in areas other than Asia. In this case, where should we focus on the discussion of the law or how to define the area itself?
This question is quite interesting. From my perspective, if the storage is in another country, but if you look at the legal aspect, you have to choose a country to sue him, right?
If the storage is in another country, but you sue him in the United States, this question will appear in the issue of evidence collection.
You can say goodbye to someone, but if the storage is in another country, there will be an issue of evidence collection.
For example, we may have heard of a very famous case before, which is that Mega Upload was sacked by the United States. I don't know if you know about Mega Upload.
Mega Upload is an online sharing platform, which is a bit like P2P file sharing, which is very similar to Grokster. After he was sacked in the United States, he moved his server to Australia.
You can't catch him in the United States. The United States does not have the authority to catch him, and only Australia can catch him.
So that's Mega Upload. I think the interesting thing about streaming is the aggregation part, which sometimes uses different methods to collect signals.
I don't know if this answers your question, because this question is quite interesting.
He said yes. OK, thank you. I guess I'll talk more about it later.
But I think this question is interesting. If you put it in another country, the structure is the same in Europe and the United States.
But in different regions, there are different technical restrictions, as just mentioned by the questioner.
For example, I am in the United States, so I can't let Asians see it. This is stipulated in the contract.
The contract comes from the front end, which is the so-called media company. He will stipulate that if you are downstream, such as streaming, you can play my media.
Then I have to have regional restrictions. If I don't do it, then you violate the contract. That's another question.
I hope this answers your question. Next, let's talk about the legal part.
I will talk about these two cases. I think the first case in the copyright industry is that ABC sued Aureo.
Aureo has fallen because of this case. After half a year, Fox sued Dish Network. If you are in the United States, you must have heard of Dish Network.
What happened to the two of them? ABC sued Aureo because Aureo was still alive.
I emphasize that because Aureo is no longer alive. When Aureo was alive, he provided a very powerful service. He opened a platform on the Internet, and each consumer paid $12 per month.
After paying $12, you can choose the channels you want. After choosing these channels, Aureo will catch the signal according to the list you choose.
If you are sensitive, you should be able to catch the signal. Did Aureo give money to these broadcasters? No.
He used technology to catch these signals. After catching the signal, he stored it on his cloud. After storing the cloud, he sent it to the consumer and received $12 per month.
This is how Aureo made money. Of course, it's funny that Aureo sued Dish Network in January 2013.
This is a very obvious violation. Because you didn't pay money at all. The problem is back to the aggregation part. The source of the signal is illegal.
You didn't give money to these broadcasters. Of course, these broadcasters will be angry and jump. Because they can't get a dime. Your client paid money to Aureo, but Aureo did not give money to them.
This is a very obvious violation. The problem is back to the aggregation part. The source of the signal is illegal. The problem is back to the aggregation part.
This is a very obvious violation. The source of the signal is illegal. The problem is back to the aggregation part. The source of the signal is illegal.
The name of the previous broadcaster is that you did not pass my authorization to steal my signal and play it today, so it violates my right to broadcast publicly.
Most people here do not know the status of the U.S. law. The status of the U.S. law is similar to that of Taiwan's constitutional court.
The U.S. Constitutional Court will only accept less than 50 cases a year. The U.S. Supreme Court will only accept cases that have a serious legal explanation.
The U.S. Supreme Court will only accept cases that have a serious legal explanation.
Google was sued by the EU in June.
The second case I want to mention is the one I just mentioned.
Google invented a machine.