Ok, welcome everyone to today's Tara Talk. I'm today's host, Zhang Yanyong. We are very honored to be able to invite our speaker today, Lu Yi, which is a very special field. Because most of our Tara Talks are based on material science or science, but today we invited Lu Yi to talk about the topic of material science.
The topic that Lu Yi will talk about is the discussion of copyright in streaming, a comparison of the U.S. and European regimes, understanding streaming and copyright.
Lu Yi is currently a candidate for the doctorate of law at the University of Washington. His main field is the law of intellectual property rights, anti-Thorax and economic analysis.
At the same time, he also served as a legal advisor to the 2H online store during his time at school. He is now in the doctoral class. Before he was in the doctoral class, he was an intern at the U.S. and European law firms in Washington.
He is also very interested in the spirit of entrepreneurs, so he joined the China Entrepreneurship Interaction Association to serve as a counselor.
He regularly holds meetings and talks to promote the spirit of entrepreneurs in Taiwan. Before he came to the United States, he was an intern at the U.S. Department of Justice.
During his time at school, he represented Taiwan in the international business dialogue in Germany and the Harvard-Asia International Relations Conference.
He also has a very handsome photo on my bio. If you are interested, please take a look.
During his time at school, he represented Taiwan in the international business dialogue in Germany and the Harvard-Asia International Relations Conference. He also has a very handsome photo on my bio. If you are interested, please take a look.
If you are interested, please take a look.
The online streaming service we use now is also part of the online streaming service. In fact, the online streaming service has changed a lot of human privacy habits, including YouTube and Hulu.
In fact, the online streaming service has changed a lot of human privacy habits, including YouTube and Hulu.
This is my outline today. I will briefly share with you.
Because today's PowerPoint is shared by me in the seminar at the Department of Justice, so the content may be a bit deep for everyone.
First, if you have any questions, please feel free to interrupt me.
Second, because I am thinking about everyone's state, I will not talk so deeply in each session.
If you have any more detailed questions, you can ask me in person or leave a message to ask me.
This is the order of my speech today.
First, I will tell you why I am doing this research and how I do it.
Next, I will start with a little bit of technology.
But this technology is not as much data as Li Gong-ge.
I will only briefly talk about the background structure of the streaming service.
Fourth, I will take some European and American cases related to streaming and compare them.
In the end, I will find something in this comparison.
I can say that if future companies want to do this, they often ignore some things.
I hope to make some suggestions.
If the audience here is interested in this area in the future, you can listen to it and refer to my thoughts.
This is the online streaming service.
There are many services, including music, video, audio, and news.
Amazon, Spotify, Hulu, and Netflix.
This is the background.
Traditional media, in addition to doing wireless TV, are now jumping in to do streaming.
For example, NBC and ABC are also actively jumping in to do this.
Next, why do we need to pay attention to streaming?
There is a name in the lower right corner, which is Cleaning Perkins.
Cleaning Perkins is a well-known startup in the U.S.
It specializes in online business.
At the beginning of this year, it published a research report.
It shows that consumers use the internet, and companies invest in it.
This is a very interesting intersection.
This shows the perspective of corporate investment.
In the past, corporate investment was mostly in traditional media, such as TV or large-screen advertising.
This year, the data shows that at the end of this year,
the investment of online investment will exceed the investment of traditional media.
What does this show?
It shows that companies are starting to shift from traditional media to the internet.
At the end of this year, the investment of online investment will exceed the investment of traditional media.
Let's talk about corporate investment first.
Let's look at it from the perspective of the market.
In 2017, when we estimated the market,
this report is from McKinsey, a well-known management company.
McKinsey predicts that the annual growth rate of streaming will continue to rise compared to 2014.
If you look at the three numbers, North America, Western Europe, and Central Eastern Europe,
in 2017, they still accounted for about 1 to 1.5 percent of the total number.
This is why I chose to compare the European and American systems.
Let's look at it from the perspective of per capita consumption.
From the perspective of the company, the investment is slowly increasing,
and the per capita consumption is increasing.
The market is still concentrated in the North American and European markets.
This is one of the main reasons why I want to study.
Next, let's talk about the core research.
First, let's talk about the structure.
The structure of streaming is mainly divided into three parts.
The first part is the aggregation on the far left.
Basically, if you use a TV as a metaphor,
streaming only changes the signal from wireless or wired to the Internet.
To put it simply, the structure in the background is actually divided into three parts.
The first part is the aggregation.
The aggregation is the content created by TV or major media companies.
These streaming will collect these signals and put them on the cloud.
I think everyone has heard of the storage format on the cloud,
the so-called MP4.
It compresses the storage process.
During the compression process,
the original wireless or wired signal will be transformed into the cloud storage format.
From signal to format.
Under this format, MP4 allows the streaming process to be relatively stable.
It is also a technology standard that has been in progress.
Maybe in a few years, it won't be MP4 anymore.
It may be faster and more fluid.
Of course, there may be many reasons why the Internet media is lagging.
Storage format is one of them.
MP4 becomes a very important part of the entire streaming structure in the second stage of storage.
After storage, it is sent.
In fact, in the part of sending, it will also be converted from the storage format to the format of sending.
I won't go into detail about the format of sending.
If you are interested, you can check on the Internet.
What is HLS?
What is MPEG-DASH?
What is Smooth Streaming?
These are the technical terms.
Basically, it is converted from the storage format to the format of sending.
There is something called Streaming Endpoint in the middle.
Streaming Endpoint is a bit like the concept of a middle book.
When it is converted from storage to sending,
Streaming Endpoint allows consumers at the back end to see the videos without the sense of lag.
This is the main structure of streaming.
I converted the original signal into a storage format and then sent it out.
It is smooth in this process.
But there is a storage in the middle.
And the so-called gathering function.
Gathering process.
The problem will appear at the very beginning.
Why is gathering a common problem in streaming?
Let's go back to the paper itself.
Excuse me.
Okay.
There is a question about this page.
The feature of streaming is that it can store the data in the cloud.
Then there is a distribution.
You mentioned today that you want to focus on the region.
That is, the United States, Europe, and so on.
But if today you can imagine that someone is in Asia.
Then he can somehow use VPN or something to watch Netflix.
The data is not in the Asian region.
In this case, where should we focus on the legal discussion?
Or how do you define the region itself?
This question is quite interesting.
OK.
From my perspective.
From my perspective, if the storage is in another country.
But from the legal point of view.
You always have to choose a country to sue him.
Right?
If the storage is in another country today.
Suppose your storage is in Taiwan.
OK.
But you sue him in the United States.
This problem will appear in the issue of evidence collection.
It's not about what's in the law.
You can sue someone.
But if your storage is abroad.
Then there will be an issue of evidence collection.
The so-called issue of evidence collection is that.
For example, we may have heard of it before.
Very famous case.
That is, Mega Upload was bought by the United States.
I don't know if you know the case of Mega Upload.
Mega Upload is a network sharing.
It's a bit like P2P file sharing.
It's like Grogs.
After he was bought in the United States.
He moved his server to Australia.
Then you can't catch him in the United States.
You know what I mean?
The United States has no right to catch him.
Only Australia can catch him.
So that's Mega Upload.
I think the interesting thing about streaming is.
Aggregation part.
I'll talk about it later.
Sometimes it will use different methods to collect signals.
I don't know if this answers your question.
Because this question is quite interesting.
I don't know.
Because of his understanding of the question.
My question has been answered.
But I don't know what he thinks now.
Let me see.
He said yes.
OK, thank you.
I guess I'll talk more later.
Right?
But I think this question is interesting.
That is.
If you put it in another country.
By the way.
This structure is actually the same in Europe and the United States.
OK, but.
He is in different areas.
He will have different technical restrictions.
That is.
That's what the questioner just mentioned.
That is, I'm on the distribution side.
He can restrict that.
I don't want.
Let's say I'm in the United States now.
Don't let Asians see.
This is stipulated in the contract.
That is.
The contract comes from.
The front end is the so-called media company.
He will stipulate that.
If you are downstream.
For example, downstream is like streaming.
You want to play my media.
Then I have to have regional restrictions.
OK.
If you don't do it.
Then you violate the contract.
That's another question.
OK.
It should be.
I hope there is an answer.
Next is a little deeper.
That is.
Talk about these two cases.
One is I think.
In the copyright.
In our industry.
The first case is that everyone will know.
It's ABC to sue Aureal.
Aureal has fallen.
Because of this case.
Then after half a year.
Fox sued Dish Network again.
OK, Dish Network.
I think if everyone is in the United States.
Must have heard of it.
OK, what happened to the two of them?
OK.
The first point is.
Aureal, this company.
When he was still alive.
I emphasize because he is gone.
When he was alive.
He provides a very powerful service.
He opened a platform on the Internet.
Then every consumer.
As long as every month.
Give him 12 dollars.
Then you can.
After 12 dollars.
You can choose inside.
Some channels you want.
After choosing these channels.
Aureal will follow.
These options you choose.
Then catch the signal.
OK.
If you are sensitive.
You should have heard it now.
I'm going to catch the signal.
Did Aureal give money to these?
Broadcaster.
These media companies.
No.
He used the method of technology.
Catch these signals.
After catching.
12 dollars per month.
He makes money like this.
Of course this thing.
It's funny.
He seems to be in January 2013.
Get up this service.
The next month will be sued.
Because this.
It's obviously illegal.
Because you didn't pay at all.
This question is back to just now.
This paragraph.
Because the source of your signal.
It's illegal.
You didn't give money at all.
These media companies.
Of course these media companies will be angry.
Because he can't get a dime.
Then your.
Your client gave money to Aureal.
Aureal did not give money to them.
This question is here.
OK.
So this case is like this.
How to fight.
That's it.
All the way to.
Federal Criminal Procedure Court.
OK.
This is a little show.
The law behind it.
If everyone.
I assume that everyone should not be legal.
So I won't talk about it.
OK.
This is actually their violation of the law.
That is to say.
There is a very important right in the copyright law.
It is public transmission.
Or public broadcast.
OK.
That.
This one in front.
Broadcaster.
That is to say.
In the name of the media.
You didn't pass my authorization today.
Then go.
Steal my signal.
Then play.
So it violates my public broadcast.
The right to broadcast.
OK.
So.
Then.
Uh.
Let me make it simple.
Because most people.
Should be here.
Should not know.
A state of American law.
That is to say.
Uh.
The state of American law.
With.
Taiwan's Constitutional Court.
A bit like.
But.
It can be handled with cases here.
OK.
The U.S. Federal Criminal Procedure Court.
It will only take less than 50 cases a year.
OK.
Very few.
That is to say.
The concept of succession.
That.
Criminal Procedure Court.
Uh.
Not the Criminal Procedure Court.
Federal.
Uh.
Supreme Court.
He.
Accept this case.
There must be a law.
Very serious.
Legal explanation.
Will accept.
This is the first point.
OK.
The second point is.
He.
In the judgment.
Uh.
Often take.
Legal history to do.
OK.
To do the explanation.
That way.
Then he may be wrong.
Wait a minute.
That is to say.
Uh.
Federal.
Supreme Court.
He.
Will have the so-called.
Majority opinion.
With the so-called.
Dissenting opinion.
Then I will only introduce today.
Majority opinion.
Because I think.
The discussion is too deep.
Everyone.
May not be able to accept.
Unacceptable.
So.
Uh.
I will introduce to you today.
His so-called.
The majority opinion.
OK.
Because the U.S. is a pretty.
Uh.
In the law.
He is a.
Very open.
Can't say open.
Very encouraging.
Or.
We can't.
There.
Are the same ideas.
To debate.
A.
System.
So he will allow.
The U.S. Supreme Court.
At the Supreme Court.
Inside.
He will have the so-called majority opinion.
Majority opinion.
And.
Dissonance of minority opinion.
Because they are all one opinion.
OK.
Then.
Uh.
Right.
Wrong not necessarily.
Because they are just standing.
Stand.
At one of.
More.
The result of the vote.
But the result of the vote.
Does not mean.
Their opinion is right.
Because.
There are many people on the scene.
It's not about the law.
So let me explain.
The status of the U.S. Supreme Court.
So.
He will have.
The so-called majority opinion.
With minority opinion.
Now.
The screen is seen.
Is the majority opinion.
They are.
When judging this case.
What is their logical sequence?
The first is that he put.
Uh.
Before he dug out.
There are two times in the United States.
Uh.
The revision of the Constitution.
One is in 1906.
One is in 1976.
The revision of the Constitution in 1976.
He put.
The front.
He put this.
The so-called cable TV.
Put it in the revision of the Constitution.
OK.
The first point.
It makes people feel strange.
OK.
It's the judge.
He thinks.
He actually put.
Cable this thing.
So.
Let's make it clear.
What is cable?
HBO.
OK.
It's.
He put HBO.
With.
This thing.
It's the online stream.
In fact.
This thing.
It's a very strange.
Process.
Because.
How do you get HBO.
Go with.
Do you compare with Aurel?
Yeah.
So.
The first point.
It makes people feel strange.
But he did it.
OK.
That.
Uh.
HBO.
He's in.
19.
He came out in the 1970s.
Uh.
70.
Or 80.
I forgot a little.
He is.
From the so-called cable TV.
Cable TV.
It's what we all know now.
Wireless TV.
The way to sign a wireless TV.
It's me.
Uh.
Call.
It used to be a call.
He might be online registration now.
Or what.
Then call to HBO.
Then.
He will sign with you.
OK.
That.
1976.
In fact, these two.
Cases.
These two cases are.
One is called Fortnite.
One is.
Teleprompter.
These two cases.
He said.
Cable TV.
He is.
It's not.
The so-called.
We talked about it earlier.
Public transmission and public broadcast.
OK.
Then.
But in.
In 1976.
When the law was revised.
He actually put these two.
Cases.
It's.
Two slaps.
Because these two cases.
Federal.
Supreme Court case.
Basically.
Should.
Congress.
Is.
To respect.
But Congress does not respect.
Congress.
No matter.
It's the judgment of the Federal Supreme Court.
He said.
HBO.
Uh.
This.
Like HBO.
Or like other cable TV.
They are.
Their state of transmission.
Is.
Public transmission.
OK.
So this is.
A little bit.
Legislative history.
And.
And this is true.
In this.
In the majority opinion.
He is.
The judge of the Supreme Court.
Take this.
Legislative.
This.
History and purpose.
To explain.
He said.
Uh.
Today you.
The operating mode of ARIEL.
This is what we all see.
This.
This operating mode.
With.
The so-called cable TV.
Very similar.
Where is the point?
He said.
First.
Cable TV and ARIEL.
Can all choose Taiwan.
OK.
He said.
Then he said.
Uh.
They said.
Just turn on the TV.
Then.
One is to turn on the TV.
One is to turn on the computer.
OK.
That's it.
This is them.
Their first.
Very similar place.
OK.
The second point is.
He.
That.
That ARIEL.
He will go to the side.
That is to say.
No.
You.
This is not the same as.
That cable TV.
Where is the difference?
I have a cable TV today.
He may be a line.
Then a line.
Can be at the same time.
In an apartment.
I admit.
But you today.
ARIEL.
What is my state?
I log in every person.
Password.
Account password.
Then choose Taiwan.
He.
My choice.
With your choice.
Different.
That is to say.
Everyone.
Everyone is here.
I.
Today I log in ARIEL.
I like to see.
It's different from what you like to see.
My choice.
The result.
Different from your result.
That.
How can this thing be called.
Public transmission.
Public.
Because.
Must be public.
Transmission.
ARIEL.
Very capricious.
OK.
He thinks.
No.
You are just a process.
The so-called public.
You are just a process of transmission.
In the end.
Still a lot of people watching together.
He does not think.
He thinks.
I am today.
Cable.
Also a line.
A line to sign.
You ARIEL.
Also a person.
A person.
A person to log in.
That.
A person.
A person to log in.
With a line.
A line to sign.
The conclusion is the same.
Are very.
What is the conclusion?
Many people can see.
For example.
If I have ten people to log in.
Then.
I can.
For ARIEL.
Customers.
There are ten people.
To see.
Then.
Then the judge thought.
You.
This is the same as Cable.
Cable.
In 1976.
I think it's public.
Public transmission.
With public broadcast.
So he thinks.
He thinks.
Cable TV.
With ARIEL.
The so-called streaming mode.
Is the same.
OK.
So the conclusion is.
They are the same.
So.
Because they are the same.
In 1976.
The law.
Say you are illegal.
Yes.
The law.
I think this is.
Public transmission.
Then you.
You are not.
Authorized.
So it's illegal.
Yes.
The conclusion is.
OK.
Then.
I don't know if you have.
Any questions.
Just.
I'll stop for a while.
Because it's important here.
In fact.
I have a question.
But the question.
May be more like.
A technical question.
That is.
Yes.
HBO.
For example.
With.
21st century.
Or with FOX.
Buy the rights to the movie.
He is.
No matter if he has.
Go pay that money to buy.
He knows what his object is.
But I haven't used this.
ARIEL.
So I don't know.
He is like.
The same.
Just say.
For example.
I want to listen to Justin Bieber's album.
I want to go.
I know I'm collecting.
What data.
Or.
It's a bit like a pirate bay.
He just put it there.
For others to use.
He is passive.
Um.
I think.
How to answer.
That is.
You.
Because he's gone.
Then I'm not.
Actually, I haven't used it either.
Because.
He has been shut down.
That.
My understanding is.
He is actually a bit like.
The concept of one-stop service.
I don't know how to say that.
That is to say.
After you log in.
He is.
He started.
It's a bit like Wix.
I don't know if that's the right way to describe it.
That is.
Because I'm using Wix.
When you make a website.
He is.
Maybe at the beginning.
Give you some options.
Then you hook up.
Hook up.
He will automatically do it for you.
This is Wix.
His recent function.
I think he's a bit like this.
His service is a bit like this.
That is to say.
After I log in today.
Then.
I just have to choose.
Have.
I like to watch.
Program.
He will go.
Catch this signal.
That's it.
That is.
He will.
Take the initiative.
Catch this signal.
Then you can watch.
That is.
His concept is like this.
Um.
Thank you.
I have a question.
I would like to ask.
It is still.
For this Ariel.
Um.
The way to use it.
Because I haven't used it before.
Oh yeah.
But I want to.
The question is.
He said.
After I got in.
Hook up.
Then he would give me one.
Because Wix is after I hooked up.
He would let me see me.
What does the website look like.
Then I will.
My website.
Look like this.
Right.
But.
Then Ariel said.
After I hooked up.
Because according to your.
Your favorite.
This questionnaire or something.
I recommend you this package.
Then this is my package.
Or.
After I hooked up.
He gave me a shuffle.
Then.
Randomly.
Give me.
Directly.
The picture came out.
Then started to broadcast.
Right.
A movie.
Because if it is a break.
That's really random.
Then I can't imagine.
He is.
How many.
That one.
How many people have autonomy.
All can be discussed.
But relative to the first one.
Because the first one.
Actually buy.
Different.
Cable package.
In fact, it is very similar.
He just added a questionnaire.
In front.
Then I think the judge.
This.
Do a comparison.
I don't think it's weird.
Right.
This is.
Is that you stand in the angle of Ariel.
Ariel.
He said so.
He is.
Because indeed.
His model is very similar to the first one.
Is.
The first one is.
I hook.
Hook.
His business model is the first one.
That's what you just said.
Hey.
Hello.
I'm listening.
In fact, he actually hooked.
In fact, what you just said is.
That's right.
He belongs to the first one.
That's me.
After I choose.
Only those.
Signal.
He went to catch the signal.
He is according to your preference.
To catch the signal.
OK.
After catching the signal.
You can only see those.
Things you catch the signal.
OK.
That.
That's right.
So he belongs to this kind.
He is like.
He is indeed like Cable.
That's right.
But.
His controversial point is.
OK.
I can talk later.
It depends on whether you can understand.
Can I ask another question?
Which one?
Because I just heard.
Cable TV.
I'm Qiqi.
Sorry.
Hua Lu.
That's it.
Can you hear me?
Can you speak louder?
Sorry.
OK.
That.
I can.
Can you hear me clearly like this?
Yes.
OK.
I ask you.
Just before.
It seems that in June this year.
Google was sued by the EU.
Say they are on the Internet.
Is.
Provided.
Let them.
Is.
Comparison.
Google.
Search.
The result.
Will favor.
Google.
That.
Business.
May have.
Google money.
That.
This is also.
You.
Are you talking about this area now?
Is.
We.
As consumers.
We are using Google.
This free service.
When.
We may not be aware.
Say.
Google.
This.
Search engine.
In fact.
Has already been tampered with.
Uh.
Strictly speaking.
Does not count.
Is.
Strictly speaking.
Does not count.
What I study.
But I.
I probably know that.
Thing.
Like this.
I probably know that.
That thing.
Is.
Uh.
That thing.
Is.
I.
Also in the United States.
Is.
It is not in the copyright law.
It is stipulated in.
It is stipulated in antitrust.
Haha.
OK.
Is.
If you are interested.
I can talk about it in private.
Because this thing.
It.
Is involved in.
Two area market.
Different.
For.
Market economy.
It has different interpretation.
OK.
Is.
I don't know how to say that.
A little.
A little bit.
Not really a.
Answer the question.
Ha.
So.
So you are talking about this.
Ah.
Ariel.
He went to catch.
That ABC.
Search engine.
Is.
Because he is equal to.
Use illegal way.
To get others.
Spend money.
To build things.
He is because of this.
Illegal.
Should say.
Because of this.
So ABC sue him.
OK.
That is to say.
You go to catch.
Not to catch the search engine.
Is to catch his signal.
Is the front.
We.
In the technical section.
Is.
You go to catch.
His signal.
But this signal.
In fact.
In the law.
In the US law.
He is actually.
Is a part of the public.
So he is illegal.
To get these signals.
Because these signals.
Is to be authorized.
Is to say.
In the middle.
Streaming company.
Is to pay.
To these.
Ah.
Media business.
But he didn't pay.
So he was sued.
OK.
Sorry.
I can.
Follow this question.
Ask again.
Will this.
Interrupt you.
Or do you want to.
Answer together at the end.
It doesn't matter.
Because if.
Can't finish.
I'll jump.
Good.
Is related to.
The question just now.
My feeling is.
Different.
These two questions.
A little bit different.
Because today.
ABC sue Ariel.
Is more.
ABC production.
I think so.
I can't describe it.
Right.
The fact that.
Your wallet.
Was stolen.
By Google.
To sell it.
Not pay.
To manufacturer.
I steal your things.
To sell for free.
And I'm making profit.
And manufacturer doesn't make a lot of money.
So manufacturer sued.
This intermediary.
But.
Google's matter.
Is more.
Consumer.
Power loss.
Is to say.
Consumers don't know.
When I'm searching.
Actually.
Continuously being advertised.
Then potential.
May affect.
Consumer behavior.
So I'm always.
My wallet has always been.
Stealing money out.
So it's more of a consumer harm.
More not.
Manufacturer is harmed.
But if that's the case.
To compare.
These two cases.
Actually not quite the same.
My feeling.
Correct.
I just said.
These two are different things.
Is.
These two.
Is the latter.
It's more of a market economy.
That is to say.
Google that.
Because Google's problem.
In fact.
Uh.
In the EU.
In my impression.
If I remember correctly.
You can.
Go to Google and see.
Then in my impression.
His.
The point of being sued.
It's because of him.
Because he's in.
Searching.
On technology.
He is.
The strongest.
OK.
Then.
He's the strongest.
As a result.
Because he was in 2002.
Or in 2003.
He wanted to enter the EU market.
but.
A lot of people resist.
OK.
The so-called resistance.
That is to say.
I just don't want to use your Google today.
This so-called API.
Or something.
OK.
Fine.
And then Google.
He just.
Use free.
The first stage.
Let a lot of.
That kind.
Consumers or small and medium-sized manufacturers.
It's not the original.
It's.
Europe also has a similar Google service.
OK.
And now the problem is.
That is to say.
Similar to.
These services.
Local service providers.
They can't live at all.
The reason for not surviving.
Is because.
After Google came in.
To a lot of free.
To buy these.
Middlemen.
Then.
Put this.
Put this ad.
The placement.
Use Google.
What about Google.
Use this method.
Use commercial means.
You can't say.
Right or wrong.
But he just said.
You.
People are free.
Then.
Sign a contract with me.
But what is the price of signing a contract with me.
Don't follow the EU.
Don't follow.
Not the EU.
Don't follow the EU.
Local.
Search engine.
Company cooperation.
This is the first point.
Then he.
Use the contract.
To tie.
These middlemen.
This way.
OK.
Then.
This is what led to these.
Originally in Google.
European market.
Rise.
Similar.
Search engine.
Company.
They don't have advertising revenue.
OK.
Then there is no advertising revenue.
Then.
What to do.
As a result, Google.
He is using the second trick again.
That is to say.
I am today.
Put the price.
May be used very low.
Right.
Use it for free first.
Then use it.
Put this price.
At a fixed price.
It's even lower than other manufacturers.
Then.
In this case.
The third trick is what Qiqi just said.
That is.
Since I don't let you.
Consumer use.
Second.
Then.
Finally.
I let everyone.
Can't find you.
So.
I think this is.
This is quite excessive.
In Google.
In Europe.
Because he wants to.
Occupy.
All of Europe.
Search engine market.
Then.
Just let.
Is to use this business method.
Let all other.
All other.
Similar to Google.
People who serve.
Can't come in.
So.
I will say this thing.
Is.
Because in the EU.
The state of processing.
Different from the United States.
So.
You can.
You can talk about it later.
That is.
If you are interested.
You can talk to me in private.
Because the EU.
Processing.
Market economy.
With the United States.
Processing.
Market economy.
Attitude is different.
Very clear.
Then.
I have a hidden question.
That is.
You just talked about that area.
The reason he was sued.
Mainly because.
He went to steal someone else's.
That.
Steal.
Right.
Then I want another example.
That is.
For example.
Taiwan.
Or China.
Free movies.
Provide platform.
Then he went.
Catch that.
Western Hollywood movie.
Then.
Just put it on that platform.
Let people watch for free.
The case you are studying.
Is.
Belongs to.
That look.
Right.
In fact, that is easy to debate.
That is directly illegal.
That is.
Right.
But.
I.
More details.
Should.
My question is.
Go.
Like Ariel.
I.
I don't know.
Answer you so fast.
Can you.
But.
It does need.
Some.
More rigorous.
Analysis.
But you ask me now.
Is it similar or what?
But my personal feeling.
Is similar.
My personal feeling.
My personal feeling is similar.
Because.
I don't know if there is time.
That is.
Europe has appeared.
That is because.
Today is the United States and Europe.
Europe also has similar cases.
But.
Not in that kind.
Asia.
That is to say.
Put it on.
It is similar.
To.
Catch the signal.
Then.
Catch that.
Uh.
Not catching the signal.
That is to say.
It provides you with something.
Then you can.
Uh.
Download.
A package.
Then that package.
Can let you go.
Free.
Go to the football game.
OK.
Then that.
The European court concluded that.
You are still like this.
No payment.
You let consumers.
To do.
Enforce consumers.
To create this.
Illegal behavior.
Or.
So.
I think this is.
A case.
I'm like.
I feel like.
Like you just said.
But I'm not sure.
Yes.
Did you answer?
Yeah.
Very clear.
OK.
So.
I want.
Any questions?
OK.
So.
Oh.
No problem.
321.
No.
OK.
So.
This is.
The so-called.
That.
Opinion.
OK.
That.
I have.
In the seminar.
I mentioned.
That.
A minority.
Oh, not a minority.
That is.
It is a minority opinion.
Or.
Anti-opinion.
That.
I think it skipped.
Because.
This.
If you are interested.
You can talk to me in private.
Because.
Opposed to opinions.
In fact.
That is.
In fact, in the United States.
It became.
Subsequent mainstream opinion.
OK.
So.
In private.
If you have any questions.
You can ask me again.
Because after all.
I understand.
Is mainstream.
Oh, not mainstream.
Is the state of majority opinion.
OK.
Oh, that.
Then.
We look at.
This.
Dish Network.
Hey.
I don't think time is enough.
Let's jump to Europe.
Can I do this?
Host.
OK.
But in fact.
That.
We started a little late today.
So.
You can probably.
Talk as much as you want.
OK.
It doesn't matter.
I.
Just jump to Europe.
Because everyone feels.
Because of this.
The United States and Europe.
Jump over.
May feel more interesting.
Europe is a little bit more.
Um.
Let me put it simply.
Is.
Everyone may have learned some.
Law 101.
Is.
The so-called mainland law.
With.
British and American law.
Like this.
OK.
That.
If you want me to be concise.
Say.
Mainland law.
With British and American law.
I learned this.
Is it so many years?
Right.
So.
If you ask me.
Where is the difference?
The difference is.
The first step.
If you have seen it.
I go back.
Is.
If I study American law.
At first.
Must be from.
Case facts.
With.
Case.
That.
What does it mean?
The United States.
From.
A judgment.
Thing.
Run to.
This step.
Run to this law.
OK.
Is.
So.
He has a behavior first.
Then this behavior.
They.
The so-called.
Human judge.
And then.
After organizing these opinions.
Finally.
Let the Congress.
Go to the law.
And then.
With this judgment.
Very similar.
Thing.
So.
Like just now.
Uh.
A little bit.
But.
Is.
This is what I just said.
Hbo.
When the law was revised.
Why.
Very tricky place.
Because usually.
After the revision.
Left to Congress.
Congress should.
According to this revision.
To do.
So.
This is.
American politics.
A very strange point.
OK.
That.
This is the United States.
Is.
From the so-called judgment.
To.
The state of law.
That.
In.
Mainland law.
Is.
It's not the same.
Mainland law.
He.
Is.
Directly.
He will.
Uh.
The current state.
Then.
Directly.
Set a law.
Then.
The following case.
Is.
OK.
So.
Probably.
American law.
With.
Mainland law.
The biggest difference is here.
Is.
Mainland law.
His analysis method.
He must be.
The method of analysis.
Must be from.
The law.
Or.
This.
So-called.
Directive.
Is.
This.
Instructions.
The so-called instructions of the EU.
To do.
Explain.
To.
After the explanation.
Then.
What kind of.
Different ways to explain.
Is.
Expanding.
Or.
How to explain.
That.
So.
This is.
Everyone.
Uh.
If it's not a law school.
Is.
You can imagine.
We.
Before.
This is how I learned in Taiwan.
OK.
The teacher will talk about these things first.
And then.
Use the so-called hypothetical case.
Is.
Some so-called.
A lot.
Then.
Simulate the operation of this law.
May.
Happen.
OK.
So.
Now.
It's the same.
Because.
Europe is also similar.
Same as Taiwan.
It's also a major law department.
So.
Look at his law.
Is.
This is one of the.
A very important law.
Then.
If everyone.
It's not a law school.
Just take a look.
Then.
As long as you know.
There is a.
There is a clause.
He is talking about this.
Is.
All.
EU.
Member States.
Is.
He must provide this.
Uh.
Is.
Very close to the United States.
The United States is a public performance.
That.
The EU is the so-called communication.
To the public.
Of their works.
OK.
So.
Uh.
It's easy to operate.
Some people say it's easy to operate.
The point is here.
Is.
Subsequent cases.
With.
Surrounding this.
These words.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Seven.
These seven words.
Is.
The so-called.
So.
Wait a minute.
Uh.
The next case will explain.
What is communication?
What is public?
OK.
So.
This is the core question.
OK.
So.
The next case.
Is.
ITV.
With.
TV.
Catch up.
Is.
It's the most recent.
Can't be the most recent.
These years.
More important.
About.
Uh.
This clause.
The case.
OK.
But.
TV.
Catch up.
His actual.
He's running.
Very close to.
Come up.
The difference is.
TV.
Catch you.
It's not his.
Catch the signal.
Only the British Empire area.
So.
Only in the United Kingdom.
Other consumers of the other EU.
Can't catch it.
OK.
So.
TV.
Catch up.
The thing he does is like.
He also is.
Catch the signal.
And then didn't give money.
The early years.
Now there should be.
Because they.
Then later.
There should be.
I see them now.
Still.
Running.
Didn't let Ariel fall.
Ariel is dead.
Don't give money.
OK.
TV.
Catch up.
It should have been later.
OK.
At that time.
12 years.
11 years.
When he came out.
Didn't give money.
Don't give money.
He was sued.
It's.
Very close to that Ariel.
But for us to learn law.
I think.
Wow.
How to be so brave.
It's.
It happened in Europe.
Then it happened in the United States.
Then.
He was.
Catch the signal.
Don't give money.
OK.
Then.
I think this side.
Is a series.
The.
Directed to the so-called communication.
To the public.
Do explanation.
OK.
Then this is the mainland.
The boring place.
Oh.
It's not as interesting as the United States.
He is.
Directed to this.
Conditions.
Do explanation.
OK.
Then he explained that.
First.
Is.
His.
I'm sorry.
I'm a little interrupted.
Correct.
Is.
Your side.
This.
TV catch-up.
In 2013.
Yes.
Then you.
The one in front of you.
Ariel.
In 2000.
If I remember correctly.
2014.
Correct.
Oh.
2014.
OK.
So.
They are in time.
Did not know each other.
What will the other party's result be?
Do not know.
I want to clarify this point.
Because this is an interesting.
Correct.
OK.
Oh, really?
Thank you.
I.
But.
Because if.
Well.
If someone has already tried it first.
Then he hit the wall.
Then the other person will know.
What do I have to pay attention to?
But these two.
It's almost parallel.
Yes.
OK.
But you can also think about it.
The EU has already happened.
As a result, the United States.
But they are actually the same.
Because.
Their service.
Actually, it's almost time.
Just.
Um.
But they are one year apart.
My feeling.
I guess.
Uh.
This is the time of judgment.
What is the time of judgment?
It should be one year.
Yes.
But their service time is about the same.
Oh.
OK.
I see.
So they can be more than time.
Ha ha.
Oh.
OK.
The number of times you want.
At least one year.
So.
So they are like this.
I think their time is about the same.
Just that time.
OK.
Just happened to show up.
Ha ha.
So.
OK.
Of course.
The EU judges faster.
Um.
Because he is.
Bye bye.