So after I graduated from university, I think I did an RA, if I remember correctly, at Professor Chen's place, right?
I did it for a year or two
After that, I went to Canada's McMaster to study for my PhD
When I was studying for my PhD, one of the tutors was Dr. Trenner
He was doing a course on music perception and intuition
If you're interested, you can ask him why he chose to do music
or intuition and cognition
I don't know much about intuition, but my impression is that
doing visual psychology takes up a large portion of the work
So why did I decide to do intuition? I think it's interesting
I don't know, it's just my guess
Yongyi has a website, you can go check it out, it's really scary
The publications are as long as ghosts
Other than the publications, there's also awards and media coverage
I think that's really cool
I hope one day I can tell my parents that I'm a journalist
Without further ado, let's welcome Yongyi to share his research with us
I'll turn off my mic so you can hear me
Can you hear me now?
I think it's okay
I'm a little shy
I don't even know if I have to give a score
Today is July 8th, I'm guessing my highest score is 87
I can't go any higher
That's about it
I can predict the results
You have to turn on the audio so you can hear the laughter
I don't think there's any feedback
I think we need feedback
Forget it
It's pretty funny
I'm being encouraged, I'm indeed a person who studies truth psychology
It's different
I'm probably just making things up
I'm not really interested in hearing
There's no deep reason
First of all, I'm very interested in music
I only found out later that most people do visual research
Most people talk about intuition
It's directly implied that it's visual research
I only found out later
If you're doing hearing research
You have to say it's particularly famous for auditory
Otherwise people will get it wrong
It's pretty interesting
I think there are some phenomena in hearing
It's different when it comes to other senses
There are some special problems to deal with
I think that's what makes hearing interesting
It's a special place
Okay, let's get into my presentation
I'm going to start studying how to share my screen
Okay, while you're studying
Let me tell you
Just in case there's feedback
Let me turn off the microphone
If you have anything you want to say
You can type it in
You can also speak
Okay
Let's go
My PhD research topic is
It's very vague
Dynamic Auditory Communication
It's vague
It's about how to change your hearing
In a dynamic situation
How to change your hearing
This includes
For example, you're listening to me now
All my voices change at any time
For example, every time I make a sound
There's a millisecond
And then it disappears
Or listening to music
It's kind of like that
And then
And what I want to share today is
My experiment
From a traditional laboratory
Psychological laboratory
And then do it
More complicated
We think it's closer to the real
Interaction
Under the environment of human interaction
That is
From a small laboratory to a large laboratory
Between each other
There are some research methods
Needs to be adjusted
And then I just want to explain today
Take our research as an example
How do we do this
So my sub-topic is
How do psychologists do research
And there is a step-by-step explanation
Explain
What are the problems we encounter
And then
We think
In our situation
How do we solve it
And then
By the way
Just
Please help everyone
The place is
September
Taiwan's Science and Music Magazine
There will be a
A special special issue of music psychology
And then
I want to put this
Related research
It's a draft
Go over there
As a
A small topic
Just share it
Just as a science book
Share it to readers in Taiwan
Then I didn't write it myself
The experience of doing a science book article
Then if I hope
That is to say
I hope to make today's speech
Into different fields
People interested in science
Can probably
Psychologists
How do we do research
Especially in
In such a special situation
If you think
On the content
Or how to explain
How can it be adjusted better
That is
I hope you can tell me
Then
I will
I'm going to take the exam in two weeks
So thank you very much
If there is any help
OK
it is good
The nonsense should be over
First of all, I want to say
Hearing has many domains
Like for example
You can know if the pitch is high or low
What I want to focus on today is
Focus on time
For hearing
Is a very important thing
In fact, time is for many senses
And the reaction is very important
For hearing
I think it is especially critical
Why
If you record my voice
Then take it to
In the software of the computer
Open it
Look at its radio
Its radio
It looks like
Almost like this
Then you can of course
Decode
That is to say
What is my voice
Then
Our hearing is
We have to put it together
To become a meaningful sentence
Ah
But it's hard for hearing
That is to say
Every message
The time it appears is so short
And
It won't appear again
Ah
Human beings have lived for so long
History
The history of human communication
Before the recorder was invented
We have no chance
Listen again
What happened before
How is it
So human hearing
A big problem
That is to say
We have to be able to catch it quickly
Ah
This message is displayed at any time
And then accurately
Awareness
Feel it accurately
The content of this
Then
And another
More demanding is
That is
We are not just aware of this
And we have to
Make a quick response
For example
When you have a conversation with others
What are you hearing
You will be able to understand immediately
Then immediately
Be able to react
Then this skill
When quarreling
It's particularly important
Because if you slow down
If you slow down
You lost the quarrel
It's very
It's important to speak
Right
So you see
Human beings are like this
No, I'm kidding
That
Not only in conversation
In another situation
For example, you are listening to music
Ah
And for example, you are with
You sing with others
Ah
Sing together
That
I can't just listen to other people's music
Listen to this
I'm going to
Sing my part
Because you are like this
No matter how fast your processing speed is
There must be a time difference inside
That
Ah
So
In fact, in many cases of hearing
We think it is
He keeps
Keep predicting
What's going to happen next
Then let people
Always
Let your intuition
Let your nervous response
Always in a
In a well-prepared situation
Then you can
Precise intuition to this matter
And then
Quickly prepared
To make the next reaction
So I think hearing is on time
Ah
In fact, compared to other sensory domains
Is
More demanding
This is
My task
So I think time is very important to hearing
Ok
If you have any questions
You can interrupt me in the middle
Then if there is no problem
I will continue
Then
By the way because I
Now
I share the screen
So if everyone
If you leave a message in the chat
I should not be able to see it now
So everyone can
Just turn on the microphone
It has nothing to do with me
Ok
Ah
I have a question
Ok
Please say
The
The M-I-N-G-E-R above the waveform
What is that?
Oh, that's just an example I found on the Internet
I don't know what that is
Sorry
Ok
Ok, thank you
It should be a project title
Yes
It looks like this
But I don't know
I haven't searched either
Alright
Maybe it's doing something
Voice
Voice of the computer
Some of the projects handled by the visual
I don't know
Sorry
Then I will talk about it first
In traditional psychology and neuroscience
How do we do this kind of research in the lab
If we want to know
What is the importance of time for hearing
How do we do research
For example
I
I will
Design a series of hearing with a computer
A series of hearing that opens at any time
Then for example
I can
A kind of audio file
I put it
Every note
Bop, bop, bop
All time
Every bop, bop, bop
Between each tone
Its time is fixed
The same length
For example, it's 500 milliseconds
So this way you
It sounds like a decoder
Bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop
Then you can keep going
So this
This is a very regular time
Then you can have a
An irregular time
For example, it's
Between your pain and pain
Can be
For example
Random 250 milliseconds
Between 750 milliseconds
So it might sound like this
Bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop
Just
You don't know at all
You
When will the next pain appear
And then
In this different
Under the circumstances
We can
Require the audience to do some
Intuitive answer
For example, we can make
Some of them have sounds
Most of these sounds
Most of them are exactly the same
There are some sounds
Maybe we'll just make it
It's a little bit higher or a little bit lower
We're on the frequency domain
To make some adjustments
And then the audience
Just
To participate in the experiment
The college student has to listen to that sound
If he hears a higher pitch
He'll press a button
If you hear a lower pitch
Just press a button
It sounds like
Bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop
Bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop, bop
You have to listen to the higher pitch
You have to react
And then the other
Under the circumstances of irregular time
You can also do this kind of manipulation
And then we can go and see
For example
Under the circumstances of regular time
The correct rate of his answer
It's going to be higher
Under the circumstances of irregular time
Then we can
Psychologists usually say
Oh, that's the regular time
It can help you
Have a better sense
Because you're better
Because your accuracy is higher
You can have a more accurate answer
In this case
We can also do some
Neuroscientific measurements
For example, I can measure people's brainwaves
This is a memory map
It's because of the nervous response of the brain
The nervous response of the brain
It's all about the nerve
It's all about the neurotransmitter
To do the reaction
Then we can put those
For example, the ECG map
Or the sensors for measuring muscle position
We'll put it on the scalp
That's because of the nerve response
It's going to be that wave signal
It's going to come out
So we can put it on the surface of the scalp
Record this signal
That's what we call it
The signal of the brainwaves
Then we can do some corresponding analysis
We can see that the brainwaves are
How to capture the regularity of this time
And then for example
Let's do some complicated processing
And then we'll get
Something like this
The answer is
We'll find out, for example
The brainwave
It's going to adjust the speed of its vibration
It's the same as the external stimulus
And then we just have to catch this
In the brain
Imagine the nerve in the brain
It's like a decoder
It's going to be able to accurately capture
How to produce the next second
That's the traditional neuroscience
Or psychologically
We're going to do this
A study of orientation
But this study is actually quite
OK, please go ahead
That's your time
That's the frequency
That cycle
How short can it be
You mean the cycle of my voice
Or the cycle of the brainwaves
The cycle of the voice
And then there's the brainwaves
You're going to adjust it
If it's the same as your external
Does it have a limit
This is a good question
Usually humans can catch the beat
The shortest is the shortest between pain and pain
It's 200 milliseconds
I can't sing so fast
It's about the same speed
More than 200 milliseconds
You probably think
It's almost a continuous sound
That's the slowest
It's the longest between pain and pain
It can be as long as 1,200 milliseconds
1.2 seconds
After that
You'll feel like every sound is independent
You don't think it's a continuous rhythm
You just can't
Know the pattern
What's interesting is that the brainwaves
Can only catch up
Such a speed range
It's slower than this
Or faster than this
There's no way
As for what causes what
I don't know
It's because the brain can't move so fast
Move so slow
To make us instinctively
Can't catch up so fast
Such a slow speed
I don't know
I can only say
This is what we have now
Thank you
Hello
So I'd like to ask
When you do this experiment
Do you have to eliminate
Other noise interference?
That's right
We do this kind of experiment
Because we want to be clean
So we do it in the soundproof room
And then we'll use headphones
That is, we'll use those
More special headphones
Just send the sound
Into the ear
And it's very close
The more inside, the better
And then the sound is transmitted
It's all very clean
I just want to reduce
External interference
That's right
So when you say
The so-called hearing
It means
Human beings
We can really
The sound we hear
Or include that
Include that
The frequency we can't hear
It's also in the hearing
For example, ultrasonic waves or
Very low frequency
That kind
That kind of hearing
That's what you're asking
That is to say
Physical stimulation
Does it stimulate psychological feelings?
That's what we say
Will ask questions like this
Of course
Of course there are people
Study such a question
That is to say
Where is the limit of human hearing?
Then you can see
Where is the limit of frequency?
But this is not me
Today
Is the main part of the discussion
Maybe we'll wait
Discuss again later
Like this
I don't know if it's like this
Or just
You can discuss it casually
No no no
Because of me
I'm more curious
When you say you want to eradicate
That interference
When noise interference
That's how you eradicate that kind
We don't know at all
The kind of interference we hear
For example, like ultrasonic waves
You are in that
What is that called
There is no noise at all
That kind of interference
In that kind of experimental environment
You can't guarantee
He won't be affected by the outside world
OK OK OK
Then I know
Of course we
What we do is
We already know
Human hearing frequency range
It's about 20 Hz to 20,000 Hz
In the frequency range of this Hz
We
In fact, in the experimental environment
Can still measure
In the case of measurement
We will make a comparison
As for ultrasonic waves
We generally think it's human
Physically, you can't hear it
So
So we don't care about his control
So for example
There is an ultrasonic wave in the lab
The sound of the ultrasonic wave
Or that kind of very, very, very high frequency
We don't care
So it's based on an assumption
Those things won't cause
It won't cause too much interference to humans
Yes, it really won't
And the other thing is
In the case of our experiments
We don't say
One condition is to make a trial
Of course we will do hundreds of trials
Thousands of trials
Even if there is an effect
As long as it is with your experiment
The program set by the computer
If it's not related to each other
Then the effect we observe
These external effects
It should be reduced a lot
OK, thank you
Then
Hey, copy it
That is to say
What about this POP process
Of course you can decide for yourself
See if you want to say
To accept the middle question
Or ask at the end
Or open the discussion directly
You can decide
Then but
That is
We
The prediction is that you can
You can talk for about an hour
And then
There will probably be a 20-minute discussion
Ah
That's it
As for you
Cut it in half
Or mixed together
How do you decide
Just decide for yourself
OK OK OK
OK
Let me tell you first
I actually didn't prepare a lot of POP
I only prepared about 18 pages
So
So the topic part will be finished in a moment
if
Um
Some related topics
Of course I'm sorry
I just didn't know
What's your problem
If it's related to listening or other music
We can wait until then to discuss
If this is related to the topic I'm talking about
Of course we'll put it up
Discussed at the scene
Sorry I just didn't know
Your question
With this
What I'm talking about now
What are the links
OK
That
But
OK, I'll keep going
I think the biggest problem in doing laboratory research
That is to say
If we want to understand
Between people
How to use it normally
For example, interact with listening messages
But in fact, the time law and the time law
These two messages
I experiment
I make this kind of message in the computer
It doesn't exist in the natural world
You naturally
You won't hear one
It's as accurate as a decoder
It's a completely random message
You usually hear
A little regular
But there is no such regular message
If I do research like this
In the end for understanding
My human
What is the real ability to help
In fact, sometimes it is a bit biased
So
In fact, there is a very interesting paper
Just released recently
It's called Neuroscience Needs Behavior
If you are related
Philosophy
If you are interested in scientific philosophy
I highly recommend this paper
Then I will use it first
A few pictures inside
To talk about
This research
The limitations of laboratory research
Generally, we want to know
Research can be said
For example, the neural pattern of the human brain
What is the relationship between natural behavior
Then you can take the neural pattern
As
For example, the psychological journey
Psychological journey
Psychological inner journey
This is what we want to know
That one
A better designed ideal experiment is
We can control
We know which part of the psychological journey
Or neural reaction
Corresponding to some of our natural behaviors
We can have one-to-one
Is a one-to-one correspondence
Or a simpler correspondence
But like the experiment we just did
In fact, the experiment just now
Is the experiment I did
I did it myself
Um
We
I actually designed an experiment
Human
In general
A situation that would not happen at all
Then we are studying his neural reaction
Although we can know
The relationship between these
But we can't answer directly
What is human nature
How
We can't answer
Human natural reaction
So what we know is that some humans
Supernormal ability
It's beyond his usual ability
but
Our main research topic
In fact, there is no direct understanding
This is what I think the lab is studying
Some big limitations
Especially in other areas
There is such a situation
For example
If you want to manipulate social interaction
You are in a very small lab
Basically can't do this
Because our lab
It basically looks like this
Just one person
Sitting in a small partition
Because we have to
Like I just said
Must control all external stimuli
So
Usually just sit in there alone
In a very quiet situation
Interact with the computer
And at the same time because
Uh
The relationship between our measuring tools
For example, that
Uh that
That side brain wave
That line
Long-term relationship
He can only sit there
He can't do anything
He can only use two fingers
Do the reaction
So this is actually
It's a very unnatural situation
That's some
Traditional lab environment
Some restrictions given
OK
And here
Everyone agrees
In fact, there are quite a lot of restrictions
Then I
What I want to say is
Then we
In our lab
How do we try to go
Uh
Extend to solve such a barrier
What I want to say first is
Music
It can be a good research tool
It can be a research tool
As a
Uh
To help study human mind activity
And neural reaction
He
Uh
There are some good ways
For example
I can keep
There is a good experiment
For example
I today
For example, look at this A picture on the left
I can ask the subject
Ask someone to come in
Then I'll give him a recorder
I asked him
Press the key of the piano
Then the speed of pressing is exactly the same as the recorder
That's a good one
A control experiment
And then
I can put this
The conditions I control are getting more and more relaxed
For example
I can ask the computer to produce a recorder
But this recorder is
As you press the key
Then he will go
Follow your speed
To change his own rhythm
Uh
Or you can say
Let two people play together
Multiple people play
Even when there are multiple people playing
You and the audience
Listening at the same time
That
Moving more and more to the right side of the spectrum
That's what we're talking about
Ecological interaction
Ecological validity
That is to say, what you are studying
Is able to correspond to human beings
In the case of real life
The right side is
We feel
More like real life
Because when you play music
You will also have an audience listening
This can be understood
But on the right side of the spectrum
In fact, your time control
It's getting worse and worse
For example, when a group of people play music
If they decide together
Speed up or slow down
What do you want
This is not for you
The experimenter can decide in advance
The information you get in the end
It will be difficult for you to explain
That music
Can be a good tool
Just because he can
Get some kind of balance in the middle
For example, when the two of them interact
They may not be random
Play the music they want
I can give him
Uh, music score
Uh, ask them to play the music score
And if they have
If you play the music score
If they play something wrong
In fact, we can
Record afterwards
To find out about this
So we can know
What did he do wrong
I also know
What is the correct answer
And we can set
That is to say
What is the rhythm he wants to play
So we still have some control
But even under these conditions
Their activities
Still very close
An activity of human real behavior
So we think music can be
A good tool to study
Uh, uh, human interaction
That is, hearing communication
And it can be balanced
That is, experimental control
And ecological efficiency
These two big questions
And another advantage of music is
Say
Uh
You said music is a good research tool
The reason is
It sounds like it's because he can be
That is, he can have this
From experimental control
To ecological interaction
The whole spectrum
But then you think
What kind of research tool
There is no such feature
Uh
What kind of research tool
Language
Isn't that right
Language also has
Yeah
So I think I don't really understand
That's why he's a special
Good research tool
I didn't say he was particularly good
I said he could be a good research tool
OK
Good
So did I get it right this time
What you mean is
He can span the whole spectrum
He can be a
That language is of course
You can communicate with the computer
Language
Or the language between people
Communicate with others
Yes, language is also a good research tool
My language
There is a difficulty in neuroscience
Because when you want to speak
Mouth to move
And then actually
It's a bit difficult to measure the signal
Of course, this is an externalization
But I think language is also a
Uh, it's a pretty good tool
Okay, got it
I didn't say music is the best
I just said he was one of them
And then
And the other good thing about music is
He
Even if it's a special event
But actually in each
There are music activities in all cultures
And humans actually
Spend a lot of resources
In music activities
A lot of time and resources
So, uh, we think
Research on music activities
In fact, it can also be
Uh, it's a reflection of a human being
A very basic behavior
With a capability
OK
So
So you say music is a good research tool
It means
For example, you want to measure his brain
How does the brain work
You just play music for them
Is it similar to this
Is this a research method
Uh, play music for them
Or let them
Let them play music
So that means
You can have a
A spectrum
You can go from the far left
Play music for them
I've already designed this music in advance
It extends all the way to the far right
For example, you can
Interact with the music
For example, if you want to listen to karaoke
OK
Or if there's no music
It's just two people playing music together
Oh, good
I have a question
OK
I have a simple question
It's like this
Uh, because it says here
We may start from here
More and more
More and more about music
As a research tool
This thing
So I want to clarify
A simple question
That is
What we are discussing now is
Sound is a good research tool
Or music is a certain kind
There is a specific
Subset
In the sound thing
Or do we have to discuss
Sound is a research tool
Uh
I would say it's music
Because
Um
If I talk about sound
It's just a definition
Because
Because of the sound
Um
Can you talk about your question again
Yeah, so my question is actually
You're talking about music
A good research tool
What kind of sound
Don't you think it's
You want to use it as
The definition of music
Research tool
Oh, I understand
Oh, um
Yeah
Uh
I forgot to say that
In fact, in traditional
Research on hearing
We will use
Computer synthesis
That's a very
It's like you pick up the phone
To hear that kind of sound
Or more than that
A lot of noise
And these things
I'm all of us
Basic hearing
Uh
The material used
But in general
We don't use that kind of material
And then we
And
In addition, that is to say
When we study hearing
We often present a
A completely unchanged sound
A completely correct
For example, show it for a second
But in the case of nature
All the sounds
It's probably the first time
It's gone
It won't have the same stimulus
Repeat repeat
It's been extended to a second
So long
And music
It has another component
That is to say it has
Uh
More social interaction
Component
It's not just about making a sound
It's not just about making it
Uh
I'll just knock on the table today
Make a sound
But it's that people will
According to your voice
And then he has a response
And then he makes a new action
Did that answer the question
There are
Thank you
OK OK OK
OK
Everyone's questions are very good
That
Um
In our research example
That is to say
We want to understand
Using music
Play as a
Model example
Is a social interaction model
How do we measure cooperation
And then we have to understand
Is the relationship between the leader and the follower
And then we have to
What direction to go
To do this research
Ah, this photo is
A photo of our lab
And then I just found
We had a short film before the lab
OK
Show it to everyone
I hope everyone can hear the sound
Uh, there's a two and a half minute introduction
Adrian Fung and his colleagues
Are fitted with specially designed
Caps and sensors
Put them in the front of your shirt
And wired to monitors
That measure their brain activity
And heart rate
Motion capture cameras
Record their movements too
Researchers are studying
How the musicians communicate
With each other during a performance
Without using a single word
How do they use movements
What gestures do the musicians make
That make it possible for them to
Communicate with each other
And to communicate with members of the audience
They're all wired up too
To study how they respond
Physically and emotionally
To the performers on stage
What's great about this
Is it affords us
The ability to see
How effective we are as communicators
The theater is state-of-the-art technology
Including a sound system
With incredible acoustics
Here with just a tap on a tablet
I'll make it extremely reverberant in here
Sort of like a cathedral
The room is transformed
A cool feature that serves
A wider, more scientific purpose
One that could help researchers
Design a better hearing aid
For the hearing impaired
So, ratting
Background noise is coming out of all the speakers
It's a multi-channel surround mix
And then we could test
How well does a person with a hearing aid
Comprehend speech
That's presented to them
In an environment like this
Instead of in the quiet room
But for now
Most of the research is focused on music
And its therapeutic powers
Researchers hope their findings
Will uncover how some rhythms
Might help an autistic child
Or why a musical beat
Can improve the gait of a patient
With Parkinson's disease
To understand
What's going on in the brain
We need to know how it's done
In typical populations
Once we understand that
And we know that music
Can help people with Parkinson's
Or we know that music has an effect
On children with autism
We can start to understand
The deep reasons for that
And we can perfect
The therapies that we give these people
And add to mounting evidence
That music is good medicine
For the brain
Cass Rose, CBC News, Toronto
Cass Rose, CBD News, Toronto
Cass Rose, Cabaret
Cass Rose, Caberet
Cass Rose, Cabelet
Cass Rose, Cabaret
Cass Rose, Cabearet
Cass Rose, Cobain
But this is only an obvious effect in non-seeing.
So it represents visual experience,
which may create some noise,
which makes it more difficult not to be followed,
not to be affected by followers.
Of course, this needs to be replicated.
This is a small difference.
Or did you analyze the interaction?
Did you find it?
Sorry, I don't want to talk about it.
So there's no difference between the two white bars
and the two dark gray bars.
Is there a difference?
Did you analyze it?
No, I looked at all the interactions.
Okay, thanks.
You're welcome.
We actually replicated this,
but the difference between the two dark gray bars
and the FF didn't show up in the replication.
That's a shame.
So we didn't explain much in the paper.
I don't know why.
But we found that
the body movement can reflect the direction of information transmission.
But it's not very interesting.
What does this have to do with playing music?
It's just a bunch of people moving around in the studio.
It's just who moves first and who moves last.
After they played each song,
we asked the musicians to use a quantity table
to evaluate how well they played.
We asked them to evaluate three items.
What is the overall quality of the performance?
1 to 5 points.
Is the synchronization of time synchronized?
Is there a difference in the difficulty of cooperation?
Then we compared it with the quantity of Granger Casualty.
We found that the X axis is very good,
the right side is very good,
and the left side is very bad.
The Y axis is...
I wrote Casual Density.
Basically, it's the total amount of information exchanged
by the whole system.
We found that the quality of the performance
and the quantity of Casual Density and the amount of information exchange
and the coupling of body movements are related.
The synchronization of time is also related.
However, in the second time replication,
only the overall quality of the performance is related.
In other words, the amount of information transfer...
The body movement does not only reflect the direction of information transfer.
The amount of information transfer
seems to reflect the quality of cooperation.
To sum up, what did we learn?
We learned that in multi-person cooperation,
we can observe the direction of information transfer from body movements.
Even if this is a homework based on hearing and action,
it seems that it is also an important communication channel
whether you can see each other visually or not.
The overall amount of information flow
and the amount of information activity obtained by measuring body movements
can reflect the quality of cooperation.
In fact, these three points...
For everyone, if you don't do research,
you can probably guess the result.
We think the biggest value is that
we provide a low-threshold research method.
You don't have to observe in our lab.
You can observe in any natural situation.
You can observe each other's body movements
through imaging analysis.
You may be able to observe the group behavior
between people in natural situations.
We just prove that this effect exists
in a well-controlled lab.
It should be an effective index.
I think that
if the following researchers want to study
complex social behaviors,
at least they have a tool to use.
I have a question.
I'm sorry.
I don't quite understand the second and third points.
I thought the result is that
if they are facing each other,
they can't see each other.
The result is still the same.
Yes, it is.
But the effect is weaker.
There is a main effect.
Simple main effect is that
in the direction of leader to follower,
you can see each other much better than you can't see each other.
I see.
But the effect is still the same on both sides.
This is my question for the third point.
What is the direction of causal relationship?
For example,
is the communication channel
caused by musical communication
to cause the following of your body movement?
Or is it the movement of your body
that causes the improvement of music?
I don't know.
Because if you can't see your body sway
or follow each other,
it doesn't mean visual communication.
It is the natural body reaction
caused by the essence of hearing or music.
So it is a side effect,
not a real cause.
I didn't say it is a cause.
I just said it is a reaction indicator.
It is a measurement indicator.
I said it is
when we play music,
our body does this movement,
but we still do it.
This information seems to reflect
the direction of information transmission
and the quality of cooperation.
So you don't think it is functional.
You don't think it has a function.
It is just an indicator.
It is just a measurement indicator.
I am conservative.
I think I don't know.
I just said
I can't prove it is functional yet.
In my research,
some people block the whole person
and measure the time difference
between each other's buttons.
When all the buttons are blocked,
the time difference between the buttons
will be affected.
But I think
the conclusion is
in my research,
I can only say
the result can be reflected.
Maybe it is just a related indicator.
But is the function
a part of communication itself?
Is it a part of seeing
other people's body movements?
I don't know.
Because like you said,
even if you can't see,
the body movements have this effect.
Got it.
Thank you.
I have another question for Zhang Ting.
But it is not directly
about your research itself.
We want something interesting
from your research.
If we look at Baha,
you just emphasized that
the four characters
are relatively...
What is it called?
The responsibilities are more or less equal.
So you can randomly assign
who you are.
But if we change it to
four-part jazz,
the kind of music with strong characters,
do you expect that
the effect size will be very strong?
Or will they break down?
They can't play
because they don't know
who they are.
If you don't assign,
who will lead?
I know.
This is our...
Actually, we did it.
I didn't put it here today.
But this is Experiment 2.
In the case of Experiment 2,
we don't have that kind of jazz.
We want them to play
Mozart's music.
If you look at Mozart's music,
if you look at the score,
all the melodies
are in the first violin.
The other parts
are just beats.
But we still do
the same manipulation.
Even if the cello
is just playing beats,
you still have to lead the violin
to play its music.
So this is basically
the same manipulation
as you think.
It's all the same.
The result is...
I go back to the previous slide.
This is the replication
I just talked about.
We still have
the three lines above.
The three lines below are gone.
So we're in a task.
It's an unbalanced starting point.
We're going to do manipulation.
We still see the above effects.
But it's actually
a lot weaker overall.
And then we measure
the strength of the
grandiosity between each other
in the case of the bass line.
We found that
in the case of playing Mozart's music,
the bass line is more uneven.
In the case of playing Bach,
the bass line is even.
So it does have
the effect of the bass line.
This effect actually
shows that this is functional.
Because in the case of non-syncing,
when the music itself
doesn't have this message,
has an obvious bias,
it's hard for you to have
this effect.
For example,
in the case of playing the cello,
if you don't see it,
your body swing is not connected.
But when you see it,
it still has an effect.
It means it's causally linked.
Wait a minute.
I suddenly feel like
I'm talking illogically.
Because although the body...
But we didn't...
But the music itself
is actually explained.
I think it's a little hard
I think even if there is such a difference,
it's just possible.
But to answer that question directly,
for example,
if I tie the musician to the chair
so that he can't move,
let's see what the effect of their performance is.
This is a more direct manipulation.
Do you agree with me?
I don't know. I can't figure it out.
I have to think about it again.
That is to say,
I can't move your body today.
Let's see if your performance quality
will be reduced.
Obviously,
there will be a lot of confounders.
You can't do that.
But I'm still thinking about
the lack of evidence just now.
It seems that it can only prove that
you still find that
the reaction between the body
is causally linked.
It's the connection between the follower and the leader.
But the causality of this connection
does not represent the causality
between the performance of music
and the body sway.
So it's not a good evidence.
Do you mean that?
I'm a little confused.
I'm confused, too.
Forget it.
When we were writing the paper,
different authors were thinking about it.
Some authors directly argued that
body sway is communication.
But...
I don't think you have that evidence.
I think the evidence is direct.
I just said that I was a little bit safe.
Then in the discussion,
I said it might be like this.
But I don't know.
I think there are indeed
two causes and conditions for discussion.
One is that
the body sway of the leader
leads to the body sway of the follower.
This is the analysis you are doing now.
As long as the bar on your left is higher,
it means that the causality exists.
But...
You go first.
But the other cause is
the connection between the music
and the body sway.
Is body sway
the connection between the music itself?
Yes.
OK.
The first point is
about grunge causality.
I guess many listeners may know that
it is actually argued that
causality is a big problem.
Mathematically,
causality is a big problem?
Yes.
Mathematically,
it can only say that
the amount of information transfer.
Is there really a cause?
There must be some other situations.
For example,
I have to sample
the whole universe
to make it possible.
In some cases,
it is conservative.
Mathematically,
I can only say
A predict B.
I can't say A cause B.
In this example,
you can say causality.
Because it is the difference in time.
This information
leads to this information change.
What other factors
in body sway
will lead to this change?
Maybe music
has a third reason.
In short,
I think the alternative is limited.
There is no possibility.
These alternatives
sound
not very
compelling.
So I think
even if it is a little risky,
you can still argue
that this is a causal relationship.
On the other hand,
what you really care about
is the body movement reaction.
Is this information
transmitted
by music communication itself?
Does it cause
better music quality?
better communication?
But
I don't think
there is a causal relationship.
I think
But this seems
to need other evidence.
Yes.
I am conservative.
I think you are conservative.
My bubble is gone.
So everyone is welcome
to discuss freely.
It doesn't matter if it is three-dimensional.
I would like to ask
this experiment
that you are talking about now.
For example,
how many groups
do you need
or how many musicians
to be able to
get a
less
influenced
culture
or training
from the performers?
I think
this question
is very good.
I think
this is the weakness
of this study.
First of all,
we are looking for
very high-level musicians.
You have to pay a lot of money
to buy a concert hall
for them to come.
Because of the financial constraints,
we found two groups.
We found two groups.
In terms of statistics,
we think it is better to say
that these are
called within-subject comparison.
That is to say,
compare yourself with yourself.
how much stronger
this effect is
compared to
yourself as a follower.
So even if
the sample we take
is very limited,
that is,
two groups of musicians,
a total of eight people.
But within each person,
the direction of their effect
is the same.
Is it possible that
I took some
very biased samples?
For example,
these musicians
do not represent all humans.
It is possible.
This is the weakness of this study.
I don't know
how representative this is.
I can only say
that from other
currently known studies,
the representativeness of musicians
and normal humans
is actually
similar.
It can represent
ordinary humans.
Other cultures
also have a problem
with representativeness.
At present,
it is also said that
representativeness is still OK.
It's just that
I don't have direct evidence
to say that
this effect
can represent
the effect of all humans.
I don't know.
Is it conservative?
It's OK.
I have a question.
OK.
You ask first.
You finish first.
It's OK.
The next question
has nothing to do with this.
You can continue
to ask other questions.
OK.
I have a question.
At the beginning,
you mentioned quarreling.
But quarreling
doesn't seem to be sung.
It's spoken.
So I want to know
that it can also be sung.
It's weird.
So the question I want to ask
is that
your research results
are already here.
How much do you think
it can allow us to predict
or provide us
with knowledge
about language communication
and interaction?
What kind of implications
will there be?
If there are some weaknesses
that can't be inferred,
what research
do you need to make up for
in terms of speech?
OK.
First of all,
most of the research
on body movements
and body shaking
is done
in the context of speech.
But they do it
in a small lab.
There are usually two people.
They use relevant methods
to see how similar
the information is.
There are other studies
that show
that the psychological process
used in music performance
and speech
are very similar.
In terms of music,
we also observed
a similar effect
in body movements.
Of course,
it's not exactly the same.
It's extended,
but the effect
is the same.
Although there is no direct evidence,
I think
the effect
should be the same
in terms of speech.
That's my guess.
OK, thank you.
I have a related question.
Can I interrupt you?
Do you have a number?
Someone said he had a question.
I'm afraid I'll keep interrupting.
I asked too many questions.
You just said language.
In fact,
I think
more broadly,
do you think
these are all
the phenomenon of hearing?
Or is it actually
a wider perception
or even a mental operation?
Or is it
a specific phenomenon
of hearing?
For example,
in science,
regularity
determines
how you
can anticipate
how to
process
cognitive information.
Obviously,
this also works
visually.
Next,
is the communication
of music collaborators
really limited to
the performance of music?
Or is it
all about
cooperation?
All the cooperation,
like the example
you just gave,
do they all
have the same phenomenon?
Does the sway of the body
also affect it?
Or is there
a more general mechanism?
For example,
is there any
synchronization
that helps
communication?
Can you remind me
what the first part
is?
I think
these are all examples.
The main question is
do you think
this is a domain-specific
phenomenon
or
a wider
mental operation
principle?
I don't think
there is a standard answer.
I'm just curious.
OK.
I'm curious.
According to
other studies,
in fact,
we found
that
time synchronization
is still
a bit different
from hearing
and vision.
For example,
the sense of rhythm
of vision
is actually
quite difficult
to produce
compared to hearing.
The accuracy of
tracking time
does not seem
to be as high
as the results
of the study.
But some people
have succeeded.
Vision still has
this effect.
But
what I mean is
that it may not be
the same.
The domain of hearing
is obviously
frequency and time.
But
in vision,
it will be
space and
location.
Yes, space and location.
Translated,
it becomes
statistical learning.
If there is a
fixed pattern,
I can't speak Chinese.
If there is a
fixed pattern
that appears
repeatedly,
your processing
will be faster,
better,
and more accurate.
Do you think
this is a similar phenomenon?
Or is there
a specialized
process
in the brain
to process
different areas?
OK.
I think
the special process
is because
time is
one-dimensional.
Although
it is a
single-direction
dimension,
you are always
going to the future
to make guesses.
This is
different from
the visual
pattern.
For example,
if I give you
a very regular
pattern,
this pattern
is not the same.
But it must be
future-oriented.
So,
based on your
existing information,
you keep guessing
what the
future information
is.
In fact,
it is
online processing.
So,
I think
these details
make time
different from
other senses
when it
comes to
hearing.
Because the information
is opened
at any time.
Let me give you
an example.
In the visual phenomenon,
there is also
a temporal
anticipation
phenomenon.
For example,
you should
know
this experiment.
It is
a combination
of three
random
sounds.
What is
this experiment?
This is the
first experiment
in learning
language.
For example,
there are
nine possible
notes.
There are
three notes
that are
always
connected.
Three notes
are always
in pairs.
These phrases
can be
randomly
combined.
This phenomenon
is hearing.
In fact,
if you
do the same
experiment
with visual stimulation,
all the results
are the same.
So,
this is
an online
processing
that affects
your
intuition
in the
visual phenomenon.
I know.
In each
special case,
some cases
are replicated.
But in many cases,
visually,
it is difficult
to do it.
For example,
the effect of
rhythm.
Temporal
grouping.
I know you
have done it
once in the
lab,
but
you can see
that many people
failed.
It doesn't matter.
I know.
I have done
multi-sensory.
I know it is
difficult.
It is very
simple.
You just need to
show 4 notes,
5 notes,
and people will
know.
So,
you mean
there are
domain-specific
parts.
Temporal
regularity
is a
domain-specific
part.
What do you
think is
the difference
between
hearing
and visual
regularity?
I think
the effect
is the same,
but the
processing
is different.
In
primary
auditory
cortex,
there is
temporal
coding.
In
visual cortex,
it is
where
domain.
I don't
know.
It takes
a long time
to
process
the information.
Is it
because
hearing
mechanism
makes it
noisy?
For example,
hearing
and visual
are
basically
different.
Okay.
I've been standing here
for too long.
Let me
guess.
Is it okay?
I'm done.
Please go ahead.
I read
an article
that said
if...
It's from
Sexy.
It said
if the
trigger
is
language
or
sound,
that is,
hearing,
the trigger
is
the
subject's
abstract
image.
It's
about
describing
the material
in a
more abstract
and
far-reaching
way
compared to
visual materials.
I don't know
if
it's
similar
to
processing
or
listening to
music.
If
it's
similar
to
listening
music,
I think
it's
similar.
If
it's
similar,
I think
it's
similar.
Is it
similar?
I'm
not sure.
I think
it's
similar.
It's
Okay.
So
I
don't
know
all the
details
about
the
song.
I
don't
know.
I
really don't
know.
Hello.
Are
you
calling me?
I'm done.
I just
said I
don't
know.
Sorry.
Did I
disconnect?
Okay.
Does
anyone
else have
any
questions?
Someone
is
asking
questions.
Can
I
ask
a question?
Okay.
Please.
I'm
thinking
that
if
you
tell
the
musicians
that
you
have
three
people
following
leader,
will
they
fight?
Yes.
We
actually
did this
experiment.
Our
condition
is
Beach,
I'm
the
leader.
But
we
originally
thought
that
in your
leadership
assignment,
if there
is
a
conflict,
how
can we
solve
the
conflict?
We
originally
wanted to
see this
situation.
But
the result of
the experiment
is that
we found
that only
when
everyone
can see
each other
and
everyone
is assigned
as
followers,
can we
solve
this
conflict
smoothly.
At
that
time,
we
thought
that
if
everyone
is
the
leader,
or
can't
see each
other,
they
can't
solve
the
conflict.
So
we
called it
Beach,
I'm
the
leader.
Have
you ever
tried
to solve
the
conflict?
We
thought that
if
everyone
can see
each other
and
no one
is the
leader,
they can
solve
the
conflict
smoothly.
But
only in
Bach's
music,
if
the
bassline
is
unbalanced,
this
effect
can't
be
achieved.
We
also asked
them to
guess who
is the
leader.
We
forced them
to choose
the other
three,
but
they
were
so good
that
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
answer sheet.
So
this
part
is
not
clear.
And
we
tried to
avoid
the
conflict
when
everyone
is the
leader.
We
played the
beat
two seconds
before
their
performance,
and
we
removed
the
beat
before
their
performance.
So
this
part is
not
clear.
We
also
asked
them to
guess
who
is the
leader.
We
forced them
to
choose
the
other
three,
but
they
were
so good
that
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
answer
sheet.
So
they
were
so good
that
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three,
but
they
were
so good
that
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three,
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three,
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
three
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
no
on
the
other
five
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
five
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on
the
other
five
but
they
wrote
NO
LEADER
on