Hello everyone, I'm the host for today, Zhang Yanyong, and we're going to have our 21st Terra Talk.
Today's speaker is Xu Liyan.
Xu Liyan and I have known each other for almost two years.
It's really interesting because we're at Caltech, and Xu Liyan is studying astronomy at Manoa University in Hawaii.
In 2016, we had a year-long visit to Caltech and IPAC.
At that time, we met Xu Liyan.
Xu Liyan happens to be a senior in the Department of Physics at Caltech, but he was studying astronomy at Manoa University in Hawaii.
Did I say that correctly?
I'm from the Department of Physics.
Oh, you're from the Department of Physics.
But you're studying astronomy at Manoa University.
My advisor is from Manoa University.
I see.
It's interesting because he's from Hawaii, and they were surfing.
I was surfing, so we became good friends.
Of course, his main job is still doing astronomy observation research in Hawaii.
After returning from Caltech, in 2017, he recently obtained a Ph.D. degree, so he is a new doctor.
Liyan's research is mainly galaxy observation.
In his doctoral career, he is going to talk to us about this big topic today.
He published 34 papers, but today he will focus on the latest one.
If you are interested in learning more about the previous papers, you can contact him directly.
Without further ado, let's welcome Liyan to give us his speech.
I'll mute myself.
I'd like to remind everyone to mute your microphone when you speak.
Thank you.
You can start.
Okay, I'll start.
If you have any questions, please mute your microphone.
I'm afraid people won't understand.
Oh, sorry.
We forgot something.
We need to clap.
We need to mute our microphone when we clap.
Okay, you can start.
Okay, thank you.
As you can see, my title is Characterizing Faint Sub-millimeter Galaxies with Posture Lensing.
If you don't read astronomy, you can only understand Characterizing, Faint, and Width.
I'll explain what they mean.
In short, I'm studying a galaxy called Sub-millimeter Galaxy.
The wavelength detected by this galaxy is called Sub-millimeter.
Sub-millimeter is shorter than millimeter.
Millimeter is in kilometers.
Traditionally, people use 850 micrometers to study Sub-millimeter Galaxy.
Now I'll explain why I'm studying this galaxy and what I'm studying.
Okay.
Why do we study this galaxy?
It's related to the evolution of the universe.
You can google the history of the universe.
You'll see a similar picture.
The age of the universe is 13.7 billion years.
Maybe you've heard of it.
It started from the Big Bang.
The history of the universe is shown here.
Then there was a period of time called Inflation.
At that time, the temperature of the universe was still very high.
It was all gaseous gas.
Until the temperature dropped to the ground.
The gaseous electrons in the universe were recombined with the gaseous atoms.
They became neutral gas atoms.
From then on, light can start to run freely in the universe.
Before that, any light would be scattered by those gaseous electrons.
From then on, light can run freely in the universe.
At that time, the universe was scattered by those gaseous electrons.
Okay.
But the temperature of the universe was still very high.
So there were a lot of neutral gas atoms in the universe.
After the temperature dropped to the ground.
The temperature of the gaseous atoms dropped to the ground.
The temperature of the universe was still very high.
So there were a lot of neutral gas atoms in the universe.
Before that, there was the so-called Dark Age.
Okay.
Basically, in the Big Bang, Inflation, and Cosmic Microwave Background.
During this period, I think that this part of history is a matter of physicists.
The theory of explosion is a matter of physicists.
This is a very physical thing.
And Big Bang.
From the beginning of the formation of the galaxy.
After the first galaxy was formed.
This part can be done by astronomers.
Astronomers can do this part.
I said that the temperature of the universe.
Because the universe is constantly expanding.
The temperature slowly drops.
And these gaseous atoms.
It can be further combined into gaseous atoms.
Okay, gaseous atoms.
If the temperature is cool enough.
After gravity collapses.
It will form a star.
Then the star will...
Everyone should have heard of the star.
Just like our sun.
It produces the reaction of fusion.
So it will shine.
Then it will generate energy.
Okay.
Then the star will not be produced one by one.
They are produced in groups.
That is to form the so-called galaxy.
The galaxy is...
A galaxy is basically more than a billion of stars.
Okay.
It is a system of galaxies.
So from this time on.
After the beginning of the galaxy.
It is to produce a lot of galaxies.
The universe produces more and more galaxies.
Okay.
Then we study...
I mean this part.
I am studying the so-called...
Galaxy formation and evolution.
The formation and evolution of galaxies.
That is very important.
I want to study...
The star formation.
The history of star formation.
That is the so-called cosmic star formation history.
We want to use...
That is to say.
From the first star to now.
The evolution of the universe.
You have to understand the evolution of the universe.
One of them.
You have to understand.
It is very important.
How to say.
One of the important factors.
Is the star formation.
Because.
If you look at astronomy.
No matter what you are studying.
No matter you are studying.
The evolution of the galaxy.
Galaxy formation and evolution.
Or you want to study.
The stars.
For example, our solar system.
Or study the comet.
The asteroid.
In the universe.
No matter what kind of weather you study.
It must be related to the comet.
Related to the stars.
Because you have the star.
After you have the star formation.
These stars.
Merge together.
Becomes a galaxy.
So it is related to the galaxy.
Then you.
Comet.
Comet system.
Like our solar system.
After the comet is formed.
Then.
Some dust around the comet.
Slowly formed a comet.
Then the comet goes around the comet.
Like the comet.
Nebula.
This is also.
So.
You can say.
Astronomy.
No matter what you are studying.
I say astronomy.
If it is.
The physics of cosmology.
It doesn't count.
Astronomy.
Basically.
Whatever you do.
No matter what you do.
Will be related to.
Star formation.
So the history of star formation.
Star formation history.
So it is a very important.
If you want to understand this universe.
This is a very important thing.
OK.
Then.
I believe I have.
Convinced everyone.
Star formation history.
Is a very important thing.
But.
Star formation history.
When we do research.
Found.
This picture on the left.
Is the so-called.
I put the star formation history.
This thing.
Brighten it.
Then this place.
This axis on the left is called.
Star formation rate.
Density.
Is the star formation rate.
Then you can imagine.
Star formation rate.
Is every year.
Its unit is.
Ah.
Star formation rate.
Divided by.
Time.
Then its unit is basically.
Every year.
Basically every year.
Can produce.
How much.
Solar mass.
This.
This unit is.
Solar mass.
Is solar mass.
So this part is called.
Star formation rate.
Then if you are in volume.
So it's star formation rate.
Then in unit volume.
Then this is.
NPC is a.
Ah.
The distance unit of astronomy.
Then.
Don't.
Don't care how it comes.
Then it is a distance unit.
Then three dimensions.
So this part is.
Ah.
The orbit is green.
In unit volume.
So it's called star formation rate.
Density.
Horizontal.
This is look back time.
So the more to the right is the longer.
OK.
Then this look back time.
Can be corresponded to the so-called.
Redshift.
Called redshift.
Ah.
Then this.
I will explain it later.
Because this is.
For people who don't study astronomy.
Should not know what this is.
OK.
But you can.
I can tell you now.
The more to the right is.
Ah.
The earlier.
The universe.
That.
Zero.
This place is now.
OK.
So the time travel is from the right to the left.
Not from the left to the right.
OK.
Then this picture is basically a.
Star formation.
History picture.
Then you want to.
Measure this picture.
Ah.
You.
We.
Ah.
Will find.
There are two.
There are basically.
There are two kinds of observations.
Is very important.
That is.
Ah.
When we used to.
Probably in the 90s.
When.
The end of the 90s.
We have some.
Ah.
Satellite.
That is the space telescope.
We go to measure.
The whole universe.
Background radiation.
That.
There are different wavelengths.
Background radiation.
That.
Then I mentioned.
Cosmic microwave background.
That is.
CMB.
Here.
Ah.
Then this.
Is the intensity of light.
Then.
Horizontal.
Is the wavelength.
So this is basically.
Light wave.
That.
CMB.
Probably in this place.
Then we will find.
There are two components in this universe.
CMB does not count.
There are two.
Very important components.
One is called.
Cosmic optical background.
It is visible light.
Background.
Then the other part.
It is called.
Cosmic infrared background.
It is the background of infrared.
Then we found.
These two.
Background.
Their amount.
Is almost.
Almost.
What does this tell us?
Because in this universe.
Horizontal.
They will emit.
Ah.
Polar light.
Visible light.
Or near infrared light.
That.
Horizontal.
Directly emitted light.
Basically.
This is the component.
Optical background.
OK.
But.
This.
Universe.
The.
Horizontal.
In this universe.
Star formation.
OK.
About half.
It is not.
We can.
Directly observe.
It is called.
Dusty star formation.
What does it mean?
That is.
When you.
A.
Area.
When a lot of stars are produced.
Then.
A lot of new stars.
Huge stars.
They.
Soon.
Will fall.
Then become.
The so-called supernova.
Supernova.
Then.
These.
These huge stars.
They produce.
They are.
A lot of heavy elements.
Then.
By the end of the year.
It becomes a supernova.
Will explode.
Then.
Will put these heavy elements.
That is.
Talk about this.
Space in the universe.
Then.
These heavy elements.
Some of these heavy elements.
For example.
Carbon.
These things.
They will form.
Star dust.
That is.
Dust.
That.
Dust particles.
That is.
Like dust.
Floating.
In space.
That.
Dust.
Will be.
Directly emit light.
Oh.
These straight.
Horizontal.
That.
Light is.
External light.
The visible light.
Near infrared.
Is the near infrared light.
These dusts.
Will be.
These.
Parts of the light.
Absorbed.
Then.
From our perspective.
From the observer's point of view.
That is to say.
It'll block him.
Block that part of the light.
But after it's blocked.
The energy is residual.
After it's absorbed.
He will.
Radiate again.
Recharge.
These energies.
About half.
Will be.
These dusts.
Absorbed.
So we call.
Dusty star formation.
Or.
Dust.
Hidden star formation.
Or.
Dust obscured star formation.
Anyway.
The point is.
These star formations.
Will be.
Dust.
To.
To be.
Obscured by these dusts.
Then.
They absorb the energy.
Then emit infrared light.
Oh.
That is to say.
You have to understand.
The star formation of this universe.
These two different.
You can directly observe.
The other is.
You can't directly observe.
Then.
These.
You can't directly observe.
You have to.
In a longer wavelength.
To observe.
That is.
Far infrared light.
Or.
Sub-millimeter.
Or even.
Millimeter.
This.
Kilometer.
I just said.
Sub-millimeter.
Is.
Less than a kilometer.
Wavelength.
OK.
So.
Simply.
Follow-on.
In this universe.
There is a large part.
Star formation.
Is.
Blocked by dust.
Then.
You want to understand.
That part.
Star formation.
You can only observe.
This wavelength.
Longer wavelength.
OK.
Then.
I just said.
I mentioned.
This is called.
Redshift.
This thing.
Then I will explain.
What is.
Redshift.
Then.
Simply speaking.
If you have studied physics.
You should know.
The effect of Duplo.
When.
When you.
This thing.
Uh.
This wave.
If it goes away from you.
When.
The wavelength you receive.
Will be stretched.
Or.
Simply speaking.
It's frequency.
Change.
Uh.
Frequency.
Change.
Uh.
Short.
Or long.
Frequency.
Change.
Uh.
Slower.
Then.
If something.
Is close to you.
Then.
Its wavelength.
Will.
Uh.
Short.
Or.
Frequency.
Uh.
Change.
So.
You hear.
The ambulance.
For example.
If it's close to you.
Its sound.
Will change.
The pitch will be higher.
The pitch of the ambulance.
Will change.
Uh.
The pitch.
Will be lower.
Okay.
The wave.
Also has this Duplo effect.
Okay.
Then.
When we observe.
The object.
In the universe.
Uh.
When you feel a pulse.
Yeah.
Uh.
It's short.
Very short.
Uh.
When you get.
It's short.
Yes.
Uh.
Um.
uh.
Redshift
Uh.
Um.
Yes.
Redshift
Uh.
Yes.
There.
Uh.
That.
Redshift
Um.
Redfift
Red
Hand
The most common unit of distance is light year
But
Basically light year is a
Astronomers
use it
to do science education
and talk to the general public
Astronomers almost never use light year
This unit
Astronomers will use
Distance unit may use
Part second
But if it is
Like my research department
We will not use distance unit
We will use relationship unit
Why?
Because when you reach a large
dimension
The so-called distance
is no longer an objective fact
For example, I am standing here
and another person is standing here
The so-called distance
We are both
in the same time and space
We measure the distance
It is an objective fact
But when you discuss the entire
universe
The size of the universe
When the distance is very far
The so-called distance
must be defined
The distance is no longer an objective fact
There are different definitions
of distance
Why define it?
Because our universe is constantly expanding
So it is a very complicated
And it involves the evolution of our universe
I don't have time to talk about it today
To put it simply
The picture on my right
Is the relationship between distance and redshift
Is the distance in Giga light year
Giga light year is
Giga is billions
So the light year is billions
Or
Age in Giga year
There is a lookback time
This curve is the time
When we
Redshift to the right
How long ago we saw
This is called lookback time
The other is called luminosity distance
Angular diameter distance
Line of cycle movement distance
And Naive Hubble distance
These are all distances
That is the distance under different definitions
In conclusion
I won't talk about these distances today
How they are defined
And what they can do
But in conclusion
We can directly measure the distance
Is this luminosity and angular diameter
These two distances
But I won't talk about it in detail
To put it simply
The conclusion is
It is not very convenient to use distance
Because you are talking about the distance
And these distances
The relationship between distance and redshift
Is linear
Even the angular diameter distance is strange
To
Redshift 1 or more
It is decreasing
So it is not very convenient to use distance
It is not a convenient variable
So usually when studying cosmology
Or galaxy evolution
We use redshift
As our distance
So we often say
How much redshift is your galaxy
Basically, the larger the redshift
Ok
Sorry
Can you hear me?
Yes
I have a question
You have to calculate the original wavelength
In addition to the redshift
How do you know the original wavelength?
The next step is to talk about it
Basically
Redshift is a very important variable
Otherwise
If there is no redshift
When you do some modeling
You only have a free parameter
So we need
Do a lot of
Measurement and modeling
We hope we will know
Redshift
How to measure redshift
Basically observe the wavelength
Divide by its original wavelength
And subtract 1
I want to emphasize that
Measurement of redshift is very important
Basically it is optical
Whether you are
Studying the star or galaxy
They are all similar
You use optical
Optical theory
Optical theory is usually visible light
Or near infrared
Ok
Usually you use a large telescope
We have two modes of observation
Visible light telescope
Or near infrared
One is called imaging
Imaging
You can imagine
It is taking pictures
It is directly taking images
The other mode is called spectroscopy
Basically it uses
The concept of light in physics
You observe a star
After the light passes through the telescope
Finally
There will be diffraction
We can measure the intensity of light
As a function of wave length
Ok
How do we measure redshift
We know
Today's sky
Whether star or galaxy
We know
What should the original spectrum look like
Redshift equals to 0
So we need to know
But this is not difficult
Because a lot of these things
There will be a lot of absorption lines
Or radiation
Absorption line
Or emission line
Hα
Oxygen
These things
Basically, after listening to the study for a long time
We must have a galaxy
There must be a model
And these
Emission line
Or absorption line
How much is it?
Because we are on earth
We can do it in the chemical lab
We can know
These absorption lines and emission lines
Their wavelength
Without redshift
How much
Let's say today
Two galaxy spectrum
We found this
We have these spectrum
We all know
How much it should be when there is no redshift
Then we can know their ratio
The ratio from here to here
Then we can measure
The redshift of this galaxy
Is there a problem here?
If not, I will continue to talk about the next part
Basically, the redshift event
It is the concept of redshift
Now back to my topic
Why do I study the sub-millimeter galaxy?
I just mentioned
Because there are two kinds of star formation in the universe
One is that we can directly observe
Visible light can be directly observed
The other half is
Will be absorbed by dust
Radiation
That part
Can only be observed
In the far infrared or sub-millimeter
Sub-millimeter
The observation of sub-millimeter
There is another point
The so-called negative k-correction
Now I will explain
What is negative k-correction
I just said
There is a redshift in our universe
So I drew a graph on the left
This graph is a very typical
Star formation galaxy
There is a galaxy
It is a very dusty galaxy
It has a lot of star dust
So the light of the star
Will be absorbed by the dust
Then put it in the far infrared
Basically this part
The smooth part
Is the far infrared light
The far infrared light emitted by dust
The left side
This is the star
And this part
What is hot
I said I put the far infrared light
This part is colder
Right part
This is radio
This is a synchrotron radiation
If he is consumed by the paralleloscope
The paralleloscope rotates
Then release
Synchrotron Radiation
I forgot the Chinese name of Synchrotron Radiation
But it releases radiation
Its light wave is here
Anyway
Then I did this thing
I put a light wave
Redshift
From 0.5 to 10
As I said just now
Redshift is what causes the wavelength to change
But it is not very far
As I said just now
It is 1 plus z
OK
So your wavelength
You observe the wavelength
The original wavelength is 1 plus z
So you can imagine
When you have a galaxy
If you can move it freely
If you want to move it further and further
What I see
The light wave will get fatter and fatter
It's not just moving
It's getting fatter and fatter
Because it is 1 plus z
There are two effects
First, when you move it further and further
Its light wave will get fatter and fatter
But the second thing is the so-called inverse square law
When you move a star
Or a galaxy
If you move it further and further
Naturally, what we observe is getting darker and darker
It's the same as the square
So you see
When you move to a higher and higher Redshift
Its overall normalization
It's getting lower and lower
Because it gets darker and darker
But the other effect is
You move it to the right more and more
Then there will be a very interesting phenomenon
Just because
The light wave formed by cold dust
It's like this curve
Then we observe
Millimeters
Or millimeters
When we observe the wavelength
We found
A dusty galaxy
When you move it further and further
We observe
The flux
Almost unchanged
Why?
Because of two effects
The first effect is
When you move it further and further
It will naturally get fatter and fatter
But the other effect is
You move the light wave to the right
So what we observe is getting closer and closer
More and more to the right
We observe
Like this galaxy
These two effects
To a certain extent, it's a little offset
So this effect is called
Because of Redshift
Cause you
Offset the effect of distance
This effect is called Negative K Correction
There is actually another
Positive K Correction
Positive K Correction is
For example, if you observe
If you observe the radio
When you move it further and further
In addition to
The further the distance
The further the brightness
When you move the light wave to the right
It will also make you
Make your brightness lower
So this is called Positive K Correction
Both of its effects
Cause your brightness to be lower
Negative K Correction
Redshift
The further the distance
The effect is opposite
It's a little bit
So it's called Negative K Correction
And then when we observe
Often in the
About one millimeter
These two effects are almost offset
So you observe
Hello, I have a question
Yes
Please ask
My question is
If you say
The emission of dust
Is because its energy is
Absorbed by dust
After that, the dust releases energy
So it's actually a bit like
Thermal Equilibrium
Blackbody Radiation
It's not a perfect blackbody
It's called Modified Blackbody
Hello
Hello, can you hear me?
It's not a perfect blackbody
It's a blackbody radiation
But
So it's basically thermal radiation
Right?
It's called Modified
But its spectrum to some extent
Corresponds to temperature, right?
Yes, that's what I just said
This is very smooth
Then I have a question
Why is the temperature of different galaxies
The same
It will be different
Why is the temperature the same?
Different
Hello
I can hear you
It won't be the same
So the temperature is different
I can hear you
This part
This part is the so-called
Thermal dust
When the temperature is different
Its shape will be slightly different
Hello
Can you hear me?
I can't hear you
OK
But you have to assume
This point will never run away
Can you hear me?
Yes
It's broken
What?
You have to assume this point
It's broken
I
Basically
You probably want to say
If their spectrum is different
It won't be so good
But it should be
The example I am giving now is just a typical example
OK
But the typical example is like this
Then when your temperature is different
Its shape will be slightly different
But it won't be so bad
They are basically similar
But the temperature is different
The shape is slightly different
Then they all have a similar effect
I just said
It's not 100% perfect
It's just about
Does this explain your question?
Yes
It's not perfect
Thank you
The example I am giving now is just a typical example
But different Galaxy's spectrum will definitely be different
But they all have a similar effect
But it's not perfect
OK
I will continue
I will draw this effect on the right
This is what we observe
This Galaxy is called Redshift
This is Redshift
This is the intensity of light
Then the different color curves here
It corresponds to different observations
So like here
0.8 microns
It's about 800 nanometers
800 nanometers is red light
OK
It's positive
0.8 microns
No difference
Here is 500
500 micrometers
450 micrometers
About
About 850 and 1 mm
These wavelengths
Are near here
Almost flat
OK
So
The conclusion is
When the wavelength you observe is
Sub-millimeter or millimeter
You have a good effect
No matter how far you move
The brightness you observe
Almost unchanged
So with this effect
You can use it to detect
Detect
Very high redshift galaxy
Very far galaxy
Very early galaxy in the universe
If you use a more traditional
Visible wavelength
You will find that its brightness drops very quickly
So of course, your distant galaxy is very dark
It's not easy to observe
If you use radio
Radio is wireless radio
If you use wireless radio to observe
You will still see this picture
It also drops very quickly
So it's the same for distant galaxies
It's very hard to observe
If you want to observe
You have to do a long exposure
Observation is very deep
The deeper you are, the farther you can observe
But sub-millimeter or millimeter
This is almost flat
So you can use this technique
To detect
Compared to visible light or radio
It's much easier
Much easier
To observe these distant galaxies
This is why sub-millimeter is very important
I'm going to talk about
Now the point is
What I'm studying is called sub-millimeter galaxies
In the 1990s
Kearny used
Sub-millimeter
Telescope
It's a telescope
Called JCMD
I will have a photo later
To shoot a famous field in the sky
Called Hubble Deep Field
Because this field
They used Hubble telescope
To shoot a very deep image
This is the image taken by Hubble telescope
Visible light image
Then they used JCMD
To shoot the same area
This
The image on the right
Is a sub-millimeter image
With JCMD
There is a bright spot here
There may be a bright spot here
This is a
Sub-millimeter source
Before JCMD
We only use some
Space telescope to measure the background
We can measure
Sub-millimeter
But we don't
Understand
What source is this background
From
With JCMD
Resolve the background
Into individual sources
We can see the individual sub-millimeter
I just talked about
Sub-millimeter galaxies
Sub-millimeter galaxies are basically dusty
They are very
Intense
Star formation
Very intense
Starburst gas
Why is the sub-millimeter
Very bright
Originally
If it is red
If we have a dusty galaxy
Its peak
About
Its wavelength
About 100 micrometer
But when you move to
When redshift is above 1
When the distance of your galaxy
Is above redshift 1
Its peak may move to
About millimeter
Or sub-millimeter
Why is it
Very bright
Its original wavelength
Is about 100 micrometer
100 micrometer is
In astronomy
This wavelength is called distant infrared
Distant infrared
Because it is
Above redshift 1
When we observe it
The wavelength we observe
Is below
Sub-millimeter and millimeter
Wavelength
Ok
This sub-millimeter galaxy
Is a very dusty starburst galaxy
It is usually difficult
It is written here
It is difficult to observe in visible wavelengths
Or so-called rest frame UV
These visible wavelengths
For these distant information
When it is emitted
When the light is emitted
It is a rest frame UV
When we observe
It is redshift visible
So we observe it as visible light
But when it is emitted
It is actually UV
These sub-millimeter galaxies
Because it is very dusty
Basically their UV
Often absorbed by dust
So in visible wavelengths
You often can't see them
Can't observe them
When it is sub-millimeter wavelength
You will find
A very bright source
Ok
I will continue
How to observe these
Sub-millimeter galaxies
As I said
In the 90s, they used JCMP
To find these sub-millimeter galaxies
This kind of telescope is called single-dash
It only has one antenna
Telescope
Ok
Basically using this kind of single-dash
To scan our sky
Is the most effective way to find these sub-millimeter galaxies
I will introduce later
Another technique
Interferometry
I will talk about it later
This kind of single-dash
I will talk about the conclusion first
The conclusion is
It is the most effective way
To scan the sky
To find these sources
It has a problem
Its resolution is very low
Why?
Basically
The image we took
Is proportional to the wavelength
And is proportional to the size of the telescope
This is basically
It comes from physical light
It comes from light
If you have studied light
You should be familiar with this
So today we observe
Sub-millimeter or far-infrared
Or radio
These are relatively long wavelengths
On the contrary, if you observe visible light
Or UV
Those are relatively short wavelengths
These long wavelengths
This lambda is very large
So the image resolution
Will be worse
If you want to make your image resolution
A little better
You have to build a bigger telescope
Let your diameter
Build a bigger telescope
I will talk about this later
Talk more
This kind of single-dash telescope
Because the wavelength is long
So its resolution is very low
So it has two problems
The first is that if the resolution is very low
You observe a source
Then when you want to go to other wavelengths
To find it in other wavelengths
The corresponding point
Is the counterpart
You don't know where it is
Because its resolution is too bad
So you have to
You don't know where its precise position is
If you want to know its precise position
You need to use interference
Do further observation
OK, my next slide
Will talk about what interference is
Like this picture
This is the result
The source observed by JCMP
Maybe it's a big one
Sorry, I don't have a picture here
A big one
You can't get it
Where is the precise position
But after the observation of the interference
You can get it
A higher resolution image
Then you can accurately measure its position
After measuring its position
You go to other wavelengths
For example, this is the image of Hubble telescope
Then you go to other wavelengths
To find its corresponding counterpart
Or not
This is the first problem
Its resolution is too bad
So you have to use interference
The second problem is called confusion limit
Basically, it is also caused by low resolution
Because your resolution is bad
When your resolution is bad
In our universe
Whether you are exploring the stars
Or stars
In this universe
Dark things
More than bright things
There may be a power law
Here
Then when you
There are more dark things
It means that these darker subliminal galaxies
The density
The density in the sky
Is greater than those brighter subliminal galaxies
The meaning of confusion limit
When you observe
When the resolution is very low
Then when you
If there are a lot of
Darker subliminal galaxies
Because they are a lot
Then they will all come together
Come together and become one
In other words, you observe one
A very bright source
In fact, it may be a lot of dark
Darker subliminal galaxies
Because your resolution is too bad
So you see a lot
So this will cause something called
Confusion limit
Because the resolution of your telescope is bad
So you can't observe
You will have a limit
A star that is darker than this limit
You can't directly observe
Because the stars that are darker than this limit
They are a lot
Because of your low resolution
All blend together
OK
So this limit will cause
Observe a subliminal galaxy
It has a limit
Its brightness is like this
Too many Jansky at 850 microns
I won't explain today
What unit is this mini Jansky
Anyway, it is a unit of brightness
OK
This brightness can be converted to
Its absolute brightness
Called luminosity
About 10 to 12 squares
Solar luminosity
Solar luminosity is the brightness of the sun
So this limit
It corresponds to 10 to 12 squares
The brightness of the sun
This kind of star is called
Ultraluminous Infrared Galaxy
It is very very bright
Dusty Galaxy
In other words, we use JCMP
Or use this kind of single dish
The source we can detect
It is very very very bright
Then we can't detect
Darker
This is its problem
OK, I will explain later
My thesis
How to solve this problem
Now I will explain the interference cloud
What is the interference cloud
I just said
Resolution you observe
It is proportional to wavelength
Resolution of the telescope
So you want
Resolution is very bad
If we want to improve our resolution
Then we build a bigger telescope
Let D
But this is the problem
You have to build a very big telescope
Or a very big antenna
Because we are a long-wave field
In fact, our telescope is the so-called antenna
Just like this
I think I just drew it
It is an antenna
Then we have to build a very big
Gigantic antenna
It is very very expensive
So this thing
It is not economic
So how to solve it
It is the so-called interference cloud
Interference cloud means
We don't build a super big antenna
We build a lot of small antennas
Like the picture of my background
We build multiple small antennas
Then
We accept the signal
Make a cross correlation
This technology is called
Interference cloud
Then
It is a bit like
When you put a lot of small antennas
Then spread it
Spread it on the ground
It is a bit like
You have a big telescope
But not so perfect
It has a lot
When you deal with images
It has a lot of complicated details
I won't talk about these
But basically what you can do is
When you spread a lot of small antennas
The resolution can be similar to
A big telescope
It is equivalent to increasing the low
So you can get a
Higher resolution image
So I gave an example here
Then this side
This picture is
I used JCMP
I took a picture
A very wide image
Then there is a bright spot inside
Is a
Submarine source
Zoom in
Then
Why is it called SCUBA-2?
Because we use JCMP
Observe the camera
Of the submarine galaxy
That camera
Is called SCUBA-2
Then we observe
Then we need to use interference cloud
The background pattern
This interference cloud is very famous
ELMA telescope
ELMA is built in Chile
It is the most powerful
Interference cloud in the world
Then it observes the submarine
Then you use ELMA
Observe this sky
In fact, this example is just right
This is not
Like this picture is
Observed by my group
But ELMA is observed by other groups
Then they just observe this area
Then this red dot is equivalent to
It corresponds to the same
SCUBA-2 image
This is the center of the source
Then we have ELMA observation
We get a much higher resolution image
Just found this one
In fact, it is three
Submarine galaxies
Then because our resolution is very poor
Put them together
OK
Someone may ask you
Why don't you use interference cloud
Just observe
Right
Why use
I just said
SCUBA-2
The reason is
There are two
Interference cloud observation
Compared to
SCUBA-2
Their observation is
Observationally a lot more expensive
The cost is higher
OK
Then the field of view is different
The field of view is
It can be
Includes
The size of the area is different
I use SCUBA-2 today
I use JCMP's SCUBA-2 camera
I can observe
I can observe such a large area at a time
OK
But if I use interference cloud
Interference cloud
Not for this thing
Interference cloud is suitable for
Observe individual sources
Then it can only observe a small area at a time
That is to say
SCUBA-2 and interference cloud
These two things
Their purpose is different
So why do I say
SCUBA-2 is the most efficient way
Because SCUBA-2
Although the resolution is poor
But it is
It can have a relatively large
Observation area
So it can be effective
To scan the entire sky
Scan a large area
OK
So it is still the most effective
To scan a large area
Then find the source
Then when we find these individual sources
We use interference cloud
To separate
To follow up
Then get it
Higher resolution
This is the effective way of observation
So basically the two of them
The purpose is not the same
Because it can only scan a small area at a time
So if you want to scan a large area
You have to observe
Observe here, observe there
Do a lot
To the sky
To a lot of different areas
Then there is a way to put it together
Such a large area
This is very inefficient
OK
Speaking of this
Do you have any questions
I have a question
You just said
Interference cloud basically uses a lot of
Small
What is it called in Chinese?
antenna
These antennas must be
Gathered at the same point
Or distributed well
Even a few hundred miles
Can also be distributed well
Like my picture
Usually interference cloud
It has different configurations
Will follow you
The purpose observed by astronomers
To adjust its configuration
Usually you want to hear
What is the so-called extended configuration
Compact configuration
Subcompact
That means they have
Spread it widely
So it can be moved
Yes, it can be moved
Basically, the wider you spread
Your resolution will be better
Because the wider you spread
Effectively
The farther they are
It's like you build a very large network
Let you have low increase
The wider you spread
Your resolution is higher
It is possible
Different countries
Antennas can also be formed
Such a set
Because this has been done for a long time
This has been done for a long time
Is
Different wavelengths
Like this
A long time ago
VLBI
Very Large Baseline Intergalactic
It
But its wavelength is not
The wavelength we are discussing today
I believe that
If I remember correctly, it should be longer
That VLBI
It's all over the world
The antenna
I remember the United States
There is one in Arizona
There is one in Hawaii
A little more east
I forgot
Then it's all over the world
So its baseline
So the baseline
I forgot to say
Interferometry will talk about the name of the baseline
Baseline is basically the distance between the antenna and the antenna
The VLBI I just said
Its baseline is very long
Because it is equivalent to
The size of the whole earth
Baseline
So it can do very high resolution
A kind of observation
Thank you
So I just said
Our single dish
There are two questions
The first one is that my resolution is very poor
So I'm going to use interferometry
To do more follow-up observations
The other question is that I just said
There will also be a detection limit
How do I solve this?
This is what my thesis is doing
How do I solve this problem?
Is to use so-called gravity
OK
I don't know how many of these listeners are studying physics
If you are not studying physics
You may have heard of it for the first time
The so-called gravity is Einstein's relativity
That is to say
If there is gravity, it will cause time-space distortion
Time-space distortion
Time-space distortion will cause
When the light passes through a gravitational field
It will turn
So it's like a透鏡
Like a 突透鏡
Have you ever played 突透鏡 when you were a kid?
突透鏡 can gather light
You can gather the light of the sun
And then you can burn a paper on the ground
So 突透鏡 has the effect of gathering light
Or you can say
It can make something darker
After passing through your 突透鏡
It looks brighter
So
Gravity can have this effect
Because it can gather light
So we often use gravity in astronomy
To study very distant stars
Very distant stars
When you
Suppose we observe a very distant galaxy here
We are here
But then just assume we are here
There is a galaxy cluster in the middle of the light path
Galaxy cluster
Galaxy cluster is a lot of galaxies
They are clustered together
Galaxy cluster is
In this universe
It is the
The largest
Bound system
Gravitationally bound system
The quality of the galaxy
Usually 10 to 14
Because its quality is very, very large
So the galaxy must have
Very strong gravity
So they
Can be used as a 突透鏡
So these backgrounds
These distant galaxies will be
The galaxy cluster
After having this focus
It will become brighter
So
Astronomers often use this technique
To observe very distant stars
Because very distant stars
Of course they will be darker
Because it's too far
But with the help of gravity
We can observe a brighter brightness
So it helps us
To study the early universe
OK
Hubble telescope
In the past few years
There was a program called FrontierField
FrontierField program
It picked
Six very bright galaxies
These six
Then
The Hubble telescope took pictures of these six galaxies
Very, very deep image
So there will be
A very beautiful visible image
So
The purpose of this FrontierField program
Is
To study very distant stars
It uses
The galaxy cluster as a focus
To study distant stars
So
In this picture
Let me show you
Like this
It's the galaxy cluster
The focus of the galaxy
But
There is a line here
These are all
After gravity
Distance star
In English, it's Lensed
They have been gravitated
Lensed
Distant star
If you are a physicist
You may have heard of Einstein ring
These are the so-called Einstein ring
Because it's a distant star
Then
After it's gravitated
We see it
Then we will see
A ring
The same
The shape
It's because it's a very distant star
After gravity
Okay
This is Hubble
FrontierField program
But what am I observing today?
I'm the girl up there
I'm the same
Because of this Hubble
This program
So my thesis is
I used my JCMP telescope
JCMP telescope has a scuba tube camera
Then I also went to shoot
A lot of galaxies
We shot a total of nine galaxies
Then include five FrontierField
That is
These five
Except for this
These five we shot
Why don't we shoot this?
Because of its coordinate
This galaxy is too difficult to make
It's too difficult to make in the sky
But our JCMP
It's in Hawaii and it's in the North Pole
So it can't shoot this
So we only shoot these five
So I said including five FrontierField
So
We use the effect of gravity
So we use the effect of gravity
We do sub-millimeter observation
So I just said this question
TooManyGenski
This limit problem can be solved
Why? Because if we have the effect of gravity
We observed
The limit of the observation brightness
It's still TooManyGenski
But these
TooManyGenski
It was actually darker
It is today
After the effect of gravity
But in fact we see
Better than this limit
Darker than this limit
Sub-millimeter Galaxy
That is to say, we use the effect of gravity
We can observe
Darker than the brightness of 10
These Galaxy
OK
Then there is
Today we use sub-millimeter
Observe these
There is another benefit
That is
If you observe today
It's a visible wave segment
Like this
In this image
Galaxy cluster
And those background information
Like these one by one
So you have to find a way to distinguish them
If you want to study
High-resolution Galaxy
But if you observe
Sub-millimeter
There will be no problem
If you observe sub-millimeter
These gravity sensors are basically transparent
Why?
Galaxy cluster
Most of them are elliptical Galaxy
These elliptical Galaxy are very old
Very old Galaxy
They don't have star formation
No star formation
And they don't have dust
So these elliptical Galaxy
They basically don't emit
Far infrared light
Far infrared emission
They don't have dust emission
In addition, these stars
Their redshift is about 0.5
0.3, 0.4, 0.5, 0.6
So even if they have
Far infrared emission
They won't go to sub-millimeter
So the conclusion is
The conclusion is
These Galaxy clusters
They don't emit sub-millimeter
So when you are shooting this star
Then you use sub-millimeter
To observe
You see any
You see any of these sources
They are basically background
They are all emitted from a very distant universe
Not the star itself
Because I just said
The elliptical Galaxy in the star
They don't emit far infrared emission
So this is a very neat thing
You don't have to
Not like you are in visible light
You still have to distinguish
The background and the cluster itself
So these two pictures
Basically my
This is how it looks
And then
This blue and red area
It's basically the Hubble telescope
The area that has been observed
OK
So why do we
We have to observe these redshift stars
Because the Hubble telescope
Get these areas of very deep visible light
Then we also use sub-millimeter to shoot
We can find these
Sub-millimeter sources
And then we need to
We can also go to the Hubble telescope
To find the counterpart
It's in visible light
Right
It's not just the Hubble telescope
It also has other telescopes
That is to say
These areas are very rich
Very rich
Observations
What we do today
We are also in the area
We use
Sub-millimeter
Then the picture I showed today
The left is 450 micrometers
The right is 850 micrometers
Then we mainly use 850
Then today
The yellow circle
The circle
It's one by one
Sub-millimeter sources
Then this cluster
It's Abell 370
That's the one I just
One of the Hubble
Ok
Then
With this image
We can detect a lot of darker
Sub-millimeter galaxies
Because I said that they were observed by us
So they are actually
Lower than our original
Sub-millimeter observation
Then we have to study these darker
Sub-millimeter galaxies
What to do
Here is the explanation
The picture on the right
It's called
Sub-millimeter number count
The horizontal axis is 850 micrometers
The vertical axis is basically
Number density
That is
The number of sub-millimeter galaxies
The number of unit areas
Then divided by
Unit brightness
So its unit is like this
Because it is the number divided by
Area divided by
Flux
But basically it is
Number density per area per
Flux
If you measure it out, it's like this
Then
Usually we use this model
This is called Broken Power Law
Here is a Power Law
Here is another Power Law
Then today this red line
Is the Confusion Limit I just said
If I use JCMP to observe today
Our limit is this
Is this red line
OK, so if we observe
General sky area like this
These three are general sky areas
They are not sub-millimeter sky areas
We can only constrain this part
But if we observe today
These blue circles are all
Sub-millimeter sky areas
That is galaxy cluster
We can only observe the darker background
Sub-millimeter galaxy
Because they are lensed
We can also have
Measurement on the left side of the limit
So we can constrain
This part that we couldn't observe
OK
This picture is very basic
The darker it is, the higher the density
This is why the dark
Sub-millimeter galaxy is important
We used to have this limit
We can only observe this part of the sub-millimeter galaxy
But in fact, the dark galaxy is more
The density of the dark galaxy is more than that of the bright galaxy
That is to say
In this universe
You have to study
We are studying
Cosmic Star Formation History
Then I want to study
Dusty part
In this part
The dark sub-millimeter galaxy
Its contribution is far greater than
This brighter sub-millimeter galaxy
The reason is very simple
Because its density is higher
Although they are darker
So they contribute
If you only compare a single sub-millimeter galaxy
Then one is bright and one is dark
Of course the darker one
Will be less than a brighter one
But because
You are a power law
Its number density is a function of flux
Is a power law
Darker
Its number is much more than the bright ones
So in general
Dark sub-millimeter galaxy
Contribute star formation
Is much more than the bright ones
So they are important
Is there any problem here?
No
What about the picture on the left?
This is called
Star Formation Rate Density
But it also
Normalize itself
It is per
Star Formation Rate
The horizontal axis is the star formation rate
It is the star formation rate
How much solar mass is generated per year
Here is the star formation
Sorry
Here is the galaxy
Its number density
Per star formation rate
Log star formation rate
The picture is like this
The picture on the left
Is observed by optical
Optical
To get the curve
The curve on the right
Is observed by sub-millimeter
To get the curve
Then you will find
The population on the left
Is the optical environment
As I said
Because it is a redshift galaxy
Its redstripe is actually UB
OK
These
UVs
Or the optical samples
On the left
You will find these two populations
Here are different curves
From different papers
These two
These two populations
Almost do not overlap
Why do not overlap?
Because these
Can be directly observed by optical
Because the star formation rate
Is not so high
Because usually the more dusty
The more dusty
The higher the star formation rate
Usually like this
So these sub-millimeter samples
They are very dusty galaxies
Although they are all on the right
Their star formation rate is very high
Then there is the confusion limit
I just said
Your sub-millimeter sample is limited to
The single digit limit
And these other visible light waves
Their samples overlap
So what we want to do today is
I use gravity
I can observe the darker
Sub-millimeter
Sub-millimeter galaxies
This red line and this red line
Basically correspond
I have gravity
I want to let the curve on the right
Extend to the left
Is to extend my sub-millimeter sample
Let my sub-millimeter sample
With these visible light observed samples
Can overlap
Then after the overlap
The most important thing comes
I
I have observed
After this sub-millimeter sample
The question I want to ask is
In this place
I put this sample to the left
My sub-millimeter galaxy
In this place
Is it these
These visible light
Can see the galaxy
Are they the same thing?
Or is it completely different?
Part is the same, part is the same
Part is the same, part is different
This thing is very important, why?
Because we are
Establish, we are measuring our universe
Star formation history
I just said that there are two populations in the universe
These two populations are very important
One is directly observed by visible light
One is to use long-wave long-wave red light
These two samples
We can measure their
Star formation history contribution to our universe
OK
Both are important
Because there are two populations
We have to combine them together
Is the total star formation in our universe
OK
Then we can draw
The picture I just drew in the first page
Is the star formation history of the universe
We have to put these two observations
Combine together
But today
When we extend the sub-minimum sample here
Then we have to know
Are these sub-minimum samples
These sub-minimum samples
These sub-minimum galaxies
Is it already
Included in these samples
Right
In case we observe
We extend this sample here
Then in case these sub-minimum galaxies
In this place
Sub-minimum galaxies
Already included in these UV
These visible light samples
Then we just
We don't have to do it anymore
Because there is no need to
Study those darker sub-minimum galaxies
Because those darker sub-minimum galaxies
Basically it's you
Those galaxies selected by visible light
It's the same thing
Why do we have to go to Africa
To use more difficult
Long-wave long-wave observation to study them
Because it's the same thing
In fact
On the contrary
In case these sub-minimum galaxies
In this part of the sub-minimum galaxies
Not all
Already included in this sample
Then we have to know
OK
How many fractions are already included in it
How many fractions are not included
That is to say
We want to know how many fractions
In this part of the sub-minimum galaxy
We can directly see the visible light
How much is still visible
Still can't see
We have this information
After we quantize it
We can accurately put
This UV sample
The visible light sample
Contribute to the star formation
And our sub-minimum sample
Add them up
Because if these two samples today
Are completely independent
Then just add them up
When they overlap
This part may not be completely independent
But it may not be completely dependent
So we have to know
How many fractions are overlapping
How many sub-minimum sources
It is actually also in the UV
Will see
This is why
Study the darker sub-minimum galaxy
Very important
We want to know
How many of them
Already included in the rest-frame UV sample
So we can accurately
To measure
The star formation of our entire universe
Another important reason is
Because we found
In the past, these sub-minimum galaxies
Hello
I have a question
Can't hear
My question is
If you put them
Extend
I use typing
You can talk while typing
Because after typing, I have to quit to see
Can you hear me
Hello
Sorry
I accidentally pressed you to leave
So you're back
Yes
My question is
Can you hear me
If you extend
If it's different
You know it's different
But if you extend and overlap
How do you know it's the same
Maybe it's still different
The so-called difference means
Suppose I detect
Some darker
Sub-minimum galaxies
I detect some darker
Their star formation rate
Can you hear me
I detect some darker
Sub-minimum galaxies
Their star formation rate
What I want to do is
Very simple
Like this
What I want to do is very simple
Suppose I have a sub-minimum galaxy
Darker than this
Then I use the interferometer
To accurately measure its position
Then I go to the visible wave field
That is the Hubble telescope
Or other telescope
To find out if it corresponds to
The visible counterpart
When you have a visible counterpart
And it's a very obvious counterpart
It means
It is
It is this kind of galaxy
It is the galaxy found in the visible wave field
On the contrary, if you
Basically
This kind of galaxy
If you find it has a visible emission
It means
It is this kind of galaxy
I'm talking about
Statistically
Not a galaxy
I'm not talking about
A sub-minimum galaxy
Is it a galaxy in a paper
I'm talking about
Statistically
Can a sub-minimum galaxy
Do you know what I mean?
So what you have to do is very simple
You use the interferometer to accurately measure
The position of a sub-minimum
Then we go to the visible beam
To see if it emits light
Or if it is completely non-existent
That's it
I want to ask
I see
I understand
I may have missed it
So in this way
The visible and non-visible light emitted by a star
The brightness of these two lights
There is no certain relationship
The so-called non-visible light
Is the sub-minimum we talked about
It's actually a little bit
I'll talk about it later
Usually
It should be related
Of course
Because
Because it's with your
The amount of dust in the galaxy
Does it matter?
How much dust
It's related, right?
I'll talk about it later
Others are studying
A lower shift galaxy
I'll talk about it later
I'll continue
I hope I've convinced you
Why I'm studying the sub-minimum galaxy
Two things
I haven't talked about the second thing
The first thing is what I asked
The second thing is
The previous astronomers found
The bright sub-minimum galaxies
The brightness is brighter than the two-minimum galaxies
They are all very dusty
Very intense star forming galaxies
They are all very dusty very intense star forming galaxies
The green star forming galaxies
They are all very dusty
very intense star forming galaxies
These sub-minimum galaxies
They are all major mergers
They are conglomerates
You can look up
The answer
The answer is SMG
I forgot to mention
The darker stars are SMG
Are these also major mergers?
Or are they conglomerates?
They are not intense
Not major mergers
They are isolated disks
These star formation data
are not major mergers
They are simple spiral galaxies
...
They are not that intense
so their star formation rate is not that high
...