Can you see me now?
Ok
Can you see my screen now?
Yes?
Yes, yes, yes
I will turn off my camera
So it will be smoother
Ok
Let me tell you
There are two more people here
One is here
One is over there
The camera may not be able to see
There are three people here
If they have any questions
Don't be surprised if they are real people
Sorry
There were some microphone issues
That's why we are delaying
The topic I am going to talk about
looks a bit
difficult to understand
Functional connectivity and dynamics
and burn organization
In short
The main purpose of my research
is to look at the functional connections
between neural networks
The so-called functional connections
are the neural signals
generated by neurons
during activation
How these neural signals
are transmitted between different brains
This is the main thing
I am going to talk about today
I will divide it into two parts
The first part is introduction
Introduction is a general
background idea
If you are not a neurologist
You need to know something
to make it easier for us to explain
This is one of the main research
The second part is
the current message
It is about a
special project
The last part is all about that project
The first part is
a little bit
scientific
The second part is more about
that research
I have seen
the comments
Some people are just
talking about science
So I want to talk about
what is neuroscience
I have seen
on the internet
Neuroscience is a
comprehensive research
It includes chemistry,
medicine, physiology, medicine
even computer science and engineering
There are a lot of subjects
From the perspective of
modern neuroscience
There are
cells
and neurons
If you
enlarge the scale
There are cognitive science
and behavioral science
Finally, there is transfer medicine
It is to apply the research
in the lab to clinical
If you want to
There are micro scale,
mesoscale and macroscale
The last part is
about the research
The first part is
between neurons
The research topic is
Let me correct
The first part is
about single neurons
The second part is
between neurons
The last part is
The biggest part
is what I have done
At the same time
What I have done
will cover the last part
I will use
a simple sentence
It is about
neural connectivity
You will hear
functional connectivity
It is about
the connectivity
of neurons
There is another point
We want to see
the connection of
human behavior
For example,
their behavior
in clinical
or in cognitive science
I will talk about
functional connectivity later
Some people
have studied
psychology or
cognitive science
They have heard about
some theories
I will give you examples
The left one is
Localization
Scientists
are studying
brain function
or human behavior
They want to
find out which part of the brain
is responsible for which function
This is a result of
FMRI
You can see
the three colored areas
This means that
when the subject is doing something
the neurons in these three areas are active
This is a more
traditional theory
They think
they need to
classify
which part of the brain
is responsible for which function
Another one is called
Distributed Brain Network
These two schools
have been fighting for a long time
But recently
because of some new research methods
Most people think
this is more like the human brain we expect
In this new school
their focus
is not on studying
a single brain area
but on the functionalities of the brain areas
This yellow arrow
For example, this brain area
may send a message to this area
and this area
So the brain area
receives feedback
and sends the signal
to this area
The picture on the right
is more like what I am doing now
This is the so-called
Functional Connectivity
So how do we
study it?
How can we measure
the so-called Functional Connectivity?
In statistics
or basic definition
Functional Connectivity
is like
describing two brain areas
or two different areas
in the same area
For example,
the picture on the right
is a brain
Let's say there are three areas
we call region of interest
1, 2, 3, 3
The blue, red, and green lines
refer to
the time course
I am using the example of FMRI
This is the signal change
caused by the activation of neurons
We use these signals
as the basic research
It's a bit like the ingredients
of cooking
After you get these things
you start to use different methods
to see the relationship between them
Of course, you don't have to use FMRI
You can use many different machines
For example, the EEG of the brain
or the MEG of the brain
But I am using FMRI
for my research
So any so-called Functional Connectivity
based on FMRI
We call it
time course or time series
We use this data to do the research
Let's say you have three areas
of interest
The first thing you need to do
is to extract their signals
Then
what you need to do is
to use different methods
to calculate the relationship
between two brain areas
The most common is
Pairwise Correlation
If you use Pairwise Correlation
you will see a lot of values
For example
This is the relationship
between RI2 and RI1
If they are positive
For example, this is
about 0.5
This means that
this area and this area
are connected
Don't look at the
diagonal one
It means that
they are connected
But this is not a normal situation
This is because we are calculating
So usually after we calculate
and get this evidence
We will force the diagonal line
to become 0
This is mainly
the way we use
Of course, in this part
you shouldn't use Pairwise Correlation
Many people use different methods
For example, Partial Correlation
There are many ways to use
It doesn't mean which method is better
It depends on
what you want to observe
After that
After we get
this evidence
we will be curious
what we are going to do next
Many people
find a big problem
There are too many signals
and too much information
So
what I'm going to talk about next
is to use some new methods
so that you
can
report some data
to let everyone know
how different these numbers
represent the whole matrix
Wait a minute
Ok
So just now we have
got the evidence
What I'm going to talk about
today is
Graph Theory
and Dynamic Functional Connectivity
Sorry
Let me interrupt
Ok
I just want to tell you
If you have any questions
you can
put them in the chat
and I will
find the time to ask
Or if you have any questions
you can also ask
and I will answer
the questions
I can't see the chat
so I don't know what you are asking
If you have any questions
you can ask
Ok
Before we talk about Graph Theory
do you have any questions?
If not, let's continue
Here we have a little bit
of abstract
I will try my best
If you have any questions
we can continue later
If you have studied Maths
you will know that Graph Theory
is a part of Maths
Its purpose is
to describe the relationship
between two points
In Neuroscience
Graph Theory is a good tool
In Graph Theory
you can get a lot of different values
Each value
represents a feature of the network
For example
we will talk about
some different values later
Some values may represent
how well the signal is integrated
in the brain
or how well it is integrated
in a single system
So there will be some different messages
When you are doing
Graph Theory
there are two important things
that you must get
The first one is Node
The other one is Edge
Node is the region of interest
On the right side
this is the information
of the actual recipient
I have 36 RIs
so there are 36 brain areas
Usually we put the left brain area
in the front
and the right brain area
in the back
So this whole matrix
represents the relationship
between each of the 36 brain areas
The so-called edge
is the connectivity matrix
which is this
Usually we get this matrix
which is the one you saw before
The one above this threshold
we think it actually has a connection
The one below this threshold
we force it to become 0
We don't look at these connections
We think it is weaker
maybe because of some miscommunication
So with these two files
you can run Graph Theory
This is what we talked about
at the beginning
When you run Graph Theory
you can get a lot of different values
which represent a certain specialness on the Internet
With these values
you can get to know the Internet better
and you can also report
the differences between different things
For example, there are two groups
One is patient and the other is normal person
and you get this matrix
but if you just show this matrix to everyone
and say that the patient's matrix looks like this
and the normal person's matrix looks like this
But this matrix has too much information
It's hard for you to
find out which side is wrong
or which side is different
So if you use graph theory
you can report a number
For example, how good is the overall information of the brain
Then the number of patients may be lower
or the number of normal people will be higher
This is one of the benefits of using graph theory
So below
This is an example
That is, what kind of value do we have?
Here you can see different colors
The green part is the so-called integration
If you have this value
It represents integration
It means that the signal
How well is it integrated in the brain
Then the blue one
It's called segregation
It's a bit like two different things
It means that in a single system
In a single system
how good the information is integrated
because you can see
If this is a system
This is another system
So-called integration is the relationship between the system and the system
The yellow one is called loco majors
If you have 100 RIs
Then you will have 100 numbers
Each number represents this characteristic RI
The red one is called centrality
In short, this is the importance of this point
These two
They are the same
If you have wrong graph theory today
A matrix will have several different numbers
Suppose it has 36 RIs
So, this half side
is a matrix, only one number
no matter how many RIs it has
Also, there is a black one here, called Hubs
as in the middle
In the end, there will fastly be one
About Hubs
In short, you can have a lot
It's a bit like
connecting different systems
For example, this is a system
Here is another system
You may find signals fromone system to another
So the importance of Hubs becomes very important
Its role is like connecting different systems
There is a picture at the end
We will briefly introduce
the Hubs that are recognized so far
Here is the graph theory part
Next, this is called Dynamic Functional Converting Team
This is a bit newer
This is about 5 or 6 years
It's been about 4 or 5 years
More people are researching
We have already mentioned that
You can get a reference
This reference represents
the relationship between different RIs
In the early days
Because this reference
It's the same in time
It won't change
But with a new method
You will find that it is constantly changing
The brain is not a stable system
It keeps changing
It's called non-stationary
This functional connectivity pattern
It continues to change
The time is about a few seconds to a few minutes
From 26 seconds to 86 seconds
Its reference looks like this
From 26 seconds to 162 seconds
It will look different
This is more than 400 seconds
If you don't care about the time difference
If you have less than 5 minutes
This is the average time difference
It looks like this
But you can find that they are all different
In addition to the difference in time difference
If you use the wrong graph theory
You will find that there are many points
Originally there is a connection
But at a certain point in time
There is no connection
For example, the first one is the visual area
At this point in time
It has a connection with the other two RIs
But you will find here
It has a connection with more RIs
This is completely gone
So you can know
It continues to change
Time and space are different
Here is the relationship of time
Here is the relationship of space
Here is a video
You can see that it continues to change at different points in time
So this graph is not fixed
It keeps changing
This is 300 seconds
The duration is more than 300 seconds
So you can see
At this point
There is a connection between the two ris
But it disappeared when we go to the next time
We can prove that
Functional connectivity continues to change
Why should we study this
What are the advantages
Some people have done research before
Sorry
It's because the flow of function connectivity
It's very much related to the human cognition
For example
Some people use cognitive features
and invite the objects
they ask them to do
Work in memory taste
when the brain of manabla
their functional connectivity
is constantly changing
and when fuctional connectivity
become bigger
the performance of the host is getting better and better
So this is a piece of evidence
that tells us
Functional connectivity is constantly changing
and this change is actually
very much related to human cognition
In addition to the host doing things
When humans are resting
You can also observe
Functional connectivity is constantly changing
This is actually a bit like
the experiment I'm going to talk about
Because when I'm doing experiments
My data is mainly resting
And then
Next is
Okay, so far
I want to ask if there are any questions
Because the next one is for a specific experiment
Background
Hello
Yes, I heard
Hello, I would like to ask
If you imagine each node as a time series
Then the picture in front of you
Its edge is a direction
That thing should not be calculated by Pearson Correlation
Which one
You mean this one or the one in front
The part of the graph theory in front
It's like this direction in the brain
How do you get it
Oh yes
In the front
There is a picture of how we get the evidence
There is a place to tell you
Basically if you use
Pairwise Correlation
There is no so-called direction
But if you use other
For example, there is a so-called Bayesian Network
If you use that method
You can get the so-called
Relation
You see this one on the right
This curve is actually symmetrical
Because the method I use is Partial Correlation
With Simple Correlation
So here you can't see any relation
But if I use today
For example
Bayesian Model Network
It will tell you that I have two
RIE and RIE2
The relationship between them
Is it from 1 to 2 or 2 to 1
If you use Bayesian
You can get this information
But the one I use today
I can't tell you the relation
So it becomes
It depends on how you get the evidence
It will tell you
You are
In fact, there is also this
Your evidence
Can be used
There is directionality
There is no directionality
You can also use weighted or unweighted
That is
Each value represents a different strength
Or you can also turn it into
A binary matrix
There is only 1 and 0
1 means it is not connected
0 means it is not connected
Any other questions
Then I will continue
Okay, next one
It's more about
The experiment I'm going to talk about
Because I'm actually now
In
Our lab
There is a called
Pacific Parkinson's Research Center
So our
Most of the subjects are
Patients with Parkinson's
And some normal control
What we are mainly talking about
Is whether we can
Use functional connectivity
To find the so-called biological indicator
We call it biomarker
If we can find this biomarker
The first one is
Can increase the diagnosis rate
If you don't know
How sick this person is
You can scan his brain
Then use this method
You can roughly classify
Is he very serious
For example, today
There is a person
The diagnosis is early
But you want to know
For example, after 10 years or 5 years
How is his condition
Do we need to take some preventive measures
If we have this kind of information
We can also predict
What will happen in 5 or 10 years
In short
Because there were a lot of research
Also using
Racine state fMRI
These studies have reported
Whether you are using graph theory
Or so-called dynamic functional connectivity
You can find
Some differences between patients and normal people
These patients
Not just limited to
Parkinson's
For example, Alzheimer's
Or some depression
Or bipolar disorder, etc.
So what we mainly see today
Is if
We are purely talking about Parkinson's disease
Can we use
Racine state functional connectivity
Find a so-called biomarker
Before that, there are two important
Concepts to introduce first
Brain organization and dynamic functional connectivity
So actually this
I have talked about the previous background
Brain organization
You use graph theory
Then get a lot of numbers
Different numbers
Will represent different network features
These features
Also represent
So-called brain organization
There are two points here
For example, there are two principles
The first one is
Functional integration
It means to look at the message
Neural network message
In the whole system
Then the other one is
Functional segregation
In a single system
In fact, we can say
The human brain is in
A balance between segregation and integration
It's not all integration
But it won't
It's all segregation
Then I think
If you are doing
For example, when you are doing
Higher-level work
You need integration
Because you have different areas of the brain
To cooperate with each other
To complete this work
If you do it very simply
For example, I just need to reach out and get a drink
This action may be
Simpler, not too much effort
Then it's more like segregation
So we will say
This is the balance between these two things
The other one is the dynamic functional connectivity
We usually
We all say
We will use the so-called time-varying method
To measure dynamic functional connectivity
This method
There are many different
Different methods
One of the methods I will talk about later is called sliding window
It is one of the many different methods
Then that method is
So far
Most commonly used
Just like we just said
Because the brain is not a stationary system
So you need to know
How does it change in time?
Then in our research today
Do you want
The most interesting thing is to know
How does the brain connect with the disease?
How does the brain connect with cognitive functions?
Here is
The main method of this experiment
Let me adjust
it
There are a lot of parameters
This is a simple experiment
We have 10
There are 12
This is their
Demographic
Because
PD patients are usually
Old
More than 55 years old
Older people are more likely to have this disease
And
There are more male patients
So I usually see PD patients
It is not surprising that there are more male patients
And then
UBTRS
This thing
It's a bit like
From nature
The indicator of the disease
If this indicator is higher, it means that this patient
More serious
It's actually a bit like
Bigger
We actually
After this, we can divide it into
Many different indicators
Each indicator represents a certain
Symptoms
This means
How slow is the patient's action
Trauma
Tremor
Rigidity
PIGT
Postural Instability
And Gay Disorder
It means
His balance is not very good
Coordination between actions
HNY
This is another
If you want to know
This patient
How serious
Stage 2 to 5
2.5 is mild
Not very serious
The most serious is 5 to 6
That's more serious
Usually when we do the experiment
We need someone to cooperate
So we all follow the mild patient
About 2 to 3
And disease duration
How many days have they changed
This is their
Out of a dosage
Some people will
Do research on drugs
We usually record
Their condition
This is called apathy
It actually describes
Many patients with Parkinson's
They lost their usual mood
Become a couch potato
Don't want to do anything
Can't do anything
We call this condition apathy
Another one is depression
Although it is not
Mental disorder
It will cause depression
Or anxiety
We all record
The last one is
Montreal Cognitive Assessment
The main purpose is to measure
Their cognitive function
These are all the clinical data
What we will do later
Is to use
Graph theory
And dynamic function
To measure
Their
Function
And try to
Compare this function
With the clinical data
To see which data
Is related to their brain
I think
Let's talk about
Parkinson's disease
We call it
Neurodegeneration disease
It is caused by
Neurodegeneration
What is neurodegeneration
Dopamine depletion
It is caused by
Neurodegeneration
So
There is not enough dopamine
In the brain
Dopamine is a very important neurotransmitter
Without this substance
There will be a lot of behavior
Can't work normally
And so on
Where is this dopamine
There is a place called
Substantial Nigra
It will be here
The black part
In the middle of the brain
In a deep place
If you zoom in
It looks like this
This is a normal person's
Substantial Nigra
You can see the black part
Latin means black
This is the place where dopamine is produced
This is the patient
You can see the black part
There is not much black
It means
The patient who produces dopamine is dead
So there is not much
Dopamine
The main symptoms
You can see resting tremor
If you tell them to relax
It will move
Even his shoulder blades will move
Brachycardia is very slow
For example, he walks very slowly
Take things
The whole action is not very slow
Rigidity is stiff
We usually bend our hands
Then we will lose strength
Then they bend back
In this process
You can feel that his action is very stiff
Then the other side
Postural problem
There will be problems with their balance
Many patients will fall easily
The body is also very uncoordinated
In addition, in recent years
Many people are very interested in
Non-motor symptoms
In addition to these
There are also some
Not so related to exercise
Not so related to action
For example
If you have seen
I forgot if it was science or nature
General scientific reports
They mentioned
Many people think Parkinson's disease
Has a lot to do with gastrointestinal diseases
There are many, many patients
Complaining about gastrointestinal diseases
Many people
Many patients
Complaining about gastrointestinal diseases
So there is also a vote
Researchers are now studying
Related to gastrointestinal diseases and Parkinson's disease
I am more interested in
cognitive functions
Although they
The main problem you see
Is action
But their cognitive functions
Changed a lot
The most obvious is
Concentration and execution
If you ask them to do
Very simple cognitive tasks
They can do very well
But if you ask them to do very complicated
Need to keep switching
Method
They are easy to fail
So this is a
Proof
Their cognitive functions
There is a little degradation
As for the data I used
Resistive Function MRI
A total of 8 minutes
Then I
There is one here
Tell you
How do we do the experiment
What is the so-called data
This picture is MRI
You see
MRI machine
Usually we ask the patient to lie on the examination bed
Then the doctor will put
In the middle, this is a button
Search for them
Then the bed will rise
Send the patient to the center of the entire machine
Because the magnetic field in the middle is more stable
Then we started
Scan
One thing you need to say
MRI's noise is very loud
So we will give the patient
Earplugs
Protect their hearing
Because it is a magnetic field
So there can be no metal on the body
For example, keys, wallets, rings
All have to be taken down
Including women's underwear
So for the time being
How to change clothes
Then this is the file
The image we got
In principle
We will scan two images
The most basic
One is called T1 Weighted Imaging
This is to provide you a structural image
You can see it clearly
This image will tell you where the brain is
Gray is gray
White is white
The empty place in the middle
There is water
Brain
These two are eyeballs
The middle is the air
This image provides you a very clear
Information on the structure
In addition, we will scan the functional imaging
We call Bolt Signal
Here is written
This image is physical
If you don't deal with it, you can't see anything
You can only see the middle
CSF
Next to it
You can't clearly define the brain
Gray and white
So when we analyze
The point is to analyze this image
Ok
Because actually
The principle of FMI is quite complicated
This is what I have found so far
I have seen the simplest and most powerful
A picture can be introduced to everyone
CSF is in
When the nervous system is active
It needs oxygen, oxygen and blood
So here is
Now the nervous system is active
The blood vessels near the nervous system
Start to increase blood flow
Fresh blood
To this place
So here you will find
A lot of fresh blood
Because oxygen needs to enter the nervous system
Fresh blood will come
There are a lot of different
There are a lot of new oxygen here
Then in
Exhaustive blood vessels
When interchanging
It will produce a signal
We can produce a signal
Because MRI is
Strong magnetic field
We used to learn that Faraday's law
Magnetic field
Because of the change in magnetic field
It will produce an electric signal
Will be just
Receive the electric signal
After that, it will go through a lot of
Different image processing
You will get it
You will see this image
In addition
Exhaustive and
Exhaustive blood vessels and
The imbalance of the oxygen blood vessels
Will cause the signal
So
The picture we just talked about
The so-called Tom Cruise
Is this thing
After we get this thing
We can start the follow-up analysis
Of course the story is not that simple
Because from you get the signal
You can analyze
There are a lot of things to do
To correct the difference in time
To correct the difference in space
Sometimes it may shake your head
You can't just take his data
You have to correct these things first
These things we call preprocessing
I didn't talk too much today
Just let you know
The difference in time and space
The focus part will be
How do you analyze them
Wait a minute
Is there any
Image acquisition
Can i ask a question
Is there any problem with the scene
Is the scene
Did you get this picture
You got this picture
Then you turn it like this
Then you use
Turn it into this picture
After sending this picture in
Then he will give you this
His
Regional interest
You have to set a few points on the picture
Then he will find it
How do you know
He asked you
If we get this picture
To this side
Basically how to get there
Because I omitted a lot of things
So
I'll talk about it now
If we do it in our lab
We will get this T1 and Bolt signal
Then we will throw T1
To a software called FreeSurfer
The purpose is to do so-called
That's why I got those
RIERR333
We take this T1
We put each brain area
Label up
Give him an ID
Then we put this at the same time
The image obtained by FMI
To do the pre-processing
After the pre-processing
We want to put this T1 with the label
Two FMI in place
Because they say
The subject's head won't move too much
But we still have to put these two images in place
To make sure
The one we see
For example, the area seen on T1
On FMI
Is the same area
So this is very important
When we put T1 and FMI in place
We told the computer
Let's define a few RIERR333
From T1
If there are 100
I told the computer
I want 90
All listed
There is a step called
Time course extraction
After we put these two in place
I said these 90 RIERR333
You go get their time course
For example, the first RIERR333
Here
I'll take his time course
Take it out
Then the second RIERR333
I'll take his
Just like this
How big is that RIERR333
How big can it be
Actually this depends on you
How to do cortical postulation
Basically
This
The resolution is 1x1x1mm
If there is
Some areas will be bigger
For example, if you have a prefrontal cortex
It's a big piece
If you want a very small one
Anterior cingulate cortex will be smaller
So that doesn't necessarily depend on your brain area
What do you usually decide
Ha ha ha
This is a very tricky question
If you look at this area
There is no change at all
It's in another area
So now most people
Tend to use
It's a bit like watching you do postulation
How many brain areas do you have
Usually
At least
There should be more than 90
I know there are more than 100 in FreeSurfer
A lot of people take out more than 100 brain areas
Because he doesn't know which one he wants to see
Just take out all the brain areas
Take out all the information
Some people are very specific
They assume
Which brain area has a special relationship with which brain area
They want to see
They will have a purpose
Select those brain areas first
But indeed
At the beginning, when I was writing articles
You write articles
The question that often comes back is why do you choose these brain areas
Ha ha ha
So now people
Because I think it's a bit of a avoidance
Plus you really don't know
Where is the change
All brain areas
Ha ha ha
In fact
It should be said that we already have
Different software and different
So-called templates
You will get different brain areas
In fact, this is indeed
There is a big problem in doing imaging
Generally speaking
My answer will be
You will
We will have a defined brain area
For example, you are doing free surfer
You must know
In FreeSurfer
The brain areas in that list
We want these
There is another one called AAL
Another template
In another software
If you say this is AAL template
We probably know what brain areas
In principle
I don't think they are too different
But there is a vote of people
People who specialize in so-called postulation
They will tell you which one
Different templates will have different
Disadvantages
Last year
I don't know if you have seen that report
There was a paper last year
Nature
There is a Human Connectome Project in the United States
They are a few thousand less
Then they
Use the information of those thousands of people
And at the same time it also includes
Different modalities
For example, MIT1 image has functional images
There is also T2
Or Proton Density Modeling
Many different images
All modalities are put together
Use all these modalities
To build another template
Then I remember
More than 100 brain areas than we currently know
More than 200
So this becomes
How do you define your brain area
It's a bit tricky
At present we can only say
Which template you use
Or which software you use
We probably know what your so-called brain areas are
Any other questions?
For example
For example, that area
If you have big or small
You can set big or small
For example, when you are small
Its signal is very strong
But when you have a large area
You have to remove the signal
Actually there is
I always don't believe
For example, there are some things in the brain area
Its signal is very, very bad
Because it happens to be interconnected with the air
You can see here
There is still a brain area here
This is the prefrontal cortex
But it is already close to the sinus
So it's very close to this place
It looks okay in T1
But in FMR, you can see it's super bad
Half of the frontal area is gone
For example, in the frontal area
Some very small areas
Such as the frontal pole
That area is very small and close to the air
So its FMR signal is super bad
I usually
My approach is
I don't want to look at that area
If your signal is already very bad
You see it again
What do you say
This is because
It's caused by the difference in FMR
Or is it because your own signal is bad
So my approach is
Put those too small areas
Or in that kind of signal
I don't want those areas
Is there any
Is there any area
Where the signal is bad
Frontal
The area closest to the frontal
Because it's too close to the air
There will be a so-called partial volume effect
If you look at this picture
The signal is bad in the front area
And then there is the orbital frontal cortex
This is close to the nasal cavity
There is a lot of air there, so the signal is bad
And then the other place is the temporal pole
Just a little bit in front of the temporal
And then there is the inferior temporal cortex
At the very bottom of the temporal
Because it's already close to the skull base
So those places
I usually see
If you actually see it
The whole information sharing
If you find that there is an important change
If it's there, I'll be a little hesitant
Then go back and see if my image blurring is good
Decide again
Do I believe him
Is there anything else
Ok let's go next
Ok this is a bit
Be a little patient
Because this is a bit
It's the background I just talked about
Background for this experiment
Now I'm going to talk about
The method used for this experiment
Then you will see
The first thing I want to talk about is
Dynamic Functional Connectivity
I use sliding window
This blue is the so-called fMRI time core
That's what we've been talking about
The most important thing when doing sliding window
The first step is that you have to define
Your so-called window length
How big is your window
I use 20 time points here
That is to say
I only include
The first 20 time points
Then I do
Correlation, I use Pearson's correlation here
Then I will get a metric
This metric means
I have 54
hri
Is the relationship between these 54 hri
After finishing here
I will move my window forward
Do the same thing
You will get the second metric
How long does a time point usually last
It depends on your MRI
Scanning parameters
We have two seconds here
Then you keep doing the same thing
Until you finish
All the fMRI time cores
After that, I have a total of
221 window correlation metrics
Then the next
One important thing is
I got so many metrics
Each one is not the same
How do I report
What is their variability
Here we calculate 7
I call it network feature
According to these
According to these metrics
I calculate some numbers
Each number represents
Variability
For example, the first one I call it
Network variation
The first one is very simple
We want to see the overall variability
The first one and the second
Correlation metrics
Take all the numbers and subtract them
Then for each
221 metrics
Do the same thing on average
So the numbers we get
It's a bit like
On average
The variability of your entire brain
Then the second
Network power
This is actually very simple
It mainly adds all the
On average
The purpose of this is to get
It's a bit like on average
The strength of your connectivity
Then here
These are very similar from C to G and A
But the difference is
A is measuring the whole brain
All numbers
All elements in this metric
But C to D
C to G is
For specific
For example, this is called
We only calculate
The connection between the opposite brain areas
Then
This is
Then this is
Same on the same side
Then divide it here
On the left and on the right
So you can see that the math
Actually quite similar
But when we count C to G
The value we get is
For example, when we count C
We take the right angle
Because the right angle represents
Connectivity from left to right
Then
Here is the sliding window
That's it
The other graph theory
I made it more fancy here
I have a little bit
The graph theory and the sliding window
Combined together
So in the front you will find that it is exactly the same as the sliding window
Until this step
All the same
The difference is that when I got this metric
I didn't just add or subtract it
Do some processing to calculate
The so-called network feature
Instead, I first apply a threshold
Above a certain threshold
I determine that these connections are real connections
Under this threshold
It's not, it's an imprecision
Then I put this
Thresholded edges
There is something called
Brain Connectivity Toolbox
This is a free download on the Internet
You can run it with MATLAB
After I throw it into the graph theory
Every window I will get two
Global Feature Measure
And a Local Measure
In fact, you can get more
I just use these three for the time being
The so-called Global Measure is
There will be a number for each indicator
Local Measure is
See how many RRI it has
How many numbers
After all done
I will have 221 stats
Then there are three numbers for each window
This is a bit complicated
But in a nutshell
I got a lot of different numbers
Or the so-called network features
Then the point is to see
Between patient and normal control
What's the difference
Then the next one
it is good
In fact, this is a bit
Is there a problem
It's okay, I want to ask this one
You can continue to talk
Don't ignore me
After the analysis of the RRI
We got the so-called
These are the numbers
When using the sliding window
We will get the power
The other
Specific connection
This is inter-hemisphere
Then here is cross-hemisphere
And in the same brain
The same brain
Then there is left and right
The so-called flexibility
In fact, we take the correlation value
The correlation value of two windows
Two minus and then equal
So
In the sliding window value
If the value is higher
It means its connectivity is more dynamic
The more mutable
Then dynamic graphical approach
Is what we just talked about
Combined graph theory and sliding window
It's the same global feature
I have two
One is global efficiency
The other is modularity
It may be difficult to explain here
I can't explain
If you don't know
You may need to check
I will show you a paper later
There may be a complete
It's easier to understand
In short, global efficiency
The way it is calculated
The shortest distance between these two points
Make them equal
Do the math
Then equal
This global efficiency represents
Information
The information of the neural network
In the whole brain
How well it is integrated
So it is also
An indicator of integration
Modularity is just the opposite
It is an indicator of segregation
Modularity is actually
Under this network
Will this network be
Will it be divided into
Several different
Small networks
Then it is
An indicator of segregation
This means
If the modularity value is higher
It means
In a single system
Will be better integrated
These two points are the opposite
Integration and segregation
Then another local measure
Betweenness centrality
This is the brain area
This RRI
How important it is in the whole network
That is to see
How many
The shortest path
Through this
This RRI
If this number is higher
It means that this brain area is more important
It may be the hubs we just talked about
After having these numbers
The first thing we do is
See the difference between the patient and the PD
See if there is any difference
In addition, these numbers
Do a linear regression with clinical indicators
See what happens
Then the next one
it is good
I have to go to the bathroom
This is the result
I can tell you
If you just do a two-sample t-test
I can't see any difference
Between the patient and the normal person
Those numbers are completely the same
But when we do simple
Peterson's correlation
You can find
This is the result of sliding window
Dynamic connectivity
You can find
Let's look at the above two
Age and network power
And I put a small picture
You can know which connection it is
Inter-dimensional connectivity is related
But I can tell you
I think this is more like
Normal human aging will occur
Because I see this on Parkinson's patients
But I also see it on normal people
So this one
We won't do so much discussion for the time being
But the more interesting thing is this
This is the postural instability
Gait disorder
That is, the number of their balance and body coordination
With
On the right
This is the right
Dynamic functional connectivity
Related to them
That is to say, the more serious the patient
His right connectivity
The harder it is
Can't change
Then this is the dose of the drug
It's the same
When the drug dose is higher
They are also with
This one
This connectivity is also more rigid
You can find
If it's based on these two relationships
We can roughly think
Parkinson's disease
Their
Connectivity is not so dynamic
More rigid
In addition, because this is just
Simple correlation
We want to do postural correlation
Is to remove some
Effect
For example, age
If our condition for age is
We remove the age
If we do correlation again
In fact, you will find that only this value
Related
The same thing is significant
Only this value
With these dynamic features
Related
Then next
This is what I just said
Dynamic
Graphical features
Graph theory and dynamics
Generally
Red is PD
Blue is normal control
You can find that PD patients
Generally
Higher global efficiency
This number also represents
Signal
How well the whole brain is integrated
You will find that overall
In fact, they are better than the patient
This is a bit
Make people feel
Why is the patient better
In fact, we think
This is the so-called compensator effect
Because
We just said
Because the patient's brain
Their connectivity is more rigid
Because it is more rigid
So they become the existing
Connectivity needs to be better integrated
To maintain normal brain function
Then next
This is the so-called local measure
That is, each subject
There are several numbers
Depends on how many RRI
Each RRI will give you a number
Because I am here
Do dynamic graph theory
So you can see that there are several different windows
Generally you can see
These brain areas
PD and normal control
There are significant differences
Brain area
A bit small
Blue is normal
Red is PD
Normal people
Most of them will show higher
Centrality
It means
These brain areas
Parkinson's patients
Become less important
Because between the centrality
This brain area
How important
You can find that all of these
Relatively low
Then there are significant differences
It is worth mentioning
The red one
They are called cortical hubs
Blue
The so-called cortical hubs
So that's why
I may have to jump out
Tell you what hubs are
The so-called hubs are actually
It's important
We are talking about
If you are from Vancouver today
Where we are now
If you want to travel to Hamburg, Germany
You have two options
For example, this is Hansa Airlines
You can take a plane to the most
The simplest
This is Zurich
Frankfurt or Munich
You transfer from there
Just turn once and you can go to Hamburg
Then the one below is
Airbus
If you take off from Vancouver
It's a bit small
But it's also Zurich
Frankfurt and Munich
You can go to Hamburg
In this case
Zurich, Munich and Frankfurt
The so-called hubs
On the plane
It's the so-called hubs
Because they have more
They have more different
Airways
Can go to different cities
Similarly
There are so-called hubs in the human brain
Here on the right
You can see
All of these points are cortical hubs
According to
Previous research
Then the yellow one
Functional hubs
In fMRI or other functional images
Hubs obtained
The red one
Functional and structural
In functional studies
You will see
Structural studies
Structural images can also be seen
The bigger one
Rich club
These big hubs
Between each other
Stronger
More links
The point is to tell everyone
These hubs
Play an important role in the entire brain network
Because they have to
Like a logistics center
It has to distribute these messages
Then direct them to
The destination they need to reach
Then we slightly
Functional hubs and structural hubs
What's the difference
Someone here asked
If I use fMRI today
Graph theory
I can find hubs
Functional hubs
If I use
Structural images
Diffusion-weighted imaging
Or
DWI or DSI
Structural images
Hubs obtained
Structural hubs
The main difference is
One uses fMRI
Why
They are different
I asked someone
The researcher told me
His own suspicion is
fMRI
Very indirect measurement
The signal may contain
A lot of impurities
Blood vessels, breathing, heartbeats
He personally doubts
The signal in fMRI is too impure
So it will cause
Your hubs to be different
Hubs
Left and right symmetry
Another question
Hubs are left and right symmetry
Most of us think
For example
This is
Superior frontal cortex
They are symmetry
If you find the left
The area on the right will also be hubs
But there may be a little
Slightly different
The left may be less obvious
But we think hubs are symmetry
So which hub
Will connect
The other question is
Which hub will connect
So far
We think this big
Rich club
There is a thing called rich club
Organization
These hubs
Can be called super hubs
Very powerful
So many different
So in these big hubs
They form another
Powerful network
So this is what we call
There will be interconnection
Can
Another last thing
I want to tell you
We can go back a little
We just mentioned here
The red ones are all hubs
Insula, Precuneus
Thalamus and Hippocampus
The next one you can find
Thalamus, Hippocampus
Insula
Just now
We saw on PDs patient
Those hubs are less important
So our result
Here is the whole conclusion
The first one we said
Can we use rich club function
As a bio-marker
I wrote potentially
There are a lot of things we haven't measured
For the current result
This is possible
Just now
We did a linear regression
You will find
PDs patient
Their function
Reduce dynamics
Especially with this number
PIGD is related
In addition
Because PDs patient
Most of the time they show
Global efficiency
Their connectivity
Is better integrated
As I said
This is the so-called
Compensatory effect
This is the result of local measure
You can see
On PDs
A lot of hubs
Lose their importance
This is actually
Similar to other people's research
Because they mentioned before
These hubs are actually more sensitive
They are more likely to be affected by diseases
So our research
It's a bit like
Even on PDs
These cortical hubs
Easier to be affected by diseases
Because they lost their importance
The only one that is not a hub
Pre-SMA
Somato
Pre-SMA is another
A little bit in front of the motor cortex
Brain area
I found a paper
A long time ago
This paper describes
Pre-SMA and SMA
The function of this area
Is to control
So-called body coordination
It's interesting that we found
Dynamics and body coordination
The PIGD indicator is related
So our final result
We proposed
It is possible
This pre-SMA
You can only see it on PD
Even if it is not a cortical hub
Its importance is also reduced
Maybe because it controls this function
On PD
Is affected
That's it
Thank you
Can I ask a question?
Yes
Thank you for your sharing
It's wonderful
I have a comment
On the conclusion
Ok
First of all
I am a EEG
I am not an FHI
But these
These analyses are quite common
I think it's quite interesting
But I think
Your first point
Your research
The fact is
You want to use this as a biomarker
In fact, I think
A little
A little bit of killing with a knife
What do you mean?
That is to say
In fact, the diagnosis method
All very clear
But if you continue to draw a
If you only pay attention to
If you only pay attention to the effect level
You have to spend so much energy
FMI
Then do these very complex analyses
Then
In fact, I think
A little bit of killing with a knife
That is
A simple thing
I think
This kind of function
Especially for me
Is Parkinson's subpopulation
I think it should be easier
Easier to do
Psychology
Life Function
Then
Why is it important?
Because it seems to be my own
Related
Music
Wait a minute
I can't hear it now
There is a child
Talking
The child is not on my side
Ok
Let me continue
I think
Take this set of tools to do subpopulation
May be more interesting
Because like
Some people
For example, there is a rhythm
To help Parkinson's disease
To help them control
Action control
Although it works very well for some people
But on another group of people
Some Parkinson's disease people
The effect is very poor
Then this aspect
I don't know why
Then I think
There may also be such a problem
You can find more
General neuropsychological
Can't do
Then I think
Rather than saying this is a biomarker
I think
This purpose will be stronger
For me
Ok
Let me talk a little bit
Because I'm a little lazy
So I only put
May be a biomarker
In fact, we do this thing
There are other purposes
The first one is that I said at the beginning
The so-called disease prediction
The original
The ideal state is
Then build a very powerful
Then we can
Because of this statistical power
Can
Produce a
It's a bit like a disease model
Then if we have new patients
When we come in
We can put his data into this disease model
To try
Can we predict
What is the situation after five or ten years
Because we can't really wait for him
After five or ten years
Use some drugs to control
If we find
I knew it was possible
Will become more serious
Can we take some
Preventive measures
Then another
The purpose is
So far
Although the drug results can be controlled
Such as tremor
These can be controlled quite well
But there are a lot of patients
In fact, there is no way to use drugs
So recently there are some people
Spent a lot of effort
In the study of so-called cognitive training
They hope to use non-invasive
No need to use drugs
Just use training
Can treat Parkinson's
Obstacle to cognitive function
But before doing this
You have to know their cognitive function first
Their whole
What is the Cognitive Profile
And even which domain is most likely to be affected
Or which brain area
The brain area responsible for those cognitive functions
Is the weakest
Will be attacked
So this is why
When we do local measures
These brain areas are actually in Parkinson's disease
It's more dangerous and less likely to be attacked
That is, if we want to develop
Non-invasive
Treatment
We can say
For example, pre-SMA
We target this area
Design some cognitive functions
To strengthen the neural network of this area
It is possible to use this way
We can improve
Its cognitive function
A bit like this
This is more interesting
In addition
I know
My own research is
When listening to a more recent pattern
Pre-SMA disease is active
This is an externalization
Another question is
For example
In terms of signal interpretation
You mentioned
For example, a patient with Parkinson's disease
Compared to a person with typical control
Their signal
Will be stronger
Am I right?
But you mentioned
This is a conversation hypothesis
But I don't know what you're talking about
Because I've heard this hypothesis many times
In fact, this hypothesis is true
You can talk about it in reverse
If the signal is strong, it is a conversation
Where is the accuracy?
Do you understand what I mean?
I believe this is not my first question
What do you think of this question?
In fact, you asked this question
Many clinical researchers are asking
I would say
If you are single
For example, you only have fMRI data
Then you see
In theory, you expect patients to show
Lower value
But the result shows that the patient's value has risen
This may be a conversation effect
But if you want to talk about conversation effect
You need to have another piece of data
To support it
For example, you have behavior
When doing the same thing
The patient did better than normal people
In this case
Or there is no difference
We have another piece of data
We can say it is a conversation effect
In addition, in recent years
There is a rather popular topic
They are called male adaptation
When you see the value rise
It may not necessarily mean
It is just a so-called male adaptation
Maybe this connection
It is controlled by another network
But because of the disease
The network that controls this connection
It's not that good
It has no male function
It can't control that network
If you control that connection
Then you see the value of the connection
You think it may be
It may be a conversation effect
But maybe it's just because
The network that controls it
There is no way to do it properly
There may be a total pattern change
It's not just a problem with the connectivity
I think
The data dimension is very large
In fact, to explain
I think it's very difficult
I have another question
It's about signal processing
This is a more general connectivity issue
That is to say
If you use both signals
If you look at it
But since both signals are blood vessels
The signal at each point in the blood vessel
It's not independent
My blood vessels have upstream and downstream
My downstream signal is of course dependent
How do you know
This is a neural signal
This is a neural connectivity signal
Not a blood vessel connectivity signal
I can tell you
I have no way to know
That's why I said before
It's a very dirty signal
It's very
Not direct
And very dirty
Its signal actually includes
For example, CBB, CBF
All these things will affect
Even the whole magnetic field
Homogeneity will also affect you
So frankly
I have no way to know
Many people use other
Mathematical models
For example, the balloon model
If you want to analyze more
More precise mathematical models
It's possible to tell you
In the end
If you split the whole signal into many parts
Which parts may not come from
Neural is from other
This is possible
But I didn't list the mathematical model
So at the moment I can only say
The changes I see
We can only assume
Most of it comes from neural
So we have to do a lot of pre-processing
To ensure that the signals we get
Are not artificial
Not fake
I have another
Sorry, the last signal question
Too often heard
I never had an expert to ask me
Sorry
In addition, the structural hub you mentioned
And the functional hub
Can be different
But I think there is a place
I find it difficult to understand
For example, if I have a functional hub today
There must be a neural connection in the middle
Right?
That means I'm in the structure today
For example, I went to scan the brain today
I scanned a bunch of highways
Then the neural highway does not go
They go to the local alley
Right?
You just say
I don't go to Taipei to Kaohsiung
I just cut from Taichung today
Cut to Hualien
Go there
Right
How do you explain
The difference between the two
In addition to the signal problem
How is it possible
Right
Actually, the question you asked
No, but this is a good question
There are a lot of things in this field
Unanswered
A lot of people spent a lot of effort to try to answer
Then this is one of them
Your question is actually discussing
The so-called
Connection between functional connectivity
Structural connectivity
This is a big
It's like a star and a big field
A lot of people are doing
Just like us
In theory
If A and B are these two points
There is a structural connection in the middle
For example, there is a connection in the middle of the white matter
So in theory
When you see the functional connection
In theory, you should also see the structural connection
This makes sense
Because you must have something to let you go
When doing analysis
We often see
For example, between A and B
There is a functional connection in the middle
But there is no functional connection in the middle
There are many different
There are many roles
There are many possibilities
For example, between A and B
For example, there is no white connection
But maybe
There is a third point C
It connects A and B
It is possible that the signal is from C
It is possible that the signal is from A to C
It is possible
In addition to the signal and the possibility
We can't
Tell you why
This is why we have been trying
Want to understand the functional connection
The relationship between structural connection
I have an idea
Because like people
Generally outside
For example, our brain is being trained
General daily life training
For example, there will be a lot of complex visual and auditory scenarios
You have to interact with a lot of people
These should be well
The brain has to deal with the most
But today you lie in the FMI
For example, it is a resting state
And listen to a bunch of noise
In fact, it is a very unnatural situation
You just tell him
I just don't want you to walk the highway today
I just want you to walk a very strange one
Then lie down for a few minutes
So I think maybe
Is it because of this reason
Because it is not under the nature of nature
So I can't find the function
The same situation
This is also possible
There is a kind
In fact, when the resting state just came out
A lot of people are
There are a lot of discussions about this matter
There is another way
In addition to FMI
You can use EEG or MEG
Different modality
To measure its functional
EEG and MEG environment
Compared to functional MRI
Are closer to human normal living environment
So in this way
Maybe what you get
Will be closer to normal
Under the situation
I hope so. Thank you for your answer.
Sorry
OK
Any other questions?
Can I continue to ask questions?
Can I ask a question first?
Follow Andrew's question
OK
Do you want to ask other questions?
I might ask some
Everyone's questions
Then I will follow Andrew
You just said
How do you know
Now the correlation
Or any association
The nerve
Not the blood
If
I am not
The expert in this area
But I am thinking
Is it possible
It's a little strange
Something big
Into the blood vessel
So this thing
Will flow with the blood
But this thing cannot be used by the nerve
Then you can
Measure this thing
And cut it off
In fact, this is a bit like
I know
In fact, this is a bit like what we are talking about
Contrast Enhancement
In any image
In fact, this is often used in hospitals
If it is MRI
They will play a contrast called gadolinium
This thing will not be
Nerve-absorbed
It mainly flows with the blood vessel
Different places in the body
But there is a problem
If you are talking about
Functional MRI
You want to measure the nerve of the brain
But once you get to the brain
The so-called BBB is the blood vessel
There are a lot of drugs that can't get to the brain
So this is
The problem of contrast
In fact, another solution
There are a lot of people in the so-called multimodal modality
Because we all know
FMR has many shortcomings
So far we have not been able to
To overcome these shortcomings
Then we add another modality
The other modality
It has no FMR shortcomings
We hope to combine the advantages
For example, you often hear
The so-called FMR and EEG simultaneous recording
That is, the veterinarian brings the EEG into the FMR at the same time
Then you can go to the FMR signal at the same time
You can get EEG again
EEG signals are cleaner
It's less affected by the blood vessel
But at the same time
This method will cause the EEG signal to be very bad
Because as soon as you enter the FMR
It will often affect the signal
So I can only say
There is no absolute good way
But many people have tried
Want to solve the shortcomings of FMR
Okay, I'm done
My other question has nothing to do with this
So who asked first
My own background
Is doing machine learning and neuroscience
Then
I'm very curious about Mesoteli
Like you guys
For us
Because you use sliding windows
Then there is overlapping LAM
In a sense
You make the strong signal stronger
The weak signal becomes weaker
So the rest are those
Very strong connectivity nodes
Then you turn this connectivity
Just look at the hub
You can catch some features
Then we have some cooperation here
The plan is to say
If we don't go to the feature part
We just use the connectivity matrix
To do features
Will it be better
So usually you will find this connectivity matrix very noisy
Then like we did
If we take the matrix between different patients
To do a distance computation
We wanted to predict the result
Is it possible to see it in our machine learning method
For example, people with Parkinson's
Brain activity will be more like
Then there is a non-connectivity
And distance will be farther
But it doesn't seem to have this effect
I want to ask you
Is there any theory
Or if it's different people, the brain operation is too different
So they all have Parkinson's
Their brain connectivity may not be the same
There is something called intersubject variability
This is actually
People who do clinical research often encounter
Headache problem
Although our current research is actually a bit
I think it's a bit oversimplified
We all say
A group of patients and a group of normal people
We often say that this is the patient group
We see this thing
But in fact, because of intersubject variability
Everyone's brain is different
Everyone is unique
The degree of illness
May not be the same
So this is a reason
Why you can't see
Because everyone is really different
This thing
In our lab and our research center
Many people encounter this problem
Another thing is
The method of sliding windows
Actually so far
Although sliding windows are the most commonly used
In fact, frankly, because it is the simplest
So everyone uses it, but it has a lot of problems
The first one is how long your window length is
Then the second one is if your overlap
How long is your overlap
These are all some problems
So now more and more people
Will propose different ways
To measure the so-called
Dynamic Functional Connectivity
For example, there seems to be one
What is it called
DCC
Conditional Correlation
I kind of forgot what it was doing
But a lot of people
Just go back
To use the so-called
Mathematical model
To calculate the so-called
Dynamic Functional Connectivity
Then I can ask
You said there is a step where you do some
Thresholding
What is the threshold
0.5 or something
Thresholding is a big problem
According to the information I showed you today
In fact, my threshold is 0.3
Because I use
Simple Correlation
Generally speaking, we think that 0.3 or more
Is the so-called mild
There is a correlation
0.3 or less is more like
It's hard to say
Is there really a correlation
But in fact, I have tried other methods
There is a
Proportional Thresholding
Its thresholding is actually not based on
Absolute value
It is based on the density of the entire matrix
That is, I take the front
For example, the front
30% density
In this case, it becomes
When you do graph theory
Every edge value
Every subject has the same value
This is actually
Strictly speaking, it is a fair way
But the drawback is
It may not be so sensitive
Some things it can't detect
Thank you
it is good
Have you tried
Is it better than treatment?
I'm doing this
Live
The question is
Is there a comparison of treatment before and after treatment?
Then I am currently running in the lab computer
That is, the information we receive
In fact, there will be
We will record
When they come
OnMedication and OffMedication
Ask them not to take medicine the night before
Come to us the next morning
Ask them to take medicine after scanning
Scan again in the afternoon
The purpose of this experiment is to see
Because they all take LipaDopa
It depends on this medicine
Will it affect their cognitive ability?
Then I just used
SlidingWindow method
I can tell you in a simple way
The simplest way
The result is
The result of taking medicine and not taking medicine
If you take medicine
It's hard for me to see
The patient who takes medicine is different from the normal person
On the contrary, the patient who does not take medicine
See a lot of difference from the normal person
But this is the problem
It sounds very normal
Because the patient took the medicine
Theoretically, it is more similar to the normal person
But if I use different methods
The result I see is completely different
So I'm still thinking about it
Find out which one is the real result
The nerve
It weakens
Maybe it takes a while
Or maybe it doesn't take a while
For example
If you take medicine for a period of time
Then
Before you take any medicine
Just
Because I think
For example, the nerve
It will die
It's over
So if you go to take medicine
It's hard to say
For example, it can have a long-term effect the next day
No
For PT patients
Their dopamine is dead
Bye-bye
The so-called levodopa
It's just that the drug will produce
Something similar to dopamine
They are called left-handed dopamine
Use these things
To temporarily control his illness
Then they
The effect of the drug is really hard to say
Everyone is different
Is there a way
Or something
Let the cell regenerate
Oh this is that
Signal plasticity
Isn't that what you are doing?
You said I misunderstood you
The question on the spot
Is with that
The so-called regeneration
Cell regeneration is related
Because he is doing plasticity
So he asked this question
To be frank
I'm not very clear
But at least so far
On the PT patient
I heard I haven't heard anything like that
But I know
Because of my own research
In addition to Parkinson's disease
Another one called multiple sclerosis
Multiple sclerosis
The biggest problem with him is that the water is dead
We call demyelination
There is a vote of people who are studying very seriously
Is it possible to remyelination
Let him die of water
Then come back
It should be said
Maybe there are some drugs
Or some special
Genetic treatment or something
But this result has not yet been widely accepted
Um
If you use cognitive functions
Indeed now some people will think
He developed a set
The so-called cognitive training
Then let the patient test this cognitive training
After a long time
This cognitive training can strengthen his
One kind of neural connection
Even if you don't have so many multiple sclerosis
If that neural connection is strengthened
To some extent
It can maintain your basic brain function
That's another one
Kind of like
Another kind of training
Um
I haven't seen much
Ok
Any other questions
I think we seem to be talking for a long time
Ok
Let me take a look
Oh
Let me take a look at that
question
Someone asked me to take off the outlier
Um
I didn't take off the outlier
Because I
If you look at the picture directly
There is no patient
It feels like
Very different from others
But when we are
I didn't talk about this experiment today
But in other plans
We do leave one out
That is, when we take the patient's information
To do
Related to statistics
Another thing called leave one out
Let's say we have 10 patients today
Then we only put 9 in
And then after this calculation
Take one of them away
And then put another one in
Just throw one person away at a time
And then get a new one
So in this case, our final result
The result we report is
That effect is
You will see it every time
This kind of effect
Strictly speaking, it can be removed
Ok
Machine learning? Yes
We have a group of people doing machine learning
But I'm not so familiar with machine learning
So I'm still learning
Next door
But I have one of my own
It's called CCA
Canonical Correlation Analysis
That CCA is actually not
It has nothing to do with any image
It is purely related to clinical data
That is a little bit of the most basic machine learning
We are doing that
Multi-Modality
Multi-Variant Analysis
CCA is two data
Trying to project to the same domain
You have two different groups of data
Oh, I don't have that
If you want to merge it
Do you have CCA?
I'm doing CCA
There is actually no different
That is purely
Two different data for patients
One is their demographic
That is their age
The other set is their cognitive scores
Only these two have no impact
Can I ask
Like we are doing machine learning
We have found some data before
It seems that this kind of data you are doing
I can't find it on the Internet
Is it very private?
Can't do anything
It's very protective
No
Now a lot of
Google
Human Connectome Project
UK Biobank
German National Cohort
These are actually
Thousands of people missing
All can be downloaded
All FMRI
They all have
They have MRI
Some have EEG
Some have functional MRI
Structural MRI
Depends on their different
Labels
If you
Go to
Human Connectome Project
One of them
Human Connectome Project is mainly normal people
But they have other cooperative
Project
For example, there is autism
Or other diseases
If you
Interested in Parkinson
You can go online
PPMI
Initiative
Something like that
Or Michael J Fox Foundation
There are files inside that you can download for free
But you have to register with them first
They want to know who you are
Then you can free download
Do you have any questions?
Is there any other questions?
That's all
OK
Thank you
Applause
Bye