Let's start recording.
Okay.
Okay, I got it. Thank you.
Let's start.
Hello, everyone. I'm Zhang Yanping.
I'm your host today.
But I'll probably talk for a while
and then I'll be gone.
Because my wife's waist is twisted
to the point where she can't hold the baby.
So...
I'm going to have an emergency meeting later.
So today,
let's welcome Hanxi to share
with us...
He's the only one who has a webcam
so he's Hanxi.
He's going to share
with us about the
law related to
public safety.
Because
Hanxi...
Is Hanxi right?
Yes, that's right.
Okay.
My Chinese isn't very good.
Hanxi used to
study law.
But then he went to the police station
to study...
He studied for a while
in Yang Ming's police station.
Then he came back to study law.
His major is
the law related to
public safety.
Hanxi will share the details with us later.
No problem.
We're happy to have Hanxi here today
because he's probably our first law student.
Also, he's probably our first...
I guess,
pure humanist.
So we're happy that we can finally
expand to a more complete
academic field.
There are people in all fields.
Without further ado,
let's give a round of applause to welcome Hanxi.
I'm the only one in charge of filming.
Because
today's guest is not alone.
Today's guest is not alone.
Let me briefly introduce myself.
I'm a friend of Yuhui.
Let's get to know each other.
Why is my microphone
turned off all of a sudden?
Okay.
Yeah.
It's like
a small roundtable.
It's like a chat.
It's not a formal report.
Since we have the opportunity,
let's get to know each other.
Okay.
I'm not sure
which school you're from.
So let's...
Let me introduce myself.
I'm from UNC.
I'm from Beka.
I'm majoring in social psychology.
Who's next?
Hello.
Hi.
Let me introduce myself first.
I'm from DC.
I'm George Washington.
I'm majoring in mechanical engineering.
I'm majoring in
high-performance computing.
It's related to supercomputers.
I'm doing an internship
in Tennessee.
So you're not in DC.
I'll be back in September.
Cool.
So your name is
Zhuang Ping...
Bi Yue.
Zhuang Bi Yue.
Bi Yue Xuan Hua.
Okay.
Let's switch to Caltech.
We have two people here.
I'm Zhuang Ye You.
I'm working in Caltech
and NASA JPL.
I'm working on dark matter experiments.
I'm Yu Zhe Jing.
You can call me Zhe.
I'm studying in Taiwan University.
I'm working in Caltech.
I used to work in chemical engineering.
I'm working in environmental engineering.
That's cool.
So there's one more person.
He left a comment
in the chat room.
Oh, okay.
He's studying geography.
What field is he studying?
Geography is pretty broad.
It ranges from biology to natural science.
I'm pretty interested in this.
So we're going to
chat with Zhuang.
Physical Geography.
Okay.
You've been to Charleston.
I'm going to start.
I'm going to hand over my video.
Okay.
Hello, everyone.
I'm at Georgetown
studying law.
If you have any questions,
feel free to ask.
You can see my screen.
I think you can hear me.
If you have any questions,
feel free to ask.
I'm happy to share
my research topic with you.
I'm at Georgetown Law School.
It's a big classroom.
The signal here is very good.
I'm preparing this topic
about obesity
and soda tax.
I'm preparing this topic
about obesity
and soda tax.
I'm preparing this topic
about obesity
for the first time.
For the first time.
I think I'm getting a little bit
a little bit
a really little bit
I think the host just mentioned a little bit
but I can still give a brief introduction
to myself
to put it simply, it's actually a little bit
complicated, because I
like you guys who are watching this video
I have studied in a lot of schools
and right now
George Student University is probably the fifth
so there might be some of you here
whether it's Taitung University or Yangming University
or even UW
University of Washington
In my field,
on the one hand, I was born with a background in law
just like everyone is familiar with
well, law
and being a lawyer
I was born with a background in law and training
I also studied law
and now I am studying law
on the other hand, I am a little bit different
from other law students
in that I have my
medical background
and work experience
how should I put it
that is
my first full-time job
as you can see
was in Seattle
ICHS
International Community Health Service
International Community
Health Service
that was when I was
in UW
in 2007, after graduating from law school
I went there to work
that was my first full-time job
before that, I was a lawyer in Taiwan
but I hadn't worked there
that was my first full-time job
for a lawyer in Taiwan
in my mindset
to work in a hospital
that was a big surprise
so that year
to some extent
I got interested in medical law
and then
I jumped out
when I came back to Taiwan
I kept my medical background
so I kept my medical background
in the health law field
so
can everyone hear me?
because
it's weird
because I can't hear everyone
we can hear you
so welcome
to speak up
it's my first time
feeling like this
you can't see anyone
it's like a speech
can you speak up?
I can't hear you
will it be better if I speak up?
if you don't mind
I can see your face
it's like a speech
I'm not wearing any clothes
so I don't want to speak
there's an answer on the screen
no problem, thank you
we can
we can turn on the video
yes
you can turn off the sound
at least there's a video
it feels better
talking to a real person
ok, thank you
to put it simply
I'm a lawyer
a lawyer from Taiwan
but I'm interested in public safety law
so I chose this topic
it's 6.20pm
it's quite simple
my presentation will be divided into 3 parts
introduction
background
why we chose sugar
why we chose soda
and public safety intervention
second
case study
one of my research point
is the case of soda tax
last
I want to talk about
soda tax
Caltech is in LA
so if there are
students from San Francisco
or Berkeley
they are
in the area of soda tax
because there's soda tax in the city
it might feel better
but it's a trend
cities are moving towards it
so maybe
you will have the same problem
I talked to LA
public safety
officer
it might not happen in a short time
but it's a trend
anyway
you can listen to
their opinions
after listening
there's pros and cons
you can discuss
ok
sorry
I want to ask
what is the concept of soda tax
in California
California
city
city tax
I don't know if you will talk about it later
I just want to ask
Does the tax cover the range of hand-shaken drinks?
Like bubble tea
like bubble tea
For now
This is a good question
Because most of it
Most of the tax
Is based on that
The finished product of the drink
To tax
But
If it's a freshly made drink
Freshly squeezed juice or freshly brewed
If it includes
It doesn't look like it, but I can
I think it depends on the definition
It doesn't include
But I can check again
This is a good question
Especially in Taiwan
If you want to pass
Does this hand-shaken drink include
I don't think it's in the definition
But I can help you confirm this
Thank you
Okay
Let's cut it into three parts
To discuss
I'll do the introduction part first
Okay
I want to tell you
Why did we choose sugar?
Why did we choose soda?
This is a trend in the world
You may have noticed
You may not have noticed
But if you use Google
Use Google as a keyword
Search
This is what I did
Yesterday
You can see
The anti-sugar fad
Is now a trend
Bloomberg
The anti-sugar fad
Has become a trend
It's a trend
This is
For those who are not in New York
This week
There is a company called
Kind
FDA
Coca-Cola, Pepsi and others agree to keep sugar in the drink in Singapore
I have a question
I think there's a catch
For example, Pepsi
They don't want to reduce their sales
Coca-Cola as well
So they said reducing sugar
Is it really reducing sugar?
And then change it into other sugar-containing types
Or do they have any strategies to change their ingredients and taste, etc.
Or do they just want to keep it as it is?
Or do they want to keep it as it is?
In fact, the regulation of sugar in the sugar drink
Has included artificial sugar
So some parts have
Like Diacok
Some tags have included it
So it's included
Of course, some cities don't have it
So this is also a controversial point
Whether artificial sugar is included
I think the question is good
Because if you look at the sales
If you look at the sales
Now the consumer's preference is
Reduce sugar in some drinks
I think the manufacturers naturally develop this kind of thing
I am following up
I think
Even our school cafeteria
At least this half year
They sell sparkling water
And even the one with favor
The proportion of sparkling water is rising
And then the proportion of traditional sugar-containing drinks
Then I think this
According to some reports, this is a trend
So for Coca-Cola
In fact, Coca-Cola and Pepsi
There are actually a lot of drinks
It can actually
Adjust its proportion
Or adjust the amount of each product
It can still
Find a way to maintain a certain profit
As a manufacturer
It has a lot of strategies that can be applied
I think it should
Indeed reduce the amount of Coca-Cola
Or it may launch more
Like it now has this
Different types of Coca-Cola
Then do it like this
The proper distribution is
I don't know if I answered your question
Yes, thank you
OK, you're welcome
Ok
We have seen this international trend
Basically for sugar
For sugar-containing drinks
The next question is to ask
Why
Why do we want to fight this
Sugar-containing and sugar-containing drinks
What is the reason behind this
The main reason behind the reason is
Of course the health part
In fact, sugar-containing drinks
The two main issues
One is that traditionally
Everyone thinks of it as a tooth
This is one of the issues
But let's leave the tooth
The most important part here is obesity
What is the problem with obesity
Because of obesity
I use this picture
In fact
There are several factors that cause obesity
Probably sitting in front of the computer
Like we don't move
Inactive
This may cause obesity
Lack of exercise
Another one is diet
The ratio of the amount you eat
What kind of food
Then it will lead to obesity
What is the problem with obesity
The following is what most people are talking about
NCD
Non-Communicable Disease
In Chinese, it can be translated as chronic disease
There are four main types of chronic diseases
The first one on the left is cardiovascular disease
Heart disease
High blood pressure
The second one
It's about blood flow
Diabetes
The second one is respiratory disease
The last one is cancer
Obesity
It will lead to cardiovascular disease
Diabetes
Risk factors for cancer
Even
Leading to chronic disease
Especially diabetes
Related to obesity
One of the strongest
OK
What is the problem with obesity
The main problem with obesity
In fact, it is very realistic
In addition to causing patients to suffer from this disease
The main thing is for family care
Because this is a chronic disease
In addition to our whole society
If it's really related to everyone
The main thing is the increase in medical expenses
It's realistic, whether it's the United States or Taiwan
This chronic disease
In fact, because it takes a long time
Medical costs
The cost of care is very considerable
In Taiwan, I can give an example
Our annual budget for health insurance
The cost is about 600 billion
10% of it
Is used to
Diabetes patients
So the annual cost of health insurance
At least 60 billion is used for diabetes
Diabetes
Of course, there are many reasons for diabetes in Taiwan
Maybe everyone knows
Food with problems
Detergent, pollution, etc.
But diabetes
The cost of diabetes is so high
This is a very direct reason
So for each country
If you can control obesity
Can control
Can greatly reduce these chronic diseases
Relatively reduce medical costs
Why are we looking for this
Sugar-free drinks
Everyone is studying science
This is probably a national high school
Natural science or chemistry
I mentioned the dissolution of sugar
200 grams of sugar
Can be dissolved in 100ml of water
At room temperature
About this
The picture on the left is also provided by netizens
Actually
I was very surprised when I first saw it
It's like Coca-Cola
The smallest 350ml
There is a sugar content of about 9 to 10 grams
You can see
The more
This
Or this
Lemonade or some juice
Ice tea, etc.
If you drink a big can of cola
You eat so much sugar
Actually
If you don't drink drinks
You won't be crazy
Eat a bunch of sugar
But in the drink
It's a liquid
It's easy to take too much at once
More than
Everyone should take an average of
More than ten times
This is why
Why
Hello
I have a small question
About this picture
The cola on it
And the red cow
Mountain Dew
It's all man-made
So I can understand that sugar is added by people
But for example, the juice below
The meaning of those sugar cubes
Except for him
After extracting the juice
After extraction
Added so many sugar cubes
That means
There are so many sugar in that drink
Including natural and
The total amount of sugar
You asked a very good question
This is also
This is also the United States
I will talk about the FDA later
In the new nutrition fact
To make a distinction
Is it this added sugar
Or the sugar it already has
It lists two different things
I believe the list here
Basically all included
Is the original sugar
Plus sugar
But in fact
In addition to the original
If you look at the new nutrition fact
It's still much more than natural
In other words
Real fruit sugar
Compared to the drink
To make you drink
It's actually artificially added
The ratio is much higher
This is also his terrible place
If the real lemonade comes out
May be too sour
So you will attract everyone to drink
He added a lot of sugar
This is also what I will slowly introduce
Please say
I think Zhang Yong just asked
The question is very interesting
And let me think of another question
But before you ask me a question
Let me talk about this video first
I think the two below
Although it looks like juice
But the two of them should not be natural
So this question
In these six specific cases
Should not be established
Because if you go to buy that drink
You buy that lemonade
It says on it
How much is the real juice
Very exaggerated
So that's actually artificial
But suppose we can find one today
Find a juice
For example, fresh juice
In addition to the ingredients
The difference in the amount of sugar
In addition to the difference in the amount of sugar
Will there be some differences in the type of sugar
Because I always hear people say
Because I don't study chemistry
But I always hear people say that refined sugar
With natural sugar in fruit
Is actually a different thing
This thing
Is it considered
At the time of the law
In the data I checked
In terms of reality
These sugar powder artificial sugar and natural sugar
Is there a difference in the risk to the human body
Everyone thinks there may be
Even some people make some distinctions
Which is safer and which is not dangerous
Like some artificial sugar
Actually extracted from a plant
Some are chemically synthesized
The situation is not the same
But these data
There is no overwhelming evidence
Can prove which is dangerous
Which is safer
But we believe
Indeed these sugar powder is different
May have different effects
But so far
Scientific evidence
As far as I know
Of course because I'm not a scientist
The data I see
It's not really clear
Which is dangerous
Which is safe
Because it brings
The main part is the heat
This fat
This fat itself is a risk
Risk to the human body
What you said
The other additional risk
I think there may be
But so far
It's not clear which is the highest risk
Even without considering
High sugar content
This is a problem
You said there may even be additional risks
In addition to causing
Some artificial sugar powder
There may be additional risks of cancer
I heard people say this
But there is no accurate evidence
To prove that it is dangerous
So when you say sugar
The word sugar
In your presentation
It covers basically all
I don't know
Maybe it's just
Something that can produce sweetness
Yes yes
Basically like this
Even for this
We are talking about
Soda tax, sugary, sweetened
Beverage tax
Most of the laws
Include these
In addition to 100% natural juice
Will be excluded
As long as you add artificial
Whether it's sugar
Will be included
In the tax law
Most of the definitions are included
Unless you sell
100% natural juice
If you don't add anything else
Otherwise you will be taxed
In many cities
This is also what I said in the first video
Because
Everyone calls it soda tax
It's easy to say
This is a water tax
Or this is a cola tax
In fact, the more correct statement
With their official words
Sugary, sweetened, beverage
Sugary, sweetened, beverage tax
So you see
This is a simple chart
Oh, I forgot to say
Disclaimer
Many of these charts
Are not my original
I found it on the Internet
Because I don't have time
To add the source
Some are in my notes
So this is a special statement
But this is not my theory
I will add it
When the video is finished
Because this is left
For our private academic use
So it is recommended to use it
So you can see
Energy drink
Red Bull, vitamin water
Sports drink
Gel powder
We often drink sports drinks
This is actually a lot of sugar
Even juice
A lot of juice sold on the market
It is not 100% natural juice
It may be naturally concentrated
Then restore
Add a lot of artificial flavors
Colors and so on
So just like the classmate said
It is actually artificial juice
Even including
Ice tea
Ice coffee
It actually adds
The sugar content is also very high
Like we just saw
Peach ice tea
7 tablespoons
Sugar
In fact, it is the same as Coca-Cola
So these are all within the scope
To be taxed
Ok
Then we have seen
It was mentioned in the introduction
Sugar and
Soda are our target
Because it will create fat
Fat is what we want to avoid
A major danger factor for leprosy
Then next
How to avoid
Intervention
This is a picture on the Internet
Including
U.S. sugar consumption
You can see a very obvious trend
Almost a linear trend
From 1822 to 2005
The consumption of sugar
Has been rising
This is what I want to talk about
From the point of view of the law
The government's intervention measures
Can be divided into four categories
The first is the so-called complete ban
As you are familiar with
I use the picture of this drug
For this drug
The government's way is to ban
Even with criminal law
Basically can't hold
Can't sell, can't make
Can't use such a thing
This is the law
Even in terms of drugs
This kind of ban
For example, we just talked about drugs
In fact, there are different levels of drugs
It may not be the same in all countries
I don't know what's going on in your city
But at least in Washington D.C.
A while ago, it was a hot topic
Legalization of drugs
Basically you are here
It's not a crime
But in Taiwan
Drugs are the second level of drugs
Same thing
So the first level
Of course the first level is the most serious
But the second level
In fact, the relevant criminal law is also quite serious
When I was a lawyer in Taiwan
I just witnessed
Especially foreigners
The case of using marijuana in Taiwan
Of course they all want to advocate
In our country, marijuana is legal
Some even say that he went to the Netherlands to use
Then returned to Taiwan
It was detected that there was marijuana
Anyway, we can see
This is the first way
Then use criminal law to regulate
The second example
I said it was a mode
I said it was a restriction
This is also easy to understand
I use cigarettes and alcohol
Everyone is familiar
The government can regulate
You can only buy cigarettes or alcohol at the age of 18 or 21
Even the purchase of cigarettes and alcohol
Restrictions
I don't know how you are in the city
Like where I live
It's actually Maryland
I don't sell alcohol in the city
Basically, you have to buy alcohol
Go to the liquor store
It's basically using that way
Make you feel less convenient
You want to go shopping
By the way, bring a bottle of beer back
It's quite difficult
You need to drive to the store to buy
Sometimes you think it's troublesome
Reduce your drinking capacity
Even for the behavior after use
For example, you can't drive after drinking
Can't drive a plane
Can't drive a bus
Restricted
For example, cigarettes and alcohol
The third one is more interesting
I call it Nudge
Why talk about this
I don't know if everyone has heard of Nudge
This is actually
I use this picture
It's actually a book cover
It is almost
One of the most famous law professors in the United States
He is
Case Sunstein
He has been to Taiwan
He advocated
Nudge
Nudge is actually not a novel
It's not worth it
He basically said
Use information to provide
Environmental settings or speech
To affect human behavior
The most famous example in his book
The manager in the cafeteria
As long as he changes the position of the vegetables
Will affect the amount of vegetables
The amount of vegetables for children
In other words, if he moves it
To the front, the middle, where everyone sees it
I saw it at the beginning
It's easy for everyone to take more vegetables
I hate vegetables
Anyway, the first time you see it, you will take it
Will affect the amount
This is actually not so much
Because in fact
All department stores, supermarkets
Even the bookstore boss knows
He wants to sell the most
Put it in the best position
But this mentioned
This is a bit
I use information to provide
Use position settings to change human behavior
Unknowingly change human behavior
But basically this is not really forced
This is to let the parties
Make decisions with their own free will
It's just that his so-called free will
Unknowingly received some of my default settings
Or some of these
Position settings
Information provided
Affects your own decisions
This is the third mode
I call it light push
The fourth is actually
Basically the government does not care
Just open
Fully provided by the market mechanism
Like Taiwan
If it is Taiwan's
Just mentioned this
Or these sugar
There is no control at the moment
You can add as much sugar as you want
But it's possible because everyone is afraid of getting fat
So the habit is to say less sugar, micro sugar, no sugar, etc.
The government basically does not interfere
So there may be
These four modes
Can actually be used
For sugar-free drinks
We want to reduce everyone's intake
To achieve this
Reduce fat
That
Sugar is of course not difficult to understand
The first one is of course not difficult to understand
Or we will ban it
Just mentioned
Artificially added sugar
Even artificial sugar
We can ban it
Like anti-fat
The fourth is also not difficult to understand
Just open
Basically the current situation
Taiwan's situation is that sugar is not in charge
In fact
The more interesting thing is actually the second
The so-called restrictions and the third light push
The second restriction is actually like the example of Singapore
They set 12% sugar content
In fact, there are restrictions in the United States
That is to say
Many school vending machines
Are not allowed to sell some sugar-free drinks
He uses this place restriction
Especially for elementary school students, middle school students, etc.
Restrict their access to sugar-free drinks
This possibility, etc.
This is also a restriction
About restrictions
I want to introduce a case
We don't have any students studying in New York
There used to be a mayor in New York
His name is Michael Bloomberg
He is the boss of Bloomberg
He used to be the mayor of New York City
From 2002 to 2013
This person is a billionaire
Very rich
I remember he didn't know the news
Often take money out to do things
He is also famous for public health
Very enthusiastic
This may be related to his undergraduate degree
But anyway
He invested a lot in public health
Bloomberg Foundation
Sponsored a lot of public health research
He is also very concerned about obesity in New York
Even for sugar-free drinks
He came up with a way
One of the ways
This is called
Potion cap
Simply put
Restrict these vegetarian restaurants
Can't sell large cups of drinks
Restrict the amount of drinks
The size of the cup
Simply put, you can buy a small cup
No matter how many cups you want
But the restaurant can't put such a large cup
Sell a large cup of drinks
Restrict the amount of a cup
In 2012, he proposed this policy
This policy
Later died
You can imagine
When it was first launched
Many people are very angry
Restaurant owners are very angry
Because selling drinks is making money
The biggest in the United States
American Beverage Association
Very powerful
They also pay
Advertisement etc.
One of the most famous
I drew a picture
He was laughed at
Old mother
Nanny
We don't need a nanny
Tell us how much cola to drink
This example and this picture
Too famous
Discuss relevant issues
Even in New York
People often talk about this
Why did this thing die later?
The interesting part of the United States
The interesting part of the public service law
They are using the method of litigation
They filed a lawsuit
Challenge New York
Administration
The court basically believes
Bloomberg is not
Use through their parliament
New York City Parliament
To restrict this portion through the law
It is used in a similar administrative order
To stipulate the portion of the restaurant
The court believes that this should be
The facts stipulated by the law
You can't do it directly with administrative regulations
New York City's law
So it was postponed
Anyway
The case was lost
But he had tried this
New York City
Is it possible to add soda tax?
I have a plan in my research
I will interview public officials in New York
They are proposing
It won't happen so soon
But they have tried
Use this portion
Another case
This is a British case
If you have been to the UK
They called
Traffic light system
You can see
He listed several items
Fat
saturated fat
And this
Sugar and salt
He used this traffic light
If the product contains sugar
Or salt
Far more than one person
You have to mark a red light
Remind everyone
If it is normal, use yellow light
If it is safe, use green light
So you can buy a product
You can see
It is marked in the front
So this is what we just talked about
Nudge
Let consumers decide
Do I want to buy this product
But
It is a pity
Since 2013
This policy is voluntary
It is not mandatory
In the UK
You can provide information to consumers
But there is no law
Next is the US
Nutrition facts
This is the law
On the left
Modern nutrition facts
Label
On the right
New label
You can see
Calories
More
Definitely
This byful
Japanese
We Jul 26
July 1
data
,