If you have any questions, you can just type them in the chat box.
No, he just said to start recording.
Because when I pressed it, he told me that my memory was full.
Okay, I'm going to turn off the microphone now.
Okay, bye bye.
Yeah, so if you have any questions later, you can just type them in the chat box.
Or you can just turn on your microphone and ask questions.
It doesn't matter.
Because in fact, this video, if I were to talk to a person who does biological math, it would be about 20 minutes.
But in fact, I think it should be far more than that.
Because I hope to let everyone, even if it's not a biological math background, to get a little bit of an idea of what I'm doing.
At least have a concept.
Okay, I'm going to start.
My topic today is mainly to discuss how a cell decides to extend itself in one direction.
As you can see, the nerve cell on the left side of the projection film, it only extends in one direction.
Or it extends in many directions.
Like the nerve cell on the right, it extends in many directions.
So how does it control such a mechanism?
This is actually a very, very big problem.
And in different biological systems, they may use different methods to control it.
But no one has actually asked this question yet.
So today I'm going to use the mechanism that we already know, the mechanism that the organism extends in a certain direction.
Let's understand this mechanism and then study what kind of nature it has to decide whether it extends in one direction or in many directions.
So my topic today is Principles that Govern Competition or Coexistence in Rho-GTPase Driven Polarization.
Rho-GTPase is a protein.
It's a very interesting protein.
We're going to go all over it today.
What does polarization mean?
Let me explain it to you now.
First of all, for a cell,
Modeling people often think about how to model a cell.
Generally, you would imagine that you have a cell membrane.
There's a cell tissue inside.
There's a cell box inside.
There's DNA in the cell box.
We don't care about DNA.
All the protein is floating in your cell tissue.
If someone asks me how much of the protein in the cell tissue is dense,
Different proteins are different.
For example, I'll tell you that the density of the protein in the cell tissue is about this much, a fixed number.
Let's make an assumption.
The whole cell is uniform.
The density of the same protein in the cell tissue is basically the same.
In this situation, a cell can't tell which side is the head and which side is the tail.
For a person, it is very important to distinguish between the head and the tail.
Because first of all, you need to know where your head is.
You even need to distinguish between the front and the back.
Front and back.
Back and side.
Left and right.
So a lot of this kind of asymmetry is very important to the cell.
It's not just a whole individual thing for humans.
For a cell, it's the same thing.
For example, if this is a mobile cell,
For example, if this is a tissue,
It needs to know where it's going.
It needs to know which side is the head and which side is the tail.
The tail will shake and it will swim to the other side.
Even if it's not a mobile cell,
It could be, for example, your intestinal mucosa cell.
It needs to know which side is the side with food or poop.
And which side is the side with blood vessels.
Because it's trying to get nutrients from one side to the other.
So it needs to know which side is the head and which side is the tail.
It needs to know which side is the head and which side is the tail.
So for biological cells,
It's very important to establish this front and back axis.
Usually, the way this is done is
A certain protein may have a completely uniform distribution in the cell.
It needs to go through a certain process.
It needs to gather at the same end of the cell.
And then from that end,
For example, it starts from that end.
The skeleton of the cell grows from there.
For example, if it wants to secrete protein,
The secretion ball will move forward along the cell skeleton.
So it needs to gather the protein to that side first.
After the cell skeleton, it will let everyone go that way.
If this is a long-term cell,
It obviously needs to grow a cell skeleton first.
After the direction of this axis, it needs to go.
The source of all this is that we need to polarize a certain protein.
That's what we call polarization.
It needs to be gathered to the same end.
In the process of polarization,
In fact, it's not just a problem of building an axis.
Another problem is,
Do you want to build an axis, or do you want to build a lot of axes?
Let's say you want to transport something out.
Do you want to transport it to one place at a time,
Or do you want to transport it to a lot of places at a time?
For example, what you see now is
The nerve cells of the hippocampus.
In fact, no matter what nerve cells,
That's pretty much how it grows.
In the beginning, it only grew to one end.
It only grew to one end when it was very small.
Then it started to grow to a lot of places.
These things that grow to a lot of ends,
Things like trees, we call them trees.
The tree is the place where the nerve cells receive information.
After the tree grows, it starts to grow the axis.
It only grows to one end.
A nerve cell has a lot of trees, but it only has one axis.
So it needs to switch from growing to a lot of ends to only one end.
Then the axis will grow very, very long.
So the information that the nerve cells receive
The same information is passed to the same axis.
So obviously, for the nerve cells,
When it grows to one end, when it grows to a lot of ends,
It's a very important thing.
This is the main problem I have today.
Our lab is not actually doing nerve cells.
Our lab is doing hemoglobin.
Hemoglobin is the only thing on top.
It's called Saccharomyces cerevisiae.
In short, hemoglobin,
Hemoglobin is what we brew beer,
Or beer yeast,
Or yeast for making bread.
We often encounter it because
If you put it in a non-oxidative space,
When it eats sugar, it will dilute it into alcohol.
People are a kind of wild creature,
So they love to drink.
So we like hemoglobin very much.
In addition, we often use hemoglobin
It produces a lot of carbon dioxide.
Then it will make the bread fluffy.
Anyway, this is cold knowledge.
I just want to tell you what is hemoglobin.
Hemoglobin is the one we see above.
What hemoglobin does is it will sprout.
If you have read biology in high school,
You will learn the name of sprout growth.
That is to say,
The way hemoglobin gives birth to children is
It will first try to gather a certain protein to one end.
That end will become its head.
It will grow a tooth from the head.
The tooth will become its baby.
Then the tooth will split out again.
It will become a baby.
This is the way hemoglobin gives birth.
So for hemoglobin,
It is very important that it only grows one head.
What is the reason?
Because when it is split up,
Its DNA will be divided into two parts.
Then the average one part is divided to the child,
One part is kept by itself.
If it grows two heads today,
It will have two children.
At this time, it does not know how to divide its DNA.
Many times, the child will only get half of the DNA.
Then it will die.
So for hemoglobin,
It is very important that it only grows one head.
But at the same time,
The one below is also another kind of sprout.
But it is the kind of sprout that grows spores.
But hemoglobin is very close relatives.
They basically use the same system
To decide how to grow their heads.
But the sprout that grows spores
We call it Aspia gossypia.
Aspia gossypia
It does not only grow one part at a time.
Because if it grows like this,
It will grow into a pipe.
It will become a very useless sprout.
One important thing for it is that
It needs to split up.
If it can grow today,
Then grow forward, split up,
Everyone splits up,
It can grow into a secret net.
That secret net can absorb
The nutrients of the whole land or tree trunk.
So for these sprouts,
It is important to grow many heads at a time.
But controlling how they grow their heads
Is to decide the protein at the end of their heads
Is the same kind of protein.
This kind of protein is called Rho-GTPase.
It is called Rho.
This kind of protein is called Rho.
The most important question today is
This Rho-GTPase protein
Why does it have the same mechanism
To decide these two different results?
What kind of method
Can control it to grow one part or two parts?
Today, my speech will be divided into two parts.
One part is my theory
To discuss
This Rho-GTPase protein
How does it
From a state of uniformity in a cell
To a state of uniformity in a cell
How does this mechanism
Decide whether it grows one part or two parts?
This is the first part.
This part is mainly used for
Phenolphthalein and some other things.
The second part is
I want to start from the actual biological body
Actually, I'm using yeast.
To verify the knowledge I got from the previous theory
Whether some rules
Are applicable to this biological body.
So I'm going to divide it into two parts.
One part is very mathematical.
You'll see me shaking there.
But you'll see me showing the persimmon
And see my cat running.
The other part
You'll see the video of yeast.
So far, are there any questions?
I have one
Maybe I missed it.
I feel a little weird.
I think you're talking about
These bacteria have
Have consciousness
It can decide what it wants to do.
It's not a bacteria.
It's a cell.
Anyway, you know what I mean.
It decides where it grows.
Is it active?
Actually, it is.
For example, a yeast
There are two ways it grows.
But anyway
Yes, it is active.
The so-called active means
It's not random.
I know it's not random.
Because from the outside
It doesn't look like it's random.
I mean, it decides where it's going to grow.
For example
Let's say there's a plant today.
It's going to grow in the opposite direction of gravity.
Or grow in the direction of gravity.
And then you turn it 90 degrees.
It will find the direction of gravity again.
So it's actually
In the direction of gravity
It's passively deciding where it's going to grow.
Maybe in the middle is some very simple
Some underlying mechanisms of physics
It may not be a conscious process.
But if it's a cell
I can't imagine
It can decide
I want to put all the proteins in the same direction today.
And then it goes in the same direction.
OK
I think I'll answer a simple question first.
If your passive and active definition is like this
If it is
It's a very simple
Today there is a
There is a source of information.
And then it reacts to that source of information.
And then if this simple process is passive
That's right.
It's a passive mechanism.
This is the easy part.
But the hard part
It's not my major.
Maybe it's
So you think consciousness is
It's not a chemical reaction.
Or consciousness
Consciousness is not a chemical reaction.
With some biological cells
The combination of reactions
It may also
The same pattern
It's the same as getting a message and then reacting.
It's just that this process is very simple.
Or it's a very difficult question.
That's right.
It's hard to answer that part of the question.
And then that part is what I can't answer.
But I think it's an interesting question.
But just the simple part
Yes, it is
You can use a set of message transmission systems
To
To react to external messages
For example, this serum
It's
It's going to be with another kind of
Gender serum
Then it will try to grow there.
The reason is that the other one will release pheromones.
Then it will grow there.
If you think this is passive
That's right. All the processes I talked about today are passive.
OK, thank you.
Are there any other questions?
If not, I'll go down.
Otherwise there is a question.
OK
So
Let me say first that I haven't been on any creatures.
So what I mean is that
It's not like a serum.
For example, you just said that there is a
Gender
Does the serum have a gender?
It's just that you said you want to match that example.
Someone releases pheromones
So this one will grow over there.
So what you mean is that
He can't decide for himself
Contact that
Sexuality
Is that right?
Is that what it means?
As long as someone releases pheromones, he will
not
It should be said
This is what we see.
That is to say, if you give him a group of serum today.
Then you put a group
So the gender of the serum
We will divide A and Alpha.
A and Alpha can be matched
That's it.
So if you put a group of A and a group of Alpha today.
If you mix them together
You can imagine it as a group of boys.
A group of girls all mixed together
At this time, some people will run to
Match with others
Some people will not match with others
Some people don't match
It's because they're in the wrong direction.
Some people are because they
It's not right at all
Pheromones
But
So this is a phenomenon
Is this his decision?
Or did he decide not to say that?
Because I would think
If this environment is for him
It's his mating that's more beneficial to him.
After this mating
After giving birth to a child
If you can adapt to the environment
Those who did not mate successfully
They are likely to be killed by the gods.
Then gradually
This group of cells that will react
So they are in the process of evolution
Learn to react to pheromones
Is this a proactive process?
I think it's a big question
This is how we understand the process
But how do you determine
Is this a conscious thing?
I think it's a big question
I just said I can't answer
OK, thank you
Are there any other questions?
Then I'll go down
it is good
In the past, there have been several studies
We gradually realized that
These
I just talked about
It creates a front and back
The principle of this polarity
Is a
This mechanism of our so-called Turing text
Turing
Everyone should have heard a little bit
Because there was a movie a while ago
It's called
The Mutation Game
The handsome guy in it
Is playing Alan Turing
So everyone should know who Alan Turing is
Everyone may know
He does computer
And he is
So-called mechanical consciousness
Contribution in this area
In fact, he is a super genius
I am studying this whole field
Biomathematics
Basically all
What is Turing text?
Before
Everyone has always had a doubt
For example, you see a tiger today
It has a pattern
You see a leopard, it has a pattern
You see some fish
It may have a pattern on it
The pattern becomes a pattern
These patterns
How did it come out?
How did these patterns come out?
If you say there is something
To control these patterns
That controls its thing
So you have to go forward
Then found
It seems
It seems to be in a certain step
That pattern will need
There is a way to self-release
From a completely uniform state
Pattern comes out
It does not need to be controlled at all
It will automatically grow a pattern
So everyone is very confused
What does this machine look like?
Alan Turing
First, with a very simple partial equation
This conclusion
He said
If this cell is good
Or a piece of land
If it has two chemical substances
One is activator
Then the other is substrate
One is
How to say activator?
Activator should be easy to understand
What it does is activate
The other thing is substrate
This is its value
What does activator do?
Once there is this activator
It will have a positive feedback
Then let more activators grow
Activator in the process of growing
It absorbs the value and becomes activator
For example
There may be an activator today
The process of its positive feedback
He went to catch another substrate
Then turn that substrate into activator
So in this process
Once activator grows
He will have a positive feedback
To make himself more and more
But at the same time
In this process
It will absorb the substrate
So the substrate will become less and less
If there is such a process
With activator
It spreads very slowly
Then substrate
If it spreads very quickly
In this way, it will
Such a system can make
Point
A whole piece
It can also make a strip
It can make a very interesting pattern
It can make a counterpoint
It can even make a piece
No substrate part
So the same system
As long as you give it different parameters
It can run
Different pattern results
So this is a very interesting thing
The picture on the right
Is that we took one
Entering its black and white photo
Then take the photo
Its brightness
That model will automatically
According to the brightness above
To run
Its pattern is all white
Or dot or semicolon
In short, this is a very cool thing
Everyone realized
It turns out that such a system
Can make a piece
Nothing
Run out of the pattern
That such a system
What does it have to do with the activator I just talked about?
The activator is probably like this
That is to say
Rho-GTPase
It is a protein
It has two forms
One is when it sticks to GTP
This form is activator
This form is active
It can guide the downstream
All biological reactions
To go to it
Then there is another form
It is a non-living form
It is Rho-GDP
It is Rho-GDPase
So this protein
It has a non-living form of GTP
Then it switches between these two forms
That
When the active Rho-GDP
It spreads very slowly
Then the active Rho-GDP
If it spreads very quickly
This becomes a
Healing mechanism
So actually in the cell
The way it works is like this
That is to say, we have a Rho-GDP
It is stuck on the cell membrane
Because it has a tail
That
Once there is a Rho-GDP
It will try to
Turn other Rho-GDP
Into Rho-GDP
So everyone sees that the red arrow
Is a positive feedback
At the same time, it also has another form
Called Rho-GDP
I just told you that it is a living form
Its tail is wrapped
So it can be in the cell
Happy in the cell
It spreads quickly in the cell
There is an
Activator substrate system
It just happens to be its activator
It spreads very slowly
Then its substrate spreads very quickly
And its activator
It has a positive feedback
The way we model this thing
Is that we have a partial differential equation
That is to say
If we put the active form
Called U
The inactive form is called V
That
The change in time
Will determine
How fast it spreads
And its
I just put three arrows on it
To give it a reaction
At the same time
Its V
The change in time
It depends on how fast it spreads
And its chemical reaction
It's just a little bit special here
Because the reactor
That part
It's basically
If anything grows out of U
It must have disappeared from V
It can only be exchanged between V and U
So its
That term
It's positive and it's negative
What this means
Is that the whole system is qualitatively consistent
There is no term in here
It will automatically
Grow out of
Rho GDP
Or U
There is no term
Any particle
Disappears from the system
I have a question
Okay
That is
What is the unit of UV?
Is it density?
Or something like that
Yes, it should be
It should be concentration
But because it is
For example, the concentration on the entire cell membrane
So it is
It is the change in position and time
But it is concentration
So this is weird
There is a problem with this
I think your big D
U and big D
It's not a dimensionless value
That is to say
You are discussing
A
Rho GDP
With a Rho GDP
Interaction
Discuss with you once
Ten Rho GDP
With ten Rho GDP
It won't be the same
Because your big D is not dimensionless
Do you understand? It can't be multiplied by ten
Because it is not a value without units
I don't understand
Yes, I don't understand
So U and V are equal
You said concentration
It's actually a concept of density
For example, unit volume
At this time
At this time, at this position
Its density
Then DU and DV are the rate of expansion
For example, the unit may be
The unit should be
Every second
Then the molecule should be
For example, square meters or square meters
It should be similar to this concept
That is to say
DU and DV
Its concept should be
Every second it can
It should be one square meter per second
It should be like this
How much can it move outward every second
Is this outward expansion
OK, confirm
Yes, that's right
But like this
What did you just say
One U
One rho gdp
OK, good
You remove the big F first
Because don't worry about the big F
Both sides of this square
There is this small U or small V, right?
So the two of them
The units in this place
Will be the same
Then you put
What is the right side of the square?
Divided by two X
Then X is the unit of length
Then on the left
Divided by a T is the unit of time
So your unit of big D is actually
Distance per square unit time
Yes, yes
So the dimension on both sides
Is it right?
But the distance per square unit time
This value
In your change
You discussed
This whole distance
For example, the size of your change
Or you only look at one at a time
Or you only look at ten at a time
This value will keep running
It won't be unchanged
Unless you take data
Time also changes
But it won't
Because you take data
You keep looking at it every second
Keep looking
So your value will change
From that
From you
OK, all the way to that
All the way to that
The unit of the expansion constant
I followed up
And then you said
So why does it
Why does it change
It's a fixed value
Then
You said why does it change
I really don't understand
Wait a minute
I'm the only one who doesn't understand
Is there anyone who can help me
Say
What does this mean
I think it sounds a bit strange
Because it
Yeah, I understand
It's a rate of expansion
The rate of expansion should be related to the environment
Instead of GDP or GDP
For example, you say the rate of expansion
Yeah
The rate of expansion has nothing to do with GDP or GDP
Yeah, if you look at this rate of expansion
It should be said that
On the cell membrane
The rate of expansion is a slower value
And then in the cell nucleus
The rate of expansion in the cell nucleus
It's another faster value
But
But in
In different locations
Different time points
As long as it is
As long as it is on the cell membrane
The rate of expansion is the same
As long as it is in the cell nucleus
Oh, okay, I know
I know how to ask
Then I change a question
This big D
Big D U or big D V
These two values
What does it have to do with
It will be with
It will be with the nature of these two cells
What kind of cell is it?
Right?
Correct
Is there anything else?
No more
It's basically
Theoretically, you should
Theoretically, when you write this governing equation
You should hope these two
These two numbers are basically used to present
To some extent
It's just about the relationship between this interaction
Right?
Just the two of them
But if you do
No, I mean the two of them
If one is a stone
Or one is a protein
Obviously that D will be very different
I can't even write
Correct
So it is
Characterize the nature of your system
Or the nature of the unit in the system
But
It looks like your persimmon
Dimension
Will still be with
For example, how big do you put these cells
It doesn't matter to cultivate
It looks weird
Wait, why am I
I think I can understand it
Then I also know
I understand your question
I think I understand the question
But why
That D
I guess what you mean is that
I said Zhang Aiyong
What you mean is that
That D is not a constant
It's actually a variable
Right?
Will change according to the unit you choose
Correct
So why is this a problem?
I can know what that thing is
It is a constant
Yes, you set a system
Then you change a system
You change a constant
So why is this a problem?
Yes
This is equivalent to
Your expansion equation
In fact, it is the same as the general heat transfer
The expansion equation is the same
Yes, it's exactly the same
Heat transfer coefficient is related to temperature
It changes with temperature
No matter what it does
It won't be a problem
So I don't understand
I don't understand what the problem is
My feeling is that
This thing is not
I won't say it's a problem
But I will say it's not enough
Is it not beautiful enough?
Because it actually
Yes, it's actually a heat transfer
This is a matter of aesthetics
Because it's not enough
Generalize
I think I have to think about it
Because I think we've been stuck for a long time
It will take up a lot of your time
I basically understand this equation
Because this is actually
It's a heat diffusion equation
It's an expansion equation
Then add the heat diffusion
Yes
Ok, let's continue today
Thank you, I'm sorry
No
So
That expansion constant
It's only two kinds
One is
One is the expansion constant of U
It will be on the film
It's a slower value
But it's the same in different positions
Then
The expansion constant of V is faster
Bigger
Speaking of this, I suddenly thought of
You just said
Their number
Anyway, you just said that
Magnitude is called magnitude
So you don't need to add another
Magnitude equation
For example, the total number must be zero
No, because he himself
He himself
I write it like this now
He will already be constant
The reason is good first
The expansion side
He will only run to the side
He won't
He won't disappear, right?
So the expansion is already constant
What about the part of the reaction?
You just disappear
Because his reaction rate on the V side
Is negative f of uv
Then the reaction rate on the U side is
f of uv
So
Anything disappears from V
He will use the same rate
Come out from U
So he will automatically say
Yes, I understand
OK, thank you
What about this system
Basically
You will see that
Rho gtp
He is
If he is anywhere
He has a little bit
More rho gtp
He will
Cause a positive feedback
Then he will suck a lot of
Substrate
Then it becomes
Just suck a lot of rho gtp
Then it becomes a lot of rho gtp
Gathered in that position
The problem is now rho gtp
At this time it causes a
Rho gtp vacuum
But in that cell
Part of it is
It doesn't seem to have
Is rho gtp
The concentration is very low
But at this time
Because in the cell
His expansion rate is very fast
So this concentration vacuum
Will be quickly
It's the rho gtp in other places
Once it's subtracted
It will be quickly sucked
To the cell membrane
So such a mechanism
Will quickly put
The whole cell
Rho gtp
All gathered
To the same cell membrane
This is basically the
Turing mechanism
In my special example
More intuitive explanation
If I plot it directly
It will be like this
That is to say
What you see today
The orange text you see here
The orange is
The x-axis is the position
Then the y-axis is
The y-axis is the concentration
Anyway, this mechanism
It will basically let you
Random
It will automatically grow out
All of these objects
Will try to gather
To the same location
Then it will form a
Concentration peak
According to our understanding of the Turing system
That is to say
How long is this cell
Today is 3 microns
If I am today
On top of 3 microns
Model this system
It will grow out a peak
But if I use 6 microns today
It will grow out
It will grow out two peaks
But we found
The next thing that happens is
These two peaks
They will
There is a bit of competition between them
Because they are both
Absorbing the same pool value
Then so
When a peak
He grabbed
That is, he
He will grab another peak
When the peak
He will put
He will absorb
Faster than the other
Then
So he put
Another peak
Things inside
All grabbed
So he
Although
A Turing system
Theoretically
Like the picture we just saw
The same
It can grow out a lot of dots
But actually
In a
Energy
Quality
In the system
If you grow a lot of dots
A lot of dots
They will compete with each other
In the end
There will only be one
So
In a quality
He will
There will be competition
That competition will decide
He has only one peak
We can understand it this way
That is to say
This part
You may have to
Just believe me first
Just
A peak
He absorbs
Absorbing these
The ability of the pool value
Actually determines
His
Concentration of the peak
That is
The height of his peak
Basically
Decided
His ability to absorb
Like the one on the right
The one on the right
He has a stronger ability to absorb
So if you look at his
Under the pool value
He will also cause
A relatively large
Valuation vacuum
And then
He will be more over there
That is the concentration of the cell value
Will be lower
At the same time
If you look at the small one
Because he has a poor ability to absorb
So he won't be so fast
Take
All the cells under him
Grabbed
So the cell value under him
That one
The concentration is higher
At this time he caused
Say
Say here
There is a
The concentration of the cell value
Because in the cell value
His
His expansion is very fast
At this time
The substance will be very fast
From the small peak on the left
Run to the right
And then
This is what happens at this time
That is
Everyone
Run over
Then he will be sucked to the other side
This is probably
Why two peaks
Will compete with each other
A
Rationale
In fact
We are in the real
There is such a phenomenon
In the school drama
That is
In fact, like me
Of course not only
One
Rho GDP
One Rho GDP
Between him
There are other molecules involved
But basically
The concept is still the same
That is, everyone can still see
Say
I helped him point
Great
That is
Basically everyone was here
See that
That positive feedback
He is not going to
Promote his own activation
He is
He will catch one
One
Scaffold
Is a framework
Protein
That protein
Will stick to another
A protein called GAP
But this GAP
Its role is
It is used to put
Rho GDP
Becomes Rho GDP
So once there are so many
Rho GDP
After that
He will call out this green
And this yellow
Then this yellow
Will try to turn blue into yellow
So this
This one
Is a positive feedback
So basically
In the school drama
We can see
I was just modeling
That thing
In the school drama
We do see
If today
Don't let that
Green
This protein
It's the one you'll see later
The black part
Is this green
Green protein
Or you let this
Red red protein
He is
That Rho GDP
In the school drama
It's called CC42
This protein
If you let it shine
You'll see later
First
It will grow out of a lot of points
But
There will be competition between these different points
And then there's only one point left
Everyone can see
These two are the same cell
Different proteins
There are two
And then it becomes one
And the one below
It's the same
It's
At first
There will be two points
And then these two points
Finally it becomes a point
Excuse me
So this competition
This is not a simulation
This is real
Yeah, this is from the microscope
See below
If
If you put that protein
If you put a fluorescent protein on top
And then it's under the microscope
Recording
Recording the fluorescence
And then
Yeah, I'm turning black and white now
So
The fluorescent part is black
Hi, I have a question
I've been looking
I've been looking for trouble
It's
My question is
It's the time under the video
Is that unit a second?
It's a second
A few minutes, a few seconds
So it's time under the video
So
This whole video
It's probably
What ten minutes or something
Yeah
And then he competed
This process is probably
It will end in less than three minutes
How much is the distance between the two points
The diameter of the entire cell
It's about
Five
Millimeters
No, no, no
It's ten to the sixth square meter
Millimeters
It's the diameter
So the distance between the two points is about
Two meters
So this kind of cell
In the spread
Speed
Will
In this ten-odd minutes
Will be less than
The distance between the two points
Otherwise
Your F
The parameters should have time
It won't be
Because you wait
Interaction is infinite
It's not
Every moment
To achieve its effect
Like this
The F inside
Is
The parameters of the reaction rate inside
There is time
It's
It's in the F
Will be
Every second
How much
How much more can be generated every second
The concentration of U
Directly like this
The parameter in front
There is time
OK
I also have a question
That is
GTP will consume GDP
That consumption is
Will
As long as there is GDP
It will definitely consume it
Or
It has a certain criteria
To a certain extent
Even if it has GDP around it
It doesn't care
No, we are
We are
We didn't imagine
It has a threshold
That is
As long as it
GTP will consume
That is
GDP will consume GDP
Right?
Then
Then I mean
This consumption is
There is actually one less
That is
It has a key
For example, you can see
There are two keys here
Right?
So it is
For example, this one
This key rate
With
Road GDP
Is related
Then come back
The rate is related to
Road GDP
So today if there is
Very little road GDP
A lot
A lot of road GDP
Very little road GDP
That
Then this positive feedback
It will work hard to put the value
That is road GDP
All become
It keeps becoming road GDP
Right?
Then but
Road GDP
It is also going back
It will also run back
So this is a bit
Depends on
This middle balance
So
So GTP
That is the pink one
Will also have a chance to turn blue
It is not
Right
It is a
It is reversible
Right
Got it
Thank you
Right
So in this
In this complex amount
It is a two-way arrow
In the original simple amount
It is also a two-way arrow
That is
It can run on the model
It will fall back
But because
Because
Because if at that point
There are a lot of road GDP
The positive feedback will keep running
It is easy to be sucked
Hiding on the model
Ok
That
That's right
So we are in the project
Sometimes found
Indeed this system
It will indeed
At the beginning
Several different
Peak
That is
Several different
Different blocks of road GDP
But they will compete with each other
Until the end
There is one
That
The next question is coming
Ok
If I told him
Um
These two road GDP
Peak
They will definitely compete with each other
That
Then we solve it
Why only get a
A
A front end
Such a question
That
In this case
Those that will grow
How does it differ
In the end
Under what circumstances
These road GDPs
Peak
It will not compete
This is my main question
And then I found
In fact, a very simple thing
You just need to increase the length of the cell
Long enough
That is
If it is a short cell
It will be over soon
But if it is a long cell
It actually started
It will also compete very quickly
But the competition
It seems to be competing
The speed becomes super slow
There is no
There will be a little competition at the beginning
So it disappeared
Just a few
This peak and this peak disappeared
But in the end
These four
They seem to stay there all the time
Then it lasted
A very long time
it is good
That
So why is it like this
I slightly
Let me confirm
If my understanding is not wrong
Between them
There should still be a rise
It's just that it's an equilibrium
Does that mean
Of course there is a rise between each other
That is
Yes, they are actually
Still competing between each other
The speed of that competition
Becomes very, very slow
That is, the competition at the beginning is very fast
I don't know why the competition at the end
Very slow
If my own understanding
According to that
If you look at the expansion formula
Because it
Blue turns red
And red turns blue
It's two-way
So if your distance is long enough
If they each reach the local balance
Then they are the last
Those few peaks
Will not compete anymore
because
Ah yes
I mean this
It should be like this, right
Yes yes
It should be like this
This meaning
Yes
I guessed it myself
I am
Confirm
Yes
But according to what we said earlier
If there are two peaks over there
They should compete in the end
That is
They are right
They are indeed
Local has reached an equilibrium
That is to say
You will see this on top
There is a small peak
There will be a small
Concentration
There will be a place
Is
It's more concentrated
Then this
This value
On this side
It's a little bit
This value
With
Its activator
This is itself
Equal
Then this side
But under this balance
The concentration here
Will be higher
Under this balance
The concentration here
Will be lower
Leading to
It will still compete in the end
Theoretically
This mechanism
Should be
How long
Still have to
Have a way
To do
But if it looks like
If the distance is long enough
Indeed they
The blue line
Will have a slope
So it will lead to
Flow from high
But at the same time
The orange line
Will return
Return to blue
So it's possible
The orange line
It will turn blue
Speed higher than
Blue
High place
Flow to low place
Then they will reach
A kind of balance between each other
If the distance is long enough
Ah
But because
In this system
Its blue
Sorry
Because in this system
Its blue
So it becomes
The effect of blue expansion
Will
Far greater than red
Should say so
OK
Then
Caused
Theoretically
It should run like this
Yes
Theoretically it should be competitive
Then everyone wait for me
It seems that someone
Because I'm going to argue
Want to enter our house
Wait for me
Sorry
Pervert
Ask them to come in and listen to the speech
He is not here now
Can't hear it
They have a speech
They want to talk about that today
Just said
They want to talk about Maya culture
And there is food to eat outside
Why do you think they will come in
Speaking of this
That one
Discuss a topic with everyone
That is
We are now
Tara
That is the fund
In fact, it can explode
That is food
There is food
Because
Ah
We are now with
The education department wrote the grant
Is
It can be written up to 400 yuan at most
But it has to be reported in time
That
We only buy this city now
So it actually costs more than 100 yuan
Less than 200 yuan
Then
If everyone wants
In fact, we think
What what
No
He should be talking to other people outside the door
Don't care about him
Oh ok
Then I will tell him quickly
Wait for me
We are discussing another thing
So if everyone wants to say
Every time I open Tara
Buy some donuts or something
In fact, you can
Send me some votes
Then
I will transfer this money to you
Then those votes can be used to report the education
Is the account of our project
Then everyone can
Save a little money
Every time you have a meeting
You can buy some donuts
Then you think about it
If you are interested
We can discuss
Sorry
Then you can continue
Should
Why did you go to find other people
Correct
Where was I just now
Just now everyone is talking about
There should be an equilibrium here
Then
If the distance is too long
It should be said
If the distance is long to a certain extent
Between him
Why is there an equilibrium
Actually, I don't understand
But
Let's leave it alone
Because now I think
Maybe it will be a bit difficult to explain
why
There will be no equilibrium
But
Actually we
There is a way
Directly from
This is called
Stability Analysis
That is to say
If I look today
Two
Exactly the same
Peak
Then go to see this
Peak solution
If there is stability in math
Will find
He
In fact, it will never be unstable
He will always compete
This is already
Is
This is what we
Directly use math to prove
Say
He will always compete
This thing
Just me in this speech
I usually don't put that
Take out the math
So I hope everyone can believe me first
Say they will definitely compete
This thing
But I know this is a bit
Excessive thing
It becomes
Everyone just have to believe me
But
But anyway
Yes
Then it becomes
This is very strange
In the end
If it is already mathematical proof
He just
He will definitely compete
That is in the end
Is
In the end
Why are they competing
The speed will become so slow
Later found
It's like this
That is to say
Because at first we guessed the distance
Because we are very obvious
We just made the distance longer
So we guessed the distance at first
Then I guess the distance
They did it for about half a year
I found out later
Oh, it's not the distance
In fact
Will affect the most
Is the amount of protein in it
Ask us today
If we are modeling this system
That is to say
If it is a small cell today
And a big cell
Then we all assume
At the beginning
The concentration of protein in the cell
If it's the same
Then when I put that cell
When it gets longer
At the same time
I also added all the protein
So if
Then
This is the first thing
The second thing
The first thing is more trivial
The second thing is to say
We suddenly found this thing
That is
If there was a peak
You keep stuffing protein in it
Keep stuffing protein
The amount of protein
Damn
The mouse is gone
If the amount of protein becomes more
That peak will increase
That is, it will become more
More concentrated
But it doesn't grow to a certain extent
It just grows horizontally
That means
It actually has a boundary
You can't go beyond that boundary
You can't grow higher than it
The reason for this boundary is actually because
If you are a little more familiar with this system
If you realize this thing
This is actually a bi-stable reaction
That is to say
The concentration of U
At the highest point
Is stable
Then the lowest point
Is also stable
So if it goes beyond that point
It will come back by itself
Then it stops at that point
Then this bi-stability
This nature
It actually comes from
Every time a peak comes out
It will cause a value vacuum
Value vacuum will
The higher the peak, the more serious the value vacuum
But it can't get worse infinitely
Because it can't get negative
So it will stop at a certain point
Then it limits
You basically can't grow that high anymore
Because it will become lower when it grows higher
The value will not be able to support the peak
Will grow higher
Basically such a concept
If you look at it from a mathematical point of view
If we plot f of u, v
Assuming that this f of u, v is
a u square b minus b u square
It is a
As far as I know
The simplest
This system
Polarized reactor
a and b are a constant
Is a reaction constant
There is time in it
Then u and v are density
If it is such a reactor
It actually looks like a green curve
It's not right at first glance
This is obviously a 2-dimensional
Why does it look like a 3-dimensional
That's because
In
Steady-state
How to say steady-state
In steady-state
d u d t is 0
So these two things
Now it becomes like this
If you add the two things
That f of u, v will just disappear
Then
If f of u, v just disappears
You are on both sides at the same time
If you do two points for x
This thing will come out
So the density of v and the density of u
It's actually a linear relationship
This is actually a reaction
This is the reaction
That is to say
q is a constant
It's basically the level of the basal
The density of the basal value
Then there will be one in the middle
The vacuum of the value
This vacuum of the value
It will actually react directly to that u
That is
How high is the density of the activator
This can be solved directly
After solving
v is equal to this u plus q
If you bring this in
You will find that it is actually a three-dimensional
This three-dimensional means
Today everyone will see this f of u, v term
Then I need a mouse now
This f of u, v term means
In fact, if x is u
The axis is f of u, v
Now there is no f of u, q
Because v is replaced by q
OK
There are two points in it
These two points are all stable state
That is to say
If the density is slightly deviated
It will run this way
Then if it is slightly deviated on both sides
It will run to the middle
Then this is an unstable state
In short, if both sides are
When it is almost zero in density
It is directly zero in this world
When the density is zero
It is a stable state
Then its density
When it is in this position
It is also a stable state
So it will cause
It will cause
Your peak rose to a certain extent today
It stops here, it will not rise anymore
This is a stable state
The following is also a stable state
So in such a system
In fact, everyone will find that
If there are two peaks today
And this big peak
It must be higher than the small peak
It will have a density gradient
Because of the relatively narrow peak
Its density here will be higher
The higher the peak, the lower the density
But in fact, if today there are two
Different big peaks
But it's just a wider one
One is narrower
If the height of the two is almost the same
At the same time, the base density
The height will be almost the same
At this time, the middle one
That density gradient
It becomes very, very small
Because the density gradient is too small
So this competition will become very, very fast
Follow up here
Have
Ok, let's assume that everyone has followed up
If you don't follow up
You can directly accept this conclusion
That is to say, we found out
Because
First two things
One thing is because there is a U peak
It will cause a V vacuum
This vacuum can't run down infinitely
This will definitely decide
A peak height limit
We call saturation point
It is saturated there
So in such a system
Saturation point must exist
This is the first one
Then there is
If the height of the peak
When it is close to the saturation point
At this time, even if the two peaks are not the same
The competition between them
Because the density gradient is very, very small
So it becomes very, very, very slow
Except for that part
I also did this thing directly
I'm in my model
Change all the parameters I can change
Then I go
So in each one
The two axes are different parameters
This is the total value
Or this is the length
Or this is the reaction length
Or this is the expansion length
Can be changed
After I changed it
I put the time between the two peaks
Plot out with color
At the same time, I put the saturation index between them
Not the saturation index between them
This is the peak saturation index
The so-called saturation index
Its definition is
The closer the peak height
The closer it is to the saturation point
Its color is more yellow
Then everyone will find
Competition time and saturation index
It's almost completely correlated
If I put the competition time
Plot in the y-axis
Then the x-axis is basically the height of the peak
I will get this dot
Every simulation here
If you turn it into a dot
You get a trend like this
Trend
This trend means
If I have two peaks competing today
They compete very fast
So there is a group of dots here that is very fast
In addition, there is a group of dots
It will become very, very slow
Because this curve
It basically becomes like this
It is a very dramatic switch
So it's almost a switch-like response
As long as it protrudes a little bit
It will become very, very slow
So today it's like a cell
It's in this state
Look at this state
Between the growing dots
Make a choice
Then we found this kind of
In fact, it is not limited to the f of uv that I just showed
That is, its f of uv can be replaced with various f of uv
For example, I just used this picture
That is to say, there are three arrows
One up, one down, and then a positive feedback
Today we can make that positive feedback smaller
Make that positive feedback bigger
Today we can add an additional negative feedback on that positive feedback
Or we can make that positive feedback
The positive feedback is actually
Active form to suppress the speed of its own fall
This is also another kind of positive feedback
We can change these f of uv in any way
They will get the same conclusion in the end
That is, the more saturated the two peaks
Their competition will be slower
Then this is a switch-like response
So to make a conclusion
First of all, if there are several clusters today
That is, several different peaks of low-GTPS
They will definitely compete
Then that is to say
If these several peaks are all saturated
Their competition will be very, very slow
If it's very, very slow
Basically in a biological system
You can almost say that they are two non-competing peaks
They may have to spend billions of years
To be able to compete
Then we are in the biological system
So we just think it's not going to compete
This is part of my theory
Any questions?
Okay, if not
The key question is actually
Whether those mathematics can be reflected
In the biological system, right?
At this time we did something called
Septim Mutant
That is to say, this is also a small
I have a question
So can I make the same conclusion
So your experiment can't go
That is, you can't go from the results of the experiment
To probe
What is the content of that big F
Yes, because in fact
My model only has U and V
Then a real model
It actually needs more protein in it
Then I cut it into a simple form
So in this simple form
What should the F of U and V look like
In fact, it's hard for me to say
But I just said a very important point
No matter what form the F of U and V looks like
It doesn't matter
The point is that no matter what form it looks like
They will actually compete
And they will switch to non-competing
Because I think you will compete
Then it will reach the Global Equilibrium
The biggest reason is
If you go back to the front
That partial T U is equal to big D
Then that is partial partial U plus F
Then the other one is minus F
In fact, if you add the first line and the second line
Then you can get rid of F
And your big F doesn't depend on T or X
So you can just get rid of it
So the whole Global Dynamics
It's only related to U, V, X, T
It has nothing to do with F itself
So from here, can I conclude
In fact, from this equation
Theoretically, it shouldn't have anything to do with the connotation of F
Because it's an elliptical equation
I just spent an hour talking about this
That's right
OK
I just have
So
So your experiment will focus on
Is
It's a bit like the diffusion itself
Can this be verified
Instead of F
You can test the content of F
Is that right?
I don't want to test what the content of F is
OK
But if what I just inferred is right
No matter what the content of F is
First of all
A system
If they peak
They can compete at the beginning
But they may become a
Can't compete
It's a very, very slow competition
This
Then this will depend on a saturation point
Then I have to prove that the saturation point exists
So this is what experiments need to test
OK, I see
OK
Thank you
I have always
Who else just now
Is it
I have always wondered about the so-called competition
This word
Because from your equation
Your
Your source term is that F
It doesn't have time
It doesn't have time to be its
What do you call it?
Self-variable
So this is an elliptical equation
Then it's only related to the boundary conditions
It will always reach a
Steady state solution
So just now your data proved
It will eventually have a
Steady state
That is, a stable solution
That has a stable solution
It means that it won't change at any time
That won't change at any time
It means that
There will be no so-called competition between them
Relationship
So I have always been
I can't understand why
Math can prove
They will have a competition
Because there is a competition
Because
Can I interrupt you first?
OK
So that's it
Today
But indeed
It can reach a
Stable state
That is, the steady state solution
It may have two peaks
Right
But that doesn't mean
That steady state solution is stable
So this solution
It may be
Noise in any cell
Just
Get a bigger one
A smaller one
If it is unstable
This situation will make them compete
Then
Let it from a
Two-peak steady state solution
Becomes only one-peak steady state solution
Because there is only one
Steady state means
It won't change at any time
Yes
Steady state means
It won't change at any time
But if you leave the steady state
It may go to another steady state
At this time we will say
The original steady state is unstable
So this deviation
Must be in
Initial condition
It appeared
It can't say that this system is halfway
It reached
The current system reached the steady state
Then you have to say
It has a noise
Caused it to go to another place
Because when you have this noise
When it appears
Your system is completely different
Yes yes
This system is different
So
So you can't use
When I wrote this system
I should add a noise term later
That's right
Because in the cell
Noise is something that exists at any time
But if
Your source term
Source term should not only be f
Then uv
Should be f, uv
Then there is a time t
Then this system
May be a noise of time
It doesn't have to be a noise of time
That noise term doesn't need to be a noise of time
Oh
Just turn it into a snow machine
It will be in
It's a snow machine
Take data
You are in your take data
Throughout the history
There will be a moment suddenly
There will be fluctuation
I think that's what that t means
Yes
So actually I think
I probably know what you two are going to say
In fact, that is to say
If you just look at this value
It will actually reach the equilibrium at the end
Regardless of the equilibrium
That is
Is stable or unstable
It just shouldn't change
But if there is a fluctuation
It may suddenly fluctuate
Then put the unstable equilibrium
The whole is biased to another place
But this
This fluctuation should actually be written
There is a t in that F
But you didn't write it now
I think that's what it means
Yes
I understand what you are talking about
Theoretically, that's right
But anyway
Because I am now
Just because it's simple
I didn't write that noise term
But if
If its initial condition is noise
In fact, it won't really run to two peaks
Stay
That is
Like this
It's just that there is noise
It won't grow two exactly the same peaks
Then as long as they are two
These two peaks are a bit different
They will definitely compete
The only stable or steady state at the end
I can understand what you want to say
But what I want to say is that this picture
Can't represent what you want to say
Because this picture only shows
Its solution has not yet reached
Steady state
But I understand what you mean
I know
Yes
It did not reach the steady state at the beginning
If you put the steady state at the beginning
It won't
It will be stuck there
Then you have to give it a little bit of noise
It can only run to one
So what I mean is that this picture
There is no way to explain what you are talking about
But I can understand what you want to say
Sorry
Because I am doing the value simulation
So I have always been
Strange
That
Some strange
Yes
What we do is to solve
Solve two peaks
Then solve a peak
Then
Prove that the two peaks are not stable
In this case
Once we know that the two peaks are not stable
In fact, when we run the simulation
Even if the solution is there
The simulation will not run to that solution
It is not an attractor
It will run to the stable
Steady state solution
So they almost never really go
Unstable solution
From a mathematical point of view
It will definitely
It's what you just said
Put two peaks, one peak
As long as there is no noise
Your equation is always that group
Then its source term noise is exactly the same
It will definitely become the same solution
Because it is an elliptical equation
In terms of numbers, that's another problem
Because you can't prove
The numerical method you use
No numerical
Numerical noise
Because I just mentioned it
Ok that's it
I think
The simulation I just showed
The main noise term
Is my initial condition
Sorry, let me wipe it
How many more in your head
I just said
7.30 right
Yes
And 1, 2, 3, 4
But there are a lot of animations here
Otherwise I can walk faster
Then basically
I want everyone to watch the movie
Then
Otherwise we are like this
You finish it first
If we have time at the end, let's ask questions together
Thank you all
Deal
Ok
So now the situation is
I want to see in the game
Can really see this
Is
Composition from fast to slow
So it can grow two buds
First of all, we do one thing
When we were simulating
Let the composition
From fast to slow
The fastest way is to put that
The distance is long, right
So now we make a longer cell
This longer cell
What actually happens is
A real yeast
You should see two cells in the picture
Is a large cell
After the small cell
They will break
They are now broken
But after that
I let one of its proteins
Is responsible for breaking it
This protein is basically
Very unstable at 37 degrees
But stable at 24 degrees
So that protein
It is invalid
The result is that it can't be separated
The result is like this
You can look at the top cell first
It first grew a tooth
At this time, only one tooth grew
At this time, two teeth grew
OK
The following one
It grew a tooth
It grew three teeth
At this time, we can almost guess
When it only grows one tooth
Because it's not broken here
So its entire cell is all connected
It obviously has two
It looks like a cell, but it's not broken
But at this time, it only grew a tooth
We can almost be sure that
This is probably what we did before
But it grew to a certain length
But it found that it would grow a lot at this time
If we use the same method
Let's go inside
The one I just talked about
Is that the protein emits a silver light
You'll see
For example, let's say this one
This cell cycle is over
It seems to be happening too fast
It stopped growing
At this time, a bunch of them would grow at the beginning
A few of them disappeared
Only these two remain
After these two remain, they no longer compete
Then it becomes two teeth
At the same time, there are many of them growing at the same time
But in the end, these two compete
So it only grows one
This is the same situation
So we see that in the same group of cells
There are a bunch of cells here
And each cell actually
Some of them will grow on both sides
Some of them will grow on one side
In a population
About 65% of the population
It will grow two teeth
It looks like
I ran out of the previous solution
At the beginning, many different peaks came out
Then the small peak was quickly competed
After the big peak stayed
The competition became very slow
Then they will move forward
Then there are about 65% of the cells
It's two teeth
If I just said
The conclusion of the mathematical side is correct
If we put the whole system
If the amount of protein in the system is adjusted
Then my peak should be from saturated
It's not saturated
So it has to go from compete very slowly to compete very quickly
Right?
Then we should see less
Two-button cells
So what we do is
We are now comparing
The first bar is wild type
Except
Normal, non-separable yeast
Then the second bar is
Normal yeast
But it's inside
That red or blue guy
It only has half the amount
Then the third bar is
The yellow guy inside
The yellow protein has only half the amount
Then the fourth bar is
Both red and yellow have only half the amount
Then
The last bar is
All proteins in this cell have only half the amount
Then when we do this comparison
We found that
The more protein
It will have more cells
On both sides
Then the less protein
The less population
It grows on both sides
This means
This is pretty much
In line with our experiment
Our theory
Then
But then people will say
Maybe it's not a matter of distance
Maybe it's not a matter of protein quality
Maybe the distance plays a bigger role
Like you see the cell on the left
Is it longer
So it's slower
Because
Because of the spread
Because the longer the distance, the slower the spread
Then it will be more unbalanced
This is another assumption
But we found
If we go to the two-body cell and the one-body cell
Then measure the length of their cells
Then we found that they didn't have much difference
So this time I put this alternative hypothesis
Rejected
My own hypothesis is better
Then another hypothesis
Is a mathematical hypothesis
I said you talked so much math in front
It's really a bit boring
Because in fact we don't need this math
To explain this
Today if our competition process
Is a peak to put another peak
To compete
That is to suck dry
Let's say we have two peaks today
They don't need to saturate
Then these two peaks are higher
But there are more things inside
So it takes longer to suck dry
So if we are
Fixed at a certain time
It's going to start growing
At that time it will start to grow two
See, you don't need a saturation
Such an explanation
Then I want to reject this hypothesis
So I did this
In fact, in a math system
In addition to the positive feedback I just mentioned
It actually has a negative feedback
In a normal system
It still has a negative feedback
In the model
If we remove this negative feedback
It will increase the saturation point
The result of increasing the saturation point
That is to say
If the original amount of protein
Is the same
If you just increase the saturation point
At this time it will become less saturated
At this time it should
Compete faster
Because it's sharper
So it depends on
In the actual cells
If you remove this negative feedback
Is it like we thought
It will become faster
We found that
This cell
It is less saturated
I'll close the door
In this state
We found
In fact, if we compare
These two genes
There is a negative feedback
If there is no negative feedback
In fact, there is a negative feedback
It is
The amount of protein in the patch
Is relatively small
But even so, it still looks like it competes slower
Such a phenomenon
With my alternative hypothesis
I didn't explain it
So I rejected this alternative hypothesis
Okay
So far
The experiments I have done
It seems to be quite
In line with my math
The hypothesis
Instead of other possible hypotheses
So we got
To sum up
Three conclusions
One is
When I make the pathogen
Longer
It will become more
Its competition
The competition between the low-GTPS
It will become slower
So it becomes
It can increase by 2.5
Or even 3.5 or more
This is quite in line with my model
Then again
The saturation point can be moved
If we can move the saturation point
It means that basically
We can support the saturation point
In addition to the saturation point
In addition to this hypothesis
I can't think of any other hypothesis
To explain my last data
So I will end it here
I am basically in a lab of the military
And everyone is doing experiments
So on the left
This is my teacher
This is my senior
She has gone to Boston
They are doing experiments
This group is mathematicians
I can't write the proof
The proof part
These two guys wrote it for me
Thank you very much
I don't know how to write the proof
The following is my experiment
Thank you
Before entering Q&A
Because our time is late
So if you have any questions
You can leave
No need to force
In the dialogue room
I will post it again
There is a feedback form
You can fill in this video
Today
I am the host
How is the meeting
Then the quality of the connection
Then the quality of the speech
And so on
Then if you are interested in
The research of Jiangen
You can leave a message to him
Then I will help you forward it to Jiangen
If you want to
Leave your contact information
Then discuss it in depth
Then I will put it in the dialogue box
Everyone can please click
If you don't have any special
If you have any comments, please click
Because this information
We will apply for all kinds
This
Support or
That proposal
May use my data
Thank you for your help
Do you have any questions?
You can ask directly
Thank you for the chat box
Because I just
Can't see the chat box
Let me ask first
Is
Does anyone take this model
To study social phenomena
Because I always feel
If we take the cell membrane
As the territory of the United States
Then you use red and blue lines
Then this matter recently
Red and blue
And you see
What is mentioned in the video
Including
Basically not
Protein
Think of it as a person
Or something
Such a model
Can be used to simulate
Or predict social phenomena
Do you know anyone doing this?
What I know is
First of all, I will talk about the limit
That limit is first
I didn't model any highway
Or flying
So that diffusion
Basically
In real life
Will be defeated by a lot of this kind of fast transportation
So he can't
Model a lot of things
At least in today's society
I know someone doing
Turing pattern
Research on social science
Is about crime
More like in a local
Little city
Which point
For example
A certain area in downtown
Then it is easy to produce criminals
Then the criminals will assume
Can spread out
But at the same time there is another group of people outside
For example
I don't know if he is a policeman
Or a resident who is not a criminal
He can be a witness
Anyway, he is in the model
Dynamics between the two
He will have unknown changes at the same time
Then there are some
Criminals and witnesses
These interactions between the police
Some are like this
But in fact we have seen a lot
Purely with a
Deterministic
Model
I haven't seen a lot
Or at least
Because I'm looking
This is related to Turing pattern
Then I haven't seen a lot
Maybe a lot is related to Turing pattern
Ok very cool
Thank you everyone
I want to confirm
My understanding
This model
The most important thing should be
Between two species
The rate of spread is very large
This is the first point
The second point is
Because
In theory, this model should be
In the chemical field
Their molecular
Spreading
Between two different chemical substances
Then they
I am more curious about why
Their chemical
Expansion
Did not mention any
So-called Turing
Turing
How do you say it in English?
Because Turing
At the beginning of this
His imagined activator and substrate
Are chemical reagents
Then he imagined
In fact, this application is a lot
In the case of non-living things
Someone even found some chemical reactions
One is Diffuse slower
One is Diffuse faster
Of course they will have a rate of spread
So it won't be
It won't be mass conserved
They really have a way to
Add chemical reactions
Then he really ran out of dots
So do a lot in chemical reactions
So you have seen paper
Is the real world
Chemical substances will produce
What is this called?
Turing pattern
Is there such a thing in the real world?
Yes
Can work hard to give you
I haven't seen those for a long time
Because now it's chemical compounds
But you really are in a
Cultivator
Then you add a certain substance and another substance
Then they ran out of dots
I remember
Is there anyone
Is there anyone studying that cat?
Dog? What animal pattern?
Yes
That's more of a guess
Because if it is a chemical substance
What is your chemical substance
What is their reaction rate
All measured
So that model
How to write
But if it's in cats and dogs
We still
As far as I know
We don't know
Which one
Or
There is another
This is actually a more common
One is
But
It will inhibit
Even so
I can't find which one is the key
Which one is the key
Because there are too many molecules in the body
So I don't know
But they will point out
Look at the pattern of the cat
It's exactly the same
It must be like this
Mechanism
But no one really found that chemical substance
Even if you find that chemical substance
You have to write that thing
It is usually necessary to go through a lot of
Simplification
Because in the body
Any other questions
I have one
Common
I think
For example, like Zhang Yanping just asked
Say that in social science
Or
Social psychology
Is there a way to use such a model
Go
Do research
Then, for example, he used one here
A model like diffusion
Then someone just asked
That's it
At the beginning
When he proposed such a model
He is actually in chemistry
That is to say
But I myself
From the point of view of physics
I think
These are just
It's called effective model
It's not really
I think you can't
You have such a mathematical model
Then
To get data is the same
Then he interpreted this
Interaction
What is the nature of this system
Because
For example
Just
I think he just means
You have a quantity
Then it changes over time
It's a certain
He to another variable
How many times
You can actually write a super long
That is to say
You write super long
Then see which one comes out
Is the most like
But in fact, in chemistry
For example, in chemistry
The range of the equation
At least
That is to say
The size of the molecule
Otherwise you enter a completely different
Then you are different
So I think it's just
Effective model
Uh
Yeah, so we actually hate it
In fact, there are a lot of models
Will do this thing
Uh
In fact, like the original
It's the same
There is a
There is a mechanism
It will grow
Just
In physics
It's the same
But it doesn't mean
The mechanism of the original model
It's exactly the same
And indeed I told you today
This model is also a very
Very simplified
But there is actually a basis
That is to say
That's why I'm so happy to play with it
Because in fact
In terms of Helmholtz
Of course, this is also simplified
But in terms of Helmholtz
We know the molecule
In terms of
I can write a model
On the membrane
In the cytoplasm
And then
On the membrane
And then this scaffold
And this circle
And then they all have that protein
And if you kill one of the proteins
It really won't polarize
So these are all genetic data
In fact, it is very likely
There are a lot of data
This kind of circuit operation
But if I want to write this out
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6
No, it's actually
Diffusion equation
System
Then it's hard to study
But someone
After this simplification
It can go through some state-by-state assumptions
Then get one
This kind of simplified
So there is a theory
It's not entirely
I ran out of a model today
Then this model just
It's just
The appearance of the creature
So we think that model is wrong
I think this kind of model is
This is
Overclaiming the model
Can do things
I totally agree with what you just said
But so we will pay attention
We actually
Is that molecular mechanism a Turing mechanism?
Then we think it is
Because there are other creatures
Supporting it
If today I am directly using the mechanism
Piled up
Then this model
There is a way to see me in the creature
The phenomenon is the same
I didn't give it a direct assumption
You should look like a Turing mechanism
When my model is 8
When molecules
It can't tell it's a Turing
But it looks like a Turing
I'm more confident at this time
I think
It should be said
I don't know what the person who just asked
But my understanding
It should be what he wants to ask
You this model
What you are doing now is that you assume
Use a very logical way to infer a model
Then find this model
Results with your research data
Can
Match your research data
But such a conclusion
There is no way to prove
Your model is really
The mechanism of this real world
You can only say your model
It's just a model
It's not any law
The question I asked just now
My understanding is like this
I don't know if it's right
My understanding is the same
But the problem is
I can understand
If you have a model today
Then you can use it to infer
Then you can infer a result
Then it's the same as the phenomenon
This does not explain
How things actually happen
For example, I use a more familiar example
Even if I can model today
On Facebook
This
How to diffuse
Then how it is
Between Racism and Anti-Racism
Make adjustments
For this process
I can go to model this phenomenon
Then there is also effect
But this does not explain
I can understand that this does not explain
Then I am on Facebook
How to influence another user
Pull it to me
This is not the case
But conversely
If I can't make a reasonable statement at the beginning
Say
On Facebook
Interaction with people
Satisfy diffusion
I won't set this model at the beginning
Because you are blind
I want to set it up
I don't believe anyone sets it up like this
Like when I first started
Really
Many models do this
There are so many physics
No one talks about it
May be this mechanism
We have a lot of people here
Models mess up
Sometimes I hate it
Make us famous
But I want to talk about
At the beginning
When using this model
He also said first
We actually have a protein here
It looks like it can satisfy
This model
The assumption at the beginning
Or the description of that
Only use it
So I don't think
In the case of Jenkins
There is a big problem
Of course I don't think
You have this problem
I don't think he meant it
But
I think I understand what he said
I think
Because my model
There are some mechanistic bases
There are some
Data
Is to support
These chemical reactions
So I'm more confident about my model
But even so
Anyway, I can't say
That model itself
Is what actually happened
I totally agree with this sentence
But actually from a more scientific
If you think about it
Which model
All models are false
He must have gone through some simplifications
At least he went through some simplifications
In fact
Even when we
Understand any system
The truth we understand
It's not a truth
All the theories we understand
It's not the truth
And we don't know
There is no way to know
The theory we understand is the truth
There is no way to verify
Or
Yes
First of all
There is no way to verify
And it's very hard to deny
What we can do
Like what I was trying to do
I have a model today
Or I have a theory
If there is only one theory
It's hard for me to know
Is it right
For example, God created man
It's hard for me to know
But if I have another theory
For example, this theory
Explaining other phenomena is better than this
Or this theory
There is a way
This theory is easy to be denied
We need to compare two theories
The advantages between them
We have a way to
To be more realistic
It should look like this
In the process
Of course there is no theory
It's real
We can only try to be as realistic as possible
The process of being realistic
We try to compare different theories
Put the bad theory aside
Then compare with a different theory
Then put the bad theory aside
Then try to be realistic in this process
But our theory will never be true
I think it's totally fine
Because when you say
You are a model
It has already shown that it is such a thing
Because if you are from
Applied mathematics
Model, theorem, law
These all represent different things
So if you use the definition of people
In the field of applied mathematics
When you say it is a model
In fact, people in the field of applied mathematics
They won't care about
The mechanism behind the model
They will only ask
You have a model, you have done validation
You have done verification
Then this model is
A reasonable model
As for whether this model
Represents physics or the real world
In fact, from the point of view of applied mathematics
It's not that important
Because since you already call it a model
It means that as long as it works
That's it
But we still try our best
I hope our model can explain
Is to be as realistic as possible
Because we
After all, in the end, we want to solve the problem of life
OK
We don't have much time, is there any question?
OK, just say it
Yeah, no, because
I may have to leave at half past five
I need to leave and prepare
For the audience
Thank you very much for your support today
Thank you very much for your questions
I'm sorry it's a bit of a drag
I hope this cross-field research
Although it is cross-field
Because for me, cross-field
We are always stuck in different areas
In different areas
Our only advantage is that we can
Talk to people in different areas
Then I hope this video
Today's speech has a little bit with
Have conversations in different areas
Everyone can understand what I'm talking about
Then
Put this idea together a little bit
Be able to do something
Then I think this is pretty good today
Thank you very much
Thank you, Jian, very, very cool
Very wonderful
Thank you all again, bye