My PhD research is mainly in microfluidics for single-cell analysis.
In the content of biology, I mainly focus on cancer research.
Because we generally believe that in cancer, the heterogeneity between cells is stronger.
For example, when we treat cancer, there will always be some antibody cells that can be used for therapy.
So if we can use single-cell analysis to see the different characteristics of each cell,
and find those antibodies to lock them in for treatment,
we believe that it can improve the efficacy of the treatment.
My research is divided into two parts.
The first part is the phenotypic assay, which I will share with you today.
The second part is also what I'm doing now.
Because I haven't published the paper yet, so I haven't put it up here yet.
But the whole direction is like what Jake just introduced.
As a sample preparation chip,
we can extract circulating tumor cells from the patient's blood.
We get gene expression information from the cancer cells in the blood.
This gene expression information can let us know
what kind of drugs we can use to treat these patients to get better results.
For now, to get this gene expression information,
we usually use the whole flow of chips.
In other words, we need to use a knife.
It's more invasive, and the cost will be higher.
Today, I will share with you the phenotypic assay.
In the technology development, I mainly focus on scaling and automation
in the high-throughput single-cell device sphere assays.
First, I will tell you why we want to do this tumor sphere assay.
In fact, the purpose is to study these tumor-initiating cells.
In this process, I will share with you
why we need to scale up this assay and automate this assay.
Next, I will tell you how I enable this thing.
Then, I will use some experiments to show you the functions of my chip.
Finally, I will conclude my presentation today.
OK.
So, our motivation is to study these so-called cancer stem-like cells.
Our recent research shows that
there is a relatively small number of tumor-initiating cells.
They are called cancer stem cells.
Some people think the term cancer stem cells is too strong.
They prefer to call them cancer stem-like cells.
In fact, it is a biological mutation.
They are a group of antibodies
with some stem cell-specific cancer cells.
This tissue group has some characteristics.
The first one is that it has a relatively strong chemoresistance.
It will cause tumor relapse.
In this picture, you can see that this is a primitive tumor.
The yellow one is CSC, cancer stem cell.
The blue ones are normal cancer cells.
If we use traditional cancer treatment,
these ordinary cells can be removed.
So, we can see that the tumor size is reduced in clinical trials.
But what we can't see is this cancer stem cell.
It has a way to stay quiescent
and not be affected by the drug.
After we stop giving drugs,
the tumor relapse occurs.
So, in the research scope of CSC,
we hope to find cancer stem cell-specific therapy.
So, I eliminated it for this CSC.
The rest of these normal CSC,
sorry, these normal cancer cells,
they don't have the ability to self-renew.
So, they proliferate.
In the end, the tumor relapse occurs.
So, this is the first reason why we want to study CSC.
The second reason is that we generally believe that
CSC has a strong migration ability.
In other words, it is easier to metastasize to the secondary tumor.
We know that cancer transfer is the biggest challenge in cancer therapy
and the biggest cause of death.
So, if we can study CSC more,
it will be very helpful in therapy, tracking, and research.
The most traditional way to study CSC is to use surface membrane protein
or intracellular enzymatic markers.
For gene expression or protein expression,
we use different methods, such as full cytometry,
to separate these different types of cells.
Then, we can study these CSC groups.
But the challenge is that
many of our new markers have not been discovered.
So, we hope to use other methods to study these CSC populations.
As a substitute, cell behavior is a common choice.
We observe that CSC can survive in a suspension culture environment
and grow into a single-cell-derived tumor sphere.
In other words, if it is a normal cancer cell,
it cannot be adhered to the substrate environment.
It will produce apoptosis.
But CSC is different.
It can not only survive in a suspension environment,
but also grow into a new tumor sphere.
So, what is the traditional way to do the sphere assay?
The method is to buy a whale plate,
as shown in the picture on the bottom right.
Then, dilute the whale plate to a certain level of cell concentration.
The whale plate contains one cell.
As you can see,
the low-throughput is a distribution of the probability,
or more specifically,
96-whale plate contains 20-30 single-cells.
It is labor-intensive.
Someone may ask,
can I use automatic cell dispensing,
such as flow cytometry,
to ensure that I can put a cell into a whale?
In fact, flow cytometry has a big problem.
Because it is a flow-sorting process,
it will produce a lot of shear stress.
So, what is the impact of cell behavior assay on downstream?
We need to observe if the cell is dead.
If the cell is dead,
it is not caused by the suspension environment.
It is caused by the flow-sorting process.
The shear stress is too high,
and the cell can not bear it.
So, the cell is dead,
not because it is not CSC.
These are the existing technology limitations.
Why do we think automation is important?
As we mentioned,
CSC is a relatively small sub-population.
In the past,
only 1-5% of tumor cells have this sphere formation tendency.
We hope this assay can start with a larger single-cell population.
At least 1,000 single-cells.
Then we can have a reliable statistical power
to make our assay conclusion.
So, we think
to achieve this throughput,
microfluidics is an ideal technology
to make this assay.
So, this is our chip schematics.
We want to develop a chip
with more than 1,000 single-cells.
Because we have a very large throughput,
we also need an automatic image analysis.
Otherwise, we have to read it manually.
It is a very difficult process.
Only in this way,
can we make the whole experiment
smoothly improve on hardware and software.
So, this is our motivation.
I don't know if there is anything I didn't explain clearly.
Or you can go on.
Ok, let's continue.
I want to ask,
why CSC can survive in suspension culture environment?
This is a question.
Did you hear it?
Yes.
The question is,
why CSC can survive in suspension culture environment?
This is a very interesting question.
I will answer it in two ways.
First,
the definition of CSC is
we only inject 10 cells into the mouse.
Can these 10 cells
generate a new tumor on the mouse?
If yes,
we define it as CSC.
The predecessors defined CSC in this way.
Then, they used this traditional conventional assay
to find out
the cell population of tumors
can survive in suspension culture environment.
This is the first way to find it out.
Why?
Our idea is
CSC can survive in suspension culture environment
by moving through the local environment
to the blood vessel.
The blood vessel is a suspension environment.
If these cells
die in the suspension environment,
they can't move to other places.
So, we believe
CSC can survive in the blood vessel
and grow into a tumor in a new local environment.
We simulate this in vivo environment.
This is how we research CSC.
Firstly,
CSC was confirmed
through invisible experiment!
Why we developed this correlation experiment?
It mimics the ways
how the muscle will survive in blood vessel
and grow into a tumor in the new local environment!
Does this answer your question?
I have a related question.
When CSC is transferred in blood vessel,
is it in the form of a single cell
or a sphere?
This is a very good question.
Most of the cells
are transferred in the form of a single cell.
But in recent years,
the research of circulating tumor cells
found that
the real cause of the transfer
is the cluster.
But the cluster is not a single cell
that grows into a sphere
and then transferred to other places.
People usually believe that
a small number of cells
fall from the original tumor
and it can circulate.
You can imagine that
in a vast ocean,
is it a warship
or an aircraft carrier?
People think that
the cluster is like an aircraft carrier.
It is very powerful
and has a stronger metastasis ability.
But people think that
the cluster fell from the original tumor
and not a single cell
that grows into a sphere
and then transferred.
Does this answer your question?
Yes.
OK.
Are there any other questions?
I don't think so.
You can continue.
I want to ask a question about operation.
For example,
if a worker
is holding a pipe and dripping,
can he get a single cell?
Now,
what is the practical number?
For example, 10%? 20%?
Or how many?
The best theoretical limit
is 20% to 30%.
You can think of it as
a cell suspension solution.
Let's say I know
that there are 10K cells
in this tube.
How many of them are there?
You can calculate
that there are one cell
per 100 or 10 microliters.
Microliters go one by one.
The theoretical limit
of this operation model
is 20% to 30%.
In fact,
the control of cell density
is not so ideal
when operating.
So it will be 20% to 30% worse
than the operating limit.
It will be worse,
but it's almost the same, right?
For example,
is it 10% or what?
Or is it less than 5%?
If you have good skills,
it can be less than 5%.
If you don't have good skills,
it can be 5% or less.
It's basically difficult to do experiments.
So it's about 15% or so.
Yes,
so everyone usually...
so you want to see
if you have 96 well-planned,
you have Taipei almost 100 times,
you have 15 cells,
and you only have 1% to 5% single cell
that can grow into a sphere.
That experiment is too difficult to do.
Yes,
are there any other questions?
I don't think so.
You can continue.
Okay,
I will continue to present.
So the first thing I want to discuss is
how we achieve single cell capture
in a high-throughput manner.
The way we implement
is by microfluidics.
The principle is quite simple.
We capture single cells
by channel blocking.
So you can imagine
this is a
microfluidics,
microwell or microchamber.
This is a capture site.
The blue part is the channel,
where the water flows.
The round part is the flowing cells.
When the cells come in,
they block to this place.
So the flow basically stops.
The next cell will go to the next place.
So every well has only one cell.
If we only have
10 or 20 chambers,
a simple design would be fine.
But in this workbook,
we have to scale
up to tens of thousands of chambers.
At this time,
this simple duplication
will cause a big flow imbalance.
In other words,
if the whole
flow cell comes in,
it will mostly be upstream or downstream.
The capture rate
will be very, very low.
How do I make
the cell uniformly distributed
on this
array?
The method I use is
circuit modeling.
In fact, this whole microfluidics
is like a full circuit.
Every channel
has a flow group.
This flow group
is dominated by the capture site.
This flow group is the largest
because the size is the smallest.
The entrance channel
and the exit channel
are relatively small,
but because they are long,
the build-up resistance is also large.
The build-up resistance
from 1 to 200
accumulates in each channel.
We just said that
simple duplication won't work.
If we want a good distribution,
every branch
has the same current.
We know that
if the upper part
is short,
the resistance here is small,
the resistance here is also small,
this thing can happen.
But if we put 200
negligible resistance here,
the performance of the current
will be much worse
than what we want.
How do we
balance the current?
Flow resistance is actually
a function of channel geometry.
You can see
circular or rectangular
are different functions.
In short, the longer the channel,
the higher the resistance.
The wider the width,
the smaller the resistance.
So we use
microfabrication
to make the
opening
10 microns by 10 microns
in size.
First,
this can achieve high flow resistance.
Second,
10 by 10 can block
the cancer cell.
We believe that
the size of the cancer cell
is greater than 10 microns.
I will explain this later.
We have overcome
the microwave flow resistance
we have defined here.
What about the entrance channel
and the NC channel?
I use
microfabrication
to make a geometry
100 microns wide
and 100 microns high.
I can make the entrance channel
and the NC channel
smaller than
the cancer cells.
In short,
we use microfabrication
to control the flow resistance.
So we have a good
flow circuit to achieve
single cell capture.
This shows
three different sizes
of chips
from 800
to 12800
chamber chips.
The size is shown
on the slide.
This is a
device mirror.
Each chamber
can capture a single cell.
This is a microscope image.
The cancer cell is labeled
as green fluorescent dye.
The array
has a good single cell capture.
Now we can
achieve high-throughput
single cell capture.
How do we analyze it?
This is a comic.
I have
a