Okay
Oh
F
Oh, I forgot
Share
Share screen
Wow
Okay
Okay, so the topic I'm going to talk about today
is
Dark Matter Super CDMS
which is what I'm doing right now
and the Super Conductive Future
of Particle Physics
which is
what I'm doing right now
Okay, next page
The topic I'm going to talk about today
will be divided into two parts
The first part is
the physical part
I'm going to talk about Dark Matter
which is mainly
focused on
the direct detection
part of the experiment
What is its physics?
What is the current
state of the field?
What is everyone's goal? What are the difficulties?
How to do this experiment? How to measure this thing?
It should be more reliable
and more interesting
The second part will be my own work
which is quite R&D
People who are interested in
technology may be more interested
But it should be very related
Okay
My screen is a bit laggy
First of all, because we have already
introduced it before
What is
the basic example
of a
model and a theoretical basis
So I'm going to talk about it very quickly
So basically
Can you see my mouse?
Can you see it?
There are many basic examples
We think these basic examples
are the basic materials
we know
in the universe
But
because of some reasons
we think there are still things in the universe
that we don't know
We can't use this model to explain
But anyway, this is called Standard Model
It is the best description
If you are
interested in this
You can look it up on Wikipedia
There are six quarks
three leptons
neutrinos
and X
Okay
The point I want to talk about today
will focus on
the ones you can see on the screen
The red one is a mole
The blue one is a neutrino
Basically, this is
the most important example for us
Because honestly, in life
the most important thing is
the things you are interested in
the things you breathe
and the things that make up you
These are the only two
Okay
Then
Sorry, there are electrons
These are the three
There is another important one
The white ghost
It is called light
It sounds very mysterious
like a laser gun
So
these things
exchange light like baseball
and they will
reach the energy balance
Basically, the heat balance
After reaching the heat balance
everything will have a black hole
Okay
This is very important
Because my family often ask me
Is dark matter a black hole?
Actually, it is not
You will know why
It is very vague
This is the universe we usually see
When we look at it
the whole universe is black
Then you will say
Why do we think
everything is the matter we know
and it will exchange light
like a baseball
This is actually
the universe we see
with a good instrument
Like this
The whole universe is basically bright
The different colors
are basically the same as the black hole
It corresponds to different temperatures
Okay
You see the brightest one in the middle
It is the galactic plane
There are many planets
and a lot of energy
So there will be a lot of energy
Okay
My mouse
Okay, you see the back
This part is very red
The energy here is very low
It only has a foreground
It only has a background
The background is the whole background of the universe
It is very cold
It is only 3 degrees K
But basically it has a temperature
So we can still see it
Okay
This picture is basically
filled with colors
How can we say there is any dark matter
that we don't know
Let me see the next page
Because there was a very wise man
He said
Vader was seduced by
The dark side of the force
The force is what gives Jedi his power
It's an energy field
created by all living things
It surrounds us
It permits us
It binds the galaxy together
It sounds very confusing
I don't know what he is talking about
So I will focus on it
The dark side of the force
It is the dark side that binds us together
This phrase is from 1976
So you can imagine
This is probably the time
when we started to be interested in
dark matter
I think this statement is correct
We started to have dark matter
Okay
So
Actually
What does this mean
There is a picture here
The center is the brightest part
The brightest part is the center of our galaxy
Then the horizontal axis
is the distance from the center of the galaxy
to the outside
The vertical axis is
the particle
in that position
The speed of rotation around the center of the galaxy
Then you can see
the yellow data
The yellow data is
the stars over there
Okay, like the sun
So we can see those stars
are moving
We know how fast they are moving
Then the yellow data
is the part of the galaxy
That is
the size of the galaxy
300 years ago
But then we found
We can keep looking out
According to the dark radiation we just used
Our instrument is getting better
We can see the infrared
Then we see
the blue hyperfine structure
The blue dot
That's basically
the light source
You can keep pushing
to the outside
The position of 50,000 light years
It can be connected
This is what we know now
The size of a galaxy
Okay
Then we go through
to see
What we see
The speed of these particles
We can go
Okay, there's a point
According to the relativity
It's basically Newton's law
According to
the traditional law we know
We can guess
We just see the speed
We can guess how much mass there is
It goes around this kind of thing
It goes around the inner side of the orbit
So we get
We get the following line
Okay
But actually
What we observe
The speed of rotation is the line above
Okay
So in the middle
You will find that
The speed of rotation
is the speed of the line above
The actual weight of the orbit
is much more than
what we can see
Okay
So we really can't see it
In the 1980s
That's because our instrumentation
is not good enough
There's nothing you can't see
Okay
So for a while
Dark matter still had some
controversy
Then in the 1980s to the 1990s
We started to know
that everything we can see is almost right
So we started to think
Is it that the particles we know
can meet this nature
The answer is yes
There are three kinds of particles
There are three kinds
Anyway, there is one
There are three kinds of particles
It does have this nature
But what we know
Here is a point
We think we don't know
Some people
What we already know
It basically has something to do
with the particles we already know
Because the particles and the particles
are composite
They have a proportional relationship
Because they will
use it when they change
So according to all the stars we observe
Those stars are the particles and the particles
We can reverse the most
How many particles are there
Can it
cover our
missing mass budget
The answer is that it can't exceed 6%
Can't exceed 6% at most
Okay
So basically we think
It may be new physics
The more things
The answer is that it shouldn't be like this
Because the quality you see
You estimate it as a line
So you mean
If I have more images I can't see
Will fit the original data
That is to say, when the upper line is
When the upper line is more
So why is it bigger when the upper line is more
Let's write a book
Is it easier to turn like this
Then assume that the middle is symmetrical
You can think of it as all in the middle
Ok
Just that
Transverse speed
Yes yes yes
Oh no
It's the speed of turning
So actually you can see
Its speed
What is the real speed
Hundreds of kilometers per hour
That every second
So it's really slow
Basically it is
It doesn't have to be close to the speed of light
Ok
This number will be a bit important
So actually darkmatter
There are a lot of clues
I won't say it's evidence
I haven't measured it yet
So there are a lot of clues
This clue is actually the most suspicious
There are a lot of reasons for him
Don't think like this
But darkmatter has a lot of other clues
I put it in the background
If you are interested, you can ask
Ok
So anyway
We have to have extra quality
To produce extra power
Or somehow you want your theory
To explain this question
Is there any use of darkmatter?
Ok
Then I will jump directly to
This is what I saw recently
I think it's very interesting
That article
And I think you should know better than me
Ok
You should know who this is
Yes
This is my
This is the latest issue of CERN Courier
An article
It's
I magnified the focus
But I still have citations
So I magnified the citation
It says
Let's see where to start
Ok
Let's see
Here
It says
Basically they say
EPR pair
Refer to ER Einstein Rosenbridge
And one part that connects the two
Part of the black hole geometry
And then
This idea spring
By many theorists
In particular in the context
Of ADS-CFT correspondence
Ok
Let's look back
The point is
The problem with this theory is
I think it's motivated by
What I just said
So it can work
In galaxy scale
But the problem is
It can't
Or it's not good enough
In phenomenology
To work
To estimate
Something bigger
For example, I just said
A galaxy
Then it will have a
Modified gravity effect
But the problem is
We have another observation
If there are two galaxies
Then these two galaxies
Have a dark matter
Then they contrast
We can see two
Things like matter
Dark matter and non-active matter
This kind of local
Dynamic behavior
It doesn't have a good way to explain
Its work now
Is to say
If it is a whole universe
It will have
Modified CMB
Is it effective?
Ok
I actually framed another part
How would
Emergent gravity affect
The physics
Someone asked me
There are many different explanations
For example, extra dimension
EREPR
Modified gravity
Modified Newtonian dynamics
It's a standard name
But why do we want to do dark matter
I think the reason is simple
Because dark matter can be done
Even if you
Don't think it's a good
Maybe it's the right theory
But rule out and prove it
Should be equally important
So we are doing this now
But I would say this mod is difficult to do
But someone is thinking
For example, microgravity
Some light experiment
That
The details
I think you should know better than me
So I don't really understand
There can be special
That
It means
Right
So what I just imagined
Assuming there is an extra dimension
Contact
Then your thinking
3 plus 1
Will be proportional to
This contact
Its size
So if you are here
Bigger or smaller
It's more likely to be proportional
To the outside
But this
Compactify
Dimension
Right
Assuming the size
Is not constant
Here is so big
Then it means in different places
Four or more
Its size will be different
Should be possible
I don't know how they do it
But
The point is that someone thinks so
Then
I think
I'll jump back
Faster
Where did I say
Ok
Actually
It's more interesting
That
If someone is interested in other
Various
Prediction
Various observations
So
We have a missing mass
A
So
What you see now
Is our Milky Way
This is what we think of Milky Way
The Milky Way we see
Then next to it, I help you zoom in
That's our solar system
Then we go around the sun
The third one over there
Why is this important
Because we do experiments on the earth
Everyone knows how important it is
What about the picture in the upper left corner
Is to say
This is not a special phenomenon
That is to say, only our Milky Way Galaxy
Because before
A lot of people think
Will you observe like this
Is it because we are in the Milky Way
So we are in the Milky Way
That is not the center of gravity
Then observe there
Then you have to correct it
Such a
A constant change
That
Will there be a problem with this experiment
But this thing
It's basically a
A
A whole observation of the 70s
Completely broken
This person later got that
President's Freedom Award
He observed a lot of galaxies
Then there is such a phenomenon
So what you see in the upper left corner is
I said that
The speed of rotation
It's really flat, isn't it?
But if you
Gmm is equal to R squared
In fact, it should be
In contrast to once
That is, it will keep going down
Uh, once
V squared will be in contrast to R
OK, so we really think
What should it look like
It should look like this
It's a little bit of lag
There is a halo
Something like a light cloud
OK, so this thing is called Dark Matter Halo
Then we are in that
Inside, so we have been constantly
In Dark Matter Halo
Uh, moving is being soaked inside
A feeling of being soaked inside
I have a question, then you
Uh, that is to say
How big is it
Its scale
Its effect will come out slowly
Because you want to look at the Galaxy scale
Then I said, for example, the solar system scale or the galaxy group scale
It will also have a laser curve
Then when you draw it out
Is it the same as that
Oh, I forgot to put that thing
That is
This is very interesting, you can ask a question
How long does it take for us to turn the sun
One year, right?
Then we solar system
How long does it take to turn the galaxy
OK
Basically, there is no life
Can feel the difference
So you can imagine
We are in a
With
The center of the galaxy as the origin
Coordinate inside
Surrounding the sun to do local rotation
Can you
So basically in this Dark Matter Halo
Inside
We are actually in a fixed position
Local place will keep turning
So what will you get in the end
You will
If you measure the local
The speed of that halo
I said
Dark Matter
Wait a minute, you just asked
The speed of the planet
Ok, let me tell you
The speed of the earth itself around the sun
Will dominate this
This measurement
OK
So actually someone found something very interesting
It should be said that Propose is a very interesting concept
Because we are
Relative to our life
And the time scale we use
We are in Dark Matter Halo
Solar system in Dark Matter Halo
Basically fixed
That point is not moving
Your whole life will not change
A pixel on the earth
But the earth has been around
So the earth is equal to
The solar system is sitting in a
Constant Dark Matter Week
A Dark Matter
Wind inside
Keep moving in the same direction
Then we have half a year
Half a year is against it
This is called Dark Matter Annual Modulation
It can be a
Probing
Dark Matter as a particle
A very important phenomenon
About ten years ago
They measured
And then all the other people couldn't
Reproduce that experiment
Do you know this
In addition to the
The scale of the solar system
It's a little bit bigger
But smaller than the galaxy
See
There are a lot of stars in the galaxy
Is a lot of
Oh, I don't know
I don't know
Because usually we
We are
Anyway, everyone is talking about
What clues are there in Dark Matter
Just use a few scales
Galaxy
It's a bunch of galaxies
It's called Megastructure
And then there's the whole universe
There are about four
Will there be a star group in the middle
I don't know
Maybe someone is doing it
The next one
But
Oh, yeah, I have that doll up there
That's it
So
Then we think it's weird
Since we're sitting on the whole earth
Including ourselves
Do you feel like you're being blown by the wind
Or has the ghost been pushing you
The answer is no
So
A very popular theory
That is
We're all surrounded by
Dark Matter
OK, just like we're all surrounded by air
But they basically
Won't put their
Momentum to us
It won't interact with us
OK
This is smaller than air
Because we're actually air
I don't feel the interaction
But Dark Matter basically has a theory
The first two are the substances we already know
And then they interact with each other
In the form of throwing the ball
So they can pass on
That's what we know
And then
It's all Dark Matter next to it
But Dark Matter has no way to catch the ball
Just stand there and watch
Of course
But he has gravity
Yeah, so
So we put one over there
Gravity pole
It's the only thing that can interact with us
It's pulling us
So we can
Basically this is the only
We can see that
The reason for the Rotational Curve
OK
Because it has a gravitational interaction with us
Can this be localized?
Let's say we have a
Dark Matter here
Let's say it's a ball
Would it enhance
The gravitational pull between the substances?
How does it interact with you?
Oh, yeah, that's what I just said
Microgravity
This thing is very interesting
You either measure a very large scale
why
Because you can have a very large group of Dark Matter
You can measure the great pull
Then this approach will become
There is a
What is it called?
Lensing is Gravitational Lensing
In fact, we can use what we know
Baryonic Matter
But a lot of people are doing
There is a galaxy far away
Then it also has a
Dark Matter Halo
And then there's something behind it
So we can see what's behind it
Then we can see
The effect of this galaxy
Can we go to
So this lens
How heavy is it?
Then we can see how bright this lens is
So we can guess how heavy its Baryonic Matter is
I don't know
I don't know why I have to talk about Baryonic Matter when I do astronomy
Standard Model of Matter
How heavy is it?
Then this is a way
There are a lot of measurements
Measurement and
Does it match?
But it's a total
Because if you measure it like this, it's a total
Because you're looking at a very far
A very far galaxy
As a mirror
A lens is not a mirror
So a lot of people are doing
Is what you said
Can I do it on Earth?
For example, I'm on the table
I know how heavy this apple is
How heavy that banana is
How big is the gravitational pull between them
But if there's Dark Matter in the middle
How much should it change
The problem with this is that you can control all the experiments
But their signals are small
Because things are light
So it's hard to do
But if there's a breakthrough in this part
It will be a completely different
For Theory
But this is
This is more like what you're talking about
We're measuring the magnitude of the current current
This we know
Because if Dark Matter
If it's small, it's not
But it's like this
So
The problem here is
How big is your sensitivity?
How big is your experiment sensitivity?
Because we're measuring the magnitude
It should all be from astronomy
Just look at the big
Gravitational Source
I don't know
I don't know what they're doing right now
But someone is doing it
This is actually a very interesting experiment for me
But I think it's been five or ten years
Should all be very
Test performance
There will be no breakthrough
I have a question
Dark Matter seems to be man-made
Oh
This is a completely
Different idea
You have to talk about
Just talk about man-made
That's what LHC wants to do
I'll talk about it later
Yeah, because if it's man-made
Maybe you can measure the difference
Oh, I know what you mean
Theoretically, right?
It's Gravity
If it's a pile of matter
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes
But I don't think I can measure it
The reason is the same as just now
Because your weight is small, it's hard to measure
So now the problem is
Of course we know there is
Golden mass
But I'm not sure if it's dark matter
No one knows what it is
But what you can imagine is
You can modify what you originally used to do
Assuming something
Assuming Newton's law is right
That is, there is less matter
Or Newton's law
Then you have to modify that
Anyway, either case
You have to come up with a theory
What we are doing is to treat it as a particle
Yes, it's a particle
To do
Its only interaction is gravity
OK
This is what I want to talk about
So it just stands there and doesn't do anything, right?
So our current assumption is
Dark matter doesn't interact
This sentence is correct
If you talk to astronomers
In all of our roles
Dark matter will never work with you
What are you doing
OK
But what is our hope
Our hope is
Next page
It's a very, very, very
Small chance
It's actually going to be with us
This red
Red is straight or neutral, I forgot
Anyway, it interacts with our normal matter
But what are its conditions
Its condition is to be small
That is to say
You want this opportunity to be small
In all previous experiments
It looks like it has no interaction
But you will feel that
It's already so small, so why do you have to assume it
There is actually another reason
Because
We are directly
Attack Dark Matter
Before we measure directly
We have a lot of other theoretical examples
It predicts
New example
OK
It's not just what we know now
Then these new examples
With
The whole complete
The larger and more complete theory
Its interaction is very weak
Weak to all other
The experiments we have done before
It looks like it has no interaction
But it is not completely
This is the point
Then it is more important
That value
Is what we should be able to measure
As long as we design a
Dedicated experiment
So some people think
This is very important
In fact, we can't measure
It's not that it doesn't interact
But we don't have a very sensitive way to measure it
So we always thought it was completely
But in fact
If we measure it today
We think it should interact with us
This sensitive detector
There is still no interaction
Then we can rule out the old theory
Which we did many times
I will talk about it later
So what is the current situation
The current situation is
The earth is over there
Red is our experiment
We put it on the earth
Then we are in the dark matter
So as the center of the coordinate
Dark matter has been hitting us crazy
Then we hope that many
One will hit our detector
Then hit the detector
The situation is actually quite serious
Like you hit the ball
I wrote it there
Come in and out
It passes a little bit of kinetic energy to the detector
Then what we want to measure is this little bit of kinetic energy
it is good
This is what we want to do
How do we actually do it?
Okay, let's start to move on
That is to say our project
This is not our project
But I want to talk about it first
The two most popular methods on the earth
Then I want to
Then we have to say in our work
Why do we think this is better
This is the first method
Called Time Projection Chamber
That red line is dark matter
Dark matter comes in
After a lot of times
It hit the bucket
Detected matter in the basket
Then like hitting the ball
Then go out
Then it passes the energy to the line like a caterpillar
What is that line?
Inside the bucket
Is our so-called
Target Matter
What do I usually talk about?
Anyway, it's Target Matter
Then it passes a little energy to this
Material
The atomic box of this element
Then the atomic box
After some energy
Pass this energy to it
Electrons on the track
The electrons will move forward and then fall
Then the light will come out
The light is the yellow line of the caterpillar
OK
Then this flash of light
It will spread out
The PMT above and below
PMT is called Photon Multiplier Tube
Photon Multiplier Tube
Basically it is a very sensitive light sensor
You can measure that light
Then I just talked about it
Then it will absorb the energy
Pass it to the electrons and then fall
Then you know that the moonlight
The light released is a fixed color
Is a fixed energy
So you look at the energy of this color
How strong it means
How many electrons are released
Then you can push it back
How much energy did it eat
OK
This is the first signal
Then the second signal
Did I just say
It will have an electron moonlight
Then the electron moonlight
In addition to this kind of falling
This ratio is separated
OK
What about these electrons
It is in this up and down vertical direction
Put a very, very strong power plant
I wrote it there
It's probably thousands of volts per centimeter
For one
You look at the picture below
The vertical direction of the barrel is probably tens of thousands of volts
It will use this very strong power plant
Put
The electron is pulled all the way
Just drag it all the way
It's a virtual caterpillar on top
OK, that virtual caterpillar hit the detector
It has a secondary signal
So there is such a method
Can you
Then because it is pulled up
Speed is a fixed speed
It's probably a fixed speed
Is the electron in the material
Drifting speed
So you count that
Flash, flash is basically a moment
Just flash and see
The speed at which you receive the electron
The time difference in the middle
Can you reverse the distance
OK, do you know what I mean
If you have a row of electrons being drifted
Then every one reaches a different distance
You reverse the whole thing and you get a track
Then through this track
You can vary
Roughly
Different
Hit your example
So you can tell
Is it that we already know the particle hit us
Or its behavior is consistent
This is what we should expect
This is called Time Projection Chamber
What about its problem
OK, let's talk about its advantages
Its advantage is
The material is usually
Liquified
What
That
Xenon
Or
Argon
Argon, Xenon
These are the two types of deflection
So it's actually a very heavy element
Then we
We know the heavy element
It's a bit like
If you hit a heavy thing today
Hit the air molecules with you
The air molecules will get more
Energy or something heavy
It should be heavy
So if today Dark Matter hits
Hit a heavier atomic box
It can leave more energy
Then we know that this energy is equal to the square of M
The square of the atomic box
So the signal is very big
And it's actually easy to scale up
Why scale up is important
Because basically there are
How many Dark Matters pass through your detector
How big is it with your detector
How many atomic boxes are there
So if you have a two-fold detector
Basically
The rate of the expected signal should be twice
They are easy to put a lot of
They are basically a big bucket
A super high voltage
It sounds crazy, but it's actually easy
Basically
To summarize
This is state-of-the-art optimization
Of a widely used
High-energy physics technology
Invented in the 70s
OK
They want to state-of-the-art
Optimize this very widely used
What are the benefits
They can scale up very quickly
And they know what problems they will encounter
So currently this approach
Is the most sensitive
In terms of event rate
OK
The second one
Another one is Solid State Detector
Why is this thing
Let me talk about it
What you see on the picture now
The part that I enlarged
That little metal box
Inside that metal box is next to this
Carton
That blue thing
Is a solid state
Its principle is actually the same as the one
The state of the art
You run in and hit it
Then give it energy
Energy makes it flash
OK, and then the flash
Light
Can be blown out
And then the top and bottom of this picture
That label
Called TES
TES is
We know the most sensitive on Earth
What is it
It's called Transition Edge Sensor
I'll talk about it later
OK
It's very, very sensitive
And then
In addition to this signal
You can also get another signal
It's a deposit
Basically it's heat
It's heat in the crystal
Because energy is heat
If you think about it
Then the heat will flow out
The whole box is hollow
Nothing
So heat can't get out
Heat stays inside
OK
The only track that can be sent out
It's the top and bottom
It has two caterpillar wires
It will send heat bath
So you can eat all these heat
Then measure the heat
Then you
What is it called
You can identify
What hit us
Is it a particle we know
Or a particle we don't know
OK
What is the advantage
This kind of Solid State Detector
Can be operated under cryogenic temperature
For exquisite energy resolution
With ultra-low noise
But
What does it mean
It's super expensive
OK
It can have a lot of special phenomena
Our collaborators
In Berkeley
In different laboratories
This kind of thing
It can play a lot of magic
Recoil threshold depends on material property
You can invent
Very exotic material
Then let them eat
This
After hitting the ball
How to send it to you
Then you measure
OK
I know that Chicago University is now leading
They are doing CCD
To put it bluntly
The CCD chip in your camera
Take it to Dark Matter
After hitting
Then walk a small line
Different particles walk that line
The behavior will be different
So you can be very, very
Accurate judgment
How much energy is flowing now
What kind of particle is it
Then come again
Because we do superconductor
It is also a very sensitive material
And graphene
What is graphene?
What is special about graphene?
Its conductivity
is
Not all the same
It's the same in every direction
Like your guide
It's basically like this
It's like this
It's on the same plane
There are six directions
It's not zero
Then in the other six directions
Or it's the six-fold symmetry
It's very interesting
When your particles come in
If it runs in the direction of the conductor
It can
No matter how small the energy
It can pull
I should just talk about bandgap
Leave a place for bandgap
It's even weirder
It's superfluid
It's also very sensitive
And it's even weirder
Fermi arc
This is what we did in Caltech
It's basically in a certain direction
Its bandgap is also zero
You can imagine
These things
They are all superfluid
But what's the problem
The problem is that they look like
It's the subject of research
Instead of using it to study other people
It's very, very expensive
But why is this interesting
I'll tell you later
Its dilemma
It's harder to scale up
Without meeting new challenges
While maintaining your budget and sensitivity
You know
The biggest experimental background is sensitivity
No, it's your budget
Can you understand
OK
So after talking about
Time projection chamber
And solid state detector
This is a monoplot
It's the whole field
The current state
Horizontal
It's your assumption
The quality of dark matter
Why do I say assumption
Because no one measured
If you measure it, you know where it can be drawn
You assume
How heavy is the dark matter you can't measure
OK
Then you have to know
How heavy is the dark matter particle
Then you know
The dark matter halo
How heavy is the total dark matter
So you know
How many
Particle in terms of number
The flux has been flowing through you
Then you can't measure
Then you can know
The chance of interaction with me
Can't be greater than how much
Otherwise I should measure
So the axis is the chance of interaction
Is the upper limit of that opportunity
This is
The interaction between dark matter and detector
The chance must be less than that line
If it's higher than that line
We should measure
This is the logic of the picture
So it actually has two directions
One way is that you
The bigger the detector
Like that time projection chamber
In theory, you can expect more events
If it can be measured
So if you can't measure it, you can keep the line down
It means that the higher the sensitivity
You still can't measure
Then the other one is that you can measure
The smaller the energy
Then can you know that
Because very light particles hit you
The energy left is very small
Then can you go to the left of this picture
To draw that line
Because you know you can measure this kind of energy
But you didn't measure
Then you can put it there
This part
Is the solid state
This is the main direction of this field
Everyone wants to push down
To make the detector bigger
But if you want to push to the left
You need a better detector
Then you will ask
What if to the right
To the right is like this
Why do we want to do a dedicated experiment
To measure dark matter
Because we have a very very
Very powerful machine
We have been using it
When they built it
Their reason besides looking for
The exposure
They actually want to find
I think it's fair to say
The super symmetry theory
Then the example of the super symmetry theory
It used to be the best for dark matter
The most anticipated thing
Their goal
Basically around TEV
Or sub-TEV
So that's where I put the soil
Then you will ask
Do we want to measure them now
The answer is that LHC has not been able to measure
And it has exceeded
The earliest version
Super symmetry theory
In other words, we have basically ruled out
The original super symmetry theory
So now there are a lot of super symmetry theories
They are looking at the original super symmetry theory
According to our continuous measurement
They think it is a
Super symmetry theory should have
What new phenomenon
Looking at this thing
So basically you keep going
Is more sensitive
To measure the super symmetry theory
Is there anything wrong?
But it can't be measured
It's already weird
If you are interested
You can ask me
So now Susie's
The expectations are probably all on the map
Everyone is surprised
Because almost all of them are in the places we have ruled out
So now a lot of new theories
Come out
If it's not a super symmetry theory
It's another one we've never thought of
The dark side
Just like you know
It's the dark world
We can't see it
It's very weak
Interact with the world we see
But it's a completely
Standalone dark world
It can have very light particles
Then we have to have
Very new technology
Go to the left of this picture
So this is our goal
Then you can see the top
Inside the SSD frame
The four lines on the far left
That's basically what we experimented
Four different operations
This is the most leading
Then we are going to propose the next technology
Push us down again
Push it to the left
Sorry
So this should be
OK, this is the last page
So the first part
Do you have any questions?
Oh, this is
Ok, this is
Our most popular theory now
It's called
Let's talk about popular
Anyway, it's everyone
The theory that most people are experimenting
Is WIP
WIP
Win
Sure
That
WIF
WFP