Hi, everyone. I'm the host for today. I'm Zhang Yanyong.
We're going to have our 23rd Tara Talk this year.
We're honored to have Dr. Wang Lingya as our speaker today.
She's my senior at NTU.
Wait a minute.
Lingya studied medicine at NTU.
After graduating from the PhD program at NTU,
she came to Nanyang University.
She's actually our neighbor.
We've met quite a few times.
After doing her PhD, Lingya majored in virology.
That's the topic she's going to talk about today.
Today's topic is Molecular Biology Study of Hepatitis C Virus and Autophagy.
Is that how you pronounce it?
Yes.
I don't know. If I pronounce it wrong, Lingya will correct me.
Without further ado, let's welcome Lingya.
Oh, right. Autophagy.
There are two things I want to remind you of.
First, if you don't want to speak,
turn off your microphone so that you won't have noise.
Second, when you clap, remember to turn on your microphone so that you can hear.
Let's welcome our speaker.
Hello, everyone. I'm Lingya.
As the host just said,
I'm doing my PhD in Nanyang University.
I'm majoring in virology.
When you watch a movie,
you'd think that you're walking around in a white gown in a lab.
But in fact, the most commonly used technology in our department is molecular biology.
So today, I'm going to talk about some methods of molecular biology
and how it's used to study viruses.
I'll talk about autophagy later.
Molecular biology.
As you can imagine,
biology is a big topic.
But molecular biology is about small molecules.
We learned in middle school that
DNA converts into RNA and converts into protein.
So the so-called genes are all on DNA.
After a series of synthesis,
it becomes protein.
When we study viruses,
we study almost everything.
It's either DNA, RNA, or protein.
These things are very small,
so you can't see them with the naked eye.
So our experiments are often done on
very small transparent objects.
For example,
a 100-microliter or even a 1-microliter object.
Basically, you can't see it with your eyes.
So if you go on a trip,
you might not know which one you're holding.
They all look the same,
so you don't know.
This is mainly about molecular biology.
It's about looking at the performance of DNA, RNA, or protein.
I just mentioned cells.
We also taught this in middle school.
Cells look like this.
There's a cell box, a cell paper, a cell film,
and there's a lot of air in it.
But the textbook will draw it cuter.
It's more like a starfish.
But in fact, the cells under the wire
are filled very slowly.
You can see this is the cell box,
and then the cell film,
and in the middle is the cell paper.
There's a lot of air in the cell paper.
All the so-called air
is actually made up of a lot of film,
all kinds of bubbles.
This is a little bit bigger.
You can see there's a lot of film,
a lot of bubbles.
These films and bubbles are actually all fat.
They're all made up of lipids.
Different bubbles have different functions.
Some are producing energy.
Some are making protein.
Some are making cyanide.
They're helping our cells maintain a good operation.
We need these cells.
Out of all these cells,
the autophagy we're going to talk about today
is actually a cyanide job.
To put it simply,
when our cells have
old bacteria,
or broken proteins,
or even when there's a virus infection,
or something from the outside,
it's all based on this cyanide
to get rid of these bad or old things.
Since it's a function of cyanide,
it will naturally follow the death of cells,
or cancer,
or like our immune response.
Because of the immune response,
the immune response needs to get rid of
some bad things from the virus or bacteria.
For example, neurodegenerative diseases
are all related to the function of this cyanide autophagy.
What we're going to focus on today
is infectious diseases.
Viruses are infectious diseases.
The function of autophagy
is mainly...
This is a cell membrane.
This brown one is a cell membrane.
We can see that
there are a lot of membranes in our cells.
It is a small membrane
made up of some fat
in a circle.
It will slowly get longer
and become a bubble.
Inside this bubble,
it will contain the bad things
that it will destroy later.
This bubble is called autophagosome.
I don't know how to say it in Chinese,
so please remember it.
It's called autophagosome.
It has a lot of enzymes
in this bubble.
These enzymes are used to
break down proteins.
When these two membranes are combined,
the substances in their cells
will be different.
This enzyme will
break down the proteins.
Let me talk a little bit about
the later process.
Every department has its own
application science or basic science.
The virus science I do
is very basic science.
It is purely studying
what protein, what gas
will react with the virus
in the cells.
When people ask me
if I'm doing medicine,
if I'm doing vaccines,
if I'm treating cancer,
it has nothing to do with clinical trials.
So when we talk about
basic virus science,
a lot of people think it's boring.
Today, I hope everyone
can understand this field.
How does autophagosome work?
From a simple membrane
to a circle,
it's easy to break down proteins.
As you can see in this picture,
this is a small membrane,
phagophore.
It will slowly become
a complete circle, autophagosome.
At the end, it's a fusion membrane.
The lysosome that breaks down proteins
is called autolysosome.
There are a lot of other proteins
that control the whole process.
Because the membrane doesn't
automatically merge together.
There must be a protein controlling it.
We can see that when phagophore
is still a fragment,
there is a protein called ATG5.
It will be specifically
combined on this membrane.
So when we monitor
the number of membranes in our cells,
when we specifically monitor
the membrane of this fragment,
we will look at the performance
of the protein ATG5.
If ATG5 performs well,
it means the membrane performs well.
So we call it a marker.
It's specifically for marking.
The marker on autophagosome
is LC3.
So in the experiment later,
if we talk about ATG5,
it's marking the membrane.
If we talk about LC3,
it's marking the autophagosome bubble.
How do we know
if the protein has been
broken down?
There is a protein called P62.
Every time it's in the autophagosome,
it will be wrapped inside.
So if it's broken down in the end,
we can see that
the performance of P62 will drop.
So these three things
are what we mainly do
when we do autophagosome,
to monitor how far it has come.
Why do we need to study
viruses and autophagosome?
We just mentioned that
autophagosome has the function
of cleaning the skin.
It can remove the protein
from the virus.
In theory,
autophagosome should be useful
to fight against viruses.
But many studies have found
that some viruses will
use autophagosome
to reproduce the virus
to fight against the virus.
This is a typical example
of how the virus
kidnaps the mechanism
inside the cell
to reproduce itself.
The virus is actually
something between
living and non-living.
Why is it non-living?
Because our cells
are made up of cell nucleus.
There are a lot of cells
that can produce energy
but not the virus.
The virus has some
scattered DNA and RNA
and a shell
made up of protein.
That's it.
The virus itself
has no biological ability.
But because it contains
DNA and RNA,
it is considered
a living organism.
So it is between
living and non-living.
The virus itself
has no biological ability.
It has to infect the cell.
So when we
are outside,
we don't see
the virus floating around.
It will die if it is outside.
It has to infect the cell.
The reproduction rate
of bacteria or cells
is 1 to 2, 2 to 4, 4 to 8.
If we look at
the reproduction rate,
we will find that it is a log curve.
When it reaches a certain level
of oxygen or space,
it will start to die.
This is the growth curve
that a normal cell should have.
But the virus is very different.
It is made up of
a lot of DNA and RNA
in our cells.
There are also a lot of
shell proteins.
It is a bit like a factory
that produces parts.
When it is ready to ship,
it will assemble everything.
So if we look at
the virus in the patient's blood,
we will find that
the virus in the patient's blood
will decrease at first
because the virus is all in the cell.
So we can't detect it.
In the second stage,
when the virus is in the cell
and it is producing these parts,
we will feel like
the virus is all in the cell.
When it is ready to ship,
it will release it all at once.
So it is like an explosion.
This is why patients
who are infected with the virus
sometimes feel like
they are fine and
there are no symptoms.
But suddenly,
they are very weak
because the virus
is all out.
This is the difference
between A, B, C, D, E, and G.
There are many kinds of
hepatitis B virus.
In fact,
most people are studying A to E.
A and E
are eating something
that is not clean.
They are eating something
that is contaminated by the virus.
A and E are all sick.
They will be fine after a few weeks.
But B, C, D,
they will all
be infected.
As you can see,
when the virus is still
hiding in our cells,
this is called the incubation period.
At this stage,
our cells
do not detect
any foreign matter inside.
Then it can escape our immune system.
This is why some
virus infections
eventually lead to hepatitis B.
It is hiding in our cells.
Hepatitis C virus
has an incubation period,
but it can also become hepatitis B.
Hepatitis B can eventually
turn into liver cancer.
Not every virus
can turn into liver cancer.
So,
the current
hepatitis C virus
is still very common
in the world.
Many researchers
are still studying it.
Hepatitis C is an RNA virus.
Simply put,
when it infects cells,
it will decompose.
Then the RNA
will come out.
The first thing it does
is to rob
the protein
in our cells.
It is called the intracranial network.
After it robs the protein,
it is like saying,
don't make cell proteins anymore,
virus proteins
are made in large quantities.
Large amounts of virus proteins
will help it make more virus RNA.
More virus RNA
will make more virus proteins.
This is how
a lot of RNA and protein
are made in our cells.
Finally, it is assembled
and released in one breath.
Many studies have found that
HCV's RNA
copies are on the membrane.
There are many kinds of RNA in our cells.
Sorry, I have a question.
Can I interrupt you?
Or do you want to
ask one question at a time?
You can interrupt me,
but there will be lag.
My question is
this.
I see.
My question is
you said that
this thing will go in
and remove this
and do this.
It sounds very smooth
and like an animation.
I am curious
about this.
Is it from some data
or can it be
visualized?
Actually, there are many steps.
Visualizing is one of them.
For example, someone
can see that
the virus particles
are on the surface of our cells.
They can also see that
the cell membrane goes in
and the virus is eaten.
This is visualized.
However, in the research of
molecular biology,
we can't just see it.
It may be an accident.
We can see that
the surface of our cells
also contains some proteins.
The virus uses
its own protein to interact
with the protein on the surface of our cells.
It is like a door
that opens a key.
It goes in.
This is an interesting point.
Why does the surface of our cells
have proteins to let the virus
combine?
It is similar to rice.
After many years of evolution,
it has found a way
to enter our cells.
The protein on the surface of the cell
is not specifically for the virus.
It also has its own function.
The virus
uses the protein function
to let it enter the cell.
Of course,
the whole process
also has a lot of proteins
in it.
If all of them are drawn,
there will be a lot of proteins in it.
This is the result of evolution.
The control proteins
are not drawn in the soil.
Does this answer your question?
I have a question.
Please ask.
Yes, thank you.
You said that
RNA
allows cells
to produce protein.
Does it also produce
more RNA?
I forgot
the name.
Can it produce
protein and RNA at the same time?
It is like this.
This is called
an intracranial network.
This function is specifically for protein.
After the protein of the virus
is produced,
the RNA of the virus
is produced on the other membrane.
What is the other membrane?
This is what everyone is studying.
Our lab found that
it is made on the
autophagy membrane.
Some membranes are responsible for protein.
Some membranes are responsible for RNA.
After making a lot of them,
we put them together
and throw them out of the cell.
The process of throwing them out of the cell
is like HCV.
It is actually
a virus that
has not broken the cell.
Some viruses
will break the cell.
It means that
when it goes out,
it will kill the cell.
This will kill the cell
and make our body weaker.
It is like your body's cells
keep dying.
Killing cells is not very powerful.
It means that once it kills
your host,
it will die.
It is like Ebola.
It will kill people.
As long as you isolate
those people,
they will be fine.
HCV or HIV
will cause AIDS.
It will lurk
and not kill you.
It can exist in the natural world
for a long time.
Does this answer your question?
Thank you.
I have a question
about that page.
This one?
Yes.
This page is...
I thought
the growth of cells
is exponential.
So it starts with
log and then becomes exponential.
It starts with lag phase
and then log phase.
Of course,
our cells cannot
keep growing
because of space and nutrients.
So when it reaches a critical point,
it will enter
the death phase.
This is how
the life cycle of cells
looks like.
If it doesn't die,
it will become cancer.
I see.
So the virus has
a mathematical
growth
or something else?
Actually, every virus
is different.
For example,
let's take a look at
the flu virus.
We have heard about
H5N1 before.
That's because
it has
9 RNAs.
Each RNA
will produce
different RNAs.
So it will produce
9 different RNAs.
For example,
the 9 RNAs must be
mass-produced.
When it is packed,
the 9 RNAs must be packed.
So it may catch the wrong 9 RNAs.
For example,
the number of RNAs
is 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9.
Then the virus will die.
The number of RNAs produced
and the number of RNAs packed
are different.
So
we can't
calculate
the number of RNAs
in a mathematical way.
There are many accidents
such as mutation
or wrong packing.
But we can't
figure out the exact number.
We can only use the approximate number.
It's hard to explain.
The reason why we do
HCV and autophagy
is that
we have a cell
that is infected.
This is a cell
infected with HCV.
We found that the green bubbles
are the autophagy bubbles.
Why do we know
these green bubbles?
Because we mentioned that
the marker of autophagosome
is LC3.
So we can detect
the LC3 of the cell.
When you see LC3,
it means it is autophagosome.
So if we can see
the LC3 in the cell with HCV,
it means the cell is doing autophagy.
This is the process
of infection.
I mainly want to show the below one.
The darker the color is,
it means more and more.
It means under the infection of HCV,
the LC3
will be more and more.
It means
the autophagosome
bubbles are more and more.
PCC2, as we mentioned before,
will be separated at this stage.
So we can see
it will be separated at the end.
It means the autophagosome
will be completed
in the cell of HCV infection.
Let me
introduce the meaning of these two methods.
In the cell dye,
we can design
what we often hear,
gene engineering.
It is the DNA outside the body
that we can design at will.
For example,
we want the gene series
to be put in.
The DNA series will be put in.
Then we put the protein gene
that we want to show.
After the DNA RNA makes the protein,
the protein will be green.
How to make it green?
We send the DNA
from outside the cell
to the cell.
The DNA makes RNA and becomes protein.
Then we can see
the green protein in the cell.
So
like this picture,
because of this protein,
we let it receive
a green protein
behind it or in front of it.
So it will be bright.
Otherwise, the cell itself will not be bright.
What if
the protein is not bright?
Because
not every protein we want to send
from outside the cell.
After all, sending from outside the cell
is an artificial method.
We can assume that
this is a wave.
The cells on the wave
have the protein we want.
Then we can use the antibody to recognize it.
This is the first antibody.
Every antibody
will only recognize one target.
This is a very transferable thing.
So if you have an A protein now,
you have to use the A antibody to recognize it.
This Y-shaped thing
is the antibody.
Its head is the target
we want to recognize.
It's very transferable.
But its tail
is almost the same
as everyone else's.
So we can use the second antibody
to recognize this butt.
Then the second antibody's butt
will receive a bright thing.
We use this method to detect
some non-bright proteins.
Then you might ask,
why don't you just take the first antibody's butt
and receive a bright thing?
We have tens of millions
of proteins.
If you have to design
an antibody for every protein,
and its tail has to emit green light,
red light, or blue light,
then you have to make a protein
every time.
It's a waste of money.
So you can imagine
that the second antibody
is a transferable tool.
It can recognize
all the
second antibody's butt.
So if you want to study other proteins,
you only need to change the first antibody.
You can use the same second antibody
to make it glow.
The so-called glow
is like the cell dye we just saw.
If we want to see
how bright the protein is,
if we look at the cell dye,
we can adjust the light
to make the color
look bright or dark.
This is not
credible.
It's just to see
where the cell is,
but it's more or less.
We still have to do it in other ways.
This method
is to briefly introduce
that the middle piece is a cabbage corner.
If you haven't eaten cabbage when you were a kid,
it's probably like that.
That thing
looks like a solid to us,
but for a small molecule,
the holes in it
are very large.
Each protein has electricity.
So after charging,
the protein we take out of the cell
is the protein of all cells.
We want to separate it.
After running the electric current,
the smaller protein
will run farther.
For example, if we add protein from here,
it will run to the back
after passing the electric current.
The larger protein will be stuck on top.
So using this method
can separate a lot of proteins
from large to small.
Because the cabbage corner
can't do more experiments,
so we have to run it again
and lay it down.
The cabbage corner was made of paper.
Then lay it down
and run the electric current
to print it on the membrane below.
It can be imagined that it is a piece of paper.
Although its material is not paper.
On this piece of paper,
there will be
proteins arranged from large to small.
If you want to measure
the protein position here,
add it to the antigen
and add another antigen
to make it glow.
Then we can detect the signal.
The so-called detection signal
is a traditional method of using a film.
It is the kind of film that everyone knows.
We know that when there is light,
the film will turn black.
This means that the more protein,
the more light it receives.
The more antibodies it receives,
the brighter it glows,
the darker it gets.
So if we go back to this,
this means
that there is very little protein.
Then the one on the right
means that it has a lot of protein.
So we can use this method
to separate the various proteins
in the cell
from large to small
and then use antibodies to detect
how much it performs.
Back to HCV and autophagy.
There has been research
that HCV's RNA
copies will be on the membrane.
There are so many membranes
in our cells.
What membrane does it use?
Our lab found that
it uses the autophagy membrane.
Where does the autophagy
make so many steps and so many membranes?
First of all,
this is also an electromagnetic map.
You can see the curved
phagophore in the cell.
It looks like this.
Then it will be assembled
into a circle,
which is autophagosome.
I just said
that it may not be true when the eyes see it.
It may just happen to be
put together.
So we really have to prove that it will be
integrated together.
As mentioned earlier,
we put the ATG5,
which is specialized
to label the
phagophore
marker.
ATG5
means phagophore.
We send the DNA
with green light
to the cell.
It will show the ATG5
with green light.
The ATG5 will run to the membrane.
Simply put,
the phagophore in this cell
will be green.
We use red light for the other cell.
The phagophore in this cell
will be red.
If these two membranes
are combined,
it will turn yellow light.
If not, you will see
red or green.
So we use this method
to see if these two membranes
will assemble
and turn yellow light.
This picture
may be a little small.
I don't know if you can see it.
When our cell
is under pressure,
for example, starvation,
it will make the cell
starved or
infected by the virus.
The autophagy will start to occur.
Then we can see
the ATG5
phagophore formation.
We can see
the yellow dots
on the membrane.
These are yellow dots.
These are all yellow dots.
This means that
in the HCV-infected cell,
the membrane will
be
fused together
into a
circle bubble.
It won't be fused
with the membrane.
It will be controlled by the protein.
This is just an example of
how the protein controls the
fusion of the membrane.
Some proteins will
run to the A membrane.
The B membrane
may also have another protein.
These proteins
interact
to pull the two membranes
together
and cause them to fuse.
It depends on the protein
to fuse them together.
We found that
there is a protein called
syntax-insider.
It will
fuse the membrane
together.
In order to prove
the function of a protein,
the simplest way is to
show it or not.
For example,
you suspect a protein
to do something.
In order to prove
the function of the protein,
the simplest way is to
remove the protein.
If the protein is removed,
the function of the protein
will not occur.
How can we
prevent the protein from
functioning?
We designed some RNAs
and sent them
to the cell.
The point is
that the RNA
we designed
will target the
RNA we don't want it to show.
Then it will
cut off the RNA.
We just said that
DNA makes RNA,
RNA makes protein.
If we let a gene's RNA
be cut off,
it can't make protein.
This is just a technique.
This technique is to
prevent the protein we want
from being made.
We can see that
ATG5
is the marker
on the membrane.
We can also see that
Syntaxin7
is the protein that
will merge the membrane.
The green one is the membrane,
and the red one is the protein
that will merge the membrane.
We can see that
Syntaxin7
is really
on the membrane.
Next,
we use
the method of
red and green membrane.
In the cell of
HCV,
the red and green membrane
will be merged.
We can see the yellow dots.
But when we show
the protein,
there are no yellow dots.
This means that
the existence of this protein
is important for
the green and red membrane
to be merged.
Without it, the membrane won't be merged.
Next,
if the membrane is not merged,
it is useless.
This method is called
membrane flotation.
This means that
we take out all the protein
in the cell,
and use a different concentration of sugar.
At the bottom is 80% of sugar water.
It is almost a piece of water.
The higher it is,
the thinner the sugar.
After going through a super high speed reaction,
the lighter protein will float to the top.
We just said that the membrane is
some fat.
It is very light.
It will float to the top.
We want to
separate the structure
of the membrane.
We don't want to mix with others.
We just want to take this membrane.
We found that
this is too complicated.
In short,
after we separate
the structure of the membrane,
we found that
the independent membrane
is broken.
Even if it is not
synthesized into a circle,
it has a way to
reproduce the HCV RNA.
This may be easier to understand
later.
In other words,
the structure of
ATG5
is enough to support
the reproduction of HCV RNA.
We can also see
from another result
that LC3,
B and C
are virus proteins.
We can see that
the virus protein
is on LC3.
This means that
we let LC3 glow,
we let the virus protein glow,
and then we put the image
together.
We found that
the signal is at the same point.
It means that it is there.
This is the structure of
the virus RNA.
It is also on LC3.
There are virus proteins
and virus RNA on LC3.
We also found that
HCV not only uses
the membrane
to reproduce,
it also uses the entire membrane
to reproduce.
To make a simple diagram,
when the phagophore
is made,
it needs to rely on
SYN7 to
combine them together
to form a circle.
We found that
HCV can reproduce
on these three membranes.
But
ATG5 will
decompose the protein
at the end.
What happens at the end?
If it starts to decompose the protein,
it is not good for the virus
and the virus will
try to stop
the process.
How does it stop?
We use another
LC3
that emits red light and green light.
When it is at the phagophore stage,
because it emits red light and green light,
we see that it is yellow.
When it is
merged with the last step
to become autolysosome,
the green light will be decomposed
but the red light will remain.
This is actually a cell observation method.
When you see yellow,
it means that it is still in autolysosome.
When you see red,
it means that it has entered the last stage.
Look at this diagram.
When it is still at this stage,
it will be yellow.
If it enters the last step
to decompose the protein,
it will turn red.
In the case of virus infection,
from 6 hours to 12 hours,
one day to two days,
we can see that
it is always yellow.
Until the 24th hour, it is still yellow.
It means that it is still at this stage
until the 24th hour.
It is always very late.
It becomes red after two days
and enters the last stage.
What mechanism keeps it
at this stage,
the autolysosome stage,
instead of entering the last stage?
There are two proteins.
One is Rubicon.
Rubicon's performance rises first.
UV-REG's performance
rises later.
What are these two proteins doing?
It is easier to explain with a diagram.
In general,
the function of UV-REG
is to let these two moles
merge,
that is, the autolysosome and the lysosome
merge to enter the last stage.
But at the beginning of the virus infection,
it will let Rubicon
perform a lot.
It will squeeze out UV-REG.
This protein is
specifically for this fusion
not to happen.
If it doesn't happen,
a lot of autolysosome moles
will accumulate.
The more moles,
the happier the virus will be.
Because it can reproduce with these moles.
It wants these moles.
It doesn't want them to merge
But at the late stage
of the infection,
it may not be able to stop it.
UV-REG will come back.
It will squeeze out Rubicon again.
It will let this fusion
continue.
At the end,
because it can no longer stop
the fusion of these moles,
it will use other moles.
This is the experiment of others.
It has nothing to do with our lab.
Our lab has reached this stage.
When HCV is infected,
it will trigger
the occurrence of autolysosome.
It will produce
this membrane.
Cytosine 7 will let
these moles merge
into a complete circle.
It can reproduce on this membrane.
It doesn't want this membrane
to merge
at the last stage.
So that it can have
endless moles to attack
and reproduce.
That's about it.
This is the research
I did in our lab.
This is a very basic
research on molecular biology.
Basically,
we haven't done
any clinical trials
on how to treat this virus.
Our job is
to see
what happens
after the virus infects the cell.
Then we control the protein
so that it can reproduce.
Okay.
I'm done.
I have a question.
Before we start
the Q&A,
let's thank Linya for her speech.
Thank you.
My question is
the protein...
Sorry.
I'm lagging.
You can continue.
The host is lagging.
The protein
will make the membrane
into a circle.
How does it...
The protein
is like a signal
to make the membrane
into a circle.
Or is it induced?
It can change the curvature
of the membrane.
Let me find a picture.
I don't know if you can see it.
On this membrane,
there are some proteins.
On the other membrane,
These two proteins
cooperate
and mix together
to make the two membranes
merge.
As I mentioned,
the protein
of Synthase C7
has a function
that
on the membrane,
this and that
mix together
to make the membrane
merge with each other.
This is what the protein
is doing.
The membrane that it will merge
is not only the membrane we just mentioned.
It will also merge many other membranes.
This series of
Synthase C7
has 1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8...
The whole series of proteins
are all doing the
membrane merging.
There are many different types of membrane in the cell.
So different members
are responsible for different membranes
to merge together.
Does this answer your question?
Yes, thank you.
So the protein is very large, right?
If it wants to
stir this...
Actually, they are all very small.
The protein itself is actually quite small.
Mainly because
the protein has a
3D structure.
You can imagine your hand
can be flat,
but you can also bend it.
And you still have fingers.
You can interlock your fingers with others.
If you hold it together, it will become a very small group.
The same goes for the protein.
When it is doing what it should do,
it may become a very small group
when it is interlocked with others.
Because it merges closely together.
I understand. Thank you.
There should be no more questions.
Am I talking too fast?
I have a question.
Did you hear that?
Yes, I did.
My question is
to confirm
if I understand.
You said
when you are infected
by HCV,
I forgot the name.
A purple and a blue protein.
The light blue one
will be inhibited.
The purple one will come in.
So it can't be interlocked.
From a pharmaceutical point of view,
is it possible that
in the middle stage,
I can make a lot of
UV rays in the cell,
and it won't happen?
This is the protein in the cell.
This is not the protein of the virus.
The protein in the cell
has what it should do.
So if we
target any protein
in the cell
to affect its performance,
it may harm your cell.
So the virus is
a bit like
hijacking.
It hijacks
the cell
to do what it wants to do.
But if you say
it will hijack the protein
to do what it wants to do,
we will eliminate the protein.
Then the virus can't be reproduced.
This is because the virus
has its own function in the cell.
If you eliminate it,
our cells may die first.
Hello? Can you hear me?
Oh, I see.
This is much more complicated than I thought.
Yes, so in fact,
from a pharmaceutical point of view,
we have done a lot of
protein things.
Do you have any questions?
I have a lag with you.
I just heard it,
so you can finish it.
No, that's it.
Anyway, it is quite difficult
to make medicine
for protein.
You have to find a protein
that only affects
the virus
but not the person.
But this is rare.
Protein is useless
in our human body,
but in terms of natural evolution,
very few proteins are useless
in our body.
Okay, any more questions?
I know I'm lagging,
so when I heard that
everyone had no questions,
it should have been a while.
No, I don't think so.
Thank you.
Okay, we are done.
Thank you again, Linya.
Thank you.
That's all for
our talk today.
Bye-bye.