Okay, no problem.
Hello everyone, I'm Dinghao.
I'm a postdoc at Caltech.
The topic I'm going to talk about
is mainly my research on some of my papers.
My research is about
designing an artificial system
and hoping to use that system to detect cell-cell contacts.
My ultimate goal is to use this system
to dissect the entire neural circuit.
Oh, in the field of neuroscience,
the most important answer that everyone wants to know
is how our brain functions,
so that we have all kinds of different emotions
and how reactions to the environment stimulate.
How to stimulate.
But about 100 years ago,
Raymond Kahar had a very elegant study.
And the elegant study proved that
our brain or neural system
is mainly operated by these neurons or other cells
to transmit all kinds of neural messages
and ultimately have a behavior.
This is a very famous neural doctrine.
So a lot of research now
is focused on how different neurons
communicate with each other.
This is a very complicated problem
because our brain is a huge machine.
Like what I'm showing in this picture,
it's a reward circuit.
This actually includes a lot of brain areas,
like the hippocampus, prefrontal cortex,
and the famous basal ganglia,
nucleus, convent, VTA.
These different brain areas connect with each other
and operate and calculate
to achieve a goal.
And another more complicated aspect
is that even in the same brain area,
there are different neurons
that receive different messages.
And after synchronization,
it's transmitted to another brain area.
And the calculation of the other brain area
may be transmitted back.
So these connections are what we...
What we want to answer right now
is the idea of connectome.
We hope that by understanding these connectome,
we can have a blueprint
of how our brain or neural system
is wired.
And then we can use this basic knowledge
to calculate
the changes in the message transmission
of the neural cells
that may lead to different behaviors.
Like this.
But in fact,
in addition to neural cells,
there are many other different cells,
such as glial cells.
Many studies have found that
these glial cells
actually affect the function of our neural neurons.
For example,
like this astrocyte,
the heart-shaped neural cell,
is...
It has been found that it can actually
clean up some of our neurotransmitters
and make it turn over faster.
And it's also found that...
Sorry.
It's found that it can actually transmit some signal
and affect the whole synaptic property.
So the connectome or microcircuit
that we originally thought of
is like this.
In addition to neural cells,
we still need to consider
the function of these neural glial cells
to have a more complete picture
of how our brain functions.
And then I mentioned earlier
that understanding these microcircuits
can help us know how our brain works.
Another point is that
many...
We already know that there are many neurological disorders.
It actually has something to do with
the wiring of the neural circuit.
Like schizophrenia,
phrenia,
or some psychological diseases.
It actually has something to do with it.
If we know how the normal brain works,
we can further study
the causes of these disorders.
I hope to get some answers
to help these patients.
So far,
there are many different tools
that have been developed
to help us understand
how to dissect,
that is, to analyze the entire brain circuit
or neural connection.
Here are some examples that are commonly used.
For example, Serial Electron Microscopy,
which is an electronic microscope.
There is another one called GRASP.
Its full name is
GFP Green Fluorescent Protein Reconstitution
Across Synaptic Partner.
This means that it has a fluorescent protein
that divides engineering into two parts.
I will explain this later.
There is also Tango.
There is another popular tool
called Rabie Virus
to trace neural connection.
These are all great tools,
but they all have different
shortcomings.
For example, Serial EM
is to take a small sample
and cut it into pieces.
Then use EM to take the whole image
and then reconstruct it.
Then look at its very fine-detailed
neural morphology
or the connection of different neural cells.
Usually, a small one-millimeter-cube
size sample
takes about five or six years
to complete its analysis.
It also requires a lot of human power.
So this is not a very efficient method.
Because it is not very efficient,
it can only analyze a small sample of an animal.
If you want to analyze 10 different animals,
different variations,
it may be a bit difficult
or require more time and more manpower.
Another is CRESP, a genetic tool.
It can be used in
mice or
I'm going to talk about Drosophila fruit flies.
It is mainly divided into two parts of this fluorescent protein.
Normally, it emits green light.
After dividing it into two parts,
they will not emit light.
Only when the two parts are very close,
they will be re-combined
like this.
So the two parts themselves do not emit light.
When they are re-combined, they will emit light,
and you can see the green light.
Then it can detect
that two cells are close to each other.
Its disadvantage is that
it...
Sorry.
It can only see where it is in contact with.
It can't make any further modifications
to affect cell poverty.
In addition,
its binding is irreversible.
So there is a concern that
it may affect the connection between the cells.
The dynamic.
Connection to dynamic.
Another system is called Tango.
It mainly has a G-protein couple receptor.
Its feature is that
when it binds its ligand,
it will recruit a protein called arresting.
Arresting comes to activate
its downstream signaling transduction.
Then the engineer added a protease to this protein.
Then this receptor has a transcription factor.
Then there is a sequence in front of it
that will be cut by this protease.
So when the protein is binded,
the protease will cut this part.
Then it will release the intracellular transcription factor
and drive downstream gene excretion.
Its advantage is that
it has these reported proteins,
either fluorescent proteins
or mutant proteins.
You can control some of the features in its cells.
But the disadvantage is that
it is only limited to G-protein couple receptors.
In our neural system,
there are many...
For example, this is a dopamine receptor.
It is a G-protein couple receptor.
But there are many receptors that are just IN channels.
So it can't be used in this place.
In the mammalian,
there is a very popular tool
called re-engineering the RebVirus.
It can monosynaptically trace upstream neurons.
The point that needs to be considered
is that we need to do surgery
to inject this virus into the brain
to express,
to let this virus
to transmit to its Gag cells.
It has cytotoxicity.
So usually the research
can only be completed within a week.
Otherwise, the cells will die.
But another point is that
I just mentioned that it can only be used in the mammalian.
Even so, its efficiency is not very good.
I have tried this tool before.
Different brain regions.
Some brain regions may have special neurons.
It's harder to let the RebVirus
jump to their upstream partner.
So the important purpose of my research
is to generate a system
that can be used on all transgenic animals.
I hope it won't have any toxicity.
So we can safely study
the property and function of these cells.
In addition to tracing the neuron
or the connection between the cells,
we can also manipulate their property.
So my main design here is that
if a cell, not necessarily a neuron,
has a ligand
and the other cells have a corresponding receptor,
when these two cells have contact,
the binding will generate a cell signaling
to the downstream cell.
Then we can either express some fluorescent reporter protein,
or express some gene or mutant that we are interested in.
Or it can be RNAi.
So here, we used a very important
signaling pathway in animals,
Delta protein and Notch protein's signaling pathway.
So let me briefly introduce
the structure of Notch protein.
It has a very long hRSA domain.
Most of it is EGF repeat.
This domain will bind its ligand, Delta,
and when they bind,
the current hypothesis is that
if the ligand is endocytosed,
that is, if it is brought in by the cell membrane,
it will generate a force.
It will open this structure called NRR.
After Notch binds,
there will be two cutting points
that will be cut off by Proteus.
One is S2 and the other is S3.
So the original S2 cutting point
is in the NRR structure.
So it's embedded inside the structure,
and Proteus can't digest the S2 site.
So it won't be cut off
until Delta binds.
After it binds, it opens this structure,
and the S2 site can be cut off.
Next, its transmembrane domain
also has a cutting point called S3.
S3 will also be cut off.
Then its intracellular domain
is a transcription factor.
It can move to the cell membrane
to activate downstream gene expression.
So here we use this logic.
We replace some domains
that will affect the cell's endogenous domain,
like EGF repeat,
it will bind the endogenous Delta ligand.
So we replace it with an antibody here.
Then its intracellular domain
will drive endogenous downstream gene expression.
So we also replace it
with a yeast transcription factor called GAL4.
So our idea is that
our new synthetic receptor
can recognize its own ligand.
I'm using CD19 here.
After it binds,
it uses the NRR domain in the middle
and transmembrane domain.
It will have S2, S3 cleavage.
Then it will release intracellular GAL4.
Then it can drive either GFP
or any gene expression.
It depends on what kind of study we want to do.
We call this whole section track.
It's Transcellular Activation of Transcription.
First, I'll test
whether our designed ligand and receptor can work.
So we use it in the cell line.
Here I show you the control.
Red represents the ligand.
The cell line with or without ligand.
My reporter is GFP.
So when you see the cell with receptor,
it has no GFP
because the co-culture cell has no ligand.
When I change the co-culture cell
to the cell with CD19,
you can see that most of the receptors
and positive cells
start to show GFP.
Here you can see the difference in the amount of GFP.
You can see that the amount of GFP
increases with the co-culture time.
The blue line is the control cell.
The orange line is the test group.
To make sure that they have cell-cell contact,
not because my ligand-positive cell
releases any weird factor
to trigger the downstream gene expression.
So I put the receptor cell
and the ligand-positive cell
in the same play.
But I put less CD19.
So they generate their own colonies.
When they grow up,
only when the two colonies
have direct contact with each other,
the ligand-cell line and the receptor-cell line
will have contact.
This is the receptor-positive colony.
This is the ligand-positive colony.
Only when they have direct contact with each other,
the cells produce green ligand.
The rest are dark.
We use the cell-cell line to prove
that our system can function normally
and detect cell-cell contact.
We hope to use it in the in vivo system.
We use the fruit-gene model.
It is a well-established genetic model.
We have a lot of tools to study it.
The life cycle is relatively short.
The fruit-gene model is about two weeks
from the soft to the mature.
The most important thing is that
the nerve system is similar to the mammalian brain.
We hope to use the nerve system
to imply the mammalian brain.
Let me briefly introduce the central nervous system of Drosophila.
They still have neurons and glia.
Their neurons are not like our brain.
There are a bunch of neurons in the brain.
Their synapses are in the same area.
Drosophila's cell body is mainly
around the edge of the nervous system.
These regions have no synapses or connections.
In this area, the synapse is only there.
Besides neurons, there are many other glial cells.
I will go into more detail about these later.
One thing to remember is that
what I will talk about later is not about the neural pill itself,
but about the cells themselves.
First, we want to test whether our system can detect
the contact between glial cells and neurons.
We can see that neurons and glial cells...
The first part is to see if we can detect the contact
between glial cells and neurons.
Then we want to further use our system
to see if we can trace the contact between neurons.
First, glial-to-neuron.
There are different types of glial cells in the ToSoftware.
The contact between neurons is different.
For example, the surface glial is wrapped around the nervous system.
It's more like a protective film.
They don't have much contact with our neurons.
On the contrary, different types of glial cells,
such as cortex glial,
are mainly wrapped around the neural soma.
Or the astrocytes are mainly
infiltrated into the neural pill
and wrapped around the synapse.
These different types of astrocytes
have more contact with neurons.
So what we want to test here is
to see if the ligand is present in the glial cell,
can we detect the connection between neurons?
So here I have all the bioreceptor proteins
in all the neurons.
Then we use the ligand in the glial cell
to see what happens.
This diagram shows
what the ToSoftware's Lava Brain looks like.
There are two main parts.
The central brain,
which is the main area of the brain.
And the ventral nerve cord,
which is like the spinal cord.
The first thing I want to show is
if our system doesn't have any ligand,
its background is quite weak.
It only shows up in different tissues.
When the ligand is present in the astrocytes,
we can see a lot of neurons are labeled.
This is mainly because
the ligand and the receptor present in the neurons
are combined
to stimulate the GFP protein in the lower part of the brain.
Here I use another driver.
This driver is called ELAM.
This is an astrocyte-specific gene.
So using its promoter,
we can see that
the ligand mainly shows up in the astrocytes.
But the REPL
is a protein found in all glial cells.
You can see that the pattern between them is different.
When these glial cells are shown in different populations,
we can see that
the pattern of the label changes a little bit.
For example,
in this brain area,
I will zoom in to show you.
In this area,
the driver doesn't show a lot of GFP expression.
In the next slide,
I will zoom in to show you.
I want to show you that
our system is quite specific.
This is mainly because
we can see so many green neurons are labeled.
in the same area,
the cell body doesn't show a lot of ligand expression.
It's darker here.
It's mainly because
the process of these neurons
will have contact with
this
row of glial cells.
But here,
and these two places,
that's why
we have
this
strong
GFP expression
in these neurons.
Next,
we can prove that
our system
and our tool
in Drosophila
can work.
The question we want to ask is
can we use our system
to label
astrocytes?
Mainly because
astrocytes
has been proven
that
it has
a very important
role
to control
synaptic function.
For example,
it can
control synaptic contact
by
eating
those
unused synapses
or unused processes.
It can also
help
synaptic formation
of
neurons.
Astrocytes
have been studied
that
astrocytes can also
react to
neurotransmitters.
It can
control
the level of
neurotransmitter release.
It can also
control
neuronal activity.
However,
all these studies
assume
that astrocytes are
a homogeneous population.
Some tools
can be used
to
knock down
gene
function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
However,
all astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or
to
knock down
gene function.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or
mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or
mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or
mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or
mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or
mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or
mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or
mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or
mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or
mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or
mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or
mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or
mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or
mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or
mutant gene.
All astrocytes
can be used
to
knock down
gene function
or
mutant gene.
Either
your head
has to be transparent
or you have to
punch something
on a mouse's bone.
It's not possible
in real life.
In my system,
you have to
express two
ligand and receptor
and three reporter.
If you can't
use
transgenic animal
or other virus
to express, it's impossible.
Also, human brain
has
limitations.
I just mentioned
that I don't know
if you are there.
Now CRISPR
is very popular.
It can
make it easier
to
change
the genetic profile
of different animals.
You can
do transgenic animal.
In other words,
using CRISPR,
we should have
more opportunities
to test
on different animals.
Like rabies virus,
it's a good tool.
Many papers
published
about it.
The problem is
we can't use it
on birds.
Birds can't
get rabies.
It's rabies virus.
This tool
is transgenic.
If CRISPR
looks promising,
we can use it
on different animals.
As I mentioned,
there is a kind of
sea...
dolphin.
Tuff fish.
Yes, dolphin.
It has a strange
and special behavior.
It will
draw on the sand
in the sea
in a symmetric pattern
to attract...
It's amazing.
If I have a chance,
I want to study
its brain.
Really?
Why is it like this?
I don't know.
But the pattern
is like
the pattern
of a
shark.
It's big.
I think
it's interesting
to study it.
But
it's not
transgenic.
We can only use
functional MRI.
But it can't
be that good.
I'm thinking
how to
develop it
so that we can
understand
its brain.
I was thinking
if you change it
to a
magnetic field
or electrical field,
you can use
MRI technology
to locate it.
But the resolution
is not high enough
to see such a small thing.
It looks like a piece.
It's bright here.
So it's useless.
I remember
I saw
a speech
or something.
They were using X-ray
to look at
the structure
of the brain.
The structure of the brain.
The brain is
very small.
X-ray
has a strong trajectory.
I think they were thinking
if they can
use X-ray to dissect
such a small brain,
the resolution will be good.
Maybe in the future,
we can use it
to dissect
large animals.
But
I don't know
how long
the technology will last.
Maybe in the future,
there will be a big breakthrough.
I think
there is a big gap.
it's very helpful
for animal models.
But animal model
literature and
human models
have a big gap.
Both sides
don't know how to
cross the gap.
There is no bridge.
Maybe
the closest
is primate.
Primates
may have some...
Yes.
I think
it's very obvious.
If you are a primate,
you do some
obvious things
like
aggression
or mating behavior
or
hierarchy.
But if you are
a high-ranking animal,
like a stork,
you are very close to a primate.
But if you are
a high-ranking animal,
you are very close to a primate.
But if you are
a high-ranking animal,
you are very close to a primate.
I think
it's a very complicated social behavior.
I heard people
do jealousy
on mice.
I heard people
do jealousy on mice.
do love on mice.
It's painful.
Yes.
I was thinking
how to use
this system.
But
if you really use it on humans,
there will be some
limitations
on human brain function.
Yes.
But
we can't
do research on humans.
we can't do research on humans.
But I think it's cool.
I think your resolution
is very high.
It's quite
big.
I don't know where the people in front sit.
It's amazing.
You can see everything in detail.
It's mainly
through social contact.
So we still have to
test
its sensitivity.
Minimal area
that you need to
see the difference.
So
you still have to
see
how big is your contact area.
And
if your concentration
is high enough
to see
its downstream
performance.
You can adjust it
slowly.
My main work is to adjust
this tool.
So it can be used
in
tracing neural circuits.
And
Yeah.
I don't want to talk alone.
Do you have any questions?
YuQing asked a question.
I don't know if Jenny is still here.
I don't know.
I'm here.
YuQing is here.
I mean Jenny.
There's another one.
Yeah.
I think
maybe in the future
after I have more
information,
this is just the basics.
Maybe in the future,
I still need something like
telekinesis or
computer simulation
to really
understand
brain function.
Now I can only
provide a tool
with a blueprint.
Just an established
blueprint.
In the future,
I want to
control
Apple's
cell property.
So I can be more selective
in my research.
Does anyone else have a question?
Please go ahead.
There's a drug
called LSD.
Is it...
I think...
I don't know if it's related to this.
Is it that
after taking the drug,
what will happen?
Is it related to
this research?
After taking the drug,
it will control...
LSD will
simulate
those things, right?
It's a bit like...
Yeah, I didn't say it myself.
It should be like that.
I don't know.
It mainly works on...
I'm not sure
if it's doping
or that...
What's it called?
It's like
the same place
where the drugs work.
I kind of
forgot what it's called.
It works on
a certain neurotransmitter
circuit.
So it's like
what I just said.
There's a reward
circuit.
It's mainly
in that area.
Like that area.
The brain area
is very popular.
It's related to
reward and addiction.
It's related to reward and addiction.
Talking about
reward system.
I'm not a
biopsychologist,
so I'm not sure.
But the reward system
is very popular now.
It's related to addiction.
You might have mentioned it, but I missed it.
Other than addiction,
it's also
related to...
Like a lot of
psychological disorders,
like autism
or
etc.
They have
abnormal repetitive behaviors.
They keep doing it.
It's like
what?
Like obsessive-compulsive disorder.
Right.
It's because their reward system
has a problem.
When they do these behaviors,
their reward system will keep firing.
As a result,
the abnormal
unnecessary behaviors
will keep firing.
Some imaging researches
are doing this.
ADHD.
Right.
As I mentioned,
we
research
connectome
in the brain.
The purpose is
to make a normal reference.
Then we can
study
schizophrenia
or other
brain related
disorders.
What are
the differences
between them?
Right.
Schizophrenia
has excitatory
and inhibitory
differences.
Do they have
fewer connections?
Or
do they have
fewer synaptic strain?
I think
many professors in our department
like your researches.
Our department
has a close relationship
with
Engelsheim.
They do
schizophrenia.
Oh.
Right.
They push patients
into the brain.
Your image.
I remember
there was a talk
about functional MRI.
Right.
It's about ADHD.
It's about
image.
They do
function
structure.
In the past, MRI
did anatomical
structure.
They did
anatomical structure.
Now they do
firing pattern.
It's called functional.
Right.
I remember.
It's 7.25 now.
Any questions?
If not,
3, 2, 1.
Thank you.
Let's continue.
If you have any ideas,
you can
share with us.
Thank you.