Wow, you should be able to see the screen now.
I'm starting to record now.
I can see it now.
In 2011, I started, I worked on several projects before I joined Professor Citrin's lab in 2014.
And mainly we have been focusing on two types of optics, two types of phenomena in optics.
Basically, nonlinear optics and quantum optics.
So this is my talk is arranged.
I'll first introduce my outline, why we care about this study and why we want to do this research.
Then I'm going to move on to two other setups.
One is a semiconductor laser with feedback.
And I'm going to introduce the setup and one of the applications that we have been working on last two years.
The next I'm going to discuss a single photon emitters as we are now capable of generating one single photon at a time.
And we're going to discuss when we place a single photon emitter in front of mirror with feedback, with time delay feedback,
but complex or maybe complex phenomena we are hoping to observe.
So I'll just start with very, very basic discussions.
So this is a most fundamental feedback system.
It's very general use in maybe like mechanical engineering.
When people study about the control theory, when they place a signal in front of anything,
and then use the measurement result to feed it back into the system and see what's the phenomena they will observe.
Most of people want to control them.
And this is a big deal in control theory when they try to study this dynamical systems.
So here we see like very, I try to reduce the amount of equation that I have.
So this is the most simple equations.
This is equation of motions.
So equation of motions, instead of just the original experimental parameters,
there could be because we have feedback.
So we'll have the delay time.
We have the feedback strength or other things included in the study of the equation of motions.
So this could be applying optics.
On these slides, I show two different setups for optics.
One on the left is an integrated photonic circuit included inside this small optical electronic component.
So basically they generate the photon within the wave intensity to generate random numbers.
So I'll discuss this in more detail later.
But it's a well-studied system.
People can use it to generate entropies and or other entropy source.
So the one on the right is a very similar setup.
If you imagine the semiconductor laser, a laser diode is now replaced with a single photon emitters.
So if here anyone know about laser, you could imagine it's a cavity.
And then you have a luminant source within the cavity and generate lights.
And when the cavity has the same wavelength or they have the wavelength couples to this quantum dot.
Actually, this is a quantum dot in the system.
They could able to generate very high, very pure and very identical indistinguishable photons once at a time.
And we're now interested in placing this single photon emitter in front of a mirror.
And study how we can, how we are able to control it.
And or maybe we cannot control it.
And this will see very interesting dynamics.
So this, so I began with the semiconductor with feedback.
This is this system where typically we'll call this external cavity semiconductor laser.
The system is shown on the right.
We have a laser.
We place it in front of the mirror.
And we found a simple but I think quite clever way to control this feedback strength feeding back into the laser.
And then we can measure the intensity using just a high speed photodiode.
And while doing this, we're also measuring the voltage with the intensity.
So in here we see the external cavity length.
So that's another critical parameters in our study.
So that length, well, two times of this length divided by C is the delay time, which we'll discuss later in this slide in the presentations.
Okay, so this is the theory describing the external cavity semiconductor laser.
Basically it's, well, obviously it's called, it's developed by Len and Kobayashi, these two guys.
We basically describe the system with three parameters.
We have electric field.
We have optical phase when it's entering the, when the feedback light is entering semiconductors.
And we have the carriers or carrier numbers, which related to voltage measurement as I described in the previous slides.
So, in this system, there are, so we have, so basically with this model, we can, we have the three equations of motions.
And typically when people study nonlinear dynamics, people will study the behavior near the equilibrium point or in near, well, yes.
And in our case, it's called external cavity mode.
Basically, when you set this three equations to zero, then you're able to solve a set of solutions that it's stable, or it's just equilibrium, it's equals to zero.
So as I mentioned, we have the external cavity frequency.
This is related to the delay time.
And we have the relaxation oscillation frequency.
That's some, that's related to the current, the drive current.
And yes, we can move on.
So, in the first step, one of the most interesting thing that we are looking for is looking for a bifurcation diagram bifurcation diagram is when we change one of the parameters.
In the increasing or decreasing, we'll see the dynamics change according to these parameters.
And the two parameters, two figures below, these are showing the intensity as a function of these parameters.
These parameters could be the cup, the feedback strength, as I mentioned before, or you can change the external cavity length, or you can change the drive currents.
And we see this bifurcation, you start very well, quite simple.
This is we usually call this continuous wave.
Basically, we have the laser, but it might increase or decrease the light a little bit.
Then we have a jump.
Then we increase this to, we have this bifurcation branch.
So this two branch, that's showing that there's two stable solutions.
So in the intensity, we'll usually see periodic regions.
Basically, we have a sine wave.
Then the next we'll have, we will enter two other branch.
At this point, we'll usually see quasi-periodic.
The next, we'll see chaotic intensity.
Well, which is usually a big blur or very random thing.
And that's how we use it for random number of generations.
So as we discussed in the previous slides, we now have very well-studied models for a semiconductor laser.
But as most of you must know that a laser is just a bunch of photons.
Even though we can describe the model in very well in electric field and carrier numbers.
But when we are generating a single photon at a time, we might see different behaviors.
So changing from semiconductor lasers to a single photon emitters.
That's the second part of my research.
And the one I show on the right is a single photon emitters.
We have a few layers of mirrors.
They're called bright reflectors or just mirrors.
You have a quantum dot embedded in the center of this, of this pillar.
And then, so we have the photons emitting or count very confined in three directions.
And we can control the photon frequency a little bit, but not too much.
We can control and how fast we want to excite or excite the quantum dot and get a very nice photon, a single photon.
So I'll first start with some results I have for semiconductor lasers with feedback.
I'll first describe the properties and then I'm going to discuss one.
Only one of the applications that we have is called optoelectronic oscillators.
So this is basically our experimental setup with the probe on the right.
We can measure the voltage and the intensity at the same time, which is very, yeah, it's very interesting.
But somehow it hasn't been studied in the last 10, 20 years.
People usually focus on the intensity, not optical intensity, but not the carriers.
So now with this, we'll be able to get voltage and intensity at the same time.
So this is one of the first few bifurcation diagrams in experiments.
The one I showed you before is theoretical bifurcation diagrams.
So because we're only taking the AC signals, so there's not very change.
There's not that much change in the in the vertical directions.
Only the oscillations are being observed here.
So the parameters that we are changing is the feedback strength.
As we can see, as we increase the feedback strength, we start from a laser, basically just a CW laser.
And then we have a quasi-periodic regime and then we enter a periodic.
Then the next we have chaotic signals.
So we were also able to measure the optical spectra at the same time.
We see that in the CW regions, there's only one optical frequency, meaning just the laser is very stable.
You only have one frequency.
The next we have quasi-periodic regimes, which more than one external cavity mode are being excited.
Then the next we enter the periodic regimes.
When we see the period is separated by the relaxation oscillation frequency.
The relaxation oscillation frequency, I probably haven't mentioned this.
It's depending on the different semiconductor laser, depending on the laser diode and current that you're applying to.
The last, when we increase the feedback strength, we enter a chaotic.
Chaotic region when all of these external modes are being excited.
Then in a later work, we'll have another slide showing other method when we characterize how chaotic it is.
So I think I have...
So I have prepared a very short...
Sorry, sorry.
Can you interrupt?
Okay.
It's okay.
Oh, it's already running.
I think it's okay.
Is it?
It's not very continuous, but I think it's okay.
Oh.
Yeah.
Okay.
So basically, it's from what I just said, from CW to quasi-periodic to periodic, and then there are some different dynamical regimes.
Yeah.
And this, the next one is, this is chaotic time series for both intensity and the voltage.
I think we have enough for this.
Okay, so can I ask a question?
Sure.
So my question is actually for the previous, the prior slide.
So in there, the previous one.
So in there, yeah, yeah, yeah.
So you have four, not really four, but four graphs, colorful graphs here.
So the D, can you explain that a little bit?
Because other three use amplitude for the Y, but this one, this D is for frequency, right?
What does that mean?
Yes, so we have four graphs in here.
So for part, for figure A and B, this figure A is the intensity, and figure B is for the voltage.
So they have very similar behaviors, but some, because we have limited voltage resolutions, so some of the small features cannot be observed in the voltage.
The C is just a zoom in of A.
We've been from zero to 25%.
So focusing on first half or first one third of the figure A, and we have, we also have the optical spectrum of the intensity at the same time.
And yes, the four figures in the bottom are representing the optical frequency.
So they are the optical frequency offset by the optical frequency of the laser.
Is that okay?
Yeah, yeah, thanks.
Sorry about that.
So we have two amplitudes representing the intensity and the voltage.
In C and D, we focus on the first half of the intensity and compare that to the optical frequency at the same time.
So we have intensity changing, and also at the same time we can measure the optical frequency that's higher or below the, we usually call this CW frequency, but yeah.
So, and also we see that this, there's a bright stripes that they are separate by the frequency of the relaxation oscillations, relaxation oscillation frequencies.
Hello.
Uh, I can, I can ask a question.
Is this picture, is this the picture of the bifurcation when we solve the ODE?
Yes, yes, this is the bifurcation obtained in the experiment.
Bifurcation, I remember because I learned it a long time ago.
But I remember that there's a parameter that changes a little bit and then there's a completely different result. Is that the thing?
Yes, yes, yes, yes, that's right. So what we've changed now is...
So what's changed in here?
What's changed is the feedback strength, which is how much you get back when you just shoot it out.
Oh, oh.
So it's, let me think about it, let me see if there's this, okay.
Can you see this electric field, this one?
Uh, 10?
There's a Kappa behind the electric field in the Opal Archimedes model.
Uh-huh.
That's what we can actually change in practice.
Oh.
We've changed a lot of things later on, but nothing else.
This is the simplest and I think the most controllable.
Okay, okay, thank you.
So basically, we control feedback strength.
And we can see that the bifurcation diagram looks like this.
This diagram is...
This diagram took me a long time to make, and I'm really bad at it.
It took me a long time to make it.
Anyway, okay.
So next.
So in this slide, I'm going to discuss only one of the applications of this system.
So this is called an optical electronic oscillator.
This is typical use when we need to generate very high frequencies, but...
Sorry.
High frequency of RF signals.
It's very difficult for us to use a quartz oscillator,
and use other multipliers to generate the same periodic frequencies.
So on the top, this is for generating a periodic voltage signal,
because we have direct access to the voltage now.
We have very high...
Well, we have pretty high quality factors,
and then we can get the phase jitter less than, I think, 10 to the minus 4 microseconds.
So the frequency now we're generating at this, it's almost 10 gigahertz.
Okay, so the ones below, these are to generate chaotic signals.
People usually ask, we usually want an RF signal, a periodic signal.
Why we care about chaotic waveform or chaotic signals?
So the answer is quite simple, actually.
So people are trying to use...
In all the cryptographies, people use random number generations.
But usually when we have the random number generations in electronic systems,
it's typically not a real random.
There are still some type of trace that we can find,
and usually they are much slower.
So in here, we generate the chaotic signal,
and then we can use it as a type of random number generations.
There are other characterization methods for how randomness,
what's the randomness or how chaotic we are for the signal.
This is one of the results.
So this is called largest Lyapunov exponent.
As someone mentioned, sorry, I didn't catch your name.
As someone mentioned before, this is the separation when two signals at time equals zero
and time equals sometimes.
And then the separation of these two signals in its state space,
if this signal, the space or the distance they are separating
is proportional to time,
there is a very exponent and you take the log,
and then you can see if this is chaotic,
you will have a positive largest Lyapunov exponent.
This is a very, one of the simple way,
well studied way to study how chaotic a signal is.
So next I'm going to discuss what happens if we place a single photon emitters with feedback.
I think maybe Leo is here.
He also have few publications on feedback for waveguides.
So for me, I'm just going to discuss feedbacks,
a single photon feedback in optical regimes.
I'll first discuss why feedback loop is important in quantum limits.
As I showed before, this is basically how a feedback system looks like.
There are two methods of feedback loops,
where we try to prepare quantum states.
So the one in figure A, this is a measurement-based feedback loop.
So you measure something, you want to prepare either zero or one,
and then you measure it.
If it's not a target state,
you just apply a Z gate or minus something times Z gate
to feed it back into the quantum system and prepare the state as you wish.
It has been done experimentally, shown in figure C.
So this is just a feedback for, I think, single ions, I believe.
So it's easy to prepare an ion within a cavity.
So the other method, which I'm more interested,
or most people are more interested in,
is called coherent feedback.
Without making the measurement,
if we put a mirror in front of this photon source,
we can actually prepare the quantum dot in one of the target states.
So the important of this is,
or the major difference is, with coherent feedback,
we can actually prepare the dot in the superposition states.
Unlike the measurement-based feedback,
we can usually target in zero or one.
I think not many people are.
Anyway, so again, we have
the equation of motions.
Feedback schemes are control schemes using time delay.
So they are period guess, type feed control,
rhythmic control, and extended time delay feedback.
So here, the coherent feedback can be used as period guess type control
to eliminate the unstable orbit.
Okay.
So the advantage of period guess type feedback is to provide,
of course, feedback instantly.
It can be applied in every regime to stabilize a system.
It's non-invasive.
And one of the best thing is if the delay time,
which should be a controllable parameter,
the delay time, if it's matching the intrinsic orbital period,
it actually has a stabilizing effect.
And the last is it's preserving the coherent state
without making the measurement.
This is probably one of the most important for quantum systems.
So before we start on the study of feedback,
I'm going to discuss a little bit,
just introduce how a single emitter looks like.
So this, the figure on the right, bottom right,
this is a single photon emitters that our collaborating,
that our collaborator are manufacturing in the laboratory.
Basically, it's three, five semiconductor materials
with embedded quantum dot inside in the center.
They have very clever way to etch out the parts
that's outside of the regions.
So all they left is very well-defined micro pillars.
And they have the optical frequency matched to this frequency,
to the transition frequency of the quantum dots.
And we have two other parameters,
that's the coupling strength and the decay rate of the quantum dot.
Basically, if the decay rate is too high,
we call this a weak coupling regions
that the photon emits,
they emit the photon outside of the desired optical frequencies.
So, okay.
So for one single photon with feedback,
we will have studied the behavior of a single photon feedback.
So, on the right, we have three figures.
The first is without the external cavity, without feedback.
So that's emitting a single photons.
The next when we have certain condition match
for the external cavity length or the delay time
with the transition time or the rapid frequency
in the quantum dot,
we can drive the system,
even though it's in a weak coupling regions,
we can drive them in a very periodic way.
So the one that I produce in the bottom is,
I use the same method to generate the same result.
So I can compare with their result in the future.
So we can generate very long periodic signals with feedback.
As I mentioned before, the way that,
so the figure on the left, this is classical.
When we have the delay time,
that is a multiple of the period,
intrinsic period of a system.
When this system match to the frequency of the delay time,
they will have very high repetitions.
Basically, the orbit is more or less stabilizing itself.
So they have level one, two, three, four, five, something.
That's the multiple of these two matching.
The one on the right,
I use it for a quantum.
This is the same feedback in quantum regions.
Basically, we have the similar process,
but the decay or the repetition of two signals are decreasing much faster
than periodic feedback.
These are just a demonstration of how it looks like.
We have the delay time at three different colors
in the color figures.
I don't know how to say this.
The top in figure C,
we see that if the delay time is not multiple of this,
the orbit is not very repetitive.
As we increase the delay time,
we see the orbit is trying to match to the intrinsic orbit.
It's very repetitive as we change the delay time.
Next, I'm going to discuss stability analysis.
This is a very common study to study any dynamical system,
especially with feedback.
When we have the feedback,
we'll try to calculate if a system is stable or it's a repeller,
it's stable, or it's a saddle point.
The criteria or the typical method is first to find the stationary state
or equilibrium states where all the equation of motions are being zero.
The next is to find the Jacobian.
Then to study the stability,
we find the eigenvalues of the Jacobian.
For a stable system,
the eigenvalue of the Jacobian will be the negative,
or the real part of is negative.
Repeller, we have a positive real part.
The saddle point will have some of the eigenvalues being positive
and some of them being negative.
Okay, so how do we study such system in a quantum system?
How do we study such dynamical behavior
that we describe usually in a classical system,
in a quantum system?
First, it's simple because we already have the equation of motions.
The one we have here,
the phi is a superposition of three states.
We have excited quantum dots being CE,
and we have micro cavity photons being CG,
or I think I labeled CC here, sorry.
We have a photon in the external cavity being CGK.
So we can, it's not that hard to,
and then we have the Hamiltonian that describe these interactions.
So we can just apply this wave function to the Hamiltonian,
and then we can get, well, in Schrodinger's picture,
and then we can get the equation three, well, equation of motions.
Interestingly, because this G of KT is describing the coupling element
between each mode,
the population in, sorry,
the population in the external cavity is the superposition of infinite mode, right?
So this G of KT spans from negative infinity to positive infinity,
basically describe the coupling between the micro-pillar cavity
and the external cavity modes.
So we think that we have only three equation of motions,
but actually the third one is actually,
it's like infinite dimension of equation of, sorry,
of the modes that have very high dimensions.
So we see this in the denominators here,
C of CK and the summation of that going back into the micro-cavity.
As I mentioned before, what's the first, what's the steps that we have?
So first we find the equilibrium point.
So because we, so that's our showing here.
If C of C, if the, oh, shit, sorry.
If we design the initial conditions of CE, CG and CK in this very specific ways,
we'll have them all being stationary.
It's actually a stationary state and they have its own oscillating frequencies,
minus GT, minus GT.
And for this, for the state in the external cavity,
each of them, they rotate along this K axis at different rate.
But this is actually very easy to imagine if it's, so, okay, sorry.
So if you see the expression for C of CK for the stationary states,
this is a sinc function.
A sinc function is actually a Fourier transform of a square function.
So this is just a square, a steady state in the external cavity length.
It's have the same optical intensity if you imagine in this way.
So the next step is obviously try to find the Jacobian.
For that, we apply small signal models.
Again, this is a Jacobian of infinite dimensions.
It's almost infinite dimensions.
Of course, in simulations, I'll be able to only trace down a few of them.
Well, many of them actually.
So by applying small signal models, we can find the Jacobians.
With the Jacobians, we'll be able to calculate the eigenvalues.
Well, here we have make a small replacement
by just letting us to calculate the eigenvalues more easily.
The next step is actually to calculate the eigenvalues itself.
So from the result that we have,
we can write out the function of determinant of this Jacobian.
Next, we can able to calculate the eigenvalues on the top.
So there are three different case.
The first case is we have the optical frequency of our photons, right?
So if the external cavity length match to multiples of the wavelength of the photons,
we'll have the Jacobian as a function of r, which I forgot to write here.
r is you can imagine as a feedback rate.
But r is actually the rate of decay rate over the coupling strength.
So it's actually 4 gamma over g.
Let me remind you and remind myself what gamma and g is.
So it's 4, OK, sorry, 4 gamma over g.
That's how we characterize a good or a bad cavity.
So with that, we can plot all these eigenvalues.
So the one on the in case one, we have these conditions.
We have, well, so they look very similar.
But if you plot them in the same graph, they are different.
So we can have, and this is the imaginary part of this Jacobian of the J tilde,
which is, we care about this because the eigenvalues of J tilde times C over L times the I, imaginary part,
will have the real eigenvalues of the J delta.
So OK, so basically what I'm trying to say is if we have eigenvalues for imaginary tilde or pi,
this value being positive will have a stable system and vice versa, of course.
The one on the bottom, this is the real part of the eigenvalues and the imaginary part of the eigenvalues,
but plotted as different value of R, different value of this R values.
Again, when we have eigenvalues in the upper half, we have a stable and the ones in the bottom is unstable.
What I'm trying to do here is to see if this is stable.
Then we're trying to see if this can work as a stabilizer.
So if this has stabilizing effect for a state that's in superpositions,
I think I should mention here.
As I briefly discussed in previous slides,
the coherent feedback are able to prepare the quantum states in superposition states,
which is not accessible for measurement-based feedback loop.
OK, so this is typically how we draw, we call this black sphere,
but typically this is characterized how, what's the superposition of two states.
If it's here on the black sphere, it's well superposition states.
So we chose different initial conditions,
and we see that they are trying to stabilizing itself.
Well, the red curve is help you, just to help to guide the eyes.
We see that this stabilizing or the rate that this probability is decaying
match to the positive parts of the eigenvalues.
So these values actually match perfectly with this decay rate.
So we see that this, and we see this, we call this bit error.
This is, usually we want half probability of a state,
half probability for one state and half for the other.
But most of the time, when we cannot prepare them perfectly,
we have this bit error.
In this study, I'm showing you that this bit error can be stabilized as time goes.
This bit error could be stabilized.
And the next is to study the non-linearity of the excitation state or Fock state.
Okay, anyway, it's called Fock state.
Basically study how many photons are there in a quantum system.
Because in here, I only study only one excited states.
And the next step is obvious to study the different number of states.
So at this point, I only have one single excitation and two excitation states.
But good thing is we have the same Hamiltonians.
So it is possible to write out the equation of motions as we did before,
and to study the stability from there.
But that hasn't been done.
That's one of my future works.
The other thing is if this stabilize the phase error,
the phase error is demonstrated when all these initial states are aligned on the chidal.
And then we see if they are fake.
So on the figure A, this is showing they start in equal probability,
but they have different phase.
What's the dynamics of this initial states?
We see that it doesn't look like it's stabilizing,
or it might have very slow stabilizing rate that's not shown here.
Yes, so we reached the conclusions.
I show two different types of optical feedbacks.
First, I study the external cavity semiconductor lasers.
And we show the voltage and intensity bifurcations diagrams.
We are able to demonstrate one of the applications.
It's called optical electronic oscillators for generating periodic and chaotic waveform.
And then we can plot the phase portrait as we change the feedback strength,
which also haven't been done before.
Then, yeah, I forgot to show the other slides.
And then we move on to optical feedback in single photon regimes.
So we have very good results that match with other people's work.
We are able to show coherent feedback of single photon emitters.
We study the effect of external cavity length, or the delay time as
of the effect of the stabilizations.
Next, we have studied nonlinearities for single photon emitters,
where we have maybe one or two photons at the same time.
The next I show also show the stabilizing stability analysis for single excitation states.
We can improve the theoretical models that we have,
mostly in the two excitation states,
and see how we can get equilibrium states in that case.
And we're looking to study the stability analysis for two excitation states.
And we want to see, possibly, well, we are hoping to see,
in two or more higher excitation numbers,
are we going to transition to quantum chaos,
or maybe it's always stable.
Okay, thank you.
Yes, that's all.
That's an hour and more.
Hi, everyone.
Thank you, Jianyuan.
Let me ask a question first.
Sorry, everyone.
This question might be a little...
Can you talk about the application of this?
Because I think when you're talking,
you've been...
I might have missed it.
You've been talking about how to stabilize it.
But what does it do?
Do you know what I mean?
Yes, I do.
What you're probably trying to ask is,
in quantum mechanics,
what are the benefits of being able to stabilize?
Yes.
What are the benefits of quantum mechanics?
The first one is,
the method that most people want to use to stabilize
is this one.
The one in the upper right corner,
the C graph.
You can stabilize it,
but you might...
I'm not sure if you guys know much about quantum mechanics.
If you want to stabilize...
I don't know.
You can only stabilize it in 0 or 1 state.
Hello?
Hello, I'm listening.
Usually, the state we need is called K-state.
Or what is it called?
GHZ state.
Anyway, it wants to be in a superposition state.
In quantum mechanics,
a lot of things want to be in 0 or 1 superposition state.
But if you use measurement-based,
you can't stabilize it.
But now people say,
let's use coherent feedback.
But we don't know why coherent feedback can stabilize it.
Or what kind of parameters does coherent feedback need
for it to be stabilized.
Oh, I understand.
Our goal is to make it in 0 or 1 superposition state.
This is 0 or 1 superposition state.
Yes.
Okay, I understand.
Does anyone have any questions?
I also want to ask a low-level question.
I don't have a low-level question.
We need to stabilize it.
But if I remember correctly...
I haven't taught for a long time,
so I don't remember.
But if you use feedback,
control theory should use feedback.
Hello, I'm still online.
Hello, can you hear me?
Use feedback to control theory.
Yes, yes, yes.
Feedback, then control theory to correct.
Then get feedback to correct.
But in quantum mechanics,
the so-called state should be called...
You can get that state right away.
Is there a way to keep correcting
to get the final state we want?
Because in quantum mechanics,
when we want something to be in a certain state,
shouldn't we want to get it right away?
I know...
I know a little about control theory.
But I know in control theory,
it uses passive and active control.
I remember in passive control...
In fact, this should be considered
a kind of passive control.
But because it's not...
Because the point is, like I said,
this coherent feedback,
its advantage is...
Suppose this is active feedback,
how much does it measure?
Maybe use a PID loop
to add or subtract how much
to make it into the state you want.
But in quantum mechanics,
basically,
what it can use is limited.
So in fact,
the coherent feedback here
is more of a passive feedback.
As long as you don't...
You don't have this measurement process.
You can't say you're measuring
positive 0.1 or negative 0.1,
and then you feedback a negative 0.1 back.
Because the point is,
if you do this measurement,
it will affect the time
in its superposition.
I think everyone
should have heard of something like this.
If you do the measurement,
it will affect the state
of the superposition.
I see.
So it's not measuring,
but there's feedback,
and you want to reach
a stabilized state.
This is what I've been discussing
in the second half.
I see.
Thank you.
Let me ask another question.
If...
If you can now
increase its
stability,
theoretically,
can you calculate
the same...
I can hear you.
If...
If you can now increase
its stability,
theoretically,
you can now
calculate the same time
or whatever unit,
can you increase
its certainty?
I don't know much about
content information.
Sorry, I didn't hear you.
Increase its certainty.
Because now
it's between 0 and 1,
it's not uncertain, right?
In the past,
you've stabilized it between 0 and 1,
so it's uncertain.
Am I right?
No, you're not.
But here,
its...
What?
Let me think.
What's your question?
Right.
But...
Can you
repeat your question?
I'm sorry.
Maybe I didn't understand it
correctly, but I heard
someone say
content information
has a quality
that you can't
calculate
accurately.
But you can get to a certain
probability, you know what I mean?
It has intrinsic
uncertainty or something like that.
Right.
This thing...
If I understand
what you said
correctly,
this thing...
They're talking about
how to measure the final result.
To measure the final result,
because you
measured it 10 times,
and there were 7 times...
Let's say there were 7 times.
If 7 times is 1,
you'd think
you'd write it as
density matrix, right?
You'd think it's 0.7.
But it's actually wrong.
Because this thing
called quantum tomography...
It's too detailed.
I don't know how to explain it.
Quantum tomography
uses the maximum likelihood
method.
In fact, it's not
0.7.
In quantum system,
in quantum computation,
it's a very difficult
problem to measure.
But
it's different
from what you asked.
You have to ask
if the stabilization
can be reversed.
I think it can.
It's actually very easy.
If you really
implement this system,
you can...
Let me think
which picture is better.
This one.
You can prepare
a type,
and measure how long it takes.
In fact,
you just do a bunch of measurements
to see if it matches the service.
I think it can
reverse the type.
In fact,
it can verify
if what I do
is correct.
I hope it's correct.
But
it depends on
whether someone can do it.
I think it can.
Okay, thank you.
Hello.
Is this Yan Yong?
Who? Zhang Yong?
Zhang Yong is not here.
Is Zhang Yong here?
Okay.
Zhang Yong
just joined
and then disappeared.
I don't know what happened to him.
Okay, ignore him.
California hasn't
woken up yet.
I tried to
see if California woke up.
California didn't seem to wake up.
It's Taiwanese anyway.
Thank you.
Who is in Taiwan?
Actually, I just arrived in Taiwan
so I'm still awake.
I just returned to Taiwan today.
What's your name?
Zhang Ying.
My name is Zhang Biyue.
Biyue.
Okay.
Where are you studying?
I'm in DC, George Washington.
George Washington University.
Which one?
George Washington.
Okay.
I happened to be there for a while.
Yeah.
What are you studying?
Mechanics.
Oh.
I've been watching a lot of
mechanical stuff lately.
I watched Control Theory.
It's going crazy.
Because
Control Theory is a very important...
Yeah.
Before that,
I was calculating
controllability.
Then
I went to study those things.
I think Control Theory is really interesting.
Yeah.
I'm not doing Control Theory.
I'm doing fluid mechanics.
So I did Control Theory
about 10 years ago.
I know.
I think you should...
Yeah.
I just found out
that Control Theory
has such a difficult problem.
It's really interesting in math.
Yeah.
But
I just heard
that I was on
Quantum Computing a while ago.
I remember he said
in Quantum,
now computers are 1 and 0.
In Quantum Computing,
for example, 70% is 0
and 30% is 1.
It's a superposition.
That's right.
Is it like
Quantum Computing at Kyo University in Japan?
I'm just asking.
I don't think so.
I think it's from the U.S.
I'm sure it's a professor
from a university in the U.S.
So you want to stabilize
that I want to produce
a group of states
that are 70% 0 and 30% 1.
So you want to stabilize
that I want to produce
a group of states that are 70% 0 and 30% 1.
Is that what you mean?
That's right.
You're right.
It's a superposition.
The first thing
in the feedback loop
is that if it's just 0 and 1,
we call it pure state,
it's easy to do.
It's easy to do it with the feedback loop.
But if you make it 50%
0 and 50% 1,
But if you make it 50% 0 and 50% 1,
you can't do it.
You can't do it.
So superposition
is a new way
to stabilize.
is a new way to stabilize.
In fact,
in quantum computing,
there's a lot of research
in quantum computing.
Because...
I don't know if you...
In quantum computing,
did you get error correction later?
No, I only gave up after two weeks.
Anyway,
error correction is a very difficult problem.
Because you can't do both sides.
Because it's easy to do error correction
One is 1.
You repeat it 3 times
and it becomes 11111111.
You repeat it 3 times and it becomes 111111.
If it becomes 101,
you know the middle is wrong.
If it becomes 101, you know the middle is wrong.
But you can't do it that way.
Because there's
non-cloning theory,
you can't do the copy
so you need
You need
quantum correction.
It's a huge research.
It has
surface code, color code,
super math.
I've
seen some before
and I think it's super hard.
I haven't finished yet.
Error correction
can only
correct
discrete errors.
But what we usually
do is
correct
continuous errors.
It's not
that hard.
It can
do continuous
stabilizing.
I can
continuously
stabilize it
instead of
doing something
to stabilize it.
Like you said,
quantum itself
can't be measured.
It can't measure accurately.
No matter what experiment you do today,
you need to measure
to know what you get.
Or quantum computing
needs to measure
to know
what signal it receives.
Or error correction
needs to measure
to know if it
receives the wrong signal.
Like you said,
it's hard to measure.
Is there
enough
technology
to measure
or is it still
lacking?
Your question
has
two parts.
One is
generally
readout
can be done.
But if you
reverse the
superposition
with readout,
it's hard.
We need to separate
these two parts.
Generally,
readout is easy.
I can't say that.
It depends on
your system.
QuantumDot
or IronTrap.
IronTrap's readout is the easiest.
The other two
are a bit harder.
But in fact,
we all know
how to do it.
But
the result you measure
is
0 and 1.
But
if you want to
measure the state,
you need to do it
10 times.
7 times is 0.
You can't
reverse it.
It's 0.7 or 0.3.
Right.
This is
because
you usually
measure
more than one qubit.
It's not hard
to measure a qubit.
But you need
thousands of qubits.
You need to
do it
many times
to
have enough confidence
that the result is right.
You need
thousands of qubits
to
measure
a qubit.
Then you can reverse
the result.
It's hard.
And there will be
some error.
The error
is different from
the number of times you need to measure.
Anyway.
OK. Thank you.
Any questions?
If no,
let's give
a round of applause.
Thank you.
Come on, Taiwan.
OK.
That's all.
You can leave now.
OK. Bye.
Thank you.
Nice to meet you.
Let me say something.
I'll post the video
in the blog.
Only the members can see it.
If you have any questions,
you can send it to me.
Or you can contact him directly.
Or you can email him.
OK.
If
you want to join
me,
it's catchang.
Yes.
Or you can
see if you can
tag me in the blog.
Or add me.
Yes.
It's easier for everyone to contact.
And
I forgot.
Pingyuan.
Hello.
If you have any questions,
we can talk about it.
If you're interested,
I'm going to apply for a blog post.
I'm looking for a blog post
for quantum computing.
You can ask me any questions.
OK.
I'm doing
maybe not a direct relationship,
but it's still computing.
Supercomputing.
Yes.
It's really hard.
The so-called
quantum...
Sorry.
It's my wedding photo.
I'm going to cover it.
It's a big field
called quantum simulation.
I don't know if quantum simulation
can simulate
some of the characteristics
of chemical molecules.
I don't know if
other systems
can simulate
in the future.
Yes.
It's a big field.
OK.
Talk to you later. Bye.
Bye.