Oh, it's started.
Okay, let's start.
Let's give a round of applause.
Wait a minute.
Do I have to share my screen with you?
Yes, you have to share your screen.
I'll turn off my own screen.
Okay.
You have to share your screen.
Let's take a look.
You should be able to choose your screen.
You can choose the one you want to share.
Okay, I'll turn off my screen.
Can everyone see me?
Okay.
The sound is pretty clear.
First of all, thank you, Yen Ping.
Thank you for sharing your knowledge about me.
Today,
I'll talk about
how to use
air pollution
average temperature
coverage
averages temperature
averages temperatures
Who is Zhang Shiying?
Zhang Shiying is
from our lab
He gave a talk in March
on air pollution and public health
at TIRA
and
he
he is
a Ph.D. graduate
from our lab
and now
at Sonoma Technology
He also does air pollution
He is a Ph.D. graduate
from our lab
and
he