Hi, everyone. We're going to have the fourth Q&A session this year.
We're honored to have Zhang Yanping here to talk about positive emotions and human relations.
Zhang Yanping is a Ph.D. candidate at UNC-Chapel Hill.
He has been studying at UNC-Chapel Hill since 2013.
Prior to that, he obtained a Ph.D. and a master's degree in psychology at NTU.
His research focuses on positive psychology, positive emotion, gratitude, self-transcendent emotion, well-being, cultural psychology, and moral psychology.
His research includes emotional communication, interpersonal dynamics, Taiwanese indigenous psychology, prosocial behavior, political participation, and moral judgment.
As you can see, Zhang Yanping's research focuses on social psychology and social participation.
Today, he's going to talk about emotional and interpersonal dynamics.
Let's welcome him.
Thank you, everyone.
First, I'd like to say I'm sorry.
I thought I'd be here next week.
So the content I'm going to talk about today is a little different from what I wrote for Zhang Yanping.
Wait a minute. I'll close the door.
I was going to prepare a more general content next week.
I'm going to talk about a lot of projects that I've done before.
I'm not going to go into too much detail, but I'm going to put them all together and talk about a big direction and what to do next.
But I got the time wrong.
So I didn't prepare that.
So what I'm going to talk about today is one of the projects I was going to cover.
But I'm going to talk about this project.
The bad thing is that I'm going to talk about it in more detail.
So if you have any technical questions, you can just ask.
The good thing is that I'm not going to talk about the studies I shared last spring.
So if you've heard of it, you won't repeat it.
This is the first one. I'm sorry. I got the time wrong.
The second one.
The second one is when I was talking about my research interests.
It sounds like a lot of answers.
It sounds like independent things.
But in fact, it's like this.
Imagine.
I'm actually interested in how people communicate and understand each other.
What the other person wants to do.
Who is the other person?
What is the other person thinking?
Wait a minute.
In this process of interpersonal communication,
In the past, people have been pointing out a lot.
That is to say, our speech and communication.
In fact, non-verbal communication is a big part of it.
And it's not just a big part.
In fact, it's a relatively large part.
Compared to verbal communication.
For example, if I say hello to everyone today.
Thank you very much for coming to my speech.
But from start to finish.
Then you must find it strange.
But in fact, that's a constant behavior.
I didn't even move.
You can just say that my hands are stiff.
But in fact, it's not.
Just that little action.
The whole process of communication has changed.
What I'm interested in is non-verbal communication.
Non-verbal communication is largely related to emotions.
If I'm angry, I'll just crack my teeth.
Even if I haven't hit you yet.
I also crack my teeth.
I don't know if you've seen that.
There is a very famous photo of an Olympic gold medalist.
He once won a silver medal.
I don't remember his name.
Very famous recently.
Then his mouth is on one side of his mouth.
Because he's very ungrateful.
That's actually a content performance.
Will it affect
If you're talking to your partner.
It's like this.
A very ungrateful look.
There's going to be a problem with communication.
So what I'm interested in is
Emotions in non-verbal communication.
How does this have anything to do with moral psychology?
Because it's simple.
Because if I'm talking to my partner today.
Then show a very ungrateful look.
There will be a fight later.
There will be a fight.
It's about morality.
It's about who's right and who's wrong.
Why do you think I shouldn't do this?
Why should I listen to you?
But I give you this ungrateful look.
You think this is morally wrong.
Where do you see this signal from?
Then next.
For example, I walked on the street.
Then there was a street friend.
He showed me some emotional non-verbal communication signals.
But then it will affect my judgment of his situation.
For example, this guy deserves it.
He didn't work hard to get there.
Or do I think he must have been bullied.
So this society is not fair.
So I have to help him.
So moral behavior or moral judgment
And the next moral behavior
It's all in this kind of interpersonal communication.
It's all in this kind of interaction.
So it's actually a line that keeps pulling down.
And then finally.
I'm very interested in culture.
Because that's what we're going to talk about today.
Culture greatly affects how we understand others.
Like this.
We'll talk about culture later.
I won't talk about it now.
Anyway, you can imagine it.
Then I started.
Because I have two screens.
So if you leave a message, I can see it.
It won't affect my PowerPoint.
So if you have any questions, you can leave a message.
You can also speak directly through the microphone.
It doesn't matter.
So I should be able to see it.
Okay, let's get started.
First of all, thank you all for coming to listen to me today.
And it's under such late notice.
So.
I was interrupted just now.
Thank you all.
In order to express my gratitude to everyone.
This is what I used in my dissertation proposal defense.
So it's funny.
Maybe it's weird here.
That's what I said at the time.
In order to express my gratitude to everyone.
Please let me kiss your feet.
Okay.
This behavior.
Especially in Taiwan.
It's very bizarre.
Why would you do this?
But in India.
I don't know if you know.
In India.
Kissing someone's feet is the highest expression.
Respect.
And gratitude.
Grateful for the help of these people.
And cultivation.
And incense.
So this behavior is usually for.
This.
It's usually for the elders.
Or this monk.
This monk.
It's what the monks do.
Of course, it's not limited to these people.
But it's usually like this.
This behavior looks very bizarre.
But in fact, in this part of the world.
This is what everyone does.
And don't forget.
This is not a small island in the Pacific Ocean.
Then there are only a few hundred people.
This is India.
There are hundreds of millions of people in India.
Very, very many.
So it's not a.
So it's actually not a.
Very rare event.
But we don't know about these events.
I don't know.
So for us.
Grateful is to express gratitude.
Just say thank you.
Hug.
But.
This thing.
In the example just now.
It shows that.
This is often not the case.
Before we start.
Before analyzing culture.
Let's talk about why.
So why do we need to study gratitude?
Because.
We know that gratitude is a positive emotion.
I'm going to talk about gratitude today.
Gratitude is a positive emotion.
When we feel grateful.
We feel very happy.
Warm.
So he.
Psychologically.
Comfortable.
And the study also shows.
Feel positive emotion.
Will make us.
There are many benefits of mental health.
Come again.
In addition to mental health.
Physical health.
The study also shows that.
When feeling positive emotion.
All kinds of positive emotions.
Physical health will be better.
Not to mention gratitude.
Because gratitude is usually between people.
I thank a person.
Then a person is good to me.
He gives me social support.
So I feel grateful.
Then I might return it later.
So give him social support.
The study found that.
Social support.
For this.
Mortality rate.
Will it hang anyway?
Will people die?
This prediction.
Very high.
How high is it?
Higher than smoking.
Then.
Let me see if I can.
Find this information for everyone.
Take a quick look.
This is a big one in the past.
This review paper.
Then he found that.
Everyone can see me now.
This powerpoint is affiliation.
Or the one just now.
I can see it.
Affiliation, right?
Very good.
This is.
In the past, this study is.
He did it like this.
Everyone can see this.
There are a lot of bars here.
This bar.
Is these items on the left.
For mortality risk.
Prediction.
This effect size.
If you don't know what effect size is.
Don't care about it.
The longer the prediction, the stronger the prediction.
The less noise.
The top.
This pile.
Is a variety of different ways to measure social support.
Then social support.
Or good quality.
High quality social relationship.
For the mortality rate.
The prediction is very high.
If you have good quality.
These.
Quality relationship.
Then.
The mortality rate is relatively low.
Prediction is stronger than smoking.
And this smoking is not what.
Pick two a day.
What is it?
Less than 15.
Everyone can see here.
So this is a crazy pile.
You.
A crazy pile.
You are not necessarily.
Not necessarily dead.
It will be faster than those who do not have social support.
Social support is so important.
Then there are below.
But.
Aren't they consistent?
You have an error bar.
What is it called?
They are not consistent.
Your social relationship.
After adding the error bar.
Within one sigma.
Consistent with smoking.
I can accept.
You said alcohol consumption.
But I don't think smoking is good.
Smoking is right.
This is not wrong.
This is true.
And this.
You can see this.
The size of the error bar.
In fact, it has a lot to do with the method of measurement.
Because if you are today.
Especially when you.
If you ask about this smoking.
Then you pick a few.
This can be counted one by one.
But how to measure the relationship quality.
Is a very tricky question.
So it will have three different categories.
Then there are several categories.
The error bar is super big.
Because it is obvious.
The way of measuring is not very good.
It's not accurate.
But generally the idea is.
Social support.
At least.
At least it is with.
Smoking.
Can't be distinguished.
Just like this.
Like you don't have friends.
It's like you smoke every day.
Yeah, that's fine.
It's not bigger.
But at least it can't.
Not lower.
And then alcohol.
In this place.
Alcohol is a little lower.
But it.
It is still lower than social support.
Then there is the flu vaccine.
The flu vaccine is even lower.
Physical activity is here.
It's lower.
Then.
Okay, that's it.
These are the more important ones.
So.
What is the point?
The point is that social support.
It is for.
Mortality risk.
The prediction is so strong.
So we.
I want to have a good relationship.
In the end.
Wait a minute.
I see someone.
Oh.
Is the edge wrong?
Okay.
The edge is not wrong.
The edge needs help.
Need help.
But we just want to talk about this.
That is to say.
There is no social support.
In fact, it is a very.
A serious problem.
So it's not just about teenagers.
Teenage smoking is not good.
It's just that teenagers are excluded.
He might die faster.
Anyway, think about it.
This is actually quite reasonable.
This smoking.
You still have smoking.
But.
People who are excluded.
It's easy to commit suicide in the end.
So this is really a serious problem.
Okay, finally.
This past research has been considered.
It's not research.
This is a philosopher.
Many philosophers.
Maybe not many.
But there are a few important philosophers.
They believe that.
Gratitude is a very important emotion.
Because it brings people together.
He.
It is the foundation of our modern society.
Just social exchange.
Or this.
Rational exchange is not enough.
So it's a bit like a lubricant.
That's why we need to study gratitude.
But the problem is.
Just like the example we just saw.
We're not really sure.
How to express gratitude.
Or what to do with gratitude.
Because the cultural difference is so big.
So in this project.
I'm going to do this.
The question is.
Cultural variation in good expressions.
Different cultures.
How to express.
Express gratitude.
And then.
Especially I will focus on.
The difference between the United States and Taiwan.
I will explain later.
Why the United States and Taiwan.
Except.
Of course there are some theoretical reasons.
I will explain later.
Another one is because.
I'm in the United States.
So it's easy for me to get American samples.
Then I have connections in Taiwan.
So I get connections in Taiwan.
This is a.
This is a practical reason.
I'll talk about this first.
The theoretical reason.
I'll talk about it later.
OK.
Then it officially started.
We've already spent half an hour.
It's really funny.
Anyway.
OK.
So what is gratitude?
Gratitude.
This emotion.
We just.
Define it a little bit.
It's a kind of.
When we receive help from others.
Or goodwill.
When goodwill.
Will feel a kind of.
Positive.
Happy.
Joyful.
Warm.
This feeling.
This emotion.
We.
We call this feeling gratitude.
Or say.
It's usually not wrong.
As for whether.
Only this feeling is called gratitude.
We don't care about it now.
Don't care about it now.
In this place.
Gratitude has several characteristics.
Compared with other positive emotions.
The first one is.
It's usually.
In interpersonal relationships.
Produced.
Someone helped me.
Give me a gift.
Or.
Say something nice to me.
Give me.
Just.
Do something for me.
Teach me something I don't know.
I feel very grateful.
This is different from.
Other positive emotions.
But I'm happy today.
I don't need anyone else.
I feel great.
This is positive emotion.
This is joy.
But this is not grateful.
You won't because.
I'm happy.
Feel grateful.
Usually not.
We can discuss later.
If you are happy.
Feel grateful.
Why is that?
I think this question is very interesting.
But basically.
Gratefulness.
Its characteristics are.
Produced directly from interpersonal relationships.
Usually.
In addition.
It will have.
Results in interpersonal relationships.
Or effect.
We receive a person.
Gratefulness.
We usually.
Repay.
Or at least say thank you.
This thank you.
Not in the air.
Say it to another person.
So.
Gratefulness is a very interpersonal.
Emotion.
Relative to.
Other positive emotions.
So.
This is.
Later.
There is a.
Because of these phenomena.
There is a theory.
Called.
Find.
Remind.
And.
Find.
Theory.
This theory says so.
He said.
Gratefulness.
The reason why people.
Have this emotion.
Is because.
Gratefulness.
It's like this.
Think about it.
It's like a light bulb.
We usually wear a light bulb.
Then.
When.
Someone is nice to me.
I think this person.
This person is a good.
Social partner.
This.
I deserve to continue.
With him.
This light will be like this.
Will light up.
Then remind me.
This guy is a good guy.
This is gratefulness.
The thing that lights up.
Is gratefulness.
So he.
Help us.
Find.
Good.
Social partners.
And.
If.
Next time.
I meet this person.
My light bulb.
Will be like this.
Will light up again.
Remind me.
This guy was nice to me last time.
So.
I should repay him now.
Or.
I should pay attention to this person.
Next.
Make good friends with him.
So.
Can build social partners.
This social relationship.
So.
He helped me.
Find.
And.
Remind me.
Put the two of us together.
That.
We all know.
It's easy to die.
But if there is.
Cooperation.
It's easier to live.
Especially.
Good.
With good.
Partners.
Cooperate together.
Then.
OK.