Hi, I'm Yen-Yung Chang, the host of Tera.
We are going to have the second lecture of Tera this year.
Today's speaker is...
Wait a minute, I have to scroll up first.
Today's speaker is Bi-Yao Zhuang.
She is from DC's George Washington University.
She is a fourth-year doctor of mechanical engineering.
She specializes in fluid dynamics and numerical simulation.
She is going to talk about...
Flux Reconstruction Correlation Procedure via Reconstruction in Computational Fluid Dynamics.
Let's welcome her.
Hi, I'm Bi-Yao Zhuang.
I'm a fourth-year doctor of George Washington University.
I specialize in fluid dynamics and numerical simulation.
I recently learned about a new numerical method called Flux Reconstruction.
Oops, I accidentally typed the wrong title.
Never mind.
It's called...
It doesn't have a Chinese name.
It was first proposed in 2007.
The second paper was published in 2009.
Other groups joined the field in 2012 and 2013.
It doesn't have a Chinese name.
It's called Flux Reconstruction.
You can see the title here.
It's a reconstruction.
Some groups thought it was a bad name.
So they renamed it to Correction Procedure via Reconstruction.
It's basically the same.
There are two groups in the UK.
There are three groups.
One is at NASA.
One is at Stanford.
One is in the UK.
Stanford and the UK are called FR, Flux Reconstruction.
NASA is called CPR, Correction Procedure via Reconstruction.
I recently learned about this.
I think it can be used for my doctoral research.
It's just started in computational physics.
There's still a lot of room for development.
I just finished learning this.
I read a lot of papers about this.
So I have some insights.
I'm here to make a progress report.
I'm here to share with you what this numerical method is all about.
What I'm going to talk about today is...
First, let me introduce some basic concepts of numerical methods.
I'm not sure what your background is.
So I'm going to give you some basic numerical methods.
To avoid people who are not doing numerical simulation and don't understand.
Next, I'm going to introduce how to introduce Flux Reconstruction.
Basically, the first part is like a math class.
It's a mathematical introduction.
The last part is how I want to apply it to incompressible flow.
Because my main research is on incompressible flow.
The group that proposed Flux Reconstruction.
Like Stanford or the UK.
They're all doing compressible flow.
So at least so far.
If you look for literature review.
I haven't seen any group using this method.
Incompressible flow.
So I'm going to do my research in this direction.
So I'm going to give you a brief introduction.
What's my future plan?
First of all, I'm going to introduce a very important concept in numerical methods.
It's called the mass-distribution method.
It can introduce all kinds of different numerical methods.
It's the foundation of the foundation.
So I'm going to introduce it.
There's a partial differential equation.
At present, many phenomena in the natural world are unified by partial differential equations.
We call it a unified equation.
I'm going to use a symbol like L to represent the partial differential operator.
It's a partial differential symbol.
An example of L is the so-called heat expansion equation.
What you see in the video is the heat expansion equation operator.
U is an unknown function.
A function that we want to solve.
If it's a heat expansion equation, it's a temperature field.
The temperature field changes with time and space.
If it's in the fluid, it's a velocity field.
F is a function on the right-hand side of the equation.
It's a constant.
It may be related to your physical phenomenon.
For example, in fluid mechanics, F may be a gravity field.
In the heat expansion equation, F may be a heat source.
It's a thing that generates heat without realizing it.
If today's partial differential equation is its exact solution.
It's the real solution of the real world.
It's called U-exact.
Although we want to get U-exact.
Because it's the real solution.
But in reality, we can't get it at all.
I'm not sure about the partial differential equation.
But in theory, we can't guarantee that there's a real solution.
So we can't get the real solution today.
So we think of another way.
Let's assume a solution.
For example, if today's U represents temperature.
If U represents temperature.
Let's assume that today's temperature in this space.
What does it look like?
Let's assume what it looks like.
There are some unknowns in it.
Let's solve it.
For example, let's assume that today's temperature field.
It's a function.
It's a series.
Like Fourier series.
Or Laplace series.
You can write it as sigma ci phi i.
ci is an unknown function.
phi i is what we assume it looks like.
For example, I have a simple example here.
If phi i is defined as xi.
If phi 0 is a function.
If phi 1 is x, phi 2 is x².
Let's assume that today's temperature field.
If phi 0 is a function of じ, then x is its value.
If phi 1 is x, then x is its value.
Let's assume that today's temperature field has this function.
What we need to decide is who these values of  texted fields intelligence.
What we need to decide is who these values of texted fields intelligence.
How many values
Total elementaryigation
Final investigator
How many
x