Q&A
Hello, I am today's representative host, Zhang Yanyong, because our host, Zhang Jianyuan, he is actually more suitable, because he is doing Qubits, doing condensed matter, but he is now stuck on the road, he has no time for transportation, so I will represent the host.
Let me introduce our speaker today. Our speaker today is Dr. Zeng Yuqing. The topic he is going to talk to us today is ... I want to read it right, wait a minute, I suddenly can't find it, wait a minute, wait a minute.
Topological quantum phase transitions in Haldane spin chains. This is a very popular topic, because in 2016 or 2017, Topological Matter won the Nobel Prize, so we have always hoped that we could invite an expert to introduce to us what topological phases are.
Then, Zeng Yuqing, in 2005, got a college degree from Donghai University, a physics major, right? Then he went to serve in the military, and then served in the military for 1.5 years, but he served in the military at Donghai University. Why?
After I served in the military, I returned to Donghai University as a research assistant.
Then there is a published paper in PRB, if you are interested, because I don't have that number, so you can directly ask our speaker for this thing. Then he transferred to Central University and completed his Ph.D. degree. The main function is also condensed matter theory.
At present, Zeng Yuqing is at the University of Kent in the UK, and he is now focusing on numerical study on the time-reversal invariant fractional topological insulator. This is a very hot topic, so we don't have much to say, we applaud and welcome today's speaker. Oh, if you want to applaud or ask a question, remember to turn on the microphone.
Let's get started. Today I prepared some props.
I have some props. You can play with some props later.
I will talk about some of the things I have done before, which will be more professional. First of all, what is physics?
What we mainly learn in physics is quantum mechanics. Quantum mechanics is like classical mechanics, which is mechanics, or kinetic mechanics of electricity, quantum mechanics, thermal mechanics, and statistical mechanics.
This whole thing is actually studying the interaction between time, space, and matter. The interaction between matter has, for example, strong, weak, electromagnetic, or gravity.
You can take the whole world, these substances, as if they were actors on stage. The stage is the background between time and space, and there will be some interaction between the actor and the actor.
The whole thing will form a movie or a stage play.
What about matter? This is from when I was very young, for example, in high school or elementary school, I learned that we can classify matter in this way.
First, divide it into solid matter or mixtures. Mixtures, such as beer, milk tea, or air, are mixtures.
For example, alcohol, water, and many other substances, such as beer, flowers, and so on.
For example, most of the air is 4 out of 5 gas, and 1 out of 5 oxygen, for example.
Pure matter can be divided into elements and mixtures. For example, the elements in the cycle table, such as gold, iron, oxygen, and O2.
For example, the previously well-known graphene, which is basically carbon.
For example, alcohol is a mixture of alcohol and water.
Alcohol has a chemical form, such as CH3CH2OH, which is alcohol.
Chlorine is also a mixture of pure matter.
Oxygen is also a mixture of pure matter.
For example, ice is water, which is the solid of water.
Ice is also pure matter, which is H2O.
This classification is probably a little bit of preliminary understanding of matter.
To understand this understanding further, we can see that matter has many states.
This state is called phase.
There is a change between the phase and the phase, which is called phase change.
For example, the ice or water we just talked about is under pressure in the horizontal axis and temperature in the vertical axis.
For example, at the bottom of atmospheric pressure, below 0 ° C, it is solid.
This side will be liquid and this side will be gas.
The red line is from here, it will pass through a waste point and then become water vapor.
From here, it will pass through this ice point and solidify into ice.
For example, this picture.
Of course, you can't see the water vapor with your naked eye.
Because the water vapor is transparent and colorless.
If it is connected to this water drop on the glass, it will become a liquid.
You can see that this is water.
This is the water we usually see.
Ice is solid.
This picture is in our present.
It's snowing in the UK recently, and it's cold.
After the snow, many people want to do an experiment.
Put the liquid nitrogen on the snowman and then destroy it.
See what the result is.
In short, this picture of water should have been seen in elementary school.
I don't know if there is any problem.
If not, I want to emphasize that there is a critical point here.
The meaning of this critical point is that if the temperature and pressure are very high from here to the critical point, you will not be able to distinguish whether the water is a liquid or a gas.
After this critical point, there is no red line.
The red line on the left has been extended.
This point stops at this critical point.
So if this side is gas, this side is liquid, this side is solid.
This line completely separates solid and liquid.
But here you can adjust the temperature and pressure appropriately.
Then let it slowly go around this critical point from here.
Then enter another item.
In other words, the phase of the liquid and the phase of the gas are the same phase.
The three-dimensional picture of water here is actually only two phases.
There are only two images like this.
There should be no problem.
This is a relaxing video.
A few days ago, we put the liquid and gas on the snowman.
Many people came to see.
There are about 100 people here.
Other dramas have come to see.
I think this is interesting.
You can see that gas is also a pure material.
Pure materials have three-dimensional pictures of water like just now.
Now pour out the liquid and gas.
The liquid and gas are about 70K.
It's about 100 degrees below zero.
The temperature of the ice is very high compared to the temperature of the liquid and gas.
The temperature of the liquid and gas is very high compared to the temperature of the liquid and gas.
It turned the ice into a lower temperature.
If you look at the image of the water just now, it is still solid.
That's about it.
What is a phase?
What does this material mean?
You have an external parameter.
For example, you just saw that there is temperature and pressure.
Under the external parameter, the material is in a huge state, a macro state.
What are the external parameters?
For example, temperature pressure, magnetic field, or external control, external control.
For example, you add a power plant.
Or you use other elements to replace these compounds.
You do some mixing.
This mixing can also be regarded as an external parameter.
Mainly these parameters, you do these modifications.
It will affect these, because the material is composed of those atoms.
It is composed of those particles.
If you modify these external parameters, it will affect the interaction between the particles.
If it affects the interaction between the particles, it will have different phases.
The higher the temperature, the more chaotic the material is.
But if you have an interaction, the material may have a different order.
What is a macro state?
For example, the three-phase change just now.
That is, the liquid, solid, and gas.
But it is not that only the liquid, solid, and gas are a macro state.
For example, conductivity.
Conductivity is also a macro state.
Magnetic field is also a macro state.
For example, mercury.
In 1911, it was discovered by Ernst that when the temperature dropped very low, it suddenly became a superconductor.
This conductivity is its conductor.
For example, the horizontal axis is the temperature.
When the temperature is very high, the temperature is absolute.
From this place, you can see that there is a conductor here to meet the Ohm's law.
The lower the temperature, the smaller the conductor, but there is still a conductor.
But when the temperature is about 4K or 4.2K, the conductor suddenly disappears to almost none.
It is completely none.
This can be regarded as a phase change.
Because this is a macro state, the whole change.
Because there is a conductor here, there is no conductor here at all.
Here is the general conductor.
On the left side, it suddenly becomes a superconductor.
The superconductor has great application value.
For example, later we found that mercury is a pure element, but other compounds may also become superconductors.
Like these high-temperature superconductors.
High-temperature superconductors can become superconductors as long as they are at the temperature of the liquid atom.
For example, these same compounds.
You will see that there is an X in these different compounds.
There is an X here, right?
This X is when you synthesize this compound.
How much ratio do you want to put in?
How much ratio do you put in?
Then you go to burn this compound.
Then you mean that this X is your external parameter.
Your center axis is your temperature.
Different temperatures and different cross-sections.
The horizontal axis is the cross-section.
Write a P on the right is that you are in the electric field.
That's what this X means.
Write a N on the left is that you are in the electron field.
Here is electron dot and hole dot.
This place is when you are not involved.
Here is a superconductor.
When you are involved to a certain extent, when you drop to a low temperature, it becomes a superconductor.
So this place, this range is a superconductor phase.
This range is a superconductor phase.
What is a superconductor?
Then go on.
Magnetic.
In fact, there are many kinds of magnetic.
What we usually see is a magnet.
Like this magnet.
When we were in elementary school, we would take the magnet and sprinkle some magnetic powder to look at the magnetic field.
The magnetic nature of this magnet is called magnetism.
That is to say, there are many magnetic fields inside the magnet.
Many small magnetic fields.
If these magnetic fields are originally messy,
If the temperature is very high, then these magnetic fields will be randomly arranged.
After randomly arranged, the whole is not magnetic.
But if the temperature drops,
Then there will be some interaction between this magnetic field and the magnetic field.
These interactions will make these magnetic fields align in the same direction.
When everyone is lined up in roughly the same direction,
The overall magnetic nature will be displayed.
You will see that it is a magnet.
It is the overall direction.
For example, this arrow is N-level, this is S-level.
If everyone is messy, then the whole is offset.
I found a YouTube video.
Probably like this.
Can you see it now?
There should be no problem, right?
Yes, I can see it.
There is a piece of iron on the top.
After the magnet is burned red,
The red magnet will be messy.
Then there is no magnetic nature.
But after it slowly cools down,
When the temperature is low enough,
Because it has an interaction between the magnetic field and the magnetic field,
It will align everyone in the same direction.
In the same direction, there is a magnetic field.
If there is a magnetic field, it becomes iron magnetic nature.
Iron magnetic nature is the meaning of this magnet.
There should be no problem.
Another one is that it is well arranged,
But it does not have the magnetic force of the seed.
The magnet of the seed.
Although the magnet is iron magnetic nature,
What does iron magnetic nature mean?
That is to say,
How does this magnetic force come from?
Part of it is the orbital momentum of the electron.
And the other part is the magnetic field.
If these magnetic fields are interspersed,
For example, here is up, down, up, down, up, down, up,
Intersected and arranged,
It is also well arranged,
But it does not have the iron magnetic nature of the magnet just now.
But it still has a magnetic field.
Although this iron magnetic nature does not have the magnetic force of the seed,
But it is completely different from the iron that was completely messed up just now.
Because the magnetic field of the burning iron is messy.
This iron magnetic nature is very well arranged.
After that, I will mainly talk about the magnetic fields of one-dimensional.
What if it is arranged into a chain?
Of course, this is the intention below.
Because you are not taking a magnet,
Because there are countless magnetic fields in a magnet itself.
Or there are many magnetic fields inside.
Then we will discuss later.
The magnetic field is arranged into one-dimensional.
Then this magnetic field has some interaction with the magnetic field next door.
Will this cause a whole?
Will there be a state of order?
Or is it a whole?
What is the order?
Simply put, everything has an order.
For example, electronics also has an order.
Light also has an order.
Paper also has an order.
Quark also has an order.
Everything has an order.
The order is a basic physical nature.
Light also has an order.
The order of light is 1.
The z-direction of light can only be positive or negative 1.
So we see that light has a polarizing direction.
There is a left-handed light and a right-handed light.
Light has an order.
The order of light is 1.
The order of light should be divided into two categories.
One is 1 in 2, 3 in 2, 5 in 2, 7 in 2.
This kind of half-order should be half-order.
This kind is called Phenol.
Another kind is the order of the whole.
For example, the order is 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
This kind is called Phosphorus.
Light has an order of 1, so it is Phosphorus.
Electronics has an order of 1 in 2, so it is Phenol.
Sorry, go on.
That's right.
Can I?
Yes, you can.
So the spin-chain discussed later is related to the order of the whole or half-order.
These are two very different types.
Before talking about these orders,
let's talk about symmetry.
What is asymmetry?
Asymmetry means that after you have done a certain operation, the result does not change.
For example, as I just said,
parallel symmetry, rotation symmetry, mirror symmetry, time parallel, time inverse, any operation.
Can you see me now?
Yes, I can see you.
For example, I take this.
If you don't look at the pattern on this ball,
if they are all the same color,
if I turn 360 degrees like this,
I'll cover it up first,
then I'll turn a little bit,
and then I'll show you.
Then you don't know,
you will never be able to tell whether I have turned or not.
Right?
So it means that this ball has the symmetry of this rotation.
But there is already a pattern on it.
Of course, this pattern will destroy its rotation.
Because I turn like this,
you recognize this pattern,
you know I have turned.
But if this is all blue,
then I can turn this three-dimensional corner,
this three-dimensional corner.
This is a rotation symmetry.
This apple,
this apple, you have an imagination first,
there is a meme here,
and then go down here.
So if I turn like this,
then you will find that it is different.
But if I turn like this along this axis,
suppose its shape is perfect,
then you will see that it also has the symmetry of this rotation.
But the symmetry of this rotation,
only with this Z axis as the rotation axis,
you have this symmetry.
I can turn like this.
I can also turn like this, right?
I can also turn like this.
The symmetry of this apple is less than the symmetry of this ball.
Because it only rotates like this.
This ball can rotate in any way.
If this is the case,
you will see that this and this ring,
I made a finger ring,
this finger ring is the same,
that is, I turn like this,
the result does not change.
With this bagel,
this is also.
But if I turn like this,
you will not know that I have turned.
In this case,
if I put a sticker on it,
do you know that I have turned?
For example, I am very hungry now,
let me take a bite.
Now after being bitten by me,
it has lost the symmetry of this rotation.
This is also.
This bagel is also.
If I don't bite too big,
I'll take a bite first.
I bought a lot today.
I bite a little bit.
I don't bite this hole.
Then it has no symmetry of this rotation.
In other words,
what does this bite cause?
Caused a defect.
This defect will affect a lot of things.
What I'm going to talk about later is TORP.
TORP,
play a little game first.
I have a finger ring here.
This finger ring.
If I use a pen,
many people should know this.
If I go from here,
then follow this ring,
go around like this.
Go, go, go,
go around,
go around and pick it up.
Wait for the paper to turn 360 degrees,
I'll go back to the original point.
These two are not the same.
One,
I also do this.
Like this.
I also go back to the original point.
But this is not.
When doing this,
this ring is very different from these two rings.
This ring is just like this finger ring.
This finger ring is actually the same.
I twisted it a little bit.
In fact, this ring is just like this.
This ring is like this.
So you see,
I'm drawing black here.
If there is,
usually there is an ant walking on it.
After going around,
you will go back to the original place.
This ring is like this.
This ring is not.
This ring is the so-called Mobius ring.
If I have an ant here,
go like this,
go, go, go,
go around,
go,
it will,
it actually,
I'm going around now.
Go around,
the result is that this path runs to the back of this ring.
It's not the same as this.
After two laps,
I will go back to the original point.
This is a
completely different thing from a few boxes.
Oh,
go back to the video.
That
I just said,
this is symmetrical.
This is symmetrical.
That
This is
The symmetry has been destroyed.
That
with
What does symmetry have to do with it?
Because we know
that
if you
if
you have a
energy or
free energy,
if it is a certain parameter
of the function,
then you basically
free energy should be like
energy is like the lower the better
stability
that if your
first
your function is like this
that
you have a ball here,
then it is of course symmetrical.
Because this is the point of symmetry.
The point of symmetry is of course
the lowest point of energy.
But if your external parameters
change,
for example, your temperature
temperature changes
temperature decreases,
your temperature is getting lower and lower,
which causes this function to change.
At this time,
the lowest energy state
will not be in
this
symmetrical state.
And it may
choose
in
a certain
more
free energy
lower place
that this place
that of course
every place
this place
or this place
free energy
energy is as low
as it should be
on the left or
on the right
do not know
it may
it is
it
has a little bit of
orientation
to the left
or a little bit
to the right
when it is very natural
it will soon
run to
this stable place
that like
this place
that
if it is like this
you will find
it is not symmetrical
you were
originally
left and right
this has a
mirror symmetry
that is now
not symmetrical
that is not symmetrical
represents
a
order
occurred
that is
a certain
like
for example,
we just
looked at
that
distance temperature
experiment
that
burning red
iron
there is no
magnetic
burning red
iron
it
its magnetic
is messy
that
very messy
when
magnetic
although
it has magnetic
in every place
it has a lot of
this
that
order or
magnetic
for example,
this magnetic
that
but the temperature
is very high
it
every
magnetic
are
constantly
doing
this
is
constantly
in
where
the magnetic
current
it looks messy
while the correct values
and the negative
the正負
the positive
附
are
going
to
change
the
magnetic
is messy
messy
that
how to say
it is
symmetric
it
magnetic
that
moment
it
hands
is very messy
or
you have a camera
you you you this camera
to observe
and then you
shift this camera
that you find
it still messy
as just
the same mess
is that
you can not see what it is
you can not tell
you have no rotation
I did not
I did a shift
or did a
rotation
you can not tell
so
it
in the previous
film
that burning red iron
has what symmetry
it has
symmetry
also has
rotation
but
after the temperature
is reduced
it
because
magnetic
between
its interaction
the
more
strong
more obvious
that
hot
not enough
to make it
to make it messy
so it will
cause the
overall
magnetic
direction
a
that
this time
if everyone
in the same direction
when it
that you
this time
you will find
that I have
no
this
rotation
symmetry
is that I
rotate
symmetry
that
I
just that direction
originally pointed up
everyone pointed up
that I rotate
everyone
in one direction
you will find that it
has changed
that
is not symmetrical
this is called
a
symmetrical
symmetry
that
is that it
has a sequence
that you say
it is
a change
that
this is
our most
traditional
ah
material
to
occur
that
the
most
ah
a
recognition
is that
this is the
theory of
the
blue
path
that
it
should
be that
we have
a
is that
there is a
sequence of
this
is that
there is a
sequence
that
means that
it occurred
a change
that
but like just
ah
sorry
interrupt
that
sequence of
English
what
sorry
I just
want to
continue
that
ah
some things
are not
like this
ah
that
later
will continue to talk about
that
later found
ah
there is a
change
ah
it
is the earliest
a
Russian
ah
he called
Brzezinski
he found
he was
a model
that
later
because he
seems to be
published in
this story
is written
in Russian
and then
earlier than
Kostelits and
Soles
that later
no one knows
Kostelits and
Soles
they also
counted a
thing
and then
found that
it actually
has a
change
but
this model
it did not
occur symmetrical
they do
this model
is like this
just
talk about
that one
that
seems to be
here
this amount
as
is not
a
quantity
is a
is
a quantity
of words
is that
he
will talk about
the amount
here
is this amount
is
a
quantity
you have
XY
on the
plane
and then
you have
on the
square
every one
in this
square
every one
on the
square
put a
quantity
of the
corresponding
quantity
do
just write
a
internal
interaction
that
this model
to see
it did not
destroy the
rotation
because
I
put
me
in this
Z axis
as
the
axis, then
I
just rotate
a few degrees
is 0 to
2拍
0 to 360
degrees
I just
turn a little
or turn a
lot
just turn a
few degrees
any angle
you
will
say this
model
this energy is
unchanged
this
so
there
is such a
continuous
rotation
symmetry
that
there was a
theorem before
called
Mermin
Wagon
theorem
is that
if you
only have
the corresponding
interaction
then
you
have
a
continuous
symmetry
that
continuous
symmetry
that
is
below
the
equation
but
they found
that
in fact
even if there is no
continuous
symmetry
it
will not
occur
symmetry
does not
mean that
it will not
happen
and this
image
was proposed
by
Kosterlitz
and Thorez
later
we called
KT
transition
or BKT
in high
temperature
first of all
because it
will not occur
symmetry
so
as long as
you have a
limit temperature
it will not
be that
orderly
so
for example
you
write this
energy
like this
in front
of a
symbol
that
if
J is
the
internal
will be
lower
internal
base
is
the
internal
base
is
high school
the
length
of this
symbol
multiplied by
another
symbol
multiplied
by
cos
theta
if theta
is 0
if the
theta
is
then
this is
vertical
is 0
so
there is a
symbol in front
of it
so if the
energy is
lower,
of course,
it is best
to have
the same
amount
for each
symbol.
If it is
the opposite,
the
energy is
the highest
, so
the
same
energy is
the lowest
, so
it is
the lowest
energy
in the
ground state
.
Of course,
of course,
there is order,
but as long as
you have a little
temperature, as long as
there is a little
temperature,
it will not be
the direction,
it will not
be all
the same
direction,
it is
absolutely
that is
not
destroy this
if everyone
is the same direction,
then of course
the symmetry
is destroyed,
then there is no
symmetry,
but there is a
change in
that
is what
the situation
is high
temperature
when it
is
a little
when
there is a little
temperature
that
these
will not
quantities
will not be
the same
direction
that
will not be the same
that can only
can only
form some
called vortex
is
some
whirlpool
like this
at a very high
temperature
when
these
vortex
like this
regardless of
any temperature
these
vortex
because you
have to
you have to
be in
line
you have a
vortex
is
that
in fact,
this
is the first
example of
this
is that
you have a
vortex
that you have
another
opposite
vortex
that
this
positive
vortex
with
opposite
vortex
at
low
temperature
is
two
tightly
tied together
but
if the
high-temperature
when it
is a
one-by-one
solution
is
every
one
of the
vortex
are
free
in
this
line
or
this
quantity
configuration
inside
running
around
so
that
is
caused
such
a
problem
is
that
I remember
when I was
learning xy
mother, he
said that
it was not
a waste
to
calculate
its
coherence
length
,
one is
power
decay,
one is
exponential
decay,
then how
to connect
that thing
to
your
side
?
Well
,
well
if the
coherence
length
,
because
the first
is the
definition of
Mermin
Wegener
,
first of all,
if it
doesn't
have
order,
its
coherence
length
must be
decayed
to
zero,
but
it
is
very
slow
power
decay
,
well
I think
this may
be carefully
inferred
to see
its
connection here
,
I think
it seems
that there is
no way to
directly use
a very
intuitive
way to
see that
this place
is a
power-low
decay
that you
have this
picture,
for example,
you have to use
math to
represent,
for example,
the physical amount
is different
on the
left and
right
,
which
is to
use
what
things
to
say
there is
no
similar
things
all the
parameters
well
,
the
problem
is that
you can not
define a
thing,
for example,
the left
side of the
back
is still
zero,
the
right side
is
zero,
the
left
side
is
zero.
In
fact,
the
left
side
is
zero,
the
right
side
is
one,
so
they are
different,
so
we can
not
say
that
is the
old
parameter,
but
here
well
you can
only
calculate
its
value
that
is the
old
parameter,
but
you can
only
calculate
its value
that
is the
old
parameter,
that
is the
old
parameter,
that
is the
old
parameter,
that
is the
new
parameter
that
is the
old
parameter,
that
is the
new
parameter,
that
is the
old
parameter,
that
is the
new
parameter,
that
is the
old
parameter,
that
is the
new
parameter,
that
is the
old
parameter,
that
is the
new
parameter,
that
is the
new
parameter,
that
is the
old
parameter,
that
is the
new
parameter,
that
is the
old
parameter,
that
is the
new
parameter,
that
is the
old
parameter,
that
is the
new
parameter,
that
is the
old
parameter,
that
is the
new
parameter,
that
is the
old
parameter,
that
is the
new
parameter,
that
is the
new
parameter,
that
is the
old
parameter,
that
is the
new
parameter,
that
is the
new
old
type
that
is the
new
parameter,
that
is the
new
type
that
equal to
isz
is
this
case, then
this is a
quantum mechanics
model
that
its
here
is
the
internal
machine, then
it is also
xx
yx
zx
that
this model
if x
is equal to
one-half, then
you can use
a mathematical
technique called
beta
ansatz to
solve it,
then
after
solving it,
of
course,
there is
another
mathematical
theorem,
which
is the
three people
lib
that
lsm
three people
this
theorem
is to
use
you
define
another
operator
out
and then
put it
on the
ground state
and then
found
it
with the
original
ground state
is positive
and then
found
this
positive
state
of this
positive
state
is
with the
ground state
is
positive
and
its energy
to
the
thermodynamics
limit
to
infinity
n equals
when
it
is
the energy
of the
ground state
is
the
difference
equals
zero
such as
the right
side, then
here, of
course,
directly
use
numerical
above
it
to find
is
its
parity
is equal to
positive or
negative
one
of
an
excited
state
and then
these two
to
thermodynamics
because
why
I say
because
this
is
sometimes
in
finite
size
n
equals
zero
is
p
equal to
positive
one
that
this
excited
is
negative
one
but
if n
equals
two
times
but not
four times
it is
the opposite
that
in short
here
is a
positive
one
that
we
now know
that
it
is
said
that
this
four
is equal to
one
of
the
Isenberg
chain
it
has
what kind
of
nature
that
there is
another
model that
is
p
equals
one
but
you add
this
after
adding
this
one
you
S equals
one
of this
model
becomes
the
strict
solution
that
the
strict
solution
that
the
strict
solution
after
solving
its
ground state
looks like
this
big circle
is
a
spin
one
thing
that
the
two
small
points
are
two
you
see it
as
this
spin
one
plus
of the
two
so
here
can be
positive
one
negative
here
can be
positive
one
negative
so
there are
four
possibilities
that
four
possibilities
but
spin
one
it
has
another
spin
form
singlet
so
after
the whole
string up
if you
are
in
open boundary
condition
you find
the
spin
one
no one
can
match
it
so
becomes
a
free
state
come out
so
you
can see
it
has
a
boundary
and down
so
it
has
four
possibilities
but
pbc
if you
make a
circle
this
spin
and this
will
form
singlet
singlet
still
can
calculate
another
thing
is
you
put
a
string
and
cut
into
two
sides
called
b
and
you
put
this
ground state
trace
the
b part
and
calculate
its
reduced
density
matrix
this
reduced
density
matrix
suppose
if
it
is
like
a
density
matrix
there
is
your
density
matrix
should be
exponential
negative
beta
h
but
you
that
this
h
is not
a part
of
the
Hamiltonian
that
this
h
do not
know what
the
Hamiltonian
is
generally
this
temperature
beta
does not
mean
that
the
previous
temperature
absorbed
this
Hamiltonian
inside
it
put
this
Hamiltonian
called
entanglement
Hamiltonian
that
this
Hamiltonian
it
its
eigenvalue
is
that
i
is
the
eigenvalue
of the
row a
then
you
take the
log on
both sides
you will
find
that
I want
to know
this
entanglement
Hamiltonian
spectrum
that
is
to do
that
if you
do
two
you will
produce
two edge
if it
is a
your
density
can be written
as
this
product
way
that
written
this
product
way
is
obvious
no matter
what
row 0
is
that
your
omega
if
you
are
using
infinite chain
you
here
do not care
this
boundary
you
here
far far
far
then
you
cut it
in the middle
and then
go to
count
here
you
will
find
that
you
look like
this
configuration
and then
it
Intangible
spectrum
because you have
edge state
so
in
the
face
if you
cut an
edge
you
are
two-layer
decoding
if you
are
periodic
boundary
condition
that
you
will
if
you
do not
add
symmetry
then
you
Z2Z
this is
the
face
that
this is
the
face
that
you
also
here is
no
order
here
also
no
order
here
you
do not
add
any symmetry
but
you
can see
here
is
possible
here
Intangible
spectrum
is
at least
two-layer
decoding
here
is
not
necessarily
two-layer
decoding
here
no
decoding
this
is
topological
face
a
possibility
probably
like this
that
well
here
all
are
temperature
energy
so
just
that
XY
model
is not
the same
as
X
Y
model
is
not
the same
as
X
Y
model
if you want to
use
Intangible
spectrum
to see
if it
has a
topological
face
that
is also
problematic
because
we do not
know how
to define
a
temperature
Intangible
that
maybe
turn
the book
that is
so
that
Houghton
of course
you know
he took the
Nobel Prize
that
he
Houghton
and
Kosterlitz
Solace
three of them
together
to get the
Nobel Prize
that
they
the
official
Nobel
Prize
that
Houghton
picture
is different
picture of the
Houghton
there is another
contribution
that the
picture of Houghton
is a
circle
that
is a
spin
that
this stick
material
like this
words
that
Houghton
mentioned
that his
idea
after
it
soon
that
there
have
experiments
to put
the material
Material
made
out of the
course is
the 3rd
but
the
Stem
Spins
particle
that
next to this
is a
green
green particle
that
green
green words
like
Spin2
also have
a green
words
is a
a
low-orbit
through
this
green
like
for example,
Spin2
good
like
this
strong
and
then
hit
that
Super
Exchange
that
he
may
jump over
here
and then
jump back
that
will become
like this
Hamiltonian
like
this
material
good
this
along
C-axis
is a
chain
this is also a
this
is also a
chain
that
in the
chain
inside
it
through this
green
to reach
this interaction
this
Super
Exchange
interaction
that
different
chain
you see
this
to
it
will
if
also
interact
like this
then
it means
that
J'
J