Q&A
Today's speaker is Dr. Wu Xinmei, a Ph.D. student at the University of Utah, majoring in geoscience.
Before coming to the U.S., she was a graduate student of the Department of Geosciences at NTU.
Xinmei and I have met in many areas that are not overlapping.
I met Xinmei when she was a Ph.D. student at the University of Utah.
My wife and Xinmei were classmates in college.
After coming to Caltech, she met another Taiwanese friend in the Department of Physics, and turned out to be Xinmei's classmate.
She will be talking about Anatomy of Ophethal in Yellowstone from Seismic Observation.
Let's give her a round of applause.
Oh, by the way, you have to turn on the microphone to hear the applause.
Thank you for the introduction.
Today's presentation is a relatively easy one.
There won't be a lot of formalities.
I will focus on the concepts.
Because people are not familiar with geoscience or geophysics,
I will focus on the concepts and focus on Ophethal Geyser.
Ophethal is a very famous geyser in the U.S.
If you go sightseeing in Yellowstone Park, you will definitely go to Ophethal.
I hope you will find this topic more interesting.
First, let's talk about Yellowstone.
Yellowstone is on the left of Wyoming, Montana, and Idaho.
This is the intersection of the three states.
This is the area of the National Park.
Ophethal is on the right of Wyoming.
Let me introduce Ophethal first.
Ophethal is a place where people rarely go to sightseeing.
People usually go sightseeing to Ophethal.
Because it takes about five hours to get to many national parks.
So if you drive from Ophethal to Yellowstone, it will take about five hours.
If you have a chance to visit, you can come and visit.
Yellowstone is famous for its volcanic activity.
People have heard of Ophethal.
But if you come to the National Park to sightsee,
what you see is not volcanic activity.
It's more like a geyser, a hot spring, or a hydrothermal feature.
I'll go into more detail later.
If you drive from West Yellowstone to Ophethal,
it will take about 30 to 40 minutes to get to Ophethal.
So, after you drive in,
you will see the National Park,
and then you will see Ophethal.
So, after you drive in,
you will see parking lots,
and then you will see the Visitor Center.
And then you will see Ophethal.
You can sit here and wait for it to erupt.
You can find the pathway up here,
and the upper part is called the Geyser Hill.
It's called the Geyser Hill because this is the place
with the highest density in the world,
and it has the hydrothermal feature.
So, you can see a lot of things smoked or hot water,
hot springs, and some geysers.
So, if you come to Yellowstone,
you will definitely come here for a walk.
So, you can see things like this.
It's very colorful.
A lot of colors.
These colors are usually some biological,
microorganisms here.
There are a lot of microorganisms here,
so the colors you see are mainly caused by
the impact of the geysers.
So, this is the map from the north to the south.
This is the Geyser Hill,
and there are a lot of hydrothermal features
around it.
This is Old Faithful,
and it's just over there.
There's a video on the right,
because we go out there every year.
So, this is the video.
So, I thought Americans knew,
but a lot of Americans have never been here,
so they wouldn't be surprised.
Old Faithful has a lot of features.
First of all, it's spectacular when it erupts.
Second, it can be predicted.
It can predict when it will erupt next time.
And if you go to the tourist center,
they will put up a sign
to tell you when it will erupt next time,
so you can sit there and wait.
But there's usually a 10-minute error.
If you Google Old Faithful Webcam,
you can see that there's a real-time camera
looking at Old Faithful.
I heard that a lot of people who like geysers
watch Old Faithful Webcam every day.
If you're interested, you can Google it.
Old Faithful can predict,
which means that the eruption
from this time to the next time
is very stable.
So the graph on the right
shows all the statistics
from 2000 to 2011.
This is the probability.
The horizontal axis is the eruption interval,
which is how long it takes
from the first eruption to the next eruption.
And it has a peak value of about 92 minutes.
So this is the prediction
for the last 10 to 20 years.
But if we look at the longer period,
from 1878 to now,
the eruption cycle is about 60 minutes
to the present 90 minutes.
And then there's another one.
You can see there's a little peak here.
It's not very obvious.
It's divided into long eruption intervals
and short eruption intervals.
The short one is about 60 to 65 minutes.
And then the long one and the short one,
you can...
I don't know what it's called in Chinese.
Anyway, a lot of park rangers
will do all kinds of things
in the National Park,
or they'll do a lot of things.
For example, look at the length of the eruption.
The eruption time is about 2 to 5 minutes.
If it's a long eruption,
the next eruption will be 90 minutes later.
But if it's an eruption
that feels like it's going to be gone in two minutes,
the next one will be about 60 minutes later.
So all the predictions
for the Old Faithful eruption
are based on what you can see on the surface.
But the National Park
is a very protected environment.
So even if there are a lot of geologists
and geophysicists
doing research here,
they can't do research for a long time.
They might come for a few hours
or a few days.
Although the Old Faithful eruption
has been recorded
about 100 years ago,
it is still possible
to make the next prediction
based on the data from the eruption.
So why is there a long-term change
or why is there a short-term change
or why is there a long-term change?
The real mechanism is still unclear.
If you have any questions,
you can ask at any time.
Let me talk about
how we use geophysics
or geophysics
to study the structure of the fountain.
People are usually unfamiliar
with seismology.
Although seismology is traditionally
known as earthquake science,
it mainly uses some relatively large energy,
such as very large earthquake energy,
to understand the information
from the source
to the process in which you receive it.
So why do we want to study the fountain
or the interstitial fountain?
First of all,
it has a very important indicator.
In fact, all the structures
under the ground
or some physical mechanisms
are quite similar to volcanoes.
So you need a lot of water
to get to the bottom of the fountain.
There is a narrow channel
called the conduit,
and there is a reservoir
below it.
There is also a volcano,
which you may have heard of.
In the process of temperature pressure
or building,
they move forward.
You can see the animation here.
These are the lava,
because of the temperature
and pressure below,
and some mass.
The lava is mass,
and then it moves forward
to a critical value,
and then it moves back.
The lava is a mass,
and it moves forward to a critical value,
and then it moves back.
Most of the volcanic prediction
is to use the mass movement
to generate signals
and contact delays.
If you have an earthquake
near the volcano,
you can get some earthquake signals.
So geysers have similar principles.
But when it comes to studying volcanoes,
a lot of them erupt every few million years
or every volcano grows differently.
And it's dangerous to study volcanoes.
A lot of people don't want to die
because of studying volcanoes.
So if we can find a way
to understand the mechanism
of geysers,
we might be able to
apply our understanding
of volcanoes in the future
and do some analysis of volcanic disasters.
Hello.
Before you move on to the next page,
I'd like to ask a question.
Someone has a question.
Wu Mengchang has a question.
Do you want to ask it yourself?
You can turn on the microphone.
Can you use artificial geysers
and your internal structure
to create animations?
Animation?
Do you mean volcanoes or geysers?
I mean your animation.
There are a lot of studies
on volcanoes.
It's not just one or two studies.
If you go to IRIS,
you can find a lot of
visual education content.
Most of the research on volcanoes
is very complicated.
If it's an earthquake signal,
it's coming from a very deep
or shallow place.
There are a lot of ways
to analyze it.
The geyser I'm going to talk about
is a bit applicable.
If you have any questions,
please feel free to ask.
I'll talk about
traditional geyser theory.
It's what I use.
If there's an earthquake,
the geyser energy is very strong.
It will pass through
different waves.
For example,
if you put a station here,
you can receive the geyser signal
from that station.
Geyser theory uses
such a geyser signal
to analyze the source of the earthquake
or what effect it has
on the path of the geyser.
This is the most traditional geyser theory.
In other words,
if you have a geyser,
you can use this energy
to study the structure
between the source and the receiver.
If you know the source,
you can use it to study the path.
This is a bit of a trade-off,
but there are many different kinds of research.
It's scientific.
We can verify each other
and it will become believable.
I think this is the only way
to look at the internal structure of the earth.
NASA is now putting a geyser on Mars,
so it's very difficult
to predict the structure of Mars.
This is a bit of a trade-off.
Now I'm going to talk about
my own research.
I'm going to talk from the biggest structure
to the smallest structure.
This is our yellow picture.
This is a picture of Mars.
This is the Geyser Hill.
The red circle is the path.
Each red circle is our instrument.
We don't know what to look at
We try to spread it evenly.
Let's see what we can get
It's about this big
You can go and dig a lot in a short time
There are frequent circumstances where people can enter.
If an earthquake may impact an environment or human activity,
As fast as you can imagine,
it's a long forest.
this type of instrument will be more innovative in the near future
This type of instrument will be more innovative in the near future
This is not a traffic jam,
but a structure.
But what can you prevent?
What will you do?
Likewise, the signal becomes delayed and the current is shrunken because of the distance.
Similarly, the signal becomes delayed and the current is shrunked because of the distance.
Similarly, the signal becomes delayed and the current is shrunken because of the distance.
Use a common fact to distinguish between two sign boards.
you can find the signal that's stored in the noise.
Find its origin.
Find the recommendation time.
Use concrete feedback to perform cross-student calculations to find its origin.
Do you have time or distance?
Good or bad roaring dragon
But when it's high frequency
You can see I drew a box here
Blue area
High frequency when it passes through the blue area
You can see its waveform
The first waveform is late, very obvious
The second is that it has a lot
Smaller and higher frequency
Wiggle is
One by one we call coda
What does this mean
This means that the high frequency
Small wave
Relatively small wavelength
In a shallow place
When it passes through this area
Obstructions
Here are some
Objectivity
Of course, you can use some
Earthquake learning methods to guess
What is the situation
You can also be a model
I won't talk too much
Because of this
Observation results
Find out
There is a relatively large
Hello
I have a problem with the front page
it is good
My question is
Did you frame the blue box
It's obvious when you frame it
There is clustering
This is different from the other set of data
But if you don't frame the blue box
I slipped when I looked at my eyes
Really
I mean
Very difficult
Can be seen at a glance
If your test today
Ten more times
Isn't it more difficult
I'm curious
Technically
Try to adapt
For example
Machine learning
Autoprocessing
Pre-selection
Interpret
Or you can see it
This
This picture is for us
Very obvious
Can be seen
So
I think machine learning is definitely the future trend
My boss is still working with
Computer science
Want to do real-time
Real-time
To see the changes
But these are more
And especially machine learning
You need some training data
You have to have some
Know some
Knowledge
You can apply it to the future
Prediction
But machine learning is definitely
Must do
I didn't talk about this bar
This bar is
We predict
This distance
If I predict the same speed
Where will they be
So it will be obvious
You see them
1 km
But this area
They become
0.5
I think
It must be good
You have to see
Very small
But this is very obvious
We have to
To see
I think
The answer is good
So we can
Different frequency
Different sensitivity
So we can
Sensitivity and range
To estimate
This thing
How big
Relatively deep storage
Water
All to
The system
Water
If it's a volcano
It may be a lava pool
I forgot to say
The slope is from A to A
So it's just a slope
The low frequency I just talked about
Southwest
Ice Age
Northeast
Lava
The purpose is
Because
We have a lot of volcanoes
Taiwan also has a volcano
But geyser
Feature
Very rare
Why is it rare
You have so many hot springs
It actually needs a specific geological structure
To be able to
Such a condition
For O-Facebook
The first one you can see
This
Reservoir
Like a reservoir
It's not directly
At the bottom of O-Facebook
It's in the southwest
Why
Because
Relative to this
Geyser
It's easier to break
If you have temperature or pressure
Give it a lot of temperature or pressure
It's easier to fracture
So when you have water
From below
They prefer
It's easier to break
This is another
Result
Then I just said it was big
I'm going to talk about it now
It's not me
Let's talk about this little one
Smaller
What I'm talking about now
Bubble trap is this one
It's probably in this
It's about 300 meters deep
Then
The depth is about
20 to 60, but this is much smaller
This is probably
20 meters deep
Then the width
Then they said
This is another way
They set up a lot of stations
It's on O-Facebook
You can see this
It's completely different from our first station
This is a little bit denser
Then it's more focused
They don't use
The source
They use O-Facebook
Their own source
Then go and see
For example, I have an energy here
Then I have a very dense array above
My energy to this station
They will have a time difference
So they use
Array
Very dense array
All the energy
Where did it come from
I'll talk more about it later
This energy
Now
It's part of the structure
They found
For example, from the last station
Between
The energy is divided into two areas
The first area is almost vertical
Under O-Facebook
The second area is the red area
Is more to the south
A little bit
Because of this discovery
I think
O-Facebook structure
It may not be
Just a channel
There will be other
This is called
Cavity or bubble trap feature
It has an offset structure
The constraint here
Not very good
But after all, the energy still comes from here
It means that there is actually
There is a structure here
This discovery
Very important
Because you said
A lot of modeling
Geyser modeling
Research
It actually needs very
Determine
What does it look like
Do you have one
Involved in this
It's very different
So
This discovery is actually quite a lot
More surprised
Then
Conjured
This structure is too small
All
Referred
Conjured
From this reference
This is about 20 years ago
Whether it's Caltech or Berkeley
Then they just put it directly
Camera
Put the camera down
From O-Facebook
Put it down
What does it look like
If you are interested, you can watch YouTube
That feels like
Explore outer space
Satellite environment
Anyway, it looks like this
Then there will be a lot of explanations
Why do they do this
What did you find
The interesting thing is that they
In the past
Maybe the instrument or something
Will not receive more restrictions
You can't be there when it erupts
So they are
This observation
Actually did it for two or three years
Then what did you say in the first year
It's a big bubble
In the water of Bolin
Then go down
Then go again in the second year
Then the main thing is
About 20
He can
The camera can reach about 20 meters
20 meters deep
I'm not sure
If this restriction is also
If you have a feature next to you
Then its pipe is very narrow
Then you may not be able to get out of the video
Can be seen
But this kind of observation
Is very reliable
What you see is what
If it is an earthquake signal
Or some signals
He actually
There is an error
You have to measure
How much
Ok
The first half of the structure is like that
If you have any questions, you can ask now
How much time
If not, I have to continue
What I'm talking about now
Old Facebook
Your own
What is the signal
That is
This paper
He is mainly using signals
I think this will be more interesting
Ok
So if you have a station
Put it in
It should be super close
Maybe put it next to it
Then this will be
If that station is on the ground
This is the signal we received
This is a whole day
This is a 24-hour signal
So you see he is 90
About 90 minutes
Every 90 minutes
Related cycle
Then
If we only look at one
This is about 100 minutes
So there is a burst
If you look at it
Where do you think it will be
Where
I probably won't
This red curve
It is the real record
To the time of the burst
So you see before he
We think
More than 10 hertz
The signal
Even stronger than
The signal when you burst
This signal
If we zoom in
You can see a very obvious
Event
This kind of signal
From
We are talking about
Bubble collapse
For example, you cook
You cook a pot of soup
There will be a lot of small bubbles
Then slowly float to the front
Colder water
Then they will
Break off
Every event
Relative
Relative to
You can see a lot here
Recorded
Then this picture
This is the signal
You see the water coming out
The first one
Before the burst
The energy is much smaller
Then he grew up
It's completely different from them
Then
We won't talk about it today
The signal of the burst
Before the burst
Like these signals
Can bring us
How can we do research
How can we use these signals
To understand
What is it
So
There are a lot of
The first
Burst every 90 minutes
Why
So
This kind of thing
There is a fixed pattern
There will be a certain pattern
For example, here
There is no event
Then there will be more
So the first one
Let's calculate
How many
Along the time
This event
Then do the statistics
A total of 30
Is
One
A total of 30
Then
Use eruption time
As a reference
Then all the time
Relative to the time of the burst
20 minutes before the burst
40 minutes before the burst
60 minutes before the burst
Then hope that if we
Collected a lot of eruption cycles
See if there is a fixed pattern
This is the number
Gray is the number
So it has a very
The fixed pattern is
It will have a number
Peak
20 minutes before
20 minutes before the burst
Then there will be a decrease
Then there will be an increase
Then the red is
If you consider not only the number
You consider the size of each event
Then the pattern will look like this
In addition to the number
What else can be done
You can see
Each of these events
Is there a number
Or they all look different
Or they actually have a set model
So what you can do is
I don't know if you know
Cluster analysis
Use it
For example, you have
You have a box of blocks
It may have different shapes
Different colors
Then you can sort by color
You can also sort by shape
You can also sort by whatever you want
Then our sorting method is
The similarity of the waveform
For example, this looks like this
Or this looks like this
Use this to sort
Then the sorting method is
The same is the cross-section coefficient
This is not a function
We just use it
When they are the most similar
What is the coefficient
So the coefficient will be between 0 and 1
0 is the least similar
1 is exactly the same
Then this
Same
This is the time series
You can compare it
Eruption time
Then
20 minutes
To do cluster analysis
Every blue dot is every event
If this is a cluster ID
If the ID is very close
If they are nearby
It means they are more similar
If it's the same ID
That means between them
At least 0.8
The coefficient is at least 0.8
So it's from 0 to 1
If it's the same ID, it's probably 0.8
0.8 will be
The number is very similar
So the first thing to pay attention to
You can see
For example, there is a cluster here
Is it closer to the ID?
Then there is another one here
There is another one here
Another thing to pay attention to
You can find different clusters
They are relative
Relative to the time of eruption
It's different
Like this cluster
It's more likely to be 40 minutes to 80 minutes
Then this cluster
It's about 30 to 60 minutes
36 to 60 minutes before the eruption
Before the eruption
Actually nothing
Fewer events
Like this cluster
It's more like late
You
Did you spray all the water this time?
Is it before the next eruption?
It's slowly accumulating
Maybe there will be water
Fill in
Fill in the hot water
Or fill in the underground water nearby
Or it's building
Its pressure and temperature
Then it will erupt until it reaches a critical value
Then in the front
We say this is called recharge
It's a bit like recharge
I don't know how
Then the early recharge
It's more likely to have this kind of wave
That mid-range recharge
There will be a wave like this
This is actually good news
Because you have this pattern
If it is fixed
If it is every eruption
If it has this pattern
We can use it to study a lot of things
We can study
Where did this wave come from?
What is its source?
Is the location different?
Is the shape of its source different?
There are still many possibilities
Or you can use this pattern
There are many eruption cycles
If they are all the same
We can use this pattern
To do prediction
Especially machine learning
If this pattern is
Between certain error ranges
Then you can use
Such data as knowledge
You already know the knowledge
Then as training data
If you can have more data in the future
Or you can
For technological progress
You can use this information
To do machine learning
These are the four clusters I chose
Let's see what they look like
You can find an average
Let's see what this group looks like
This is the first cluster
This is the first row
The second cluster is the second row
The third cluster is the third row
The fourth cluster is the fourth row
The red one is for time series waveform
The blue one is for frequency
The units are hertz
So it's 0 to 100 hertz
The good news is that these four waveforms
If we do not see the EU flu
They will be very similar
we can see that the frequency ratio
The low frequency waveform
is likely to be 10 Hz
like this
is like this
There's only one eruption cycle
If we use the same method
We can see that the other eruption cycle
Is it the same?
Or is it different?
You will find that
These two look very similar
These two are a little different
But the low frequency part is very close
This is also good news
It's not just the eruption time
It's not just eruption time
Even the inner process
Is very close
At least 10 years
So
What can you do
I just mentioned
I am planning to do a more detailed prediction
Not just the pulses, but ability to combine the numbers
Or, you could even set the times and odds
Add lots of videos
Like deep learning machine learning
Do prediction
And if the country really gives them the green light
If the terrain is great
You could do monitoring
And make sure this works
To be more scientific
I'm curious about the bimodal eruption
Why sometimes it's 90 minutes
Why sometimes it's 60 minutes
If you have a complete data set
You can use a lot of data to do statistics
Why sometimes it's 60 minutes
This is important
Like when we talk about volcanoes
How do we predict the next eruption
Last time it was 60 million years
Last time it was 10 million years
And the last picture is also outdoors
Outdoors is beautiful
But it's cold
Not fun
It's open in winter
We went there in November
Because it's easy to get super cold
And it's open in December
But only for snowmobiles
If you want to see what winter looks like
You can rent a snowmobile in December
But it will be cold
Thank you
Please go ahead
It's hard to understand
What am I saying?
I said if it's hard to understand, you can say it
Because I will adjust it next time
Because I don't know how to do it
No, I think you said it very well, very clearly
Oh, really? Thank you
She kept nodding her head, she said it very clearly
Okay, Meng Chang has a question
You can just ask
Turn on the microphone
Okay, I want to ask
They can't see the changes directly?
So in our field
First, you have to have a source
For example, you do X-ray
X-ray or something, you have to have an energy
Or radar, you have to have an energy
To hit it
But if your energy is not strong enough
Or the frequency is not right
You won't be able to see the scale you want
The scale or the depth
So if we want to look at the ground
It usually requires relatively strong energy
You have to be
For example, have you heard of
Oil companies will use a big car
To fix it
But this kind of energy is very
It will destroy the environment
If you have been there
There will be a lot of warnings
You can't jump
Or you can't go to certain places
Some people will go crazy
Because these
They need a very special environment
This environment is relatively fragile
You can't let that water
Release pressure to the surface
So we are now
If you want to look at the underground environment
Then you have to go through
A more indirect method like us
You have to use some natural energy
Or something
But there is a limit to this
Because the source of these energies
You can't control
You have to find the right source
Find the right thing
You can use it to see
What you want to see
But my impression is
Like oil companies
They look at
They also have
I have heard that they may also use
The so-called atomic clock
Because the atomic clock
The density of the surface changes
The change of gravity
There will be a change in the structure
Very sensitive
So he can use the atomic clock
To measure
This place
What is its composition
Correct
No need for destructive things
I am not
I don't know much about the atomic clock
But I think if
If there is such a way
If you can see
Everyone should have used it long ago
So I think he should have his limits
Because there are actually a lot of
Battery
I forgot how to say
Some ways to use batteries
Very local
But it is very limited
It is limited to
The range of your ears
If your ears are small
You want to see such a small structure
But you can only see about 1-2 meters deep
But if you want to see
Big structure
If you want to look deeper
Left and right
Lateral extension
Can't see a few meters
This kind of thing
So I think every one
We all use this kind of indirect
More indirect method
This method has its own limits
So I don't know the atomic clock
But I think he must use his limits
Otherwise, everyone has used it long ago
Because the atomic clock is still
A very big country
A plan to find a way to build
Because he is
Probably only the United States, Japan
France
I'm doing these things
So I don't know
Maybe it's very expensive
But I heard before
I heard before
There is a private company
Sponsor a laboratory
Their publication
Will not be put on the table
But there is a private company
To pay for their research
So I guess the cost
May be a lot
That's about it
But the oil industry is super poor now
We are almost out of work now
So I don't know
Maybe it's hard to pay
Now the oil is super cheap
Thank you
But it's a very good proposal
Actually, I don't know much about it
Does anyone else have any questions?
Let me ask a question
Just
Because we just saw all the data
It's all in the real world
The horizontal axis is the real time
Then the vertical axis is your
But you are
Under such data
You just actually emphasized
Most of the time
The time to trigger
No matter when you assume
Or the real time
Then you calculate the time
My first question is
Then you said cross correlation
Can remove a lot of
Uncorrelated background
If you look at
Amplitude, will there be any new
Information or better resolution
This is the first
The second is that since you want to do
Cross correlation
You plug that
The position of the measuring instrument
Shouldn't it be
Very strict and uniform
But I think you seem to be
A little bit along the way
Is it okay?
Let's talk about the first government
Government
This is a very good
Good question
Generally speaking, we are
It's easy to come up with
Is the time difference
This message
In the most traditional earthquake
Because of the relationship
Or because of a lot of uncertainty
For example, your earthquake
For example, you have a small one here
Earthquake, it will decline
But not just because of the distance
It's because of what you've been through
Or is there anything next to you
Influence its transmission
These will affect the government
So the first one is traditional
Or what I'm talking about now
I'm talking about this result today
It doesn't include government information
Second, if the government
The message is to be applied here
It will be relatively difficult
But we're doing it now
Because it's not just one
There are a lot of features here
That every feature
For example, like this station
There is a very strong pool nearby
It gives it a lot of energy
For government information
If you look at the whole area
Then it will be a lot of
Localized government
But for cross-referencing
We're promoting now
There are a lot of people
Trying to include
The so-called government
But you have to be sure
It's a real signal
It's not a lot of
Localized artifacts
Then
We're going to do it again
What's the second question
My second question is
You're in this station
It's basically saying
Is there any limit
Because I think this position
Is there an average
It should affect you
Cross-correlation structure
You're talking about
You said
The address conditions below
It's just that
The distance between the station and the station
Need to be even
My idea is
Between your station and station
To be on this projection
It should be very even
Then you will
You're going to be
The result of your cross-correlation
You can make it lower
I think I don't know
That if you want
If you want to do
Of course it's very
Very very complete
But if you're really going to
It's almost impossible
But of course it's more
The more complete the better
I think we've done our best
And he doesn't allow us to go
He doesn't allow us to go
We can't leave this path
You can only be next to the path
So this is already the best
And then
Will there be a systematic effect
I think it will
But if
It depends on your size
For example, we want to look at
A relatively large structure
Our structure is here
Between your station and station
These are a little uneven
The relative error is actually for this structure
It's more minor
So when we're doing
Any research
We have to think about the first
The second one is between our station and station
Is the distance suitable
To explain something like that
So
That's about it
And then the government
This question is very good
But I'm still doing it
But of course I want to have government information
But because it's going to be too much
Localized energy
Is there any question?
Felt like
Zhen said very well
But she really understands
I don't know what she knows
But she heard very well
You can do it
What did you say
There's a lift
Right
You can do it
You can ski
Ok
Our time
Today is just right
The speaker's time is very good
I want to use
The right of the host
To ask everyone to turn on the microphone
Otherwise, there is only my voice
Let's applaud again
Thank you to our speaker
And thank you all for coming
See you next week
Bye bye
Thank you
Can I turn it off now?
Yes