I'm very happy to have you all here today for Lin Bo-xuan's talk.
Let me first introduce our speaker, Lin Bo-xuan.
She studied economics at NTU, and is now a sophomore at NTU Economics.
Currently, she is an intern at a startup company called ModLab in Pasadena, California.
Her main topic is game-related data analysis.
Today, we are very happy to invite Lin Bo-xuan to give a talk
about how to use class experiment data to test the stability of the final window match
and the results of the double-sided auction experiment.
Let's welcome Lin Bo-xuan to start her talk.
Thank you, Director Lin.
Without further ado, I'll get started.
Today's topic is very simple.
I'll just ask one question.
Are the results of the economic experiment we see on paper stable?
To be honest, in the field of economic experiments,
people are the ones doing the research.
So, if you want to say that a result is stable,
you can't just say,
if I were in Taiwan, I'd do this result.
Or, if I were in a victim group, I'd do that.
Often, we need to do a lot of different victim groups.
If we were to say that this result is right for all humans,
then it should be right to take the same result
and do the same experiment in every place.
But in fact, we often know that
this situation is often not necessarily right.
For example, let's say we measure the risk.
In Taiwan alone,
if you only measure the risk for men or women,
the set of risks may be different.
So, in fact, if we want to measure stability,
that is, if we want to do the same experiment
in many places, the result is wrong.
But often,
what we want to do
is actually very difficult in the experiment.
First, because economists know
that our research funds are limited.
Second, our time is limited.
So, often, it's hard for us to think about
whether we can do the same experiment
in every corner of the world.
So, this is a very difficult thing.
Because, mainly, there is a big limitation in economic experiments.
In fact, we hope to provide real benefits to consumers.
Because of this,
we need a lot of money and a lot of time.
We need to have a good enough time design.
Basically, it will be impossible to measure in every place in the world.
So, because of this,
we did not give up
to test whether our experiment results are stable or not.
So, there are two main ways
to do this on our website.
First,
for example,
in the case of Ultraman Game,
in fact, in the past 50 years,
there have been a lot of studies on the series of Ultraman Game.
So, basically,
there is a method
that we take the previous experimental data
and break it into a very large database
to do some meta-analysis here.
Just like what Usterbeck did in 2004.
But, like this,
there is a problem.
In fact, many times,
all the previous studies of Ultraman Game
are the same game,
but their context is a bit different.
So, in practice,
many times, your usage is different,
or your context is different,
which may affect the result of the experiment.
So, when we use this method,
we have already lost the control
of our experimental design.
Although this method
can make our database very rich.
The other way is that
we control the same experimental design,
but go to other places
to do the same experiment.
Just like Roth,
he has been to four countries in the world.
One is the United States,
one is Slovenia,
one is Israel,
and the other is Japan.
He went to these four countries
to do the same final analysis
and market game
to see if the results of these four countries
were stable or not.
This is the largest experiment
so far.
But, from this point of view,
even so,
we can only do it in a small number of places.
So, in this way,
although you can
control your experimental design,
but you can't make
your database very large.
So, today,
what we are doing is
using the third method.
It's like
you want to test the stability
of a result of an experiment.
There are three things to do.
One is the real sound,
and the third is to have a large enough sample.
The first two methods
are to give up
and control the experimental design.
The other is to give up a large enough database.
But what we are going to do today
is to have a large enough database,
and the design
is exactly the same.
But what we give up today is to give up
and control the sound.
In this case,
I can only say that we are the first article
to do this.
We have a lot of data.
But when we give up
and control the sound,
our experiment
will be done in a very
no-easy situation.
So, if we can
reproduce
all the experimental results
in the lab,
it means that the experimental results
are very stable.
As I said,
what we are going to use today
is MobLab.
MobLab is an experimental platform
for all class economics experiments.
If we take all the data from the class,
it is actually good and bad.
Of course, the two biggest concerns are
that all the students in the class
do not use money
to provide their sound.
Most of the time, they just use
the grade of the course
or other random numbers
to provide their sound.
This is what we have lost control of.
The two biggest concerns are
that many students in class
may not necessarily be
the representative sample
of the culture.
However, there are still
a lot of benefits
for us to try this method.
First of all,
there is no publication bias
in our database.
For example,
if you take the results
of the previous article
as a meta-analysis,
you may get too good results.
This is called publication bias.
However,
all the results, good or bad,
are recorded in our database.
Another thing is that
our company is
at least in the class of
experimental economics.
If you want to do a class experiment
in the world,
you basically use our company.
In fact, our sample is very diverse.
There are many different areas.
This gives us a lot of
variation to test.
Thirdly,
the environment in which our data is generated
is exactly the same.
The interface, language,
and the entire experiment process
are exactly the same.
This means that we have
completely controlled
the process of their game.
These are the three advantages
that we think
are very important.
Before talking about these two areas,
I would like to talk about
how big our dataset is.
First of all,
we can see that
this table is a total of
10 areas in our dataset.
You can see that
this data is across North America,
Europe, and Asia.
In Ultraman Game,
we have more than
15,000 sample points.
For those of you who do not know
the economics of time,
the data in Ultraman Game
is about 10 times more than
a normal article,
or 0 to 2.0.
In DoubleAction,
there are basically 2.0 more.
This is a very large sample
that we can test.
Next,
I will talk about these two areas.
These two areas are actually very simple.
The first is Ultraman Game.
In addition,
why do we choose these two areas?
The first is because these two areas
are the most abundant in our database.
The second is that these two areas
are basically the origin of
the economics of time.
In Ultraman Game,
there are two people in this game.
One is Proposer,
the other is Responder.
Proposer can decide
how much to give to the other party.
This game is very simple.
There is a ball in the middle.
You can decide how much to give to the other party.
You can pull the ball
and decide how much to give to the other party.
If you decide,
you can press Submit.
In this way, the other party can see
how much you gave to the other party.
Next,
suppose I decide to give the other party $45.
In this way,
the other party can see
that this is
a Proposer you have provided.
Proposer is
I take $55, you take $45.
Do you want to accept it?
If you are Responder,
if you decide to accept it,
you take $45, he takes $55.
If you refuse,
you both take $0.
This is a very simple environment.
It's like the simplest negotiation
in simulation life.
For example, when you go to the night market to buy vegetables,
you often say
that you might say in the last round
don't pull the ball.
It's like simulating such a concept.
This is the game interface
of our Ultraman Game.
Next, I want to talk about
double-sided auction.
The most classic example
of double-sided auction is
like Wall Street.
They are selling stocks.
You often see some pictures and news photos
that there may be a lot of machines
with a lot of stations.
Many traders are raising their hands
and shouting loudly.
It's like everyone is shouting at the same time.
How much do I want this? How much do I want this?
It's like buyers and sellers are arguing there at the same time.
So double-sided auction is
compared to Ultraman Game.
Ultraman Game has only one side.
I propose a proposal to you.
In double-sided auction,
no matter which side, buyer or seller,
they can call at the same time.
So in double-sided auction,
I will introduce what this game is playing now.
One is a buyer and the other is a seller.
So if you are a buyer today,
you want to buy something.
We are buying oranges here.
In this game interface,
the first thing you can see is
how much satisfaction you will get when you buy an orange.
This is called value.
Next, you have to raise a price.
You can pull a slider bar here.
You can move left and right
to decide how much you want to bid
to bid for this orange.
If you buy an orange,
your advantage is
your value today is
how much you spent to buy it.
OK.
If you are buying,
you have two ways to buy.
One is to bid here.
The other one is
if there are a lot of buyers in front,
they have already asked for a price.
So you can also buy directly at the lowest price.
OK.
The next one is
seller.
We have the same interface.
If you sell an orange today,
you have a cost.
So you will see your cost here.
OK.
Next,
you can pull a slider bar here
to decide how much you want to bid.
You can ask for a price here.
Or you can decide
to sell the highest price here.
So I can sell it here.
Then pay attention here.
There is a special design in our game interface.
When you decide to
ask for a price here,
if you ask for a price,
if the transaction
makes you pay a negative price,
I will make it red
to warn you
that
this transaction may bring you
a negative price.
So this is a double option
game interface.
Let me introduce
our game settings here.
This is because
in such a simple game interface,
many teachers
can adjust the game parameters
themselves.
But in most cases,
many teachers use our preset options.
In Ultimatum Game,
you can divide the money
into 100 yuan.
In the case of double option,
there are five buyers in total.
Then each person
can have three products to buy.
That is to say, there are a total of
15 things in the market to buy and sell.
If we draw this value,
this is our black line.
This is our demand curve.
Then the gray line
is our supply curve.
Before I start,
I want to talk a little bit
about the theoretical prediction
of these two games.
In Ultimatum Game,
the theoretical prediction is very simple.
If we look at it
from the perspective of the respondent,
we say that
the balance of a game is basically
that if I do this option,
the reward is higher than the other option,
then I should do this.
So if you look at the responder,
no matter what positive reward he sees,
I should accept it.
For example, if I take 1 yuan,
it is still better than 0 yuan.
So in this case,
if I get a positive reward,
I should accept it.
If I get a negative reward,
If I get a positive reward,
I should accept it.
So this is the theoretical prediction of Ultimatum Game.
But in fact,
in the past 50 years of research,
we all know that
this theory is basically written to be overturned.
This is because many times
when we do research,
we will find that
basically all the recipients
will not only give the other party 1 yuan.
This is Ultimatum Game.
Then in Double Option,
this is like a high school science textbook,
you will see Supply and Demand Curve.
If you want to solve this game,
it is actually very simple,
you have to find a price
to clear all the markets.
So if you are here,
this gray curve is the price
of our theoretical prediction.
It just happens to be the intersection
of Supply and Demand Curve.
If the price is higher,
it means that
there are more sellers who want to sell things at this time,
and fewer sellers want to sell.
So if the supply and demand are uneven at this time,
this force will force the price down.
But if the price is lower,
then there are more people who want to sell,
and fewer people want to sell.
So this force will push the price back.
This is also the intersection of Supply and Demand Curve.
This is our equilibrium price.
Then in our prediction market,
the number of equilibrium is 13,
and the price of equilibrium is 112 yuan.
So this is our game setting.
I want to stop here for a while.
Is everyone OK?
If there is no problem,
I will continue to talk about the results.
Wait a minute,
let me confirm first.
So the buyer's
willing price here is
150,
the prediction is 150,145,
140, and so on?
From 150 to 115.
So from 150 to minus 3,
how much is the last one?
The last one is about
112 or 117.
Then the other side is from 50,
and then keep adding up.
Yes.
Thank you.
OK, then I have no problem.
I want to continue.
Let's talk about
the overall results.
First of all, I want to show you
this table.
Let me summarize first.
We mainly looked at five outcome variables.
What are some of its numerical statistics?
First of all, in the Ultimation Game,
we mainly looked at two outcome variables.
One is how much proposal you give the other party.
The other is how much your acceptance rate is.
First of all, we see the first one.
In the case of 100 yuan,
on average,
you will give the other party about 36 yuan.
This number is actually
very close to the result of our experiment.
For example, if we take
Rock's article in 1991 as a benchmark,
the average of the article
is 40.
In fact, our gap is only 4%,
so I think it's a very close result.
Then the second one
we look at is the acceptance rate.
What we are looking at now is unconditional.
If we look at
the unconditional acceptance rate,
the acceptance rate is 66%.
Rock's result is about 73%.
So the gap is only 6% or 7%.
But because our offer
is relatively low,
I think our result
is able to reproduce
Rock's result at the aggregate level.
Hello, I have a question.
You just said
he made 40 and then 36.
Or let's just say
how much is the experimental
and how much is the theoretical expectation.
I think it's very close.
What I want to ask is
what do you think?
Because you didn't show
your uncertainty range.
Maybe it's actually a very stable difference,
so it's not very close.
This is
what I will continue to talk about later.
Because I'm going to show you a statistic now.
Show you an approximate
rapid statistics.
If you're right,
I should do some statistics
to see if there is a significant difference.
But in fact,
the first one is
this is one point.
If I want to do an assessment,
there is another problem.
Our sample number is very unbalanced.
Very unbalanced.
So it means that our sample number
is about more than 10,000 points,
and their sample number is only more than 1,000 points.
So in fact, many times,
when you do an assessment like this,
sometimes there are some
things that you need to pay attention to.
But in fact,
at least in the case of showing data now,
I can only say it out loud.
What I can only say now is
to see if it's close or not.
Next,
the other three are
the results of the double option.
For the double option, I'm going to use three indexes
to talk about whether this market
has been able to
refine
the prediction of the theory.
The first three indexes we look at
are the average error.
The definition of the average error is actually below.
DQ is the price of
each unit
of each contract.
Subtract.
This means
how much is the difference
from our theoretical prediction.
Next, I look at the average.
Because we often have
about 800 different market configurations.
So in order to make everyone
comparable, I use
the average price to standardize it.
So we can actually use this index
to see how much our accuracy is.
The next one is
our
Smith Alpha.
Smith is to commemorate
Brown-Smith.
This index is actually very simple.
It is the distance
between my price
and
the price of my theoretical prediction.
So I take the square here.
Then I take another one.
Next, I look at the average distance.
Then I open a number.
So it's actually like my standard error.
But
what I'm doing today is not average.
What I'm doing today is
theoretical prediction.
Next, I still use
my average price to standardize it.
So I can use this index
to measure the fluctuation of price.
The next
and the third index is Efficiency.
For Efficiency, I want to use
the above picture to explain.
So in this
market equation,
if this seller
makes a deal with this buyer,
then it shows
the above section
in the middle
is the profit I made.
It's the buyer's profit.
The following section is the seller's profit.
So it tells me
the total length of this section
is the
profit I can make
from this deal.
That is to say,
I sum up the area of
the supply curve and demand curve.
In theory,
this is the total
surplus I can get.
So this year's efficiency
definition is
the efficiency I achieve
in this market
and the efficiency
I expect in theory.
The following
can be seen as
the first one is
my average error is about 6%.
That is to say, my average price
is about 6% higher than the theory.
The next one is
my Smith Alpha.
The fluctuation rate
is about 30%.
The efficiency
is about 84%.
In fact,
these numbers are
significantly different from the theory.
However,
this is related to another problem.
In our lab,
we often let our customers
play the same game for 10 or 20 rounds.
At this time,
after more than 10 rounds,
the price will become very stable.
But here,
if we play for 10 rounds,
the customer may have gone up to level 3.
This is why the price
here is unstable.
However,
I will try to show
if our students
can play enough rounds,
where will they end up?
This is the result
of the double option.
Let's continue to see
the whole distribution.
I don't know
which computer
I used to jump out.
I don't know
what to do now.
Thank you for reminding me.
I hope you don't
knock on my door anymore.
I don't want to leave the group.
Thank you.
Let's continue.
First, let's see
the whole distribution of Proposal Offer.
Because
in our game design,
the teacher can decide
whether to play one round, two rounds,
or several rounds.
If you play more than two rounds,
it will become a repeat game.
If we divide the data
into a repeat game and a single game,
we can see
that
the first point
is
theoretical prediction.
This is theoretical prediction.
So here,
whether it is a one-shot game or a repeat game,
only about 10% of the audience
played on the theoretical prediction.
Next, we have seen
50% of the audience
played on the theoretical prediction.
Next, we have seen
50% of the audience
played on the theoretical prediction.
The first observation
is that we have a lot of Proposal Offer
on the natural focal point.
So I played 0,
10, 20, 30.
This is the first observation.
The second observation is that
only 6% of the audience
gave themselves
less than the Proposal Offer.
I gave myself more.
In this game,
there should be a first mover advantage.
I should give you 50% if I'm great.
According to the theory, I should not give you 10%.
But only 6% of the audience
gave more than the Proposal Offer.
This is the first observation.
Next, let's compare
the distribution with ROF.
This is ROF's distribution
in 1991.
As Mr. Zhang said,
we did not do a statistical analysis.
So we can only see
the distribution characteristics.
The first observation is that
the density is
about 50% to 40%.
The density is about 50% to 40%.
But this is
ROF's distribution.
So we can
give them the result.
In addition,
the biggest difference
between ROF and ROF
is that almost no one
played in the theoretical prediction.
But about 10% of the audience
In fact,
at least I and Colin
are not sure.
This may be the reason for the prediction option.
In the beginning of a game,
the prediction ball
is placed on the theoretical prediction.
So if the students
press the button
without thinking,
it means that
there is no strategy at all.
So 10% of the audience
may play in the theoretical prediction.
Of course, it may also be affected by the prediction option.
But this is...
Do you have the response time here?
I will fix it later.
According to your hypothesis,
the response time should be the lowest.
But the response time is actually very high.
But I will show the result later.
So it may not be the result of the prediction option.
Yes.
But...
Sorry, Bo-Xuan.
Can you show the previous video?
OK.
Because I just thought
if you said it was because of the default option,
then you should see...
Because the information of ROF
is very rare.
Almost none.
Yes.
But the people who chose 1
seem to be more likely than 0.
Yes.
So...
Although 0 is so high,
it may be the effect of the default option.
But it seems that there are more people
who are more likely.
If you look at the balance
as 0 or 1,
there are more people who chose 1.
Yes.
That's what I think.
Thank you for this comment.
But it is indeed...
It should be...
In this...
There should be a lot of people who play with the theory.
But it is indeed the default option.
This effect is indeed a confirmation.
But I will continue to talk about it.
Then here is
our acceptance rate.
Because I think this result is very cool.
So it doesn't matter if I talk about it later.
I will talk about it later.
First of all, because what we talked about earlier
is the unconditional acceptance rate.
What is more interesting now
is to measure the conditional acceptance rate.
Unconditional...
What is the number of offers I see?
That is to say, because we measure
the expected value of the conditions.
Then this is actually
a function of an offer.
So on this graph,
my X-axis shows
how many proposal offers I see.
What is the acceptance rate?
OK.
In this graph, the black dot represents the information of one-shot game.
The orange dot represents the information of repeat game.
Next,
the size of each point
represents
the density of the histogram
we saw earlier.
So if you put the size of this ball
projected to the X-axis,
it becomes the entire histogram.
OK.
Next, because when I was checking the data,
between 49 and 50,
there is actually a jump of about 20%.
So I thought it was strange.
So I used a specification
to measure
the P-splice linear
specification.
So what you can see
is that I think it is quite special.
If you are less than 50,
you see
that your acceptance rate is this curve.
When it is greater than 50,
there will be a big break here.
This is completely obvious.
It is very obvious.
When we measure the standard error,
we also use
a cluster.
We have a cluster at the session level.
So we use the most conservative estimation
to estimate our variability.
So in this case,
it is also very obvious.
If we put all the data together,
there is a jump of about 20% to 21%.
If we divide it into one-shot game
and repeat game,
the jump is about 16%.
If we divide it into one-shot game
and repeat game, the jump is about 26%.
First of all,
this phenomenon has not been seen
in the first 50 years.
So I think it is a very cool discovery.
Next, let's talk about 1.
First of all,
this interpretation is actually very complicated.
Because we have a lot of confounds here
that our database cannot detect.
But what we can be sure is that
at least the source of this break
is the difference in payoffs.
Because you can see that
when we come in from the left B,
you can come in from 49.99999.
Then the next is coming in from the right B,
it is about 50.0000001.
In fact, this gap is less than
how small your Epsilon is.
So this effect is definitely not
from monetary payoffs.
Or even if you are in a hypothetical state,
it is basically not from
how much your payoff is.
So it is very possible that
you have to consider
how other people
distribute the whole proposal.
Next, there are many interpretations here.
We can't uniquely pin down.
It may be like
because you are from 49.999 to 50.
There is a big gap here,
which is equality.
Because this paragraph can also mean
that I may be very, very care.
Am I equal to you?
Or this is the first one.
Or another one is that
if you don't give me 50,
I may punish you.
So this is why this paragraph
may be 10% more in the repeated game.
It may be that this 10% is more
that I want to punish you.
Or I may care about my fairness.
Or I simply
since we are not playing real money,
I just don't want to lose you.
So it means that
my acceptance rate is relatively low.
But when I can at least not lose you,
my acceptance rate is about the same.
This is what we see
in the data.
I want to ask
what is your idea?
I don't know.
Before you do this,
there is a problem.
Although you know a lot,
you just showed us
that there are very few offers above 50.
There are about 600.
So
your estimate of acceptance rate
is because
you are not using strategy method.
You are showing an offer.
So it means that
the point of return you are running now
when it is below 50
the variation
is relatively good.
But when it is above 50,
your estimate may not be stable.
But this point
is really interesting.
Because
let me think about it.
Have you ever tried
not to use
a linear return when it is below 50?
I haven't tried it yet.
But I want to try quadratic.
There is another possibility.
It is not like a breakpoint.
It is a
more complicated non-linear.
Because you fit linear,
it looks like a breakpoint.
If you look at the data directly,
it looks at least
I think it is quite linear.
If you look at the
orange repeating game,
it looks like
it is a
falling down.
But it is stable
when it is above 40.
It is like quadratic.
If you only look at
black,
it looks like
it is
between 20 and 50.
It is a steep drop.
But
it is stable
when it is below 20.
So
there is a possibility here.
It's just because
you fit a
straight line relationship.
Anyway, I will try quadratic.
But this is
what I estimated.
I think it is quite interesting.
If this is true,
how do we
reproduce this
breakpoint in the lab?
Let's look at
the result of ROS.
If we look at the data of ROS,
this breakpoint is completely invisible.
I think this result
is quite special.
We have a lot of work hypothesis
running at the same time.
But we have tried
a power test.
If we only draw the data,
the sample number is about 0.
So if we only draw 10% of the data,
can we estimate this breakpoint?
In our data, we can still estimate this breakpoint.
So it may not be because
of the problem of power in statistics.
Then another
work hypothesis is
hypothetical stake.
Is it because it's all
not about making money?
So I care more about the ranking between you and me.
At least I don't want to lose you.
So
this is my current work hypothesis.
This may be
the next article to do
is how to reproduce this breakpoint in the lab.
I think it's quite interesting.
Can you remind us
again
the population composition of your data?
For example,
the proportion of each state.
We have
seen that
the United States has the West,
the Middle West,
the Northeast,
the South America,
Canada,
the United Kingdom,
Spain,
China, Japan,
and Singapore.
What about the proportion?
About 80% of the data is in the North,
about 10% in Europe,
and 10% in Asia.
OK.
So overall,
this result
is more conservative.
It's based on the North America,
right?
Yes.
OK, I just want to ask.
But I want to add
that the problem is
all the results in the lab
are not in the North America.
Yes.
That's true.
OK.
Then I'll...
Bo-Xuan,
if you want to compare
with Ross's article,
Ross's article is mainly not in the North America,
but the data of
other works
such as Automaton Game
can be observed.
I have almost never seen any shortcomings.
Yes.
OK.
Because of the time...
You can go first.
I'll go first.
I have a question.
Because the article was written
about 20 years ago,
right?
Yes.
Do you think the change of time
has a big impact on the data?
Of course it's possible.
Because a lot of social preferences
may change with time.
For example, the value of Taiwanese
may change every few years.
So it's true that
there may be a difference.
But we can see that
there is a difference.
If we look at it simply,
if it has any impact on the shortcomings,
maybe it's okay.
Because the shortcomings may be a mirror effect.
But this is a big problem.
We can talk about it later.
Then I'll go on.
Finally, the teacher just said
to show the reaction time.
Because our server does record
the reaction time.
Then I look here.
Because in one-shot game and repeated game,
the reaction time is very similar.
So I only use one-shot game
to demonstrate the result.
First of all, the black line,
the y-axis is the reaction time.
The black line represents the reaction time.
Then the black line is
our lowest estimation.
Then the orange line,
the y-axis is my acceptance rate.
Then this is
also my lowest estimation.
Then below me,
the x-axis is
my offer.
If you don't have any concept,
you can think of it as
doing a return in each section
to measure it.
This means that
I'm fitting the data
when it's close to infinity.
It's very close.
So what the teacher saw at the beginning
was at zero.
It actually took a lot of time.
It actually took almost 20 seconds
to make a decision.
However,
at 50,
there was a very sharp drop.
It only took about 8 seconds
to make a decision.
This means that
50-50 may be
a very special allocation.
At least for them,
if I see 50-50,
I don't have to think too much
and I can decide to accept it.
Another thing is
we see a very sharp kink
at 50-50.
It's true that
no matter how
qualitative you are,
at least we can still see something.
This is the data
on the reaction time.
However,
the interpretation is quite special.
At least for Show,
at 50-50,
we can spend very little time
to make a decision.
You can't record
the proposal time
to enter the game.
Because if you want to see
if it's default...
We can see
the time it takes
to enter the game.
If you want to see
if it's the default option
that causes a lot of people to raise their hands,
you should look at the proposal time.
Yes, you're right.
We did look at the proposal time.
But I remember
it took a lot of time here.
Hello?
Let me respond.
At the close to 0,
you said
it took a lot of time.
You mentioned
that
you were thinking
at 0,
there would be a lot of people raising their hands.
At that time,
I was wondering
if it was because the starting point
of the slider bar was 0.
However,
if they spent a lot of time
to think about it,
I don't think
it's because...
I think it's a bit like
negating
the explanation you mentioned
at the beginning.
I just accepted it casually.
That's right.
But it took a lot of time here.
It took a lot of time
to respond.
But I should show you
the proposal time.
But it's true.
It's funny to explain the coding.
It took a lot of time
to look at this.
A lot of people didn't want to accept it.
It took me a long time
to accept it.
That's right.
Bo-xuan, you can
split the responder into
accepting and not accepting.
Okay.
This point is quite special.
I'll split it.
I'll write it down.
Next,
I still have some time.
I'm going to talk about the result of double option.
Double option, first of all...
Bo-xuan, before you enter the double option,
let's talk about the
Automatic Game breakpoint.
I was just thinking,
you just said that one possibility of the breakpoint
is that everyone cares about fairness.
The other possibility is that
everyone cares about
not counting you.
Is there a way to look at
the 50 proposed
in your data?
Is the acceptance rate
particularly high?
Or is it the whole breakpoint
after the breakpoint is raised
to form a frequency curve?
Because if you care about fairness,
maybe after 50 is particularly high,
there will be another breakpoint
after 51 and 52.
One-shot game is like this.
There is no repeated game.
Okay.
I'll keep talking.
I'm afraid I don't have enough time.
The next double option is...
The first thing I want to show here
is what the data looks like.
This is our predicted market.
The next one is
the price fluctuation.
This is just an example.
I have 10 regions here.
I choose a market for each region.
I draw it out to show you
what it looks like.
You can see that I only draw four periods.
Because the length is about four periods.
If you look at the first period,
everyone may be very noisy.
Then look at the second and third periods.
In fact, the price fluctuation
becomes less.
Then look at the fourth period.
The more they play, the more stable they become.
So what we want to see here is
that under the double option market mechanism,
as long as they play about three or four times,
consumers can find
a balanced price, even if I don't tell them anything.
The next thing is
what I said earlier.
Because our bidders play very short,
we want to estimate
what it is like.
If it can play a lot of games,
where will it end up?
We spent about a month
with Alex
to figure this out.
First of all, let's talk about intuition.
Don't think about intuition.
Let me give you an example.
Let's say
a lot of people here have the same experience.
When you apply for a PhD,
I want to know
how this student
will perform in the next career.
But the only information I can know
is his GPA for the next four years.
So
at this time,
if a student wants to estimate
what will happen next,
the only thing he can do is to increase his GPA
in different periods of time.
So it's possible that
I put more players in the last GPA
and fewer players in the first GPA.
So in this market,
you can look at two parts.
First, the left side is our dependable variable.
On the right side,
if T is 1,
that means I'm in the first period.
In this case,
it's back to the simplest way to go back.
This is very common.
In the first period,
if you use the example of GPA,
it means that in the first semester,
there may be a lot of variables.
Maybe it's because you're a middle school student
or you're from another school,
so it will affect your GPA in the first semester.
But in the second semester,
I only put you at the starting point.
Maybe you're a middle school student
or something like that to explain this.
I only give you a quarter of the weight.
I also give you a quarter of the weight
of your GPA at that time.
It means that your GPA at this time
may be only half,
and it can be attributed to
the population composition in front of you.
In the third period,
I put your GPA at two-thirds of the weight.
In this case,
I only give you one-third of the weight
of the starting point.
In other words,
if I can make T
converge to infinity,
then my beta2
is actually the progressive estimate
of our dependent variable.
In other words,
if we put this y
on all the indicators of the first three markets,
it means that this market
will converge to where
if consumers can play enough.
If we put this value
in front of our three dependent variables,
this is the mean error deviation.
The final price is only
1% higher than the average price.
It is not significantly different
from the theoretical estimation.
The final price change
is reduced to 11%.
Although the point estimate is a bit big,
it is also not significantly different
from the theoretical estimation.
Finally, we can reduce the efficiency
to 97%,
which is not significantly different from 1%.
So these results are basically
the same.
At least we can prove that
double option is a very stable
price mechanism
to achieve 100% efficiency.
At that time, we saw that
our data also showed the same thing.
When our students can play enough,
all of our waffers
should be exhausted.
The last word is
Can I go back to the last page?
Yes, you can.
I want to confirm
why there is no variable
next to beta 2
in the model?
Because this means that
I want to see where your final GPA
is. I bring a constant here.
I multiply here
by a constant.
This means that I am adding
your GPA
to your original
demographic variation.
Is it OK?
It doesn't matter.
If you don't understand,
I will discuss with you later.
I will continue.
What we see at the end is that
although there are some
theoretical estimates,
if there are still some gaps,
where are they?
What we see at the end is the amount of transactions.
The horizontal axis
is the amount of theoretical estimates.
The vertical axis is the amount of theoretical estimates.
The horizontal axis is the amount of theoretical estimates.
Here is the real
amount of observations.
You can see that
if the market is not balanced,
we are often under-traded.
This is because
the last 1-2 transactions
may bring us 1-2%
of the efficiency gap.
In this case,
I am too lazy to make the last 1-2 cents.
This is the main result of the double option.
We still have about 10 minutes.
I want to talk about
what I said earlier.
We have a lot of
transactions in different countries.
I want to use
some metanonysis tools
to analyze
the composition
of these transactions.
The first thing we look at
is the transactions between countries.
This is a
calculation in metanonysis.
This is a calculation in metanonysis.
It is called I-square.
If you look at the graph,
you can see that
these are
the average transactions
of the proposal offer.
Next,
we have all the transactions.
We have the transactions between countries.
Of course, we also have the transactions within the country.
What we want to know is
the proportion of transactions
between countries.
Let's calculate I-square.
Since we don't have much time,
I won't talk about how to calculate I-square.
However,
the proportion of I-square is
the number of transactions
from between regions.
We can see that
the result of the calculation is
86.6% of the proposal offer.
This is a very significant transaction.
Although we dare not say this is a cultural difference,
what we can say is
at least we can see that
the transactions between countries are very significant.
From the same perspective,
we look at the acceptance rate.
The acceptance rate is special
because we want to look at the acceptance rate of conditions.
What we have to do is
to compare the shape of the whole probability function.
In order to make it
comparable,
what we can do is
we ask for a logic regression.
On the left,
we put 0 or 0.1.
On the right,
we put 10 countries' dummy variables.
The result of the calculation is
the coefficient of the dummy variable
is the shape of the whole probability function.
We use this coefficient
to measure the variation between countries.
We can see that
only 30% of the variation
comes from countries.
This is not significant.
On the right,
we can see that
Proposal Offer has a significant variation
between countries.
The acceptance rate is not significant.
This is in response to
Roth's conjecture in 1991.
In 1991,
Roth proposed a hypothesis
that the cultural difference
between countries
should be
influenced by
Proposal Offer.
However,
the acceptance rate is not affected.
This is a good evidence
to respond to
Roth's initial hypothesis.
This is a good evidence to respond to
Finally, we look at the variation
between double options.
We look at the first round
of the market.
Then we look at
the first price
and the last price
between them.
We want to know
how the market price
is balanced.
This is the first price
of each market.
We can see that
only 27.3% of the variation
comes from countries.
This is not significant.
We can see that
the first price
between countries
is very noisy
because of
the standard error.
However,
the standard error bar
is quite large in other countries.
In the first round,
you may be wondering
what the price is.
In the last price,
the standard error bar
is very small.
Basically,
every country
can predict the price.
If we look at
the overall price distribution,
the first price
is about 0.33%.
In the last price,
the overall price is only 14%,
so the standard error bar is 60%.
This tells us that
in the beginning,
you may not know
what the price is,
but in the end,
you can get the balance
very stable.
The market will tell you
what the balance looks like.
In the end,
I will summarize
with this video.
In this project,
we tested
the stability of
the final purchase.
In the Ultimate Game,
we can see that
more than 94% of the proposals
are offered at 50%.
Many of the proposals
will be offered
at the natural breakpoint.
In terms of acceptance rate,
we saw a 20% breakpoint.
In the repeat auction,
we saw 10% more
breakpoints.
In terms of response time,
it is basically the lowest
at 50%.
In the double auction,
no matter which of the three indicators
we use, accuracy,
fluctuation, or efficiency,
we can predict
when our students
can play enough.
In the end,
we tested
all the variations.
In the Ultimate Game,
the proposal offer
has more variables
than the acceptance rate.
This corresponds to
Roth's contracture in 1991.
In the Ultimate Game
and the double auction,
we saw a big difference
between the two countries.
This corresponds to the fact that
the double auction is a very stable mechanism
in every country.
I think this is
all I have.
I will show my email.
If you have any questions,
you can email me or contact me on Facebook.
We have about 5 minutes left.
Let's see what questions you have.
Do you have any comments?
Thank you.
Please comment.
Do you have
any questions?
I will ask first.
Wait a minute.
The first question is for you.
You have to estimate the long-term result.
There is a way.
You can show us
the data
in the lab.
If you only use the first few rounds,
then you can estimate
the long-term result.
In this way,
people may understand better.
I'm not sure
how long
the gap
is.
How do you estimate the long-term result?
Let me explain first.
I mean
what you want to verify.
If it is a double auction,
then
why...
You mean Asians are more polite?
No, I mean
double auctions
in different parts of the world
are closer to each other.
However,
there is a big difference
between each country.
That's what I want to say.
Okay.
Let me think about it.
Because...
There is a problem here.
You mean
the market is
universal,
and
there is no
final
negotiation.
However,
there is a problem here.
If you don't use
the strategy method,
you can't see the
strategy of the
mutual fund.
So,
what you see
is that
in terms of
acceptance or not,
you can only explain
the 30% variation.
However,
in terms of
the actual strategy,
I'm not sure
how far you can go.
Maybe
it's because
different countries
have already explained
most of the proposal.
So,
it means
that everyone
has proposed
social norms
based on that culture.
So, there is not much difference
in terms of acceptance or not.
Maybe it's because
it's not in the proposal.
This is also
what I want to point out.
Ok, that's all.
Can I ask a question?
Sure.
Hi.
In the Ultimatum game,
0 and 100
have more than 2.
I agree with what Meng just said.
According to the proposal,
the default reaction time
might be
a factor
in the outcome.
But you said
you have an instruction
for the experiment,
right?
So, can you tell
what is
the incentive
to give
the same result
as the proposal?
Usually,
the incentive is
how many points you get
if you participate in the experiment.
But I don't know
what their design is like.
Maybe some of them
are related to the outcome
and give you points in proportion.
Some of them
just participate in the experiment and give points.
If they participate in the experiment
and give points,
the proposal or the result
basically have no effect on them.
If you compare the outcome
with Ralph's experiment,
it's normal to have more than 100 points.
Because the result
is just a result.
He didn't think of anything else.
As for the fact that
there are more than 0 points,
I think
it's just a question.
In general,
people who do the experiment
should be
from the economics department.
I don't know if this hypothesis is right.
But this is what I imagine.
And then...
There is also a postgraduate school.
Yes, postgraduate school.
It's a class
teaching the ultimate game theory.
It may teach the game theory
or something like that.
The problem here
is that
some classes
teach the ultimate game theory
and the theoretical prediction is 0.
Or
they do the experiment
before the theoretical prediction.
There is a gap.
Because if you do the experiment
after the theoretical prediction is given,
the default of many people
will be 0.
Let me respond to this.
We have seen different classes.
The smallest class
is the game theory class.
This is a response.
OK.
Can you see
the degree
of the class
related to the game theory?
Can you see this?
Yes.
We can see it.
Because we have the name of the class,
so we probably know.
What we can't see is
that they teach the theoretical prediction
before the game theory.
OK.
For 0 and 100,
there is a big difference
between these two classes.
So I think
if you can
clear the data,
or find the way
like just now,
then compare with the kink.
OK.
Maybe it will be closer.
I don't know if this will affect.
OK.
I have notes.
Thank you.
Hello.
OK.
You ask first.
OK. Thank you.
This is not a problem.
It's more like a comment.
Since
you have the default option
bias,
it seems to be a serious thing.
It will make your two curves
different from the theoretical one.
My idea is
can you...
Will it be too difficult?
Can you change the program
and make the starting point
different every time?
You can choose a starting point
to solve the problem.
Let me respond.
This is technically
easy to do.
But there is another problem
in economics.
I'm afraid there will be
the result of anchoring.
So...
Sorry.
If your starting point
is a very high offer,
you may be affected
by that point.
If your starting point
is low,
you may be affected by that point.
So we can't
control
the most
standard time.
Usually,
the way to control
is to put $100
directly on the desktop.
Don't put it on both sides.
Put it one by one.
But
in their
operation,
they choose
to put it directly at the beginning.
So there will be a prediction effect.
But in terms of response time,
the prediction effect should be small.
I have a response.
Or just change the interface
and just fill in the numbers.
Don't use Labar.
Of course,
this is also possible.
But you may have to
talk to the engineer.
But this is also possible.
But we want to change Labar.
We want to use Labar mainly
to make the picture interesting
and make consumers want to buy it.
Make students have fun.
I don't know why.
Everyone thinks Labar is fun.
I like Labar.
Yes, but there will be a lot of problems.
Of course.
Many people
operate with a tablet.
Yes, that's right.
I have a question.
Hello, can you hear me?
This question is like this.
Because you know
Zhang Anping is studying
social psychology.
He often plays
the game of the game.
But they like to do one thing.
That is to manipulate the victim.
For example, let you play the game first.
Then teach you Game Theory.
Then let you play the game and look at the difference.
But what they do more often is
let you play the game first.
Then let you watch Hitler's documentary.
Then let you play the game and see if there is any difference.
Have you ever tried to manipulate the victim?
This is what we can't do.
Because you are
giving the victim different treatments.
We can compare the experimental group and the control group.
But we are basically
because we don't have an experimental group and a control group.
So this is
what we can't do.
But of course, if we are in the lab,
we can do it completely.
But you can sell the product to the psychology department.
I'm sure of this.
This is
So we are now
going to hire a psychologist.
I think it will be an interesting tour.
Because they are writing.
And they have to write by themselves.
In fact, I think
it's ugly to meet.
That's what you're doing.
I think there is a marketing potential.
I should tell the boss about this.
And science
is also interesting.
I want to tell the boss about this.
Then Bozun
ask again.
As long as you can see
in each area,
you should be able to see which schools use
I can.
Then you have
the education level or
income level
proposal or acceptance.
But we have
each school.
I want to say that the school itself is an income proxy.
It must be some
I can.
I haven't connected yet.
I haven't connected with the income area.
You can
take a look.
You now have income data.
You have similar income or education
level data.
You should be able to find it.
But don't give me homework, please.
If you have any questions,
you can write an email to me.
Or you can find me on Facebook.
The small question I just wanted to ask
is that you said that
ROTH
between Proposer and Responder
is a hypothesis
of ROTH.
Is this hypothesis
from his data observation?
It is
from his data observation.
In short,
there are only four countries.
You can't compare the last round of data.
You are discussing
100 data points.
He can't do
statistical analysis.
He can only say what the four distribution
look like and
what my observation looks like.
Are there any questions
from the audience?
It's time to
wrap up.
Can you stay for a while?
I want to have a talk with you.
Sure.
That's all for today.
Thank you.
Let's give him a big hand.
I'll pause the recording.