Hello everyone, I am today's host, Zhang Yanyong. Welcome everyone to today's TerraTalk.
We are very honored to invite Zhang Fengxun today. He is currently a fifth-year doctoral candidate at Michigan University.
His current major is Natural Resources and Environmental Sciences, and has recently been renamed Sustainable Development Studies.
Before coming to the United States as a doctoral candidate, Fengxun studied in the Department of Insectology at the University of Taiwan.
He wrote a small paragraph about his own self-introduction. He is a community ecologist.
What he wants to understand is the interaction between species and the environment in which we humans exist.
In addition to ecology, he likes comedy, baseball, his home, and Taiwan.
Today's speech is different from the past, because we think that in addition to sharing his own research points and results, we hope that he can share more information.
Of course, we are very fortunate that Fengxun attended this year's annual meeting of the American Ecological Association a few weeks ago.
The annual meeting of the American Ecological Association is one of the largest in the world and attended by many people.
From his point of view, what important information is there at this year's annual meeting, and what breakthroughs are there in this area that are worth highlighting?
Let's welcome Fengxun with a round of applause.
Fengxun is not a formal Chinese name, but deals with issues such as sustainable development.
What is special about our association is that it is not the same as the ecological association we are familiar with.
Generally, the ecological association is based on basic science. We want to know the cause of a phenomenon, the evolution of species, and so on.
However, our association now thinks that we only understand these things, which is like being in an academic ivory tower.
In fact, this is not helpful for the development of ecology, so they think we should solve the problem more actively.
That is to say, how do we solve the problem of applying the ecological theory we already know to the major changes in the environment that we humans are facing now?
Or how do we make these relatively terrible extreme climates and other phenomena less common or milder?
This is my background, and what I want to share with you today is that I went to the US Ecological Annual Conference two weeks ago to participate in the conference.
I would like to share with you what I have seen, what I have played, and what I have thought.
I would like to introduce ESA, which stands for Ecology Society of America.
In fact, each country has its own ecological association, and Taiwan also has one.
However, ESA's annual meeting should be the largest in the world.
This year, more than 4,000 people participated in the conference.
I also went to talk to people after the conference.
I asked them about the situation in Europe.
They said it was much smaller, maybe less than 2,000 people.
This is the biggest conference in the world, and I think it is also the most complete conference in terms of discussion issues.
The disadvantage is that there are too many people, and you can't get to know everyone, and you can't have a very in-depth conversation with everyone.
So if your social skills are not good, you will be like me for a long time and don't know what to do.
I can only find someone to talk to.
So it's a good opportunity to practice talking to people.
This is a side effect.
Anyway, this is ESA's brief introduction.
I went to the conference two weeks ago.
Because I don't really know what everyone's background is, I will first introduce what ecology is.
If you google ecology or go directly to wiki, they will tell you that this is a choice between biological interaction and biological organism interaction with the environment.
In short, I want to learn how two organisms interact, including how we grab food, how we eat each other, how we help each other, and how the environment affects our relationship with each other.
All the discussions about this are ecological issues.
I don't think anyone will know what I'm talking about, because it's too abstract.
So when we talk about ecology, we immediately think of the existence of hierarchy.
Just like when we were in high school, we learned that the human body is made up of cells, and the cells make up the tissues, and the tissues make up the organs, the circulatory system, and the individual.
So in fact, ecology has a similar hierarchy.
From the smallest organism, which is a biological individual, to the vast majority of these biological organisms, which you can see in the picture below.
This should be a geoduck, I don't know what to draw.
Then with a group of geoducks, they are all the same, a group of geoducks.
Then it becomes a population ecology.
Then if you go up, in addition to this geoduck, there may be geoducks, snakes, eagles, other animals, trees, grass.
There are different kinds of animals living in the same time and space.
This forms a community, a group.
In short, many kinds of animals live in the same place.
This is called a community ecology.
If we enlarge the scope a little more, for example, we want to know that in addition to so many kinds of animals, where do they get the energy they need?
Where do their excrements go?
What kind of changes did their excrements make to the non-biological environment?
Then it becomes an ecosystem.
An ecosystem is a system.
The whole thing, biological and non-biological, all come together and become an ecosystem.
Then there are people studying ecosystem ecology.
Then to a bigger point is the biosphere.
I think this is a whole planet.
It's not a very meaningful classification.
But if you insist on expanding, it becomes a whole planet.
Then these levels, each level has its own questions to explore.
For example, people who study individual creatures will want to know how a creature grows.
How do I react to the environment and so on?
Then the population ecology of the ecosystem is that I want to know why this species is sometimes more and sometimes less.
For example, the evaluation of fish resources is one of the important parts of the population ecology.
For example, in Taiwan, I want to know how many fish I can catch this year.
When should I catch it? When should I not catch it?
This is the question that the population ecology has to answer.
The community ecology is like I just said.
Different interactions between different species.
So the most critical question is why there are so many species in the world.
How do so many species live together in this world?
Then it becomes so many species on the Internet.
What impact does the environment of non-living things in this world have?
This is the ecosystem ecology.
This is roughly the hierarchy in ecology.
I identify myself as a community slash a little ecosystem ecologist.
What I'm interested in is that I want to know how each species interacts with each other.
What impact do they have on the environment?
Or to be more direct with people.
There are many species in this system or in this natural environment.
What impact does it have on me?
What does it matter to me?
Then talk about community ecology or ecosystem ecology.
A question that everyone will ask is why there are so many species in this world.
This is a very, very old question.
It's also very old and very important.
It's also a question that we haven't answered in 100 years.
Because from the very beginning of 19
I want to explain why there are so many species of people.
I have written here that it is Brunel.
Then I put a table on the right for everyone to see.
When we want to answer this question,
I want to know why there are so many species.
What is the evolution of ecologists' ideas from the past to the present?
In short, I think it can be divided into two periods.
The first period.
The reason I'm talking about this now is because this question is very difficult to answer.
And it's also very important.
So now a lot of ecological research is actually inseparable from
The most fundamental question I'm asking now.
Why are there so many species?
Then when we answer this question,
For ancient ecologists,
The way we try to answer is
I think it's a turnip, a pit, this method.
In other words, how many resources can be used in the world?
Or how many niches can be occupied by species?
Then we should have seen so many species.
So including Grinnell, including Elton,
These are all very famous ecologists.
They all proposed various ideas about niches or ecological hypocrisy.
I will not explain their ideas one by one.
In short, the concept of this niche is a turnip, a pit.
Until about 2000,
The previous idea was that a turnip, a pit.
At most, the environment changes.
Then create different turnip pits.
So there are different species.
Sometimes the turnip pit is big, sometimes the turnip pit is small.
The density of species will be high.
The density of species will be low, etc.
So different species can coexist together.
Until about 2000,
There was a man named Steve Hoppe.
I don't know what his idea was.
But he proposed a theory.
There is no turnip, a pit.
Everything is random.
He proposed a neutral theory.
We see so many species.
Is it because of a random phenomenon?
The most classic example is that he took a long-term experimental observation station.
Then he went to study the changes in the composition of the species in the experimental observation station, etc.
Then he found that he could use a random model.
Make a random mathematical model.
You can predict the changes in the composition of long-term species.
The prediction is not bad.
Then he proposed a theory.
There are so many species in the world.
It's not a turnip, a pit.
There is a big species pool over there.
In this species pool,
ABCD may appear this year.
EFGH appeared this year.
ABEH appeared the following year.
He went on like this.
After this neutral theory was proposed,
everyone thought that we had been faking for almost 100 years.
So there was another man named Peter Chesson.
The fourth bullet point.
He proposed another theory.
We call it Modern Coexistence Theory.
He proposed this theory.
Under this framework,
neutral theory is just a special case under this framework.
In other words, Peter Chesson's framework
includes the theories we know so far.
He wanted to make a big framework
to tell us that different communities, different natural environments,
we will see different species.
Because there are different mechanisms behind it.
So he proposed a fluctuation-independent mechanism.
The first part of his modern theory is that
when the environment has reached a balance,
how many species will exist here
determines how much the resources used by these species are different
compared to the ability of their resources to interact.
How much difference does their ability make?
This is called stabilizing.
For example,
if I love to eat apples and he loves to eat oranges,
then I will eat my apples well,
and he will eat his oranges well.
If not, we can coexist in this world without any problems.
Then the concept of using different resources
is called stabilizing.
Another one is that we both love to eat apples,
but my speed of eating apples is about the same speed as yours.
So we fight fiercely.
I take a bite, you take another bite.
I take another bite, you take another bite.
So we keep fighting each other.
So no one can kill each other.
So we can coexist in this world very tightly.
This is a mechanism of equalizing.
Under this framework,
the neutral theory I just mentioned
is an extreme state of equalizing.
Everyone is the same.
No one can kill another person.
So there are a bunch of species in this world
fighting each other here.
So far,
everyone seems to be a little satisfied.
I think it's not bad.
We can use this big framework
to explain why we can see so many different species.
But in fact,
current ecologists
can't understand these theories of Jason.
On the one hand,
it seems that we are enough here.
We just need to know
that everyone fights each other fiercely,
or that everyone uses different resources.
You can explain
why there are different species here
and then continue to extend.
But when some current theoretical ecologists
continue to dig Jason's framework,
they will find that there is actually another mechanism,
which is the fluctuation-dependent mechanism.
The reason why this mechanism allows species to coexist
is because it feels that the environment is constantly changing.
So the system can't reach a balance
or is on the way to a balance.
So since we are still in a state
where the environment is constantly changing,
what we know now
is that when we see these species,
we can't use these theories
that we have obtained
in a balanced state
to explain why we see these now.
Of course, this is difficult
because we don't know
whether the natural environment we live in
has reached a balance
or has not reached a balance.
So I think this is a big question.
This is also the first thing I saw
and I think it may be a topic
that many ecologists will start to study in the future.
How to quantify a system
has it reached a balance
or has it not reached a balance?
If it has not reached a balance,
it is the fluctuation-dependent mechanism.
How do we quantify these mechanisms?
How do we use these mechanisms
to explain how many different creatures
I see in this system now?
In the fluctuation-dependent mechanism,
the main core is that
the environment is constantly changing.
So when the environment is constantly changing,
if I like low resources,
I can live a good life.
When in low resources,
I can find a way to get rid of people.
Another person may be
when in high resources,
he will find a way to get rid of me.
But because the environment is constantly changing,
we have to
adapt to the environment.
This is the concept.
It's not like what I eat,
what you eat,
and stay in a very stable state.
Now the environment is changing,
and we have our own density.
There may also be feedback back to the environment.
This is the storage effect
If you are interested,
I don't know if you are interested.
If you are interested, you can go and see
this paper I wrote.
I think he wrote it very well.
Then there is a sentence
in a relatively flat language
that tells us what the whole
Coexistence Theory is talking about.
I'll give you an example here.
What is a fluctuation-dependent mechanism?
This paper is also a good one.
Sorry, the resolution is not very good.
This is a new paper that came out recently.
In this paper,
he wants to prove one thing.
Storage effect and relative non-linearity
These two fluctuation-dependent mechanisms
is the reason for the coexistence of two species.
You can see panel A and B.
Different colors represent the density of different species.
Yellow is one, blue is another.
Then the background is either white or light,
or gray represents the richness of resources.
The background is dark or light,
which represents the richness of resources.
So we can see from panel A and panel B,
when there is less resource,
it is not so dark.
Yellow wins.
On the other hand, when it's darker,
in panel C,
blue wins.
But when we get to panel D,
he deliberately adds resources in that system.
Sometimes this system has a lot of resources,
and then sometimes he takes the resources away,
and then he adds resources and takes them away.
It creates a human-made fluctuation.
When we see a human-made fluctuation,
yellow and blue can coexist.
No one can eliminate anyone.
For example, this is the first real experiment proof.
Of course, everyone does this kind of experiment.
But this paper has a special point.
In addition to telling you that you can really coexist,
it really uses a mathematical model to really quantify
how much storage effect I can have,
how much relative non-inheritance.
So let everyone know that there are really two kinds of
environmental changes
that allow species to coexist.
It's not just that we want to say,
because of environmental change,
everyone has different levels of resources,
so of course we can coexist.
This kind of verbal argument is right.
So this is the first one.
I think it's a pretty eye-opening study.
Then at the seminar,
I also saw a few talks,
so I tried to quantify
why species can coexist in changing environments,
and what is the mechanism behind their coexistence.
Is everyone suitable for different environments?
Or is the environment I affect affecting me?
This is the first highlight I saw at this conference.
I have a question.
So you're showing this now,
for example, there are two species of yellow and blue.
Yellow and blue species.
Both of them have a feature,
which is that you can see the peak at each point.
That is, the slope is very large.
So it means that these two species themselves
have a very small response time scale to change.
Maybe less than a day.
But if you look at the D-panel in the lower right corner,
it's like external excitation.
That is, their environment changes,
their scale is ten days, five days,
a few days, a few days, a few days.
That's the width of black and white.
So the time scale of the species system
and the time scale of excitation are very different.
So you can see this phenomenon very clearly.
But if today the species must use
about the same time,
or even longer, to respond to external excitation,
then the whole model will fail.
Because it may not have time to reach the next state.
The environment has changed again,
and then it will collapse in the end.
It's a mess.
Yes, it's possible.
So what I'm talking about now,
this fluctuation-dependent thing,
is actually what you're talking about.
It's a relative concept.
If the environment is changing,
it must be fluctuation-dependent.
It can be said that my own life cycle is very short.
So even if the environment changes once a year,
I have already given birth dozens of times a year.
Yes, I have reproduced dozens of times.
So the change in the environment is meaningless to me.
So I just said that in a system,
now we want to answer this question.
Ecologists,
the first difficult point is
that we have to identify the change in the environment
for the life cycle of my species.
In terms of life cycle,
is it dependent or independent?
If it is dependent,
if it is fluctuation-dependent,
we can then ask
which mechanism is it?
Does this answer your question?
Oh, thank you.
Yes.
Okay,
next, like I just said,
this is a very old question.
It's so old that
some people don't want to answer this question anymore.
So everyone started to ask this question
in another way.
Now there are so many species in this environment.
So then,
the question just answered is
why does this environment
allow me to see so many species?
But now,
everyone may find it boring,
so ask it the other way around.
So many species,
what impact will it have on this environment?
This question
or this question
is actually not something that happened recently,
but it suddenly became obvious.
It probably started in the late 1990s.
There was a person in Europe
who did a project called Ecotron.
In other words,
it's probably like...
I don't know if everyone knows
that there is a kind of...
Give you a glass ball,
and then there is grass inside.
There are different kinds of grass,
and then there are some moss,
something wet,
like a planet.
Ecotron is very similar to that concept.
It's a microcosm.
Their idea is that
the more species there are in this microcosm,
the more biomass I will see.
I can see the more creatures in it.
It started this
Biodiversity Ecosystem Functioning Branch.
Biodiversity
How does it affect the function of this system?
Function means
what is the production volume of this system?
How efficient is this system
with the nutrient salt?
The most famous one
will be brought to everyone.
It's in Minnesota.
There is a person
who is the first person
to really do this large-scale experiment.
You can see it in the picture on the left.
It's called Seagull Creek.
It really digs a piece of land
and plants this grass.
You can see a plot.
There may be five kinds of grass in this plot.
There is one kind of grass in another plot.
There are several kinds of grass in a plot.
It goes down like this.
Or in Germany,
Jena Experiment
also does similar things.
There are different kinds of grass
in each block.
When I have a lot of grass,
does this grass
use different resources
in order to survive?
In total,
I can take more resources
from the environment.
As I just said,
there is a concept of a radish pit.
The whole pit is full.
We take a lot of resources
from the system.
A lot of biodiversity grows out of it.
This kind of research
has been done for more than 10 years.
We have now discovered
a general pattern.
When we see a lot of species
in an environment,
when biodiversity increases,
when X goes to the right,
we see that those functions
will increase.
How much resources can we take away?
How much biodiversity can we produce?
We all see a function
that increases but saturates.
This is the knowledge we know now.
However,
the knowledge we have now
is all based on grass experiment.
This is the grass experiment
I just showed here.
We all plant grass
or raise a certain
nutrient-based organism.
Then we find that
the nutrient-based organism functions well.
However,
this is not enough.
In our world,
it is impossible to have only grass.
At least there are humans.
At least insects eat grass.
Rabbits eat grass.
Lions eat rabbits.
There are many different kinds of life.
Now,
there are a few questions
that ecologists want to continue to explore.
The first is
the function of these ecosystem.
For example,
the production of biomass, etc.
Is it related to
what we need in this world?
This is the first one above.
How do we put these functions
and services
I will talk about what service is later.
Service is the function we need.
How do we put these two things together?
Otherwise, people will think that
our ecological system is
locked in a academic ivory tower.
Purely understand the phenomenon of the natural environment
and then it's over.
No more.
Everyone hopes that
we ecologists can contribute to
some changes in the environment, etc.
This is the first
ecologicalists
want to continue to study.
Next is what I just said.
All the knowledge we learn now
is very flat.
Or the same nutrient class.
But the natural environment
is a very three-dimensional state.
So should we
put the natural environment
into a very three-dimensional state?
The third one is
how can we predict accurately
or accurately
when the environment changes
to reflect
how many species will be left now.
How many species will be left
and how many functions
will be left, etc.
So these three are from
Biodiversity Ecosystem Functioning.
The three branches
I think are ecological systems.
I can't say it's obvious,
but a lot of people are doing it.
Now I'm going to talk about the first one.
What is ecosystem services?
These services mean
all people
live in this world
and learn about these
functions,
patterns,
all the things you need.
And then,
I remember it was the UN
or something.
The report of the Millennium Ecosystem Assessment.
At that time, it was clearly defined
that our current ecosystem
is actually the whole earth.
These services
are provided to people.
There are these four categories,
supporting provisioning,
regulation, and culture.
The first few are easier to understand.
Supporting services
that support the operation of the earth.
For example, the cycle of nutrients.
You may have learned
that in biology,
we learn about the water cycle,
the egg cycle, the carbon cycle,
the carbon cycle, and so on.
Or how much
production
can be used by us, etc.
Then these will support
how much food can we eat,
the water cycle,
because of the water cycle,
how much clean water
can be used by us.
This is provisioning.
Or when we want to manage
a system,
we don't want to have too many pests.
We want to maximize,
for example, maximize the number of corn.
We don't want too many corn pests.
The number of pest control
is the regulation services.
These three are relatively easy to understand.
I think,
and it is also now
a big problem for ecologists.
We call it cultural services.
What I wrote here is
you can think of everything
related to culture.
These are from the natural environment.
You get these ideas.
You get these inspirations.
You get these education.
You get to learn.
But as long as it's related to the environment,
it's not that kind of
ugly.
You don't have it.
If you don't have it,
you won't die.
But you will live unhappily.
These things are called culture.
So some people say
because nature is beautiful,
it's too beautiful.
So we can't maximize it.
We can only rely on the beauty of our inner self
to appreciate nature.
Then there are other people who say
that this is meaningless.
I say what you say is beautiful.
I can also say
that there is nothing in the world that is the most beautiful.
So how do we quantify
the services of these ecosystems,
especially the services of culture?
This is something that some people
are trying to figure out now.
And that part of people
includes a lot of economists.
Because economists are very...
I think
they are very good at estimating
the value of this thing in the market,
and then how to trade it.
So some people will think
that we will quantify these services.
For example,
a piece of clean water
is worth 2.5 million.
Then a big clean swimming pool
A big clean swimming pool
is worth 10 million.
I don't know.
Just try to quantify it
or find a way to...
I can't say that this can be traded,
but use money to quantify it
so that we can do better management, etc.
Or we can use money
to quantify
almost everything in the world
in a system of communication.
This is the second thing I think
that eco-scientists are facing now.
This is also a problem
that some scholars
who are not trained in ecology
want to help us solve.
How to quantify ecosystem services,
especially these services
related to culture.
Even when I was at this conference,
there was a special workshop.
There were quite a few participants.
Almost 100 people.
Almost 100 people were discussing
ecosystem services.
This is the second thing
that I think is pretty cool.
Okay.
Next,
I just said
that when we understand
biodiversity,
what we understand now
is relative to others.
When we understand
the impact of biodiversity
on the environment,
our understanding
of biodiversity
is relative to others.
So probably after 2005 and 2007,
some people started to think
that biodiversity
should be said
that the natural environment
is a very three-dimensional state.
We should not only consider
the same nutrient class.
We should consider
all nutrient classes.
So there are some studies
that are also going to do
pest control.
Biological control.
These studies on biodiversity
will think that
they first thought that
if I want to control a pest,
for example, this soil.
We want to control this.
This should be considered
a insect.
I don't know what kind of insect this is.
Anyway, it's a pest.
We want to control
the number of pests.
Then we should put
a kind that will eat it
at the bottom.
Or is it better to put
everything in?
How should it be put
to let the number of pests
be suppressed to the minimum?
At the beginning,
when we consider
a lot of different nutrients
and a lot of different
nutrient classes,
the biodiversity we knew
would really affect
the ecosystem function.
Does this still exist?
This is the initial idea.
Until recently,
there have been more researchers
who have invested in this research.
Then we will think that
in addition to different
biological classes,
should we think of the
whole environment as a
network?
It's a concept of a food network.
There are a lot of food networks.
There are a lot of species
that exist in this system at the same time.
Then everyone eats each other.
Everyone grabs food from each other.
This research can actually
involve a debate
from a long time ago.
Everyone will ask
what kind of network
and what kind of food network
is the most stable state.
Before the emergence of
Biodiversity Ecosystem Function
,
everyone started to ask
what kind of food network
is the most stable.
At that time,
the pure research was
purely thinking about
how to prevent
this food network from crashing.
Maybe everyone is very good at connecting.
Connectedness is very high.
Everyone is in a small group.
It's very close to each other.
Then the small group and the small group
are not so close to each other.
How do these attributes of
each network
affect the stability of
the entire network?
Then put this idea
into the idea of
Biodiversity Ecosystem Function.
Everyone will start to think that
since each network
has different attributes,
different characteristics,
then in the state of different characteristics,
will there be different
food networks with different characteristics?
There will be different functions.
For example,
this opinion paper
is not a real data paper.
It provides an idea
that when different food networks
have different attributes,
different characteristics,
the energy flux
is not discussing
whether the entire network
will crash easily.
What we are discussing now is
how much energy flows in
and how much efficiency
flows out in the end.
Everyone started to ask this question.
Theoretically,
these are some of the network attributes.
How does it affect
the function of this part?
This question is
the question I am most interested in
asking in the future.
At the end,
I will talk about
my own research.
It's very simple.
My own research
is very related to
the question
that some ecologists
are starting to ask.
How do different network attributes
affect the function of this network?
This research,
I haven't seen it yet.
I think it's fun and cool,
but I haven't seen
too much
real data
doing this.
Now it's mainly
a very theoretical research.
In other words,
we have to use a more three-dimensional
way to understand
how diversity affects
the function
of the entire ecosystem.
We are still in a
theoretical stage.
Theoretically,
this full web,
everyone is very tight-knit,
or everyone's interaction is very strong.
I might see this kind of function.
Theoretically,
because
this can't be blamed on ecologists,
because I really want to quantify
a full web.
It's actually not easy.
Of course, many people are already doing full web.
But what everyone does is
for example,
fish in a lake,
I want to open his stomach
and see what kind of small fish and shrimp he ate.
In my own words,
A fish ate
C, D, E shrimp,
and so on.
Use various methods to see
what kind of things a species eats,
or if there are any
different species
eating and eating each other.
Use different microscopes,
or like I just said,
God content research.
We can't blame
that we don't have enough
empirical data,
but this empirical data is not easy to get.
So everyone will start to
dilute, for example,
we use
the size of the organism
to decide,
to estimate what he will eat.
Because for example,
a fish,
a goldfish,
I mean the goldfish in the aquarium,
he may eat a shark.
So we can use its size
to estimate what kind of food
a goldfish can eat.
Then use the size of the organism
and
the size of the organism
such a trait
to help each species
what kind of food
it may have.
Then build a
more realistic,
not so theoretical food network.
Then we use some attributes of this food network
to see what the function of this food network is.
But it's the same,
it's still built on a theory
that small fish can't eat big fish.
So it's not necessarily
that this is the most perfect food network.
It's just that
the biologists are starting to think
how to answer this question.
Including myself, I also think
this is the next topic
I want to continue
to study.
After finishing
these chapters of my Ph.D.
I want to do some research.
I've been
talking to
the people at the conference,
including some biologists
from France or Germany.
They all say they have
a huge greenhouse effect.
Like what I just said,
I want to make it three-dimensional,
like what you can see
on this picture.
There are a lot of things like a greenhouse.
Different food networks
are made up of different greenhouses.
Like the German
IDIV,
I think that organization is really cool.
First, they have a lot of money.
Second, the topics they study
are all my friends.
I like them a lot.
They seem to have a lot of future ideas.
This is my second
conference.
I think it's worth sharing
what biologists are thinking
about.
Third,
this research
was done by
my former teacher,
Sutiara.
She's my teacher.
But she doesn't know
much about math.
Anyway,
biologists want to
do this kind of research.
We're all looking for a cause-and-effect relationship.
For example,
why are there so many
species in the world?
What's the reason?
We saw this result.
Why are there
so many species?
Why do we get
these functions?
The reason is that there are so many species.
The result is that there are these functions.
But in addition to
actually doing experiments,
for example, like I just said,
it's hard to really
quantify
the cause-and-effect relationship
of a phenomenon
other than
the cause-and-effect relationship.
Sutiara
doesn't know much about math,
so
I just made it up.
It's based on
this theorem,
the Taken's theorem,
to develop a set of
mathematical models
or a set of
statistical methods.
We should talk about statistical methods.
It can measure
the impact of
a population
on another population.
It can use the relationship of time series
to know if a population
has a direct impact on another population.
For example,
this is the most common example.
Red and blue
are two species.
So at the time of A,
red and blue have a strong
relationship.
According to our
theory,
red is the cause of blue,
blue is the effect of red,
or vice versa.
But when we get to B,
we find that
their relationship is opposite.
It's negative.
So we say,
if red increases,
let blue decrease,
or vice versa.
We use this correlation
to infer the causality.
Red and blue have nothing to do with each other.
So we find that
red and blue have no causality.
However, these two time series
are written from the
mathematical formula above.
In other words,
red and blue, x and y,
have a causality.
But in our traditional
ecological research,
if we just do a bunch of correlations
or don't do experiments,
we can't know
the causality of
red and blue, x and y.
However,
using this method,
cross-mapping,
we can know
the causality of
red and blue.
I mentioned this method
because I saw
the experiment room
this year.
The experiment room is not that big.
It's just four or five people.
They came to give a talk.
Almost everyone came to give a talk.
It seems to me
that this method
has been developed successfully.
Let's use it.
It's a kind of
declaration
of significance.
A few years ago,
when I went to
ESA,
there were some
collaborators.
However,
it's not like this year.
Almost the whole experiment room
came to give a talk.
Ecologists, let's use CCM.
Let's use this method.
Let's not do correlations.
Let's not do x and y.
Let's use CCM.
Let's try to collect
time series data
to know who is the cause and who is the cause.
It's a kind of
declaration.
I think it's great.
Actually, ecologists are not that smart.
To be honest,
I decided to study ecology
because my math is not good enough.
I can't study physics.
I can't study chemistry.
I don't like to study humanities.
So, I decided to study biology.
I was happy to see the biology
running around.
I'm not good at math.
So,
I'm not sure
if this method
will work.
I'm not sure.
This method
requires a good time series.
As you know,
in the current
scientific research environment,
every project,
every grant
may take 3 to 5 years.
Maybe 10 years.
It's a good time series.
3 to 5 years.
3 to 5 years time series may not be long enough
to do CCM.
To do convergence cross mapping.
Next,
what I just said,
I just wrote
A detects an impact
on another population.
In other words,
if A's impact on B is
C's impact,
which is indirect,
then we get
A, B, C, these three time series.
It's possible for me to catch
A's impact on B.
But this impact is actually through C.
It's not A's direct impact on B.
In other words,
this method is not omnipotent.
I can only tell you
who might affect who.
But whether this impact is
a direct impact, I can't be sure.
In other words,
CCM, although it's powerful and cool,
it can let us know the causality.
But it still can't let us know
the real causal relationship.
Is the causality
direct?
So this method
still has some shortcomings.
But I think
it's already
a great way
to let everyone
who has a time series
to try to answer the questions
they want to answer.
Some more traditional
correlation analysis.
This is probably the last one.
Is the last one a summary?
I don't know.
I just summarized everything
I just said.
In short, we still have to ask
the most classic question.
How do species coexist?
Why are there so many species?
And now
a way to
answer this question.
We have to consider environmental changes.
Use fluctuation-dependent
mechanisms to explain species coexistence.
After species coexistence,
we are
trying to
solidify our understanding of biodiversity.
And
find a way to know
what impact
biodiversity
has on
the environment
we live in.
For example, how much food can we eat?
This kind of question.
Next is
causality inference.
We really want to know
some causal relationships.
Through time series analysis,
we want to know causal relationships.
Finally, ecosystem services.
I think it's a very
mysterious term.
I really think that Schneider University
seems to love this term.
We want to use ecosystem services
to manage our...
I forgot where it is.
Anyway, it's a country in South America.
I heard in the workshop
that our government is trying to
push the concept of ecosystem services.
We want to use the concept of ecosystem services
to manage the natural resources
of our country.
I think
these are some interesting topics.
After participating in this meeting,
I saw some interesting topics.
I want to
learn more about
the impact of
network
and
diverse ecosystem functioning.
Lastly,
I think
I don't know if this is a question
or a concern.
If you know a little bit about
ecosystem services,
you will know that
there are so-called
theoretical ecologists and
empiricists.
Some people's research is
a computer or a pile of paper
with a pile of equations
or a framework.
For example, I just talked about Peter Chesson
who proposed the Modern Consistent Theory.
Some people think
it's meaningless to just think about it.
I need to do experiments.
These two
I can't say two sides.
The communication between
these two ecologists
is not so smooth.
I think
maybe some people think it's not bad.
I don't think it's that smooth.
Because theoretical ecologists
are too smart
and empiricists
may not be able to keep up with their ideas.
On the other hand, empiricists
think we are materialistic enough.
Theoretical ecologists
think we are materialistic.
The other people are empty-handed.
So I think the communication between
these two sides needs
a strong theory.
Then I will do experiments
with these ecologists
to build a bridge of friendship.
Otherwise,
I've been thinking about
the mechanism of fluctuation-dependent
and how to influence co-existence.
It's meaningless if you can't do experiments.
Or
the most obvious example is
I did a theoretical model
and one of my
committee members said
is it useful to do so many theories?
Can you really do experiments
to verify your model prediction?
So my second chapter
is to do experiments
to see if the predicted results
can be seen
in real life.
It's like a debate.
It's like a civilized blind date.
This is what I want to say today.
What I saw at this conference
and what I think
ecologists are thinking about.
Is there any time left?
Actually,
it's about time.
But we can ask questions.
Before asking questions,
let's turn on the microphone
for two seconds.
Thank you, Feng Xun,
for the speech.
I don't know if you have any questions
or comments.
I have a similar question
or a comment.
You mentioned
network analysis
and causality interference.
You mentioned
time series analysis.
These two technologies
are very useful
in physics.
They are very useful
In fact,
they are widely used.
But I think
the biggest problem is
that
physicists' habits.
For example,
there are water molecules in the water.
There are one or two water molecules in the water.
I don't know how to use
ten water molecules.
The computer can't predict.
So I use one water molecule
and one water molecule.
So I use water molecules
and one water molecule
to check the phenomenon.
Then I said
that my model
would have such a phenomenon.
Then I went for experiments.
Then I said I understood
the flow of water.
I think this
can be delineated.
Assuming things can be delineated
in a condition
like a time series,
it would be more interesting.
Otherwise,
physicists say
they can calculate one by one,
but they can't do fluid mechanics.
Then I said I would leave it to the computer.
Then I asked the computer
to do a large-scale
numerical simulation
to simulate some strange phenomena.
If the experiment can't be done,
I said the experiment wouldn't be done.
But it doesn't mean it's wrong.
Because in the real world,
water is still flowing.
This kind of research
and operation
is actually very difficult
for a system
with complex variables.
So let's go back
to the biological ecosystem.
Of course,
you can say
it's easy to issue a paper.
I just need to build up the model
and let the computer calculate it.
In the end,
you still have to go back
to whether you can explain
what happened in this world
and whether you can do experiments to verify it.
But there will be a lot of difficulty in the middle.
Then it becomes
a very interesting thought study.
But it's hard to say
if it has an impact on the learning itself.
I totally agree.
If I remember correctly,
the talk of the person next week
is similar to what you just said.
It's about building a climate model
or a water texture model
to understand
some of the changes
in the environment, etc.
That's a very popular question
for some ecologists
right now.
Because, as I just said,
we want to know how to face this world.
So if I can
use a digital simulation
and I know
that the temperature here is one degree higher
than the temperature in a black box,
I don't know what's going on.
Anyway, the sea level will rise by 50 meters.
I feel very happy.
If the prediction is accurate,
I feel happy.
But some ecologists
think that
it's like doing
big data analysis.
You don't know what's going on at all.
You only know one cause and effect.
So I think
this is a
question that depends on
what you want to answer.
If you really just want to solve an environmental problem
or a human survival problem,
you can do a data analysis
and I can come up with
an effective solution,
that's great.
But if I just want to increase my knowledge,
I think knowledge is the most important thing.
This is very meaningful to me.
This is why I don't
like
big data analysis
or environmental studies.
That's the reason.
In fact,
there are some people
in the conference
who are trying to
use CtS
to collect
more data
to understand environmental changes.
I don't think
they have a good enough
theoretical foundation.
I don't pay
too much attention to what they are doing.
Thank you.
Do you have any questions?
If you have any questions
or comments,
I'll tell you.
The links of
Taira's website and
Taira's conference
are in the chat.
If you are interested,
you can check it out.
You can see what Taira
wants to do,
how to join,
and what other
academic lectures
we will have next year.
You can see next year's lecture
at the end of the year.
If you are interested,
I hope we can
connect more people
from all over the world
to share resources.
The more people join,
the more powerful it will be.
The link is in the chat.
You can check it out.
Do you have any questions?
If you are interested,
you can contact
or discuss with
Taira's website.
The link is in the chat.
On the right,
there is a list
of members.
If you click
on Taira's name,
there should be an email.
No?
Okay.
We didn't write it down.
Sorry.
If you are interested,
you can contact
Taira.
We can help you.
Taira's email is
tyra.public
p-u-b-l-i-c
at gmail.com
Or you can
write her email
on the screen.
fhchang
f-h-c-h-a-n-g
at umichigan
u-m-i-c-h
dot e-d-u
Okay.
That's all for today.
Let's give it up
for Taira.
Thank you.
I'm going to
stop recording.