Yes, Project Terra is an international platform for sharing information.
We hope that scholars from all over the world can share with us
the results of our current research and development,
and more importantly, what is the trend of development.
This is not something you can easily find in Taiwan.
Project Terra can also provide people who are doing research
with opportunities to exchange and collaborate.
So we hold a seminar like this every week.
The speakers are basically all members,
and they will share their new ideas and research trends.
Project Terra is a self-releasing organization
that is dedicated to public service.
We have no intention of making any profit.
All of our members are very enthusiastic doctoral students and post-doctoral students.
You can see our website.
If you are interested in Project Terra,
you can take a look at our website.
and would like to keep in touch with us,
you can join our membership.
If you can find other people to work with,
we will be happy to help you.
If you have any questions,
you can ask us directly.
We are usually very free to talk.
Sure, no problem.
I would like to remind you that
when we have more and more listeners,
we will set the volume to silent.
So if you remember to click on the microphone icon
before speaking,
you can ask questions or
if you have any questions,
you can directly talk to the speaker, Beta.
Okay, Beta, let's get started.
For some reason, I can't share the screen.
Let me re-join.
Okay, thank you, Ted.
My name is Chengxinda.
My Chinese name is Ergongcheng.
My surname is Daoda.
Today, I would like to thank Ted and Terra
for giving me the opportunity to introduce
a method we are developing.
This is a new method.
The main purpose of this method is to deal with
the interaction between light and matter.
We hope to provide a new way
to do this.
The method we propose is called
Mixed Quantum Classical Electrodynamics.
In English, it should be called
Quantum-Fixed Mixed Electrodynamics.
I will introduce to you in detail
what kind of method it is.
Okay, let me introduce myself.
My name is Chengxinda.
My background is that when I was in Taiwan,
I was studying math and physics in college.
I majored in math and physics.
Later, for some reason,
when I applied to go to college,
I saw that there was a program called
Chemical Physics in Columbia.
I thought it was very similar to what I was doing.
It was also something I was interested in.
So I applied to this program.
I was very lucky to apply to this program.
I found out that when I came to the United States,
I became a chemical physicist.
I have been used as a chemical physicist from beginning to end.
Because of this reason,
I am now working as a chemical physicist
at Penn University.
To sum up,
I use the theory of physics
and the computational method developed in physics
to study the problem of chemistry.
My professional field is
studying dynamics,
which is the theory of dynamics
and the computational method of dynamics.
Specifically,
my Ph.D. is in Columbia.
I am doing chemical dynamics,
that is,
electromagnetic dynamics in a chemical environment.
My postdoc,
what I am doing now
is a little different from my Ph.D.
I am doing the interaction of light and matter.
Today,
my talk will focus on
my postdoc work.
OK.
First of all, what is light?
We often say that light is an object.
Basically,
light is a very important thing in everyday life.
Light is basically an electromagnetic wave.
Electromagnetic waves
are basically the source of all our information.
We see things in this world.
From the greatest extent,
how do we know
what happens on other planets
or on Mars, for example?
We can
reflect the light of the sun from Mars
and see from the spectrum of sunlight
what kind of matter there is on Mars.
How much of this matter is there?
Then,
there are more possibilities
in the development of modern science.
These are no longer visible light.
We have different kinds of light
from low energy to high energy.
Then, from the low energy range,
we have NMR
to Raman
or IR spectrum.
These things are
lower than visible light.
Within the range of higher than visible light,
there is UV,
which is ultraviolet,
and
X-ray spectroscopy, which is more powerful.
Basically, our feature is that
basically,
this
spectroscopy
shows that
the stronger the energy,
the deeper we can see.
Just like in the form of X-ray,
we can see that it can
reflect the electrons in the inner layer.
So you can know what the behavior of the electrons in the inner layer is.
This is one of the functions
of light and matter interaction.
In recent years,
because of the development of nanotechnology,
we can make our devices
in a smaller scale.
So we can even use light,
the quality of light,
to manipulate matter,
to change the nature of matter.
For example,
we can put
a chemical reaction
in a cavity,
and the nature of the chemical reaction
may be changed.
Or we can put this chemical reaction
on a crystal.
This chemical reaction may have
different behavior.
There are other
different nanostructures,
nanostructures,
which can have different
effects on light-matter interaction
and change the nature of matter.
Another very important example
is that in recent years,
there is a very popular
study
on how we use
light-matter interaction
to change,
for example,
this paper
is a paper
about
the conductivity
of organic semiconductors.
They put a very thin
membrane structure,
and there is a circle
above it,
and attach it
to the organic semiconductor.
It can change
the conductivity of the semiconductor.
It can change it
from a bad conductor
to a better conductor.
But these
modern developments
all use the nature of light-matter.
When we need
to understand the nature of light-matter,
we need to discuss
what is light
and what is the difference
between classical light and light-matter.
The classical light
is in the left panel.
We regard classical light as an electromagnetic wave,
and the development
of the electromagnetic wave
is based on
the Maxwell's equation,
which is
the Maxwell's equation.
This is a Maxwell's equation
without a source.
This is a
propagate,
a electromagnetic wave moving forward
without any source.
This is the classical view
of light.
In quantum mechanics,
we regard light as a group
of energy.
Its energy
is discretized.
You may have heard of
the Uncertainty Principle,
which is
the Uncertainty Principle.
The Uncertainty Principle
in light
corresponds to
the distribution of energy.
The energy may not be
only one energy,
but a distribution of probability.
How does quantum mechanics
evolve light?
It is based on the Heisenberg equation.
The H is an operator
in quantum mechanics.
The H is an operator.
H represents the energy.
This basically
describes how light
evolves
in a space.
What is the difference
between classical
and quantum mechanics?
Let's look at
the matter.
We can see
the difference between
classical and quantum.
Classical matter
is a particle
or many particles.
Many particles
follow
Newton's law
in quantum mechanics.
We all know
classical mechanics.
A particle has a certain speed
and this speed changes over time.
In quantum mechanics,
the energy
is considered
continuous.
the energy
is considered continuous.
In quantum mechanics,
the energy
doesn't
use proofs
to describe matter,
instead we use function
named wave function.
In uncertainty principle
it is a
distribution
frame of reference
for environment
and momentum.
Uncertainty principle
is not a satisfied
you can
you can write down its
spatial distribution and
momentum distribution
of a wave function.
This wave function
follows the following thing called
Schrodinger equation
is written like this.
Since we
now know these
physical
classical and quantum
and quantum of light.
When we want to describe
the reaction of modern light
and the interaction of light and matter
our ideal state
is to use quantum light
and quantum matter.
When I have quantum light and quantum matter
together
we can
this is a set of
quantum electric mechanics
called QED.
In this QED
we can
put the whole
matter and light
in the same wave function
they will have a combined
Hamiltonian
and they can
evolve together.
This can include
all interactions
in quantum mechanics.
But this is a very large
calculation.
It is very difficult
to do a real calculation
except for some basic
model problems.
One of the reasons is
this total wave function
contains a lot of
degrees of freedom
a lot of variables.
This thing
may be in a real situation
for example
I take a real nanoparticle
or a real
particle structure
this thing
can't be done.
So we have
a compromise
approach.
We develop a set
called Mixed Quantum Classical
which is a combination of
classical quantum mechanics.
In this we
put light as classical
as classical
and matter as matter.
Therefore
we don't need to
evolve the light
we just need to know
what is the
behavior of matter.
We put light's behavior
as a time-dependent perturbation
as a
driving force
as if
something is pushing
matter
into evolution.
This is a more
practical approach.
But it has some problems.
As I said
it is OK for some problems.
This is not
our first approach.
Many people have done this.
But it has some problems.
The first problem is
it doesn't have feedback.
Feedback means
we treat the light
as bending
The system
doesn't throw
any energy
or feedback
into the light.
So
if you
take the whole system
and put light and matter
together
you will find that
this theory doesn't
conform to energy conservation.
The second problem is
it has uncertainty principle.
In other words
I should have
a standard difference
between light and matter.
In other words
I don't have
only one point
so I should have
a wide distribution.
But we have
classical light
so there is no
fluctuation.
Another problem
is time dependent perturbation.
It is a linear response.
Basically
it is a linear response.
The light pushes
the light
and it responds.
But this
is a strong coupling.
If the light is very strong
and it can change
the quality of light
this theory
cannot be explained.
The most serious problem
is that it cannot
capture a
important physical quality
called spontaneous emission.
I will explain it later.
These problems
make
classical method
cannot explain
quantum mechanics.
My work
is to develop
a new
mixed quantum classical
we can
recover
we can reconstruct
spontaneous emission
we can
enforce
influence energy conservation
we can
we can build habitual light
how can we do it?
sorry, I have a question
ok, go ahead
I want to ask
because
using quantum mechanics is a bit difficult
can't do
analytical solution
to what extent
for example, molecular
or elemental
single element
or many body
yes, usually
many body
because many body
its scale is exponential n
so
if you add
exponential n
your computer can't run
so
what we can do
is
take some degree of freedom
as classical
there are many good classical methods
to propagate Maxwell's equation
but
for example, single molecule
can be calculated?
yes, single molecule can be calculated
as a
chemist
I want to do something practical
I see
because I do high energy
I don't know
I only do one by one
two or three more
seems difficult
what we want to do
for example,
put a molecule
into a cavity
I see
ok, thank you
I want to ask
is this LR
same as
Lindblad equation operator?
thank you
open system
which one?
it's very similar
I won't write it down
but
it's very similar to
Lindblad
but it can't be written as
Lindblad form
because it's a non-linear term
it's not like Lindblad
it's a linear term
it's a time-dependent
and skewed Lindblad
ok
keep talking
I'm looking forward to it
I'll talk about it later
ok
basically
what we want to do
because we have a friend who does high energy
we have
low energy
chemical system
so we don't consider
relative effect
ok
next
let's talk about
what is spontaneous emission
the quantum theory of spontaneous emission
was written by Dirac in 1927
Dirac
of course
Einstein explained it
before Dirac
but the paper in 1927
he used
the first principle
to introduce
spontaneous emission
so
I see it as
a major contribution
what is spontaneous emission
it's basically
a transition
from a stimulated state
to an excited state
simply put
I have an electron
it's in a stimulated state
it's in an excited state
it emits the same light
it's called spontaneous emission
the most important thing about it
it's in vacuum
a quantum system
a two-level system
a stimulated state and an excited state
in vacuum
it still emits
this thing
because
in quantum theory
we use
zero-point energy
it's the
light in vacuum
the lowest energy
some theories
it's called vacuum fluctuation
although it's vacuum
it still
interacts with
the quantum system
to emit spontaneous emission
why is spontaneous emission
so important
because fundamentally
it's a quantum process
in classical theory
it's impossible
to get spontaneous emission
second
it's basically
spontaneous emission
responsible for
almost all light
we can see
it's because of spontaneous emission
zero light, flat light
visible light
it's because of
spontaneous emission
next
it's a
quantum electrodynamics
after Dirac
in 1927
after paper
a lot of people
like Pauli, Wigner
Eisenberg, Fermi
Freeman Dyson
and Feynman
started to do
QED research
what we want to say
if we take
mixed quantum classical equation
to deal with
spontaneous emission
what will happen
here
I want to explain
what is
mixed quantum classical
first
we see
you can see my mouse
oh yes
can you see my mouse
yes
ok
it's a little bit lag
if you want to stop
slow down
ok, no problem
I will stop here
ok, first question
we assume a system
a two-level system
in vacuum
this system
is completely in
spontaneous emission
no distribution
in
mixed quantum classical
there is no spontaneous emission
which is
this line
this picture
horizontal is time
vertical is
stimulated
population
that
red line
means no matter
how long
this system
will not emit any light
first of all
this is wrong
qualitatively
but we found
if
I am
not in
spontaneous emission
I have half
0.5, 0.5
half in
I found
there is a little bit
spontaneous emission
real spontaneous emission
this black line
compared
there is a gap
another
this is
we tried
a method
we tried other methods
three methods
mixed quantum classical
called
SQC
or
CPA
mixed quantum classical
there is a problem
the right picture
the middle curve
real spontaneous emission rate
red
this is
the left picture
from there
emission rate
compare with
real spontaneous emission
rate
sometimes
almost all
ground state
very close
real spontaneous emission rate
but
getting worse
more and more population
in
spontaneous emission
more and more
other methods
opposite
behavior
this is the second problem
the last problem
basically
old problem
our factory
classical factory
no fluctuation
anything about
fluctuation
must be wrong
next
the method
plus R
we call
the average length
we use
because it is the simplest
average length
in the average length
plus
LR
LIMBRA
what is the plus R
it has 3 functions
first
I put
extra relaxation
I put some population
from the top
to the ground state
this additional population
we use
according to
to deduce
in every time state
how much
how much relaxation
let it
with
spontaneous emission rate
same
this is the first thing
second
because we
took some
population
from the ground state
to the ground state
where is the energy
should be put
to the power plant
it should be
classical
part of the power plant
or plant
to
to ensure
the whole system
energy conservation
so we designed a way
the energy
can be put to the power plant
and
we designed
stochastic
defacing
I put
I put this system
there is a random process
it will
decide
the system phase
in every time
there is a random process
it will decide
the system phase
this small
stochastic defacing
introduce
classical
power plant
fluctuation
I am not running a single trajectory
I am running many trajectories
to balance the trajectory
so
we will have
the power plant
there will be fluctuation
there will be
so
we can tell
what is
What is
Okay, so let me recap it again
What did we learn from Raman Scannering?
What we learned is that
Raman Fast++R can actually
allow us to get
multi-state transitions
We can do multi-state transitions
We just need to put the correct
spontaneous emission in
We can get multi-state transitions
And it's still pretty accurate
And
Even if we don't have
a classical frequency
We don't need to put another frequency
to make it vibrate
We can still
We can still get inelastic scattering
with Mixed Chromium Classical
And lastly, let's talk about
Excuse me
Did I interrupt you?
No, no, no
Oh, okay
I have a question
Because it looks like
Raman Fast++R and Quantum
are basically the same
But my question is
For example, if you want to manually
add a relaxation
and a defacing
You basically have three parameters
to add in, right?
How do they get it?
Oh, they all
are based on
Fermi's Golden Rule
All my transitions
are based on Fermi's Golden Rule
Just like in Raman
What I'm doing is
I'm using Fermi's Golden Rule
for these two transitions
to figure out how much I need
to add
These three things
are related to each other
Everything is based on
Fermi's Golden Rule
So if I'm not wrong
If I'm not wrong
You add a resonance
intermediate state in the middle
If it's Fermi's Golden Rule
You choose an energy
and all your in and out
will be resonant with that energy
No
But
What I'm doing is
I know
For example, I know
every transition 2-1
2-1 and 2-0
are based on different Fermi's Golden Rule
Fermi's Golden Rule is a rate
There's a transition rate
In my theory
I can deduce
How much is the difference
between Errandfest and Fermi's Golden Rule
Then I'll use those three things
to add up
Let me ask
Sorry
You can move to the next slide
Yes
To the next one
The first one on the right
So
Sorry
To the one before
On the right
So the input frequency
and
in these ranges
Do you need to calculate
how to add up
the other parameters?
Or these are already
The omega i
There are ten
Do you need to add up
the other parameters
ten times?
That might be easy
I don't know
I'm just asking
It's okay
We don't need to
Every trajectory
is the same
Just change one parameter
Just omega i
Yes, I just need to change omega i
I didn't change anything
in the calculation
So I don't need to calculate again
Can I ask a question?
You are calculating
Whether it's Rayleigh or Raman
You said you want to use Fermi's Golden Rule
But in general
Your state 2 is a virtual state
So
In reality
You can't get the real coupling constant
So how do you solve this problem?
Can't get the real coupling constant
In practice
You can measure Rayleigh scattering cross-section
Or Raman scattering cross-section
But you can't get
Real state and virtual state
How much is the coupling
Yes
It's like this
I don't have virtual state
and real state coupling
The coupling I use is
Resonant
I should not say resonant
The coupling I use is
Actually 1 and 2 coupling
So
If you look back from the lab
Because my idea is
more from
Initial
The first principle
If I want to calculate
The actual molecule
To calculate this
I will use
Electronic Structure
To calculate
The real coupling
This coupling
Not the real coupling
In electronic structure
How big is the coupling
This coupling
Can be calculated
Transition dipole moment
1 and 2 state transition dipole moment
The light I hit
Whether there is resonance
I use the transition dipole moment
So you mean
You are in the molecule
You all have real state
You use real state transition dipole moment
You sum up all these real states
Yes
Because
In this
I don't have any
virtual state
It's not like
Sum of state
I have a lot of virtual state
Here is real state
Different frequency
Thank you
It is
A bit like a driving system
It is a dynamical system
Hope to answer your question
Any other questions
No, I will continue
Where did I just talk about
In the end, we want to say
The problem we want to deal with
Is a strong problem
What about this strong problem
Model triplet
It is a two-level system
Back to a very simple two-level system
There is a very strong
Classical field
The biggest feature of this model triplet
I think the coolest thing is that it is classical
Classical in quantum now
It's a bit like laser
It is a coherent state
Very close
Classical
Classical electric field
But it emits
The light wave
It is a very
Not classical
Quantum light wave
Why is this
Because of this field
This electric field
Because it is very strong
Basically, it has exceeded
So we can't use it anymore
In quantum theory
It is a bit like
Mixing state
A bit like hybridization
The picture in the lower right corner
In fact, on the left
On the left side of this diagonal
Is the Bayer state
I made
Two-level system
Generate
Sorry
Two-level system and light
The state generated by the frequency
Draw it out
After drawing the hybridization
You will find that the right side
Is the state after hybridization
It's a bit like a mix
It's a bit like a dress state
Hybridization is light
With
Hybridization of two-level system
So its energy level
Will be changed
Then
In the model on the right
It has three different
Launch
Frequency
The first one we call T
Why is it called T?
It's very simple
It's called 3 photons
You can see it from
The highest
After 1, 2, 3
Three times to the lowest
So it's called triple
3 photons
Then F is called fluorescence
Fluorescence is basically the lowest connection
The two closest connections
Between
Launch
Then the other two
It's called Rayleigh
Two Rayleigh
It goes through two photons
It's called Rayleigh
That
This
The quantum theory
Gave us three
Different frequency
It's three different peaks
Then these peaks
It will be produced
It contains the Rabi frequency
This
The gentleman on the left is Rabi
He used to be in Columbia
Very cool
Then
We can also use this
Mixed quantum classical method
Let's try
We found that if we don't put any
If we don't change any plus r
We found that this system
It's basically classical in classical out
It's classical in, it's classical out
There won't be much change
If you're a kid
Or high school
There's a physical phenomenon
You put
A pile of protein
Put in a
Tie a pile of protein
On the same pole
The pole has a fixed frequency
After a long time, they will be synchronized
This phenomenon is basically
It's very similar to what we see here
Say
I
But there are a lot of different frequencies
Running inside
In fact, we're looking at this
Mixed quantum classical
In a short time, you'll see three peaks
We can see three peaks
But for a long time, you'll find the two peaks next to it
It's slowly disappearing
Only the middle peak is left
It's basically a
Classical driving system
Classical in, classical out
Nothing else
The rest is
The same old problem
There's no fluctuation here
With this
We'll find that
The blue line is the line after the plus
We can see
There's a stable
Side peak
It won't be because of time
It's gone
Why is there a stable side peak
It's actually a
It's attributed to
Random perturbation
Stochastic defacing
It's kind of like
In this classical system
Push it from time to time
Don't let it fall back
The huge frequency
Don't let it be forever
Classical in, classical out
There's this little stochastic
Defacing is actually very important here
It can make
The two side peaks
All stable
We want to know
Here we can see
These three ratios
R, F, T
With
All classical theory
The prediction is consistent
We want to know
Is there anything else
More interesting
We can compare with classical theory
Here
We show
This graph
It's an experiment
Nature Phantomics
What did it change
It's a model triplet
Different lines
From bottom to top
Different
Infrared frequency
You'll find
There are a few
Features
The middle peak
There are some
Different
Different infrared behavior
The first one
Peak position
You can see the picture on the right
The middle line
Is
Central peak
It doesn't change much
This
Side peak
It's with
This width
Many people call
Generalized
Rabi frequency
It's off resonance
That
The experiment and theory
Very well
This peak
Basically
This
It's not hard to get
The experiment and theory
It's not too bad
We
In
In urnfest plus r
You can see
The same behavior
Central peak
Fixed
Side peak
Similar
Generalized
Rabi frequency
The picture is a bit
I want to be like the left
X and y
Opposite
If you flip it over
The color is correct
Blue to blue
This is
Can be
A very good point
Basically
It's not hard
Next
Here
There's another peak
Outside
Right
Left and right
Resonance
It may be
Higher
I'm sure
I have an impression
Please tell me
I remember
Model triplet
Very strong
Equivalent to
This connection
AC
Create another connection
My previous understanding
Right
So the calculation
Is
Method
Simulation
No use
The method
Is
Dark shift
Electrophonon
Hybridization
The wind
Relationship
Calculate
OK
The earliest
Model paper
The earliest prediction
Model triplet
Later
Many people
Explained
There is a good resource
Corinth
Work
Right
Next
More interesting
I'm comparing
This picture
I want to compare
Peak position
Can i get
Correct
Coherence emission
This one on the left
Quotient
Quantum mechanics
The whole quantum theory
Calculated
Coherence emission
The ratio
That
This green dot
Is a dot
We use
The first
We found
Near resonance
Delta omega is 0
Very good
Is there a way
We have a caveat
That is
Quantum mechanics
Based on
Rotating wave approximation
Near resonance
So we don't know
Far away
Resonance
Quantum mechanics
This calculation
Is it accurate?
So this place
We are not very clear
Is this place accurate?
We get
Quite different
Near resonance
The result is close
That right
Is a
Can
Almost beyond
Rotating wave approximation
That is
If we look at the left
Peak
For
Different frequency
Change
The red line
Right side
The blue line is the left side peak
That
Is
In this
This
It is a
It will not
Unpredictable
Because
It only focuses on
One level
This
Approximation
So it can get
The middle finger is right
But it can't get this
At this point
But our
Mixed quantum classical method
Because I didn't do anything
This
Rotating wave
So the result I got
I can get this
Linear crossing
This result
The result of the experiment is the same
On the experiment
We can see this
It is not a fixed point
It is a linear crossing
This result
Very exciting
So
We
So the last
This is the last recap
We found this
RFS class R dynamics
It can
Can simulate quantum mixing
There is no mixing
But only
Driving field
With a small stochastic
I can simulate
Quantum mixing
That we can
Very clear
Coherence emission and incoherence emission
That
I hope
These advantages
Tell everyone that we are developing
This set of theory
Very reliable
Method to deal with
Quantum interaction
But this method
There are many problems
This method
We haven't thought about it yet
This
Quantum motion
Our current material
Very simple material
Very simple
From the perspective of a chemist
We are
We hope
At least
Chemistry
Potential energy
Put in
Non-adiabatic dynamics
Different behaviors
This is a
Suitable direction
Another question mark
Can we get
Photon content detection
Because there are
The second point and the third point
Very similar
Anti-function
Because
There is another big feature
I haven't covered yet
Three-wind
Photon content detection is different
Because
It releases light
Order of relationship
Every light
For example, it
It releases the first
The next one may be very close to it
That
The first one
It must be very far away
It can't release a light right away
So when you measure
The statistical value of light
You will find
F light may be
In line with
Poisson distribution
Then T light
It is in line with sub-Poisson distribution
So they
The statistical value of light will be different
Here
We haven't tried it yet
Of course
There is no light inside
Can we get similar
Finally
There is a
If our light is not
Not
Not at zero
There is a thermal distribution
Then we
Can we
In Mixed quantum classical
Get detail balance
Or we may
Violate detail balance
The last question
It's actually a very important question
In many systems
For example, you put a two-level system in the cavity
Its spontaneous emission rate
May be changed
It may no longer be in line with
Freemius golden rule rate
Its spontaneous emission rate
Because of the cavity
Strong interaction
Caused
It
The emission frequency will change
What about our method now
Based on Freemius golden rule rate
So it may not be in line with
So this is also a
It may be necessary to consider
Then
Then we do
Method
Method development
For people
The most common thing we do
We have created a new toy
It's
We want to use it in many places
Many people hope to use it
In many places
For us
A very important question
When will it break down
This is the most important thing we want to know
The most important thing we want to know
When does it not work
That
Of course there are many
Application
These things are all
We hope to push it to
Other
Light or
Spectroscopy group
Let them try
Can we
Use the same method
Look at
We put
Chemical reaction into a cavity
It may be because of the interaction with light
To change
Its vibrational
Energy level
Because of the change in the vibrational energy level
It may have different
Reaction pathway
So it will have different chemical reactions
This is also
This is a thing we can do
A direction
Another application in the middle
Is a new theory
It's called
Model spectroscopy
Then
In this model spectroscopy
I use
Classical source
Generate quantum light
Then use this quantum light
Different light statistical properties
To
Hit the target
Then
I can see
This
Target for different
Photon statistics
Behavior
This is a
New thing
But this thing
There is no implementation
But in theory
Many people
Pursue this direction
Finally
A very
In device and material science
A very useful application
Conductance enhancement
Application
This
Conductance enhancement
Can use
Cavity
This method
We hope to use this method
To
Understand why
Conductance enhancement
Will happen
Finally, I would like to thank
My
Professor
This
Old man
Not old
My
Advisor
And
I've been
Half year
Visiting scholar
Maxine
A professor
Now
This method
Generate
Three dimension
This method
I have a
Electronic system
There is a
Classic electronic system
Maxine is a classic electronic system
Expert
This theory
With
Very
Mature
Combination
Tao Li
A researcher
He is
We did a lot of work together
Finally, I want to thank
Ted
Organize
Let me have a chance
Share with you
Thank you
Any other questions
No
Hey everyone
No one has a special question
Hey
Let me ask
One is what we are looking at
The problem is good
When we look at it recently
I
What are you doing
Light
This kind of
Interaction
In the semiconductor
This kind of
We are looking at
In addition to
Like you now
Are concerned
Light in classical way
Electromagnetic wave
If
So we do
We do more
That
So
It depends on
Light itself
Characteristics
One we are looking at recently
I
Just
Is
This kind of thing
I'm thinking
If there is
Although at the beginning
But
Light
Is recently
I think it's a hot topic
One
Have you ever thought about it
His whole disease
He is also a
That one
Border
One of the conditions
Square
Light
This slope
It's different from the circle
Not the same
In addition to the disease
There is a good moment
That you
This may be
Maybe you are now
It may not be the same
But I want to say
You can analyze it
Light
For
Maybe
Interaction between molecules
Interaction with any
Interaction
How does it react
I think
This
I am not a scholar
These things are a bit difficult
I
I am now
What they are doing
Very confident
I have
FDTD
These good
Classical electromagnetic
That
Basically
What he does now
For
Different polarization
Can be done
I think
If he does this
I think it should be
The problem you are thinking about is helpful
Great
Let's pay attention to this
Professor
I have a question
Ok
This is
This is my long-standing question
I want to know when it will happen
Melo
When will it happen
Outer tongue splitting
Then
What is your second
Outer tongue splitting
Oh
Then
I know it's probably
Only in molecules or
Molecular system
But in
Acetone system
Outer tongue splitting
Then
Do you know the specific reason
I don't know the specific reason
What is it
Because my understanding of it is the same as yours
It's in
Molecule
In the molecular system
It will be
The other one is in
Yeah
I still have to learn these things
I haven't
I probably do this
About a year and a half
Ok
I still have a lot to learn
The other thing is
Outer tongues and
What is it
It's called
EIT
Electronic
Transparency
What's the difference between these two
I really don't know
Ok
Out of my
You may ask
Ted may not know
I remember EIT
I remember EIT and
It seems to be different
EIT seems to be more in atoms
But I actually don't remember
Ah
EIT
EIT and
The effect of outer tongues looks the same
But it's completely different from molecular splitting
Molecular splitting you will see
There are three states
You see two states in outer tongues
I forgot
Sorry
It's okay
But I think this is a pretty interesting question
I think I should
I should use
Because EIT is basically
The first thing we try
Let's try to break down
This method
See if our method will break down here
It's actually pretty good
So I was thinking
Maybe our next project will use EIT
Ok
Another thing
You said you add
You add fluctuation in the electric field
Then
Add fluctuation in the classical field
Then let it be
Looks like there is
Spontaneous emission
Which electric field are you in
Is it driving force
Do you add fluctuation in the emission field
No, I'm in the radiation field
Add fluctuation
What about driving field
We still treat it as
It's a
Electric field running past
Just say
You can break it down
But this
If you are in
Emission
Add fluctuation in radiation
Then
You said your addition
You just assume
It's on time
Don't run on time
Then at a certain random time
You just let it change
Phase
Then
This thing seems to be with
Is two dimensional
Spectroscopy
The method they use
Very similar
Do you say pump probe
In two dimensional
Spectroscopy
They have
Another one called
There are two components in
One is called
Free induction decay
The second one is
Phonon scattering
Or scattering of other things
Then
The second one
Their assumption
They brought in
Model method
In the radiation field
Add a random
Phase jump
So these two things
Is it the same
Actually different
A little different
Just say
OK
I want
Just
I want to say one thing
Because i'm not really
I'm not really
Add a random phase
I'm adding a random phase
In
Two level system
Then this two level system
Random phase will react to electric field
So i'm not really
Add to electric field
That way
There are two benefits
Because
My
It is natural
There are two benefits of this method
The first benefit is
Because my two level system
Also need this defacing
It also needs
This little defacing
Correct
Its fluctuation
It also needs this thing
That
From
Then the other benefit is
Because i'm
Put
There is actually a
Difficulty point is because I put
I want to put this
Add a little fluctuation
I can't just add it
Add to a certain place
It just caused it
Self-interaction will destroy the whole system
That
So it will have a
Specific method
Add it to a correct place
That
This thing
Because
Because this field
It's not like it's not just a point
It's a whole space
And it has to meet some basic
For example, it can't go beyond the speed of light
I can't put a field
Suddenly add to a place beyond the speed of light
Right
So
We try not to add directly
On the field
So when we design this method
We put
This fluctuation is added to the two-level system
Let the two-level system
Naturally generate this fluctuation
OK
There is a more detailed question
I want to know
Why
Classical
Just
Quantum matter and classical
Field
That
Inside the model
Only when
Just when
That is
Low
Low 0
Low 1 is
There will be no emission
I always thought
OK
Thank you for asking this question
Because
Because of my time
I missed a part
That's it
Here
Mixed quantum classical
It's not pure
Pure
The most basic
Mixed quantum classical
There is a
I am in this
This
In this
Two-level system
Classical
Field
Will also
Self-interact to two-level system
Let it decay
So
This is already a non-linear system
So you see these
These red lines are not a simple
A simple
Exponential decay
OK
It is a
I will keep myself
Self-interact
So
There will be some decay
Basically
Here
This is one of our recent papers
Its point is
This is the most basic
Mixed quantum classical
Can get some
Partially correct
Some spontaneous emission
But it won't get all
Spontaneous emission
Sorry, you can go to the front page
Let me see what is called
Oh
You said
Its equation
I didn't write it out
OK
I can
I can give you
Our paper
On the paper
I can check it myself
Because I didn't
Write it all out
It's a bit complicated
Thank you
You're welcome
OK
Other listeners have no questions
Want to discuss
OK
If you don't have any questions
That's all for today
Thank you
OK
Then you
When you feel ready
Tell us
We will put the recording on
OK
That's all for today
Good night
10.30
OK
Thank you
Bye