Hello, everyone.
I am honored to be able to introduce Dr. Sun today.
Dr. Sun completed her bachelor's degree from 1999 to 2013
in Plant Pathology and Microbiology at Taiwan University.
After completing her bachelor's degree from 2003 to 2005,
she completed her master's degree in Plant Pathology and Microbiology at the same university in Taiwan.
She then completed her Ph.D. degree from 2005 to 2010 at Purdue University.
Her major is Chemical Biology.
After completing her Ph.D. degree, she went to MIT to do her postdoc.
After four years, she went to UCSF to do her second postdoc and assistant researcher.
This year, she started her new job as a Senior Scientific Researcher at Genentech.
Today, Dr. Sun is going to talk about
Use Single-Cell RNA-Seq to Tackle Complex Biology.
Now, let's welcome Dr. Sun to give her presentation.
Hello, everyone. I am Dr. Sun.
Sorry, my voice is a bit hoarse due to my cold.
Today, I am going to talk in a simple and easy-to-understand way.
Just in case, some of you may not have a background in biology.
I hope you can at least learn about Single-Cell RNA-Seq.
Here is my personal email and LinkedIn account.
Although my LinkedIn account is not up to date,
please feel free to connect with me.
I will be speaking in Chinese today,
but I am not sure what the term is in Chinese.
If you have any questions, please feel free to contact me.
I don't want to make it too complicated.
I will be focusing on technology.
I am currently working at a company,
so I can't really talk about research projects here.
I will try my best to talk about the applications of this technology,
and the principles behind it.
I hope this will be helpful to those who are interested.
Before we get into the technology,
I will briefly review the biology of NTU.
As you may already know, our body is made up of cells.
Many cells form organs,
and eventually form organs in our body,
becoming a functional human body.
An interesting fact is that our body is composed of over 20 different types of cells.
You can see that their forms and functions are very different.
For example, there are nerve cells, blood cells, muscle cells,
and even different types of cells in different organs.
Their functions and forms are very different.
Let's take a deeper look.
As you can see, our body is made up of cells.
Each cell has a nucleus,
which is a red dot.
In English, it's called a nucleus.
In Chinese, it's called a cell nucleus.
In this cell nucleus, there is a chromosome.
This chromosome is made up of our genes.
I think everyone has a concept of genes.
Genes are our genetic material.
They are our genetic material.
In this definition, genes are a DNA segment.
They can be converted into a useful molecule.
They can perform the functions and functions that they need.
The reason for the general description of gene code is that DNA is a so-called ATCG.
DNA is a so-called ATCG.
So, if we talk about genes,
the sequence obtained may be composed of these four ATCGs.
This is our so-called gene code.
In molecular biology, there is a so-called central dogma.
The principle is that we have this genetic material.
Its main structure is DNA.
It will be transcribed into RNA.
RNA will be further transcribed into protein.
This protein can perform various biological functions.
As time goes by, the central dogma is gradually extended to more different forms.
We can even find more different directions from the virus or other systems.
Today's technology involves a discovery.
In the past, we thought that DNA was transcribed into RNA.
But later, scientists found another enzyme that can reverse transcribe RNA back to DNA.
With the help of this enzyme, many related extension technologies can be built on this basis.
Today, we will mainly talk about RNA-seq.
Another way to talk about it is transcriptional analysis or gene expression profiling.
Basically, we can use gene expression to understand human physiology.
This picture shows a major timeline and milestone in molecular biology and sequencing technology.
As many of you know, the first discovery was in 1953.
In 1977, Sanger's DNA sequencing was developed.
Later, PCR technology was also developed.
PCR technology allows us to rapidly increase our DNA in the laboratory.
Many related technologies can be built on this basis.
In 1990, the Human Genome Project was launched.
After 13 years, the Human Genome Project was established.
At this stage, sequencing costs are still very high.
It is difficult to operate a sequencing project in a lab.
In 2005, the next-generation sequencing technology was introduced.
This technology has greatly reduced the cost of sequencing.
The next-generation sequencing technology is still widely used.
In recent years, the third-generation sequencing technology was introduced.
When was single-cell RNA-seq developed?
The first report on single-cell RNA-seq was made in 2009.
Because of the gradual maturation of the technology,
especially the rapid reduction of sequencing costs,
single-cell RNA-seq can be operated more widely.
Now, many extended protocols, technologies, and companies continue to develop rapidly in this field.
Why do we need to do single-cell RNA-seq?
Before single-cell RNA-seq, we can look at gene profiling.
For example, what is the difference between a cancer cell and a normal cell?
For example, we have a healthy sample and a diseased sample.
After sequencing, we can compare the gene profiling of these two cells.
Then we can find out the disease gene.
Or we can find out which signaling pathway is further activated or inhibited.
But there is a problem.
For example, a tumor may contain a variety of different cells.
There may be immune cells, tumor cells, fibroblasts, and so on.
If the tumor is broken down and the RNA-seq is obtained,
the result is a variety of different cells.
From this heat map,
we can still see that some genes are inhibited or activated in the diseased sample.
It is difficult to determine if the disease is caused by immune cells, fibroblasts, or unknown gene cells.
At this time, if we can do transcriptome profiling at single-cell resolution,
we can have a deeper understanding of each cell in a tumor tissue.
Here are some interesting graphs that I saw on the Internet.
It can give you an idea of why the so-called Bok analysis may cause some misjudgment.
For example, in this graph,
each point here has the so-called x-value and y-value.
Then you can do various calculations.
For example, the x-value is like this,
the y-value is like this,
the x-deviation is like this,
and the y-deviation is like this.
But even if you calculate all these values,
what about the relationship between x and y?
So if you just do a Bok analysis,
you may not be able to express the so-called structure behind it.
Another interesting graph is that
sometimes if you do a Bok analysis,
you may get a conclusion that leads you to a wrong direction.
For example, suppose this is your sample.
So your sample contains a lot of different animals.
Then you do a Bok analysis to see what this creature might look like.
Then you may come to a conclusion that this is what this creature should look like.
Then you will find that it is very different from the so-called real state.
The so-called single-celled analysis basically has different methods.
That is to say, under this technology,
you can analyze each animal separately
and find a lot of different features.
Then based on the features you find,
you start to do the so-called clustering.
For example, this graph shows that
you have already found two features.
One is Firm and the other is Venom.
Then even if you just add two features like this,
you can already cluster a lot of animals into at least two subsets.
One big subset will be the snakes,
which has the Venom but doesn't have Firm.
Then the other big subset may be the so-called
it doesn't have Venom, but it has Firm.
When you can add more and more features,
hopefully, finally, you will be able to
one individual item will be clustered into one group.
So this is the whole idea about why you need to do profiling at a single-cell level.
Then generally in this single-cell field,
one of their favorite metaphors is
the so-called fruit smoothie and the so-called fruit salad.
When you make a Borg RNC asset,
it's very similar to the so-called fruit smoothie.
Basically, you put all kinds of fruit and vegetables together.
The taste you drink is basically
an average taste of all ingredients.
So you may not be able to know
what ingredients are in this.
Then maybe the ingredients you taste
are some special strong ingredients.
Maybe it's an apple, maybe it's a strawberry.
But you can't know that
maybe there's some cabbage in it or something else.
Single-cell is like you're eating a fruit salad.
Basically, you can taste each individual piece of the fruit.
So somehow you'll know
what kind of composition the fruit should be made of.
So this so-called fruit smoothie to the fruit salad,
basically what single-cell RNC wants to achieve
is that you can show the individual cell type
that causes the biological response or disease.
Then this summary is a more scientific statement.
So basically, the so-called Borg RNC
measures the so-called average expression level
for each cell across a population of cells.
Basically, like I just said,
if you're doing a cancer study,
you have two samples.
One is from healthy tissue,
the other is from diseased tissue.
Then you grind it up and compare the two samples.
Its limitation is basically that
if you want to study a more complex system today,
for example, you want to study people's brains
or some more complex organs,
then this technology
I'm afraid I can't give you a very clear result.
Basically, what single-cell does,
it measures the distribution of expression level
for each gene across a population of the cells.
So using this technology,
every cell has a specific change
that can be shown.
Basically, now there are already a lot of
so-called commercially available single-cell platforms on the market.
Of course, they all have their own advantages and disadvantages.
From my personal experience,
I have two platforms of experience.
One is the so-called Fluidigm C1.
The other is called 10x Genomics.
Now I'm going to quickly introduce
the two single-cell platforms I've used before.
Basically, in general,
the so-called workflow of the single cell,
its concept is basically the same.
First of all, you have the so-called tissue of interest,
either patient tissue or cells,
which are some of the cells that you are interested in.
Then, before doing single-cell RIC,
the most important step is that you have to
prepare in your own way
the so-called single-cell suspension.
Each person may have different approaches.
For example,
the so-called FACS to do the single-cell selection,
or to do some so-called micro-dissection,
to sort out the cells one by one.
Then, when you can successfully complete
your single-cell suspension,
you basically inject it
into either single-cell platform.
Then, in the single-cell platform,
what it does is basically
to lyse the cell
and extract the RNA in it.
Then, this RNA is
reverse transcribed
into the cDNA.
Then, this cDNA can be amplified
through PCR.
After the amplification,
we build a library.
Then, these libraries can be sent for sequencing.
Like I said,
this is the so-called sequencing result.
You get the so-called sequence.
This sequence is basically
the sequence of A, T, C, and G.
Then, you may be mapping.
Because now many genes have been decoded,
including human, mouse,
and some species.
So, according to the source of your sample,
you can map it to the reference genome.
Then, you can know
what the expression of each gene is.
Then, the last step is
the so-called computational analysis.
Because this single-cell RNAC technology
is relatively new,
the computational analysis
is still under development.
This is basically the same concept.
You have a tissue that you are interested in.
First, you have to be able to
dissociate it into the so-called single-cell suspend.
Then, there are all kinds of different systems
that can make the single-cell suspension
that you need.
Then, you can further
dissociate it into the single-cell platform.
This picture is from a recent review paper.
So, what you can see here is that
the single-cell RNAC technology
has developed very rapidly in recent years.
It started with the first single-cell paper
around 2009.
At that time, the single-cell technology
was still a very difficult technology.
It was not possible to operate smoothly
at every level.
Then, the number of times you do it
may be accumulated from dozens of times.
However, as time goes by,
there are more and more different types of
different technologies,
including the droplet method.
There are also some
random capture technologies,
such as in-tube barcoding,
and so on.
Now, you can see that
basically,
the single-cell technology
can already get a lot of cells
in one experiment.
Of course, there are many technologies
that continue to develop
to get more and more cells.
Now, I would like to introduce
two single-cell platforms
that I have had hands-on experience with.
The first one is FluDyn.
FluDyn is probably the first single-cell
RNA-seq technology in the market.
Its basic process is very similar to what I just said.
First, you need to be able to successfully
dissociate your tissue.
Basically, this technology
captures cells to 96 well plate.
Basically, all the so-called cell lysing,
RT, and cDNA amplification
happen in this machine.
Its output is basically
the cDNA after the amplification.
Then you can make a barcode library
and send for sequencing.
This is the real situation of the C1 chip.
This is an image under the microscope.
You can see that
this cell basically has a fluorescent label.
So you can see that
after running this chip,
this cell is basically captured in this chip.
Then all the reactions
will happen in this reaction.
Finally, when this reaction is completed,
you get the cDNA after the amplification.
Then you can further build your library
and send for sequencing.
Then you will get your data.
According to my personal experience,
the C1 chip has some advantages
but also some disadvantages.
Its advantages are...
Oh, I may have made a mistake here.
The first one is relatively long prep time.
This should be its disadvantage.
Its prep time is actually very long.
Of course, if you let your sample
sit on the ice all the time,
you may worry that
its gene expression profile
may change during that time.
So basically, we hope that
before we get the so-called
light cell,
the prep time can be as short as possible.
But this C1 chip
still has some very good advantages.
For example, this set of technologies
allows you to capture single cells
under the microscope
one by one.
For example, this picture shows
a very beautiful single cell.
Some wells may not have single cells at all.
Some wells may have multiple samples.
Maybe later on,
when you are building your library,
you may ignore such samples.
Because in the subsequent data analysis,
you may not be able to judge
whether the data you get is from one cell
or multiple cells.
Basically, its biggest disadvantage
is the so-called throughput.
Because basically,
in the most primitive C1 chip,
it can only capture 96 cells at a time.
In the later version,
it may be able to capture 800 at a time.
But in fact, in reality,
its efficiency is very poor.
Maybe only 60% to 70% of the wells
can capture single cells.
So in fact,
the number of cells you can get every time is extremely small.
So this is the biggest problem with C1.
And later on,
a lot of research found that
even some data that had already been published,
they found that
some of the results they got
were quite related to batch.
So this technology basically,
in the current single cell field,
a lot of people have turned to other better
better technology choices.
At present,
the vast majority of single cell RNA-seq platforms,
you will probably see,
is from this company.
This company is called 10X Genomics.
Its core technology
is basically called Gems.
Gen Bits in Emulsion.
So its idea is basically
that it has a lot of these bits.
And then these bits are basically
I'm thinking the simplest way to do this is
I'm going to show you a YouTube video.
You should be able to quickly understand
how this technology works.
Okay.
Oh, Dr. Sun,
I'd like to ask if there's any sound in this video?
Eh...
It's music, so you can't hear the sound, right?
Okay.
But it's okay.
It's not talking.
Okay.
Yeah, so...
It's just background music.
I think it's easier to use the video.
Wait a minute.
Sorry, I'll turn this off.
So basically, you can see that this is the set of techniques.
It's probably like this.
If you compare these two sets of techniques,
Of course, the biggest advantage of 10X Genomics is that its throughput is very high.
We can capture more than 10,000 cells in each round.
If you compare it to 96 or 800 cells, 10X is much better than C1.
In addition, the advantage of the UMI set of techniques is that it involves some PCR processes.
This process may also cause some experimental biases.
The UMI set of techniques can basically help correct these biases.
In addition, the process of generating Gems is extremely fast.
It only takes 7 minutes to generate all the Gems.
So basically, you can make sure that your cells are in a relatively intact state.
Of course, there are some disadvantages.
For example, 10X Genomics does not sequence all the transcripts.
It only does a small part of 3'N.
So if your research is looking at variants of Gems,
You basically can't use 10X Genomics.
On the other hand, many data analysis tools are designed for 10X Genomics.
So if you use this set of systems,
You may get more help in subsequent analysis.
Next, let's talk about some real-world operations.
In the real world,
Before injecting into the 10X system,
We have our tissue of interest.
Then we may have different sample prep strategies.
To control our single-cell suspension.
Before injecting into the 10X chip,
We basically need to do a cell quality control.
We need to look at several parameters.
For example, its viability.
And basically, this cell looks like a single cell.
And then there's the cell size.
Let you know that your protocol is basically able to target the cells you're interested in.
So the take-home message here will be that
The sample prep protocol optimization is very important.
For you to get high-quality single-cell data in the future.
In the first step, it basically determines most of it.
After your cell QC pass,
You make sure that your single-cell suspension is a very good prep.
Then you can basically inject into the 10X system.
Then all these steps are basically like a kit.
And then you can just run it through.
And now Genome has developed its own computational tool.
I can do the initial data processing.
And then you get a so-called gene barcode matrix.
And then you can use this matrix to do the follow-up analysis.
For the whole workflow of single-cell data analysis,
It's basically divided into two stages.
The first stage, the yellow one, is basically the so-called sequencing QC.
That is to say, you have to see if your sequencing data is good or bad.
In this part, it's basically quite mature.
Because I mentioned before that this technique has been used for many years.
That set of techniques is basically the so-called sequencing QC.
It can almost move the whole set to the single-cell RNAC part.
So at this stage of sequencing QC,
It's basically looking at the so-called read QC, alignment QC, and mapping QC.
And now Genome has a set of its own software that can help you finish this thing.
Finally, you can get a gene barcode matrix.
And then when you get the gene barcode matrix,
The red part here is basically the so-called further data processing.
I'm going to take a little bit of time to talk about it.
The so-called further data processing here.
In the first step, I call it matrix LQC.
What it means is that basically the most important point of this step is to say
You have to get rid of some of the so-called low-quality cells first.
Because if you keep these low-quality cells in your dataset,
A big problem, it might cause a lot of noise.
And then it might make your subsequent data analysis very difficult.
So basically, after you remove some of the bad cells,
You can take your data to further normalization.
After normalization, you may need to face another problem.
After all, single cell technology is based on single cell.
So it will have a lot of unwanted variation.
For example, it may be a batch effect.
Then all the cells may be in different cell cycle status.
These may be information that you are not interested in.
Then you may need to use some computational methods to either regress it out.
Or maybe give it a score.
This may be a more detailed data analysis.
Then, in short, when you clean up these data through this step,
Then your dataset can do a lot of downstream data analysis.
It includes clustering, cell type identification,
And then you can do the so-called differential gene expression analysis.
That is to say, you can compare the gene profiling between cell type A and cell type B.
Which one is the same? Which one is different?
Or maybe you have a very interested cell population.
Then you can see what are the cell service markers.
Or you can compare two situations.
Then see which single-only pathway is being activated or inhibited.
These things are very useful information for both basic biology and disease research.
Then you can also do some network analysis.
Then some people will even take this single cell to do some so-called pseudo-time analysis.
The so-called pseudo-time is that we
Because in a lot of research, such as developmental biology,
It may look at a bit like a time course.
That is, how does this cell change from one state to another state with the eyes of time?
In the past, you may have to take samples at different times.
Then do the analysis.
The concept of single cell may be that you may not need to take so many time points.
You may take one or two time points.
Because every cell will give you some information.
Not all cells are in the same state at the same time.
So you can basically go through every cell.
It may be at a certain stage in the process of transformation.
Then it may be in this set of data.
It will give you a so-called pseudo-time.
Such information.
So this is also a very powerful place for single cell.
Let's talk about the so-called metric cell quality control.
What is it like in a real state?
How do you filter out the so-called unhealthy cells or cells you don't want?
Of course, everyone may have their own criteria.
Here are some of the most general ways.
This set of data sets is basically published.
It uses the so-called human blood cells to make a demo data.
This scatter plot is the percentage of the mitochondrion versus the UMI number.
This UMI number can be regarded as how many molecules have been detected.
So-called how many transcripts have been detected.
Then every point here basically represents a cell.
You can see that the majority of the cells are in this position.
In terms of biology, you will know that the vast majority of the cells are in this position.
So these cells have a very high UMI number.
It means that there are a lot of transcripts being detected.
So it is possible that these signals are not coming from one single cell.
These may be cell aggregation or multiplex.
These may be the cells you want to get rid of.
Because basically this signal is not coming from one single cell.
Then some other cells you may want to get rid of are the so-called cells.
So you can see that there are very few UMI that can be detected.
But it has a very high percentage of mitochondrion.
Usually when a cell is in an extremely unhealthy state, its mitochondrion will be very high.
So this is also a general criterion that many people will set to filter out some cells that they think are not worth doing downstream analysis.
The last cell that may be used for downstream analysis is this one.
So what does this analysis look like?
This is basically a result of unbiased clustering.
So you can see that the sample here is from a human pbmc cell.
Here, each point represents a cell.
This type of clustering is called t-SNE clustering.
Basically, it is a clustering algorithm.
Basically, what you can understand is that the closer the cells are, the more similar their properties are.
Basically, they look at, for example, which genes are expressed in this clustering cell, and which genes are expressed in this clustering cell.
Then they can identify what kind of cells these may be.
So in a single-cell RNAC experiment, you can quickly identify all kinds of different immune cells.
For example, this clustering is basically a B-cell.
The gene expression plotting here further confirms that when you see here, it becomes more purplish, which means that this particular gene is expressed in large quantities.
This gene is basically a B-cell mutagen.
So it further confirms that these cells do have B-cell properties.
For example, this CD3E is basically a T-cell marker.
It is also expressed in large quantities in this T-cell population.
Once you get a result like this, you can further study and compare which cells are the same and which cells are different.
Or you can compare two B-cells in a different sample.
Then you can compare the gene profiling of the two B-cells to see what is different.
In this way, the result you get will be a signal that only B-cells give you, rather than a result where all cells are averaged.
This is roughly the concept of a single-cell.
Due to time constraints, I will skip the last part.
This is just an example of what a single-cell can do.
To summarize, there are some things you may need to consider before conducting a single-cell experiment.
In my current job, I have to support many single-cell projects on campus.
Based on my experience with many different projects, I can see that data analysis is still the biggest bottleneck in this technology.
In terms of generating the data, it is not that difficult.
However, every time you generate a library of data, it may be over 1,000 cells.
To be honest, it is not that easy to analyze the data.
Even though we have a single-cell working group in our company, we still have to figure out what is the best normalization method and what is the best batch correction method.
In terms of differential gene expression analysis, which method is the best for single-cell analysis?
Basically, if you know exactly what you want to ask, your single-cell data will be more meaningful.
However, if you are not sure what you want to see, your data will be lost.
In my experience, it is very important to optimize the sample prep protocol before going into the single-cell platform.
If you don't optimize your sample prep properly, you may not get the cells you need.
Finally, I want to touch on the single-cell genomics.
The single-cell genomics development is very fast.
There are many new technologies for different biological problems.
For example, the single-cell RAC we just talked about is a single-cell suspension.
However, in some research, you may not be able to get the so-called living tissue.
For example, if you want to study the brain, you may only get the tissue after a person's death.
Or you may only get the frozen tissue.
Basically, you can't get the tissue from a living cell.
Therefore, there is a so-called single-cell RAC.
The single-cell RAC takes the tissue from a dead cell and extracts the RNA from it.
There are also other versions.
For example, if you are interested in the recombination of T-cells and B-cells, there is also a single-cell RAC like this.
If you are studying cancer T-cell therapy, it will be very useful.
If you are studying the chromatin regulation, there is also a single-cell attack C protocol.
You can see which part of the chromatin is open and which part is closed.
There is also a new technology called CyC.
CyC adds a DNA barcoding to the antibody.
CyC turns it into another RNA molecule.
CyC turns it into a pseudogene.
When you run the single-cell platform, CyC becomes an additional signal.
In addition to obtaining the RNA expression profile, you can also detect the cell service protein signal.
This technology can also help you with cell type identification.
Overall, CyC is still developing rapidly in the field of sample processing and data analysis.
This is a brief introduction to CyC.
If you are interested in CyC, you can learn more about it.
Thank you Dr. Sun for giving us a presentation today.
We will now open the Q&A section.
I hope everyone can actively discuss or ask questions about what Dr. Sun just said.
Thank you.
I just saw a person in the chat asking,
Do you mind sharing your presentation slides?
Let's see if Dr. Sun can send the slides to you.
Okay.
Another person asked,
Hi Dr. Sun, for in vivo study, would you suggest to do the qPCR on intracellular organ first,
then based on the qPCR result to design the experimental for RNA-Seq?
Do you have any suggestions for the qPCR and RNA-Seq?
For qPCR,
if there is a new project coming in,
we will not go for single cell RNA-Seq.
We will first look at the existing technology,
such as qPCR or Bulk RNA-Seq.
If you want to compare healthy and diseased,
or knockout or wild-type mice,
you may want to look at whether there is a difference in a specific single-cell RNA-Seq.
If your qPCR can already answer your question,
we usually prefer to ask them to use a relatively cheap and simple technology to confirm.
If you want to compare healthy and diseased,
you may want to look at whether there is a difference in a specific single-cell RNA-Seq.
What software do you use to do batch correction for single-cell RNA-Seq?
Are you asking about rPackage?
Hello?
Oh, rPackage.
I can answer that.
Are you doing single-cell RNA-Seq analysis?
Yes.
I believe Serat is doing single-cell RNA-Seq analysis.
Have you heard of Serat?
If you are interested,
this is one of the most popular software out there
and it is being developed for single-cell RNA-Seq.
It is being developed for single-cell RNA-Seq.
In terms of the CCA,
it assumes that your dataset is co-variant.
My personal favorite batch collection algorithm is MNN.
It is another package called SCRAN.
It is another patch called SCRAN.
it is another patch called SCRAN.
it is another path called SCRAN.
what is the method of using this feature?
the SOLIDWORKS?
can save months, few years, or million years.
the EP-1 like Dropsy or CluedTie Audio see-ent performing
the EP-1 like Dropsy or CluedTie Audio see-entering
Jason can hardly get any good result
because of the technical issue
The EP-1 like Dropsy or CluedTie Audio see-entering
Jason can hardly get any good result
because of the technical issue
The EP-1 like Dropsy or CluedTie Audio see-entering
Jason can hardly get any good result
because of the technical issue
The EP-1 like Dropsy or CluedTie Audio see-entering
Jason can hardly get any good result