Hi everyone, welcome to this week's TARA Talk.
The title of today's talk is
The Evaluation of Alternative Exposure Metrics
for Traffic-Related Air Pollutant Exposure
in North Carolina.
Let's welcome our speaker today,
Zhang Shiying, or you can call her Zhang-C.
Let's briefly introduce the speaker's information.
She's currently working at Sonoma Technology,
a company that specializes in this area.
She did her Ph.D. at UNC-North Carolina-Champaign Hill.
Before coming to the United States,
she was a master's student at the University of Texas,
then a master's student at the University of Texas,
then a master's student at the University of Texas.
She's currently working on a topic that's closely related to her research.
Let's welcome our speaker, Zhang Shiying.
Hi everyone.
Before I start, I want to show you my T-shirt.
I won last year.
My name is Zhang Shiying.
You can call me Zhang-C.
Today's topic is
how to use air quality models or model-based methods
to assess human exposure to air pollution.
I'm going to focus on the traffic pollutants.
A few days ago, the host asked me to talk about
the related issues of air pollution.
But because our company has a strict process
of reviewing things and publications,
I didn't have time to make a new video.
So I'm going to talk about my last year's video.
This photo was taken in the United States in 1948.
Why is air pollution important?
This photo was taken in a small town in Pennsylvania in 1948
called Donora.
The photo on the right was taken at noon.
You can see that it wasn't bad weather or raining that day.
No, it was a normal noon.
The streetlights were all on and the sky looked dark.
Air pollution was very serious at that time.
After that incident,
40 people died in the town.
50% of the residents suffered from
serious respiratory and cardiovascular diseases.
People said that it was very difficult to breathe at that time.
This incident caused a lot of resonance in the United States.
People said that air pollution was very serious.
After that incident,
there were a lot of social movements,
protests, and government measures.
Finally, in 1967,
the United States passed the Clean Air Act,
which is the most important law in the United States.
The Clean Air Act was finally passed,
and control began.
Was it useful?
The answer is yes.
Let's take a look at this picture.
The word may be too small to see clearly,
but it doesn't matter.
This is basically the annual air pollution concentration.
This is a measured situation.
I remember I took this.
It should be LA.
Each line represents a different city or county.
You can see this trend.
Every year, air pollution is decreasing.
So it's actually useful.
Since air pollution has decreased,
what are we doing to study air pollution?
It's already so low.
What are we doing here?
The two most important things now
are not only in the United States,
but also in the world.
The two most important air pollutants are
1. Smelly sheep
2. PM2.5
PM2.5 is called a particulate matter
with a diameter smaller than 2.5 micrograms.
I won't go into detail.
But basically,
smelly sheep is not directly released.
You won't have something that says it's smelly sheep.
It won't be like that.
The formation of smelly sheep is secondary.
In other words, it's not a smelly sheep gas.
These gases become smelly sheep
after chemical reactions in the air.
These gases that are released
may not be so harmful to the human body.
But after it's released,
it becomes smelly sheep
and is very harmful to the human body.
PM2.5 is simply a very, very small particle.
This is a strand of hair.
We all love to use this picture.
PM10 is a diameter smaller than 10 micrograms.
It's about this big.
It's a blue circle.
PM2.5 is this small.
What does being small have to do with it?
Being small means that it's easy to pass through your respiratory tract.
It can go deeper.
It can go into the lungs.
It will cause respiratory diseases
and even cardiovascular diseases.
Let's skip this one first.
This is a study
that has been very active in recent years
called Global Burden of Disease.
They publish every year
the current ranking of causes of death
and how many people die.
Why is air pollution important?
After the Clean Air Act,
the concentration of pollutants decreased every year.
But if you look at the whole world,
the cause of death from air pollution
is ranked fourth in the world.
Air pollution is very, very, very important.
This is a paper from Nature in 2015.
They divided the world into countries
and gave the most serious air pollution
emission sector.
They predicted how many emission sectors
would cause death.
So if you look at this table,
there are different pollutants in the horizontal axis.
For example, we have residential energy.
Air pollution caused by using energy.
Agriculture causes air pollution.
Land traffic causes air pollution.
You can see the two red boxes,
USA and Germany.
These two countries
cause the most death
in the traffic sector.
These are some introductions.
What am I going to talk about today?
This paper was published in 2015.
In terms of environmental epidemiology,
it is important to look at the relationship
between diseases and air pollution.
You want to use air pollution variability
to explain whether there is a disease
or whether there is a disease.
In this case,
if there are 10 people today,
5 people have respiratory diseases,
5 people do not.
I wonder if this is related to air pollution.
When I was doing this statistical model,
I found that these 10 people
were exposed to the same amount of air pollution.
For example, they were all exposed to
5 micrograms per cubic meter of PM2.5.
At this time,
the model can't see anything.
5 people are sick, 5 people are not sick,
but everyone is exposed to the same amount of air pollution.
This means that you can't do anything.
This paper talks about
the past epidemiological studies,
the past studies that link diseases
and air pollution.
What can be improved?
This slide has a lot of words.
Basically, the most important thing is
the Health Effect Institute.
This is a 2009 paper.
The Health Effect Institute
is a very famous institution
that studies health effects.
They use data from the American Cancer Society
to re-analyze and link
the relationship between air pollution and death.
As I said before,
when you do this,
you need to have all the information
about whether you are sick or not.
Secondly, you need to have data
about the exposure of air pollution.
How do they do the air pollution exposure data?
Basically, they do it in this area.
Let me translate it for you.
They have a monitoring station
set up by the U.S. Department of Environment
in the United States.
They have a station on both sides,
an air pollution station.
Their approach is
for example,
in San Francisco,
I have 10 stations.
I collect the data of these 10 stations
and calculate the average.
I say that everyone living in San Francisco
has the same air pollution exposure.
That is to say,
everyone living in San Francisco
has the same air pollution exposure.
This is the same as what I just said.
For example,
everyone lives in San Francisco.
Some people are sick.
Some people are not sick.
When I do this epidemiological analysis,
I tell my models that
whether they are sick or not,
as long as they live in San Francisco,
their exposure is this high.
At this time,
you can see that
there seems to be a problem.
Another question is
that the U.S. Department of Environment
set up these stations in the United States
to measure air pollution.
However,
many air pollution is not regional.
It does not mean that
a station can represent
the concentration of pollutants in the entire area.
The table I listed here
is the distance from the road.
The unit is meters.
The axis is normalized to roadside.
That is to say,
the concentration of air pollution
is standardized,
which is the concentration of two roads on the roadside.
On the left side of the table,
you can see that
so many pollutants
actually have a very steep gradient.
That is to say,
between 100 and 150 meters,
the concentration has dropped by almost 60%.
That is to say,
the road distance is only a few meters.
There is such a difference in concentration
within 100 meters.
Can you see such a difference
in concentration
in a station
in a certain corner of the city?
You can't see it.
The first one,
you use that kind of station
to represent exposure,
the exposure of human body to pollution.
You may not be able to catch
the hot spot in the urban.
Hello, I have a question.
Please go ahead.
The first one,
the horizontal axis is the distance,
and the vertical axis is the concentration.
In the first few meters,
their gradient looks almost the same.
But you have,
for example, CO, CON,
and NO, NO, and N.
Don't they have a lot of difference in their atomic mass?
If I take one,
I think it's just an expansion.
Shouldn't the gradient be a lot different?
Because there is still a chemical reaction.
CO may not have much reaction.
NO and NOX may have chemical reactions.
It will generate other things.
So it may laugh faster,
laugh slower, not necessarily.
OK, OK.
Maybe it's all gas.
Even particles are different.
Particles may have
some different characteristics.
I want to add that
you have to consider the gradient.
So,
there is a physical problem.
So there is a chemical process.
That's right.
OK.
We just talked about outdoor.
For example,
you use outdoor,
you use the concentration of the side station beam
to represent the pollution source.
First, you can't catch the hot spot.
Like this kind of traffic pollution source.
If someone lives,
if someone's house is close to the road,
you can't catch it.
But if it's far away,
Second,
in fact,
most people
spend more time indoors
than they spend outdoors.
This is a...
It should be a Canadian study.
They looked at
how much time
children spend
indoors or outdoors.
I used the two red boxes.
You can see
one is in winter,
one is in summer.
In indoor time,
67% in winter,
72% in summer.
It means that
most people
spend more time indoors
than they spend outdoors.
At this time,
you use outdoor pollutants
to represent...
The concentration of the beam
to represent human exposure
may also be a problem
because everyone is indoors.
Right?
So that's why
there is this paper.
The first one is
Central Sites.
Central Sites
means
those
U.S. environmental protection agencies.
They can't catch
these local sources.
Local sources can be
traffic
or any
small sources
next to your house.
They may not be able to...
The second one is
using outdoor air pollution
to represent exposure
may not be very representative
because most people are indoors.
In theory,
you should use indoor air pollution
to represent exposure.
The goal of this paper
is to use model-based...
That is to say,
use model-based methods
to predict...
to estimate
the intensity of indoor and outdoor
and use them
to represent human exposure
to see
how different they are.
We can quantify
these potential exposure errors
This is the model I used.
The three yellow boxes
are STOKE, STOK, R-Line,
and LBL AR models.
These three are models.
STOKE stands for
Spacetime Ordinary Crating.
It represents...
It's actually
an internal and external
technology.
That technology
uses...
Its input data
is the data
from these environmental protection agencies.
We use that data
to push it inwards and outwards
to the census block level.
Census block is...
Imagine...
It's a block.
When you're walking,
there's a block on the road.
It could be a block.
So we push those intensities
inwards and outwards
to these block levels.
This represents
a background level.
I use the data
from the Central Monitoring Site
to push it inwards and outwards
to these places.
But it could miss
these local sources,
such as traffic.
R-Line is a line source
dispersion model.
It's used to predict
traffic-related pollution.
It basically
takes all roads
as a line.
It uses
a simple
high-definition
method
to model
traffic pollution.
It represents local source.
We define local source
as traffic pollution.
The last LVL-AR model
is Lawrence Berkeley Laboratory
Air Exchange Rate Model.
It's used to
predict air exchange rate,
which is the air exchange rate
for each household.
For example,
how long
will the air
in your house
be exchanged
with the air outside?
Using these three models
and combining them,
we can calculate
the six blue boxes.
These six boxes
represent
exposure.
We call it
exposure metric.
We use these six boxes
to represent
air exposure.
What are they?
The first one is
outdoor stoke,
which is
outdoor air exposure.
It's called stoke.
It represents background.
Remember,
the source of this thing
is Central Monitoring Site,
which is
the U.S. Department of Environment.
The second one is
outdoor on-road.
It represents
air pollution
caused by
traffic.
It's modeled
by R-Line.
Combining these two things,
outdoor stoke
represents background
because it can't
capture local source.
If you add these two things,
you get total exposure.
We call it
outdoor hybrid,
which is hybrid between
R-Line and stoke.
These three things
represent
outdoor concentration.
Using these three
outdoor concentrations
as a base,
we can combine
the air exchange rate.
The air exchange rate
from the LBL
air exchange rate model
on the left
can be used
to calculate
the corresponding
indoor concentration.
We use outdoor concentration
to calculate
indoor concentration.
We have
three other metrics,
indoor on-road,
indoor stoke,
and indoor hybrid.
There are six metrics in total.
I have a question.
Go ahead.
Do you consider
opening and closing
the window
or just
looking at
the exchange rate
under the air condition?
You'll see it later.
We'll talk about it later.
This slide
is about R-Line.
R-Line is a dispersion model.
You have to use R-Line.
In any air pollution model,
the most important thing
is emission.
This slide talks about
how emission is calculated
and where the data comes from.
This is not
too important
to everyone.
Let's not talk about it.
This is stoke.
It's the same as what I just said.
It is an
internal and external
critting technology.
It uses
the U.S. Environmental Protection
Air Quality System,
or AQS,
which is
the big test stations.
Finally,
these two things are added up.
This is
how to calculate
the corresponding
indoor concentration
of the outdoor concentration.
This is a very simple
mass balance model.
The internal
concentration
and time change
are determined by these terms.
The first is
the outdoor concentration
brought in by the
air exchange
and the
internal concentration
of the outdoor pollution.
This includes
deposition,
which is the rate
of indoor air
being excreted.
Here are some factors.
The penetration factor
is the rate of
incoming air.
The deposition rate
is the rate of
incoming air.
The penetration rate
is 1.
The deposition rate
is 0.5 per hour.
The PEM
is the rate
of incoming air.
The particle
is lower
and the deposition rate
is lower.
This is
the question
from the instructor.
AER model
is to calculate
the window.
The answer is no.
This study
is at the census block level.
I remember
there are
330,000 houses
in this area.
In theory,
if you want to use
the model,
including the window
and air conditioning,
you won't have the data.
Because I can't go to
330,000 houses
one by one
without the data.
So we need the simplest
model.
We don't even consider
where the house is.
What is the air exchange rate?
I won't
explain the model
in detail.
All the parameters,
such as how many years
the house has been built,
how big the floor area is,
you need this model.
In the past,
this model was used
to look at 10 or 15 houses.
But now
I need to look at 330,000 houses.
I can't do that.
So I need to look for the data.
I use the County Property Assessment Record.
I can have
the data
for each house.
This is free
in North Carolina.
It's expensive in California.
I'll give you $100.
I won't explain
the rest of the data.
It's basically public available data.
There's one thing here.
For each census block,
I sample
about 10 houses.
I use the 10 houses
to represent the census block.
I don't just make 330,000 houses
and make them all.
This is my modeling domain.
These three counties
in North Carolina.
Orange County is where UNC is.
I used to live here.
Durham is where
Duke University is.
Don't go there.
This is
a snapshot.
I use
the six exposure metrics
I mentioned earlier.
This is the map.
It's shown here.
A is the Outdoor Stoke.
It uses
the data from the station.
B is Outdoor Hybrid.
It uses R-Line,
the traffic source,
and the background,
the interpolation
data.
The two below
represent
the air quality field
in the simple
indoor mass balance model.
Let's look at the Outdoor Stoke
in the upper left corner.
Most of the concentration
is between
24 and 27.
There's no spatial
variation.
That's it.
I remember
there are only
two or three stations
in this area.
If you have two or three stations
with interpolation data,
you can only achieve
this much.
Let's look at the Outdoor Hybrid.
If you add the local source
data,
you can see
the map
of air pollution.
You can tell
the difference.
Let's look at
C, the Indoor Stoke.
The station
is a transportation source.
There are different types of stations.
Some are in the background,
such as National Park.
Some are near the traffic.
That's right.
We chose the background station
for this study.
We didn't use urban stations
Did you use
the transportation model
of R-Line?
Yes, I did.
I gave the model evaluation
in my last talk.
Thank you.
Let's look at
Indoor Stoke.
A is the input of C.
C and A
are compared.
First,
the color scale is lower.
Second,
there are more spatial variations.
The concentration
of C is between
7 and 14.
Compared to
the Outdoor Stoke,
it's between 24 and 27.
Where do these spatial variations
come from?
They come from
the air exchange rate
of different stations.
What does this mean?
It means that
if you only use the Outdoor Stoke,
which is what they did,
they used that method
to predict
the exposure.
They used that method
to estimate the exposure.
On the right,
you can see
the concentration of local source.
On the bottom,
you can see the map
of the Indoor Stoke.
You can tell the difference
just by looking at the map.
The last one,
D, is the Indoor Stoke.
The input source is B.
B to D.
You can see
the variations are the same.
High concentration
near the road,
low concentration far from the road.
However, the concentration
on the top
is between 90 and 100.
On the bottom,
it's less than that.
When you go to the Indoor Stoke,
the absolute concentration
will decrease.
Here,
I'm looking at...
Hello.
I have a small question
about the front page.
This is basically a 2D model,
right?
You can also
make it vertical.
You can have different heights.
Mine is 2 meters
away from the ground.
2 meters away from the ground.
I'm just curious.
Is the terrain near here flat?
Or is there a hill?
This area is quite flat.
It's a hill to the west.
It's quite flat here.
Here,
I'm using a box plot
to show
the average concentration.
The concentration distribution
by pollutant.
I forgot
what I was going to say.
Let's start with CO.
Let's start with A.
If we only look at...
Let's compare
the black and white boxes.
The black represents
the outdoor concentration.
The white represents
the indoor concentration.
You can see that
CO is about the same.
Look at Stokes.
Outdoor and indoor
have similar distribution.
Why is it similar?
It's because
the penetration factor
and deposition factor
of CO is 1.
The deposition rate
of CO is 0.
That's why the indoor and outdoor
have similar distribution.
Look at Knox.
The penetration factor is 1,
but the deposition rate is 0.5.
You can see that
the indoor concentration is lower
than the outdoor concentration.
It's about half.
In the same situation,
PM and EC
have similar distribution.
The indoor concentration is half
If the outdoor concentration
represents the deposition rate,
the PM will stay in the indoor
for longer than the deposition rate.
After comparing the black and white boxes,
let's compare
Stokes and Unrow.
The two black and white boxes
on the left
and the two black and white boxes
on the middle.
First, look at
CO and Knox.
You can see that
Stokes is much higher than Unrow
in terms of CO.
Knox is closer.
Why?
Because of traffic pollution,
the deposition rate of
gas cars is very high.
I don't have the table here,
but I remember
that in some places,
the deposition rate of gas cars
may be up to 40%,
which means
because gas cars
deposit a lot of pollutants,
the deposition rate of gas cars
is relatively high.
In particular,
the deposition rate of Stokes and Unrow
is actually very low,
because the deposition rate
of primary PM2
is only up to 5%.
However,
the deposition rate of EC
is smaller.
This is the consequence of
the combustion of PM2.5.
Because of the combustion of engines,
it will burn slightly higher.
Here I am looking at
the spatial variation
after talking about density.
I have calculated
a value of
spatial coefficient
of variation.
The higher the value
of spatial coefficient,
the higher the value of
spatial variation.
What we want to see
is whether these things
represent exposure.
Most people
use Stoke's
outdoor concentration
to represent
exposure.
The black box
on the far left
is Stoke's
indoor concentration.
For example,
Stoke's
spatial variation
is very low.
The white box
on the far right
is Stoke's
indoor spatial variation.
Why?
Because I have added
the air exchange rate
spatial variation.
If you replace
the air with air,
you get
spatial variation.
There is a
method to
classify
exposure in
epidemiology.
Sometimes we do not
use absolute density
such as 50mcg per cubic meter
to represent exposure.
Sometimes we just
classify it.
For example,
the low-middle-high
group may only expose
0-2mcg.
The middle group
may expose 2-4mcg.
The high-middle-high
group may expose 4-8mcg.
I do the same thing here.
I divide the six
exposure metrics
into five groups,
0-20%,
20-40,
and 50-60.
The first group
is the indoor
hybrid-based exposure.
The second group
is the
indoor hybrid-based
exposure.
The first group
is the
indoor hybrid-based
exposure.
The second group
is the
indoor hybrid-based
exposure.
Let's compare
the outdoor hybrid-based
and the indoor hybrid-based.
The red line
represents
the
agreement
between
the two groups.
The higher the number,
the more agreeable
the agreement is.
For example,
the 0-20% group
is the hybrid-based
indoor group.
The outdoor hybrid-based
group
represents
50%,
49.22% of the
exposure.
The hybrid-based
group
represents
50% of the
exposure.
The highest group
represents
73%,
which is
the NOx group.
The NOx group
is the
on-road source.
The NOx group
is the
on-road source.
Your analysis unit
is the sensor's track.
No, the sensor's block.
What about your spatial resolution?
Your model could be run hourly.
I mean
you have
a sensor track
with hourly data.
Did your contingency
match the group?
Is the sensor's track
hourly data?
No, I remember
I used annual average.
This should be only annual average.
This is not hourly data.
I used sensor's block,
not sensor's track.
Sensor's track has a lot of blocks.
Let's take a look
at the worst case.
I remember
outdoor stock
is widely used
in popular
epidemiological research.
Compare to
hybrid-based indoor,
the red line
is
25.54%.
It means
you could have
such a big exposure error.
Why?
First, you didn't consider local source.
Second, you didn't consider
indoor concentration.
We talked about this.
The surprising thing
about this analysis unit
is that when you use
indoor on-road concentration,
the performance is good.
Remember that
indoor on-road concentration
is only for on-road.
It doesn't consider background level.
Why?
Because
a large part of NOx
comes from gas engine.
It also controls
spatially.
When you only use this unit,
you can see
the high concentration of on-road
and the low concentration of off-road.
As long as you can capture this,
you can capture
most of
the high concentration.
It also considers
indoor concentration.
It uses air exchange rate
to reflect
the air exchange rate
between each house.
The performance is good.
The highest group can reach 89%.
Here, I'm showing
a similar situation.
I use hybrid.
You can see
the area is blank.
Because this is
the answer.
Other things
cut out the answer.
It becomes a box.
Each box
represents
when you use
a specific exposure metric
to represent exposure,
what is the error?
Let's see
the most widely used
exposure metric,
Stoke Outdoor Concentration.
You can see
the normalized difference
is very high.
The average of NOx
is about 80-90%.
The conclusion is
that
it's complicated.
There are many
different analysis and pollution.
The pollution
and traffic
are different.
Bear with me.
Basically,
CO and PN2.5
traffic
is lower.
14% and 6%.
NOx and ECO
are higher.
40% and 44%.
When you use
the indoor infiltration model,
the indoor concentration
is about 60% of
the outdoor concentration.
It will be reduced by 40%.
When you use the outdoor concentration
to represent the exposure,
it's not right.
The concentration is not that high.
The exposure is not that high.
Okay.
It's too complicated.
This is my
acknowledgment.
I used to work at UNC.
The funding source is
EPA's contract.
EPA provides emissions
and meteorological data.
It's not on the slide.
This is a reference.
That's it.
Thank you.
Do you have
any questions?
I don't think so.
Yay!
On Saturday afternoon,
stay healthy.
Don't be so academic.
This is interesting.
You can see it with R-Line.
For example,
why is there a basketball court?
When I started
doing this,
especially after I moved here,
the Golden Gate Bridge
next to San Francisco
is a place
for jogging and cycling.
There are six lanes.
There are three lanes
on each side.
Normally, cars drive very slowly.
In terms of emissions,
the slower the car drives,
the higher the emissions.
People jogging and cycling
are enjoying
the air pollution.
My idea is
if you move
the basketball court
to the middle,
you can save
a lot of energy.
That's it.
Is there a way
to do it in Taiwan?
I have a question.
Please go ahead.
The question is
if you look at
the road emission data,
you won't stand
next to the road
and check
if every car
is a Tesla
or a diesel car.
However,
there is a free parameter.
If all the cars
are Tesla,
half Tesla, half pickup,
and all are big trucks,
how much improvement
can be made?
Is there a way
to justify
how much
public sector resources
are needed
to change the air quality
in a static way?
That's a very important point.
It's called fleet distribution.
When we talk about
traffic pollution,
a very important parameter
is fleet distribution.
Is there a difference
between fleet distribution
and model distribution?
The difference is
that we use
MOOVS,
Motor Vehicle Emission Simulator.
In terms of models,
we use MOOVS.
you can tell MOOVS
that if half of
the fleet distribution
is electric vehicles
and half is diesel cars,
you can do it
in terms of models.
But if you want
to block a street
and make the entire fleet
50% Tesla,
it's a bit difficult.
You made a very good point.
I don't remember
having seen
a similar study
in fleet distribution.
Have you seen a similar study,
coach?
He's probably taking care of the kids.
I don't remember
having seen a similar study
where we changed the fleet distribution
and changed it to electric vehicles.
I haven't seen such a study.
Thank you.
I have a question.
I'm a bit curious.
When I first saw this topic,
I thought it was very interesting.
Why did you choose that place?
I looked it up on the Internet.
North Carolina
seems to have more
air pollution.
This area is
the NC Piedmont region.
There are four areas in North Carolina.
Coastline,
Piedmont, Mountain,
and I forgot the other one.
Piedmont is like a triangle.
This area is an RTP area,
so the air pollution
is a bit more severe.
Another reason
why I chose these three counties
is because we had a project
with the EPA.
They wanted to use
the metrics I just mentioned
to do their epidemiological research.
They did a study
on heart disease
and wanted to use
air pollution data.
We had a contract
with the EPA
to do this research.
When I talked to them last time,
they said they were already
writing a paper.
I don't know where it went.
So the research you did
in this area
is quite valuable, right?
Because the EPA
is located there.
The EPA's R&D office
A lot of research
is done there.
Yesterday,
a few people from UNC
came to the lab.
I asked them,
I heard the air pollution
in UNC is quite severe.
They were surprised.
I said, really?
The air there is much better than California.
I said it's severe
compared to
North Carolina.
Even in Piedmont,
although it's a severe area,
it's still very low.
Okay.
North Carolina is a very clean area.
The population of North Carolina
is only 9 million,
which is four times the population of Taiwan.
In South California,
the population of
one county is 20 million.
Yes.
So I believe
air pollution is more severe.
Yes.
In California,
there are a lot of
near-road studies
and children's health studies.
A lot of those papers
are done by our company's
senior scientists.
They do a lot of research
in LA.
The first project
I joined our company on
was to use R-Line
to predict the air flow
of children
because of air pollution.
The system
is also
targeted at
the entire South Coast
area.
The entire South Coast area.
That area is
well-known
for air pollution.
Actually,
in Joe's
presentation,
I think
this is
a newspaper
from the 1970s.
This is
the Los Angeles Times.
It's an LA newspaper
from that time.
At that time,
they talked about
the problem of
bad oxygen.
I remember
they said
bad oxygen can reach
70 ppb.
That's high.
It can reach 700 ppb
at that time.
Some of our senior scientists
lived in LA when they were young
and they said
standing outside
can make you cry.
That's an older magnitude difference.
It's very exaggerated.
LA is a basin.
It's an air basin.
The air quality
is relatively stable.
Air pollution can't escape.
Thank you for your answer.
I want to ask
if there are any other questions.
If not,
let me promote Taira.
Got it?
I want to
simply say
that
Do you have a question?
No.
OK.
You know what I'm doing.
Let me...
Right.
Let me talk about it.
Basically,
many epidemiologists
and epidemiologists
make
underestimated responses.
The main reason is
from an economic point of view,
when you know
the air quality is bad,
you optimize your behavior.
So,
acute hospital admission
or all the endpoints
are the results
after people optimize their behavior.
So,
for example, ozone,
CO,
you may not see anything
in low concentration.
But in fact,
it's gone.
So,
from an economic
and epidemiological
point of view,
it's a big difference.
When the air quality is bad,
you can choose
a different transportation mode.
For example,
in Taiwan,
you ride a scooter,
but if the air quality is bad,
you ride a bus.
So,
it has nothing to do
with today's topic.
Interesting.
So, what's your name?
Yi.
Yi Xu.
I'd like to ask
if you work on energy policy.
Yes, I do.
I have an article
about Taipei Metro
and air pollution.
In the U.S.,
for example,
when the Energy Bureau
wants to change
their policy,
do they refer to
researchers or companies?
Or do they take an average?
No,
policy set up is basically
a political negotiation process.
For example,
in California,
renewable energy
will be 50% in 2030.
So,
the government's policy
will be like this.
The next step is
to hand it over to California
Air Resources Board
or other government agencies
to implement.
So,
under my overall policy
target,
how do I use
economic instruments?
For example,
I can force companies
to use renewable energy.
So,
our target is to
come up with a way
to use market instruments.
For example,
I can close subsidy
renewable energy
from the fossil fuel
or dirty energy.
In this way,
those firms
will endogenous
and use market
to achieve the result.
I think policy is important
for researchers.
For example,
I'm doing CO2 reduction here.
So,
our institute's funding source
is based on the government's policy.
For example,
if Trump doesn't support
energy,
we will be worried.
Will you be fired?
I don't think so.
But others are worried
about our institute.
Our institute is not only in Caltech,
but also in Stanford and Berkeley.
So,
everyone is worried about it.
But now,
it seems to be guaranteed
to be implemented in 2020.
So,
except Trump,
everyone else is supportive.
I think it's impossible in California.
Our institute is a pioneer
in environmental policy.
So,
even if the government's funding
is not enough,
we have a lot of state funding.
Thank you for your comment.
I think it's interesting.
I'll send you an email later.
I think we can work together.
Let me interrupt.
As I mentioned,
I'm a policy designer.
If I'm not mistaken,
next week's talk
is about economics.
The speaker will talk about
mechanical design.
It's not specific
about energy
or energy policy design.
But it's about
mechanical design itself
from an economic perspective.
I just realized it's related to
what you just discussed.
Yixu,
we can keep in touch.
You should have it.
I'm in control of everything.
Okay.
I'm just cyber-stalking you
right now.
Please.
I already have Zhang Xi.
I can stalk others.
Keep tracking.
Okay.
I don't know
if Jiao Yan has joined
Tyra's members.
If you're interested in joining Tyra...
She gave a talk last year.
Okay.
Yixu,
are you in Tyra?
You're a passerby.
I'm a passerby.
You can join us next time.
Okay.
I'll send you the membership form
right away.
If you're interested,
you're welcome to join Tyra.
There's a lot of people.
Okay.
The biggest problem is
you can't find students
even if you want to.
What kind of students?
PhD students.
You mean me?
I mean me.
I can't find students
if I want to.
Not necessarily.
We'll have students
after the promotion.
We'll have students after the promotion.
Thank you.