I am today's host, I am Hong Shaoming, I am now working in California as a postdoctoral researcher.
Without further ado, let's introduce today's speaker, Dr. Wei Qunshu.
Dr. Qunshu graduated from the College of Electrical Engineering, and stayed in California to study electrical engineering.
After graduating, he went to UCSD to study biotechnology, and his professor is Professor Zong Ziping.
He is mainly interested in using the perspective of engineering to use brain-to-brain meetings to study human behavior.
Over the past few years, he has published nearly 10 conference papers and two journal papers.
Without further ado, let's listen to his presentation.
The title is Towards Real-World Awareness Estimation Using Brain-Computer Interface.
Let's welcome him.
Thank you Shaoming for the introduction.
Today, I will introduce how we measure brain activity and monitor our alertness using a brain-computer interface.
If you have any questions during the presentation, please feel free to interrupt.
We can easily have a discussion.
First, I will briefly introduce the brain.
Our brain is a tube of about 3 pounds, about 1,000 grams.
The outermost part of the brain has many folds.
These folds are composed of many neurons in the brain.
There are about 8.6 billion neurons.
We know that the brain has very strong computing power.
However, compared to our most powerful computers, its performance is very good.
In terms of energy consumption, it is 100,000 times more efficient than a normal CPU.
Therefore, the brain can only operate at 12 to 25 watts.
This wattage is equivalent to the wattage of a light bulb.
So you can imagine that in some comics, when the character thinks of a point, he will draw a light bulb.
It's actually pretty close.
Because the brain's power consumption is the power of a light bulb.
The structure of the neural network is composed of cells.
There are many vectors.
The vector part collects information from other neural networks around it.
After the information is compiled into the neural network, it will decide whether to power up.
If you want to power up, you can use the axis.
Then you can power up to other neural networks.
In this way, complex networks can be used to control the whole person.
Here is a brain signal that I use more often.
It's called a brain wave.
It's EEG.
Many people have been exposed to EEG.
Especially when a newborn is born, we often do a brain test to see if his vision or hearing is normal.
How does EEG occur?
There are many neural networks in our brain.
Especially the skin.
Many neural networks are arranged.
There are some rules in the structure.
The arrangement of the rules allows the neural network to have an additional effect when it is powering up.
The change in the electrical field can be so great that you can feel the change in the electrical field outside the scalp.
The change in the electrical field becomes our brain wave signal after some processing.
If you have any questions, please feel free to interrupt me.
Our brain wave signal is...
I have a question.
There is a line below.
BlueJeans meeting is sharing your screen with bluejeans.com.
You have to press the hide button.
Oh, okay.
Or you can block it a little bit.
I'm sorry.
You can continue.
Thank you.
Okay.
Let's continue.
This is the brain wave signal.
It is a real-time signal.
You can see that it is like a time series.
It is a time series.
In order to measure the whole brain, we will try to arrange electrical fields outside the scalp.
So we will have a lot of brain waves on both sides at the same time.
We will analyze the energy of brain waves in terms of frequency.
The frequency depends on whether the signal is fast or slow.
The high frequency is the fast part.
The low frequency is the slow part.
So we will divide delta.
It is a low frequency activity of less than 3.5 Hz.
It is a very slow vibration.
If you go higher, it will be divided into theta wave, alpha wave, or beta wave.
The higher the frequency, the faster the vibration.
Our brain can be divided into different bands.
By observing the energy of the band, we can get a lot of information.
Let me introduce the location of the channel of the brain.
It has a standard way of dividing.
The name of the channel is divided into points.
Frontal is the channel at the beginning of F.
Central is the channel at the beginning of C.
Central parietal is the channel at the beginning of O.
Occipital is the channel at the beginning of O.
We can do this frequency analysis for each channel.
We can combine the change of time with the change of frequency.
We can see the energy of different bands over time.
This can tell us a lot of information about the state of this person.
We can design experiments to see if the brain changes.
We can find some characteristics in different states.
Reflect the brain in different states.
The brain interface is where we read the signals of the brain.
Then we go through some signal processing, including frequency analysis.
Or you can use a lot of other different signal processing methods to get different characteristics.
Then we use the processed signals to make it recognizable.
Then we can convert it into some commands to control.
For example, a mechanical arm or a wheel or a mouse cursor.
Or to input text or some messages.
We call this the brain computer interface.
In short, it's BCI.
What can BCI do?
As I just said, it can convert into commands.
So when we play video games, we can use it to control the movement of your character.
Of course, including the wheel and the mechanical arm.
Of course, it can also be used to monitor a person's cognitive state.
Including whether you want to sleep.
This extends to my main area of expertise.
Monitoring the level of awareness.
The level of awareness is related to drowsy driving.
A lot of people fall asleep while driving.
This news happened on July 18th.
It was only recently that a drowsy driving incident occurred.
So it's not a big deal.
It's not a big deal.
elections
keywords
So he can't hear the headphones, can he?
I didn't hear it.
Oh, no.
Let's see.
I can't.
Can you play it on your computer?
Okay.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
I can hear you.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
Max.
And then after 11 hours a day, we have to shut down
and have 10 hours of sleep.
Truck drivers are also required to take a 30-minute break
during their first 8 hours of driving.
All of this needs to be recorded
in logs like these,
which are now mostly computerized.
We now have to carry electronic recording devices
on our vehicles.
Rio says his students learn to make driving plans
to avoid getting fatigued,
and they're encouraged to stop to power nap
or just stretch their legs.
It gives you more stamina.
You're more alert, because when you're not alert,
you know, you can't make good decisions.
And that's what truckers like Rudy live by.
I start closing, you've got to pull over
and take a nap.
GoMana, eight news now.
The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration
says drowsy driving
causes up to 1.2 million crashes
every year in this country,
and it kills between 5,000 and 8,000 people.
That's nearly twice as many
as distracted driving.
Okay.
So,
this is a recent
drowsy driving incident.
As you saw in the video,
a truck hit
a construction vehicle
and
caused
two deaths and three injuries.
Drowsy driving can cause
up to 1.2 million
crashes every year,
and it kills
between 5,000 and 8,000 people.
So if we can avoid
drowsy driving,
if we can effectively monitor
drowsy driving
and manage it,
maybe we can avoid
the death and injury
caused by this.
And then,
in the news,
it was mentioned that
if you find your eyes
blind,
you should stop driving.
But I also discussed with
Shaoming last time
whether to use
eye or blink
to do
this alertness monitoring.
But there is a question
that is,
is there a way to
catch it
before it closes
its eyes
and put it in the car?
This part may want to
use brainwaves to
break through this problem.
If we use
the brain interface to do
this alertness monitoring,
we will first
measure its brainwaves
from the driver.
After we get this EEG signal,
after some processing,
we use machine learning
to build a model
that can turn the EEG
data into
alertness.
After we know its alertness,
we can try to
give it some feedback.
For example, we can wake it up,
or we can
let the car
stop driving
and stop by the road,
or force it to rest.
There are some ways to intervene.
My research is
mainly about
how we deal with this signal,
how we build a
machine learning model,
and how we can
monitor the alertness
very well.
Then we can
accurately determine
whether to make some interference.
I have a question.
I want to
clarify a little bit.
Do you mean
that your research is
a state of
mental relaxation
or a state of real sleep?
It's a state of
waking up
to almost falling asleep
before you really
fall asleep.
I didn't study
the state of the brain
after falling asleep,
because I want to catch
it before I fall asleep.
In fact,
I have
driving experience,
and I know
that my eyes were open at that time,
but the image
was already
blurred and black,
and I was not looking at the road.
I was a little out of my mind,
and then I suddenly woke up,
and I felt a little
shaky.
So you have to catch
the time point
before you fall asleep.
It depends on
when you can't support
the alertness.
I have another question.
You are now
identifying a signal,
and you think
this signal is
the state you are talking about.
Do you have a contrast group?
For example, you track his eyes,
and then I define
the behavior of the eyes,
which is to fall asleep.
Then I look for
a corresponding brain wave,
or I ask the subject to write
that I feel like I'm about to fall asleep.
What is your calibration?
This question is very good.
How do we define
the so-called alertness?
I'm going to talk about it next.
Because we think
alertness is related to your reaction time.
So we use
reaction time to
give us an objective
measurement method.
Just like you said,
using the eyes or
the way the subject responds.
The part of the eyes
is that the activity of the eyes
is also a physiological signal.
So whether he can react directly
to this behavior
is another experiment.
His role and brain wave
are the same.
It just depends on which physiological signal
makes it easier for us
to be more accurate
to determine
whether it is
alert or not.
Subject report
is an objective determination.
The subjective determination
will have some
deviation.
That is, the word
reported by the subject
cannot express
the state he just experienced
very objectively.
Many researchers
think that the more objective
determination method is to look at
his reaction time.
Next,
I will talk about how we
measure brain waves and
his reaction time.
Finally, I will talk about
how to define
alertness.
Does this answer your question?
Yes, thank you.
Thank you.
I will talk about
the experiment we did
and how to get the data we want.
We put the subject
in a simulated
driving car.
The car has a
circular projection screen.
The car is
on a dynamic platform,
so driving in it
is to simulate
the real driving situation as much as possible.
This is a device
in the brain center
of the University of Transportation
.
In this experiment,
we are doing
road maintenance
tasks.
Road maintenance
means that the subject
must maintain the car
on the road.
We will
automatically make the car
lean, forcing
the subject to
adjust the direction of
his car from time to time.
The scene is
on a straight
highway,
but the car
will tilt to the left
or to the right.
The car will tilt once every 6-10 seconds.
The subject
will feel that the car is
tilted,
move the steering wheel
to guide the car.
We will see
when the car
moves the steering wheel
after it is tilted.
This is the reaction time.
Every 6-10 seconds,
we can measure the reaction time.
In the end, we hope
to predict the
reaction time
after the
brain wave
before the tilt.
This is the
role of prediction.
Next, I will talk about
how to deal with
the prediction of
the alertness.
Every 6-10 seconds,
we will have a response time
sample.
On the y-axis,
I draw the reaction time.
I go to log.
On the horizontal axis,
I draw the time.
The unit is divided.
This is the length
of the whole experiment.
The length of the experiment
is not certain.
This is shorter,
it is only 45 minutes.
Most experiments
take more than an hour.
About an hour and a half.
Sometimes we will
ask the same subject to
come back and do it.
Let me see.
We finally collected more than 30 subjects.
There are
5, 6, 10
driving
experiment data.
Let's talk about
each point.
It's the RT we just measured.
10 to the power of 0 is about 1 second.
When he wakes up,
he can get the car back
to normal.
After a while,
his condition is not good.
After his alertness began to decline,
we will see some longer
response time.
In fact, the reaction is that
his alertness becomes worse.
We have to deal with
this RT data.
Because RT is
not a range.
Only one side has a range.
The other side has no range.
Let's do a regularization first.
Change it to a value of 0 to 1.
The way to regularize it
is to use its
cumulative distribution function.
Map it
to a
range value.
Then
let's do a
smoothing here.
For smoothing, I use a 90-second
moving window
to make the
data look more dynamic.
We turn it
into a smoother value.
This part is because
RT only samples
once every 6 to 10 seconds.
If you
use too high quality
to look at this data,
it is more meaningless.
If we use a smoothing,
we can get rid of
some of the
inaccuracies of this data itself.
So we use
this
alertness deficit index
which is an index
that lacks attention.
We use it as
a ground truth
in our behavior.
Does anyone have any questions?
Let's assume that
RT directly reflects
the level of alertness.
Yes.
RT becomes alertness
should be one of the factors.
Yes.
So it depends on the
design of the experiment.
In addition, let's assume that
in our experiment design,
the part that affects RT
is only drowsiness.
We try to
eliminate other factors
that may affect RT.
Because
similar paradigms
in the experiment
are also used
to study
mind-wandering.
Mind-wandering and
alertness are related
but not exactly the same.
For example, your subject
starts to think about other things
and his RT becomes worse.
In your definition,
it is a lack of alertness.
Yes.
It is acceptable.
So our alertness
is based on
the alertness defined by RT.
Yes.
Because the subject does not react
like you said,
he may be thinking about other things.
Of course,
the instruction of our experiment
is to teach them to focus.
Yes.
What we can do is
only up to here.
It may affect your
EEG data later.
Imagine that there are three reasons
why his RT becomes worse.
You will catch three patterns.
The three patterns
may be different.
For example, when you train the data,
the accuracy will be lower.
Because your data is not high enough.
Sometimes it is because of A,
sometimes because of B,
sometimes because of C.
It is impossible to be completely correct.
Just like what you said,
mind-wandering,
we can't control it.
However,
when RT becomes longer,
it becomes quite long.
For example, 5 seconds.
If he is thinking about other things
for 5 seconds
without following our instructions
to guide him,
I don't know what to do.
OK.
What you see
is the real
death.
Some trials,
like what you said,
may be due to other factors
or some miscommunication.
This part
cannot be ruled out.
OK.
If your task
can separate
different things that affect RT,
your model
will be cleaner.
This is an ideal situation.
Of course,
we can't cover
so many different factors at the same time.
Yes.
So,
in terms of brain science,
we often have this problem.
We can't control what the subject is thinking.
That's right.
It's a bit awkward.
I have a different idea
about brain science.
OK.
If you want to
throw data to machine learning,
if there are three reasons,
whether he wants to sleep
or something else,
your algorithm
may be persuaded
to identify
three different reasons.
But for whatever reason,
it will
indicate that
you are lying.
Isn't that right?
It's possible.
So, in the end,
his algorithm
can avoid
the longer RT time
for whatever reason.
I think we should
go back to the original question.
What do you want to detect?
For example,
if you want to promote a policy,
you want to avoid
drowsy driving.
This whole thing is set up
for drowsy driving.
But later I found that
the other important factor
that affects their driving
is mind-wandering.
Even if you can detect
mind-wandering at the same time,
when you make a policy,
these two are completely different.
How do you avoid A and avoid B?
In the end,
from the point of view of brain science,
what happened during that time?
That's the reason
I asked this question.
I think it's possible.
When you make a machine learning,
it can identify all patterns
as a lack of awareness.
This is also possible.
Like what
Yen-Yung mentioned,
if I use machine learning,
it will learn
the relationship between data.
Then you get
an overall
influence
of R&D.
I don't know what it is.
In addition,
we just
discussed that
different
cognitive
phenomena can be
disassembled.
It can be seen independently.
Or there are some interactions
between them.
If
we want to
use our data
to disassemble different
cognitive states
on this RT,
in fact,
there is no way to
just use one experiment.
It may be necessary to
do different experiments
to estimate
what will happen.
In our case,
we try to say
that there is only one
influence.
But we can't guarantee.
If we say that 90% of
our trial
is based on
our imagination,
because we
let it do it
after lunch.
We asked it to
drive the highway.
We hope to
let it sleep
in this way.
At least
in this process,
it is closer to
what we want it to
trigger.
Is that OK?
My question
has been answered.
OK.
I will talk about
this later.
This is very troublesome.
Many cognitive states
do not have a good
objective definition.
In the future,
whether it is a brain interface
or cognitive science,
this is a big problem.
Let me
continue my research.
OK.
As I said,
our brain wave can be
divided into different
characteristics.
Here I list
some of my
processing processes.
EEG will
do a
re-referencing
for different channels.
Here we
take
the EEG of
all channels to
reduce their overall average.
This can remove some
impurities.
Then we do
bandpass filtering.
The EEG
is limited to
50 Hz or less.
Some low frequency
waves may
come from
moving around
the device itself.
We will use
1 to 50 Hz
or more
to filter the EEG
and get
something that
really looks like EEG.
But there are still a lot of artifacts.
Downsampling
reduces our computing time.
Then we do
subbandpass filtering.
We divide the EEG
into different brainwaves.
Here are some examples.
Fast and slow.
They are from delta,
zeta, alpha to beta.
Then we take
their energy
and do a smoothing.
We use
90-second
moving window
to smooth
the EEG
and get our data.
Now we have
the brainwave energy
and the alertness index.
Now let's
compare the two.
The y-axis
represents
the EEG energy.
The x-axis
represents the alertness
index.
The x-axis
is the slow
reaction time.
The y-axis
represents the EEG energy.
Here are
delta, zeta, alpha, beta.
I have
several channels
with frontal
and central.
Z is the
midline.
The middle of the front,
the middle of the middle,
the middle of the parietal,
and the middle
of the parietal.
In these positions,
the EEG energy changes
in different channels
are related to
alertness.
Delta is a positive
channel. 0.77
is a positive channel.
Alpha is a
negative channel,
negative 0.28.
When
alertness decreases,
the channel
will decrease.
This part
has a variability.
Everyone
does it every time.
The relative situation
will be different.
Here I use
a distribution map
with relative
details to see
the relationship
between the brain wave
and the alertness.
The red is the positive channel,
the blue is the negative channel.
Most of the delta
is positive,
and the beta
is negative.
This graph
shows the results
of the brain wave and alertness
in this experiment.
This graph
will change
with time.
This part is to be discussed first.
If you take the brain wave
to make a frequency map,
does it have 4 peaks
in this alpha,
beta,
theta,
and delta?
Or is it a smooth
continuous frequency map?
If you
look at the frequency,
it will have
1 over f
distribution.
looks like a
decline
curve.
The brain wave
has a higher
low frequency energy
and a lower high frequency energy.
So cutting the alpha, beta,
theta, delta band
is basically just
cutting a continuous frequency map
into 4 pieces.
Yes, but sometimes
there will be some peaks.
Although it is 1 over f,
the overall distribution is 1 over f.
We call it
pain noise,
one of the noise.
But sometimes
the overall distribution
will have some small peaks.
Because sometimes the brain
can have a strong alertness
such as alpha.
Alpha is when you close your eyes
and especially
the back part
will start to vibrate
about 10 Hz.
At that time,
there is a small peak
on the curve of
1 over f.
It looks a bit like this.
What I'm thinking is
if your energy spectrum
does not have a peak,
if you cut it into 4 pieces
and then divide it into
these 4 groups of data
to do machine learning,
I don't think it will enhance
the effect of machine learning.
Because it may be
on the edge of the band
that you cut.
But if you have a peak
in alpha today,
you separate alpha
and other
data to do
machine learning training,
I think it will have a more obvious effect.
That's why I asked this question.
I understand what you mean.
So if you use
some really meaningful band
to do
machine learning,
the effect will be
better.
Yes, I agree with you.
You must put a lot of
impurities into it.
But because
the problem I'm going to solve later is
how do I say it?
I can't give up on each one.
Because each one has
mutational problems,
so each one sometimes
becomes the best feature
that appears on top.
So
there's no way
to narrow it down
to a better feature.
I have to
use so many features.
That's the situation.
OK, thank you.
OK.
I'm going to talk about
machine learning.
It's a regression problem.
Because I want to
predict
the change of
the alertness
index.
It's a continuous value.
The output of the model
must be a continuous value.
It must be close to this value.
I just did some
processing.
It's the same here.
Then I put the energy of the brain wave
and the reaction time
recorded by our experiment
in the
processed alertness
index into the model.
Then I train it.
Then I get a
regression model.
It can turn the brain wave
into the alertness index we estimated.
But there's a problem.
I've been talking about it.
Human variability.
We will
divide it into
inter-subject or intra-subject.
Inter-subject and subject
have some variability.
I want to invite you
to do an activity.
The dancer you see now
is teleporting.
Just make a sound.
I can see both sides.
So you can see this
and that.
I can see what I want to see.
I've seen this picture so many times in my life.
But I can only see one side.
I don't know why.
I really want to see the other side.
Some people see the retrograde
and some people see the subject.
Some people want to see
what they want to see.
I also
want to see the other side.
Then I go to see it.
It will follow my
direction.
This part is
the same stimulus to
different people.
Our brain
will react differently.
This is just an example.
It tells you that
everyone's brain is different.
Our brain
will react differently
to the same stimulus
at different times.
The brain wave change
related to the brain wave
is actually the same.
Different people are different.
A person does the experiment
on a different day.
Here I put my data.
I gave an example.
I just said
to use the distribution of correlation
as a relationship
between the brain wave and the alertness
of a certain experiment.
Here I have a S5-1,
which is the fifth subject.
Do the driving experiment.
The correlation we get is like this.
There are three reds here.
From Theta to Alpha
to Beta
are all positive.
But this is
the second time he did it.
The second time he did it.
We see that it's completely different.
Delta is positive.
The other three are negative.
Even Alpha is negative.
If we use his first experiment
to train our model,
we will find that
the effect will be very poor
the second time.
But we did a lot of experiments.
We recorded a lot of people.
For example, the 41st subject
when he did it for the fifth time,
he had this pattern.
It's very similar to subject 5.
So different people
have similar reactions
on the brain wave we want to look at.
If so,
I can take the data
of subject 41
for the fifth time
to train a model.
If we use it for the second time
of subject 5,
the effect will be very good.
Of course, this is what we can do
after the test.
This session is very similar to this session.
But we can't
When subject 5
comes, we have a way
to know that we want to use
the model of subject 41 to give it.
That is a
engineering challenge
or a scientific challenge.
How do we do this?
I want to ask a question.
Sorry.
The time they do the experiment
is probably fixed.
Like you said, after lunch.
The time
is probably fixed.
Yes.
This looks
a bit like
the problem I just mentioned.
There may be different factors.
The brain activity
between different sessions
may be different.
Yes.
For example,
if you want to measure drowsiness,
your second session of subject 5
is similar.
Yes.
In other words,
if you can have another task
or a subjective report
to verify
what happened in each session,
you may be able to
go back and say that
this brain wave is more like
A or B or C.
Yes, this is what I want to do.
Is there anything else
we can measure
faster?
Then we can know
that this should be
similar to the previous session.
Then we can use it.
Next,
I will develop this.
OK.
The actual operation may be more complicated than this.
In other words,
my brain activity of drowsiness
is similar to
your brain activity of mind wandering.
There is a relationship between
brain state and brain state.
It may be like this.
Everyone may have a different brain state.
Of course,
I have a brain state
corresponding to
the brain activity of mind.
But it doesn't mean
that everyone's brain state
is similar.
I don't know.
That may be the actual difficulty.
It feels like it can be done.
Of course,
it's good.
But we can't
analyze other factors
in this experiment.
It's a pity.
Next,
I will deal with
the relationship
in a data-driven way.
OK. Thank you.
I have a question.
This page.
I want to ask
about the black dots
on the image.
The black dots are the
corresponding probes
of the hat.
But the hat is actually
a spatial distribution of the sphere.
It's not a flat 2D circle.
Yes.
How did you
project the image
from the spatial distribution of the sphere
to the image you drew now?
Or is it just a visual image?
Do you preserve
the distance between each dot?
Is it a specific
projection like a map?
Or do you arrange it one by one?
This value
is only used in visualization.
So if the relationship is distorted,
it won't affect much.
Because I...
You only take
exactly the position above.
OK.
Like this is 30 channels.
So I only have those 30
channels of data.
And what happens in the middle?
That's all visualizations.
They are inserted
and projected.
I want to tell you about this.
What I was thinking is
if you process the data like this
and then throw it away,
it sounds like you will re-weight
the effect of each data.
And it may smear
what's physically happening in your brain.
I don't know what you mean.
OK.
This is purely visualization.
OK. Thank you.
Like you said, some people
use mapping as data.
And I don't like it.
Because it's like a problem.
So we just talked about
how to find
a model that is similar to
the new people in the database.
What's the advantage of this?
We call it Subject Transfer.
It transfers the model
from one person to another.
The advantage is that
we used to say
we try to collect
each person's data,
brainwaves and behaviors.
We try to collect more data
to build a model.
We believe that it will have a good performance
for the same person.
We call it Self-Decoding.
Because of some variability,
it often fails.
So we want to use
Subject Transfer.
We use a small amount of data
as an indicator,
as a brain signature.
Then we can
find a suitable model
from our database
and use it.
Then we can start
to detect
its alertness level.
What should we use
for this
relatively small amount of data?
What I'm talking about
is
Baseline Activity.
Baseline Activity
is a standard state.
can also be called
Task Activity
or Task Free Activity.
It means that
this subject is not doing anything
and it has nothing to do with your task.
Then the brain activity at that time.
In the past, there were many studies
to see
when the brain was not doing anything,
the brain's
existing activities
and the specific activities
after you really gave it a task.
Is there any connection?
On the brain wave,
we found that
from RESTing data,
you use ICA
to look at
some
decomposed
component activity.
Then you can use that
to help it in the action
imagination of this specific task.
You can find it
from RESTing data
to find out the pattern
of its action imagination.
When a person is not doing
action imagination,
his data can tell you
what his pattern looks like
when he is doing action imagination.
In addition, there is RESTing data
to predict
the performance of the brain interface.
Because not everyone
can master
how to use the brain interface.
RESTing data
can tell you
if this person is suitable for using the brain interface.
Another study
is from RESTing.
This is MRI data,
fMRI data.
It predicts
from RESTing fMRI
that under a specific
cognitive task,
the activation mapping is like this.
There is a lot of evidence
that your RESTing
data and your
task data
are related.
Back to
how we choose the right model,
I thought
if we use a small piece of RESTing data,
we can find the right model
for the new person.
Here I think
I have a lot of models
from the past
experiments.
I have built a lot of models.
The new person
is called Target Subject.
Then we record a baseline.
This is recorded
in the alert situation.
That is to say,
this person
in our
simulation driving
simulation car
is not moving,
he is not turning the steering wheel,
he is not doing anything,
the car is moving forward,
he doesn't have to do anything,
the data during that time,
we treat it as a brain signature.
We use this to estimate
who is more like
the new person
and the model in the original database.
We do a sequence
for this model,
and then do a fusion,
which is to combine those models
and outputs together.
Finally, we do a recalibration,
because sometimes
there are some offsets.
Finally,
we can give this subject
to estimate his alertness.
Any questions?
Can you explain
the pairing process again?
OK.
How do you find
a person
to pair with
a car make a session?
OK.
I have
a backup slide here.
For the new person,
I will have his baseline data.
It is
his energy in different
bands and in different locations.
We use this to compare
the data of all other people
in my database.
Then I estimate his similarity.
I use this similarity
to assume that
if he is
in the baseline state,
the pattern of these two people is similar,
then I believe
their EEG alertness
model will be very similar.
That's how I do it.
OK.
In other words,
you just showed us
a session.
According to this model,
their default baseline
activity should be very similar.
Yes.
OK.
Thank you.
I have a post-trial analysis here.
In other words,
we use baseline activity
to predict the similarity.
Is it really their similarity?
The real similarity here
is that I put
a model of a person
and a session
to use the data of another person.
Then look at their
performance afterwards.
There is a real similarity
offline.
I also use baseline activity
to estimate their
subject-subject similarity.
Then I predict
the performance
I can get.
I found that these two things
are quite similar.
You can see a correspondence here.
It's actually the same as what I predicted.
There is an accuracy here.
If I use this,
I can do what I just did.
It means that at least
part of my assumption is correct.
Because of this,
we can look at
our prediction
results.
The black line here
is the change of time
in the entire experiment.
It's a black line.
The result we predict
is to get close to this black line.
We can see that
the relevant details of different
curves can express
how accurate we predicted.
The blue part here
is the traditional way.
Each subject uses
the data he has recorded
to train a model
to look at his prediction results.
The red line is
the method I just mentioned.
We look at a small section
of baseline activity.
We use other people's models
to predict his alertness.
You can see that
on this example,
red is better than black.
This is their curve.
They are related to
the actual ground truth here.
On this example,
the method
of subject transfer
is slightly better.
I have a small question.
This concept
is like a donation, right?
If you can
find a group of people
whose genotype
or model
is similar to yours,
can you use this method
to match
their data?
Yes.
OK.
In other words,
you can only do
a few hours.
If you use this method,
you can use
an infinite amount of data.
If you recruit a lot of people,
a lot of people can match.
The data pool will keep increasing.
That's right.
Thank you.
I have a question.
The picture in the front page
is the actual.
No, the next page.
Yes, the next page.
This is
a different way
to do it.
Now you draw a line.
But if
you divide your data
a little bit,
it's a bit like
repeating the same thing
500 or 1000 times.
Your prediction
will be a little bit different every time.
Then you can put your
red line into a red band.
Do you know what I mean?
There is an error.
Yes, the range of the band
is basically
the range of uncertainty
of your model.
OK.
So every time you run,
it will be a little different.
Did you hear that?
So every time you run,
it will be a little different.
Yes, so I'm curious.
Except for the line you show now,
the uncertainty
behind each line
may not be the same.
For example,
predictability is particularly good
in this specific case.
It may actually be fluctuate up.
But the band is actually very wide.
So it may not be particularly good.
Oh.
This is a good question.
Because usually
if you plot this prediction,
you will plot 95% confidence interval.
He is actually talking about this thing.
You should plot this thing out.
OK, got it.
Yes.
But I see that it's a lot.
I probably feel that
there should be nothing to argue about.
It should be effective.
But if it's very close,
I'll be more curious.
This is better than that.
I might want to see the error bar.
Oh, got it.
Yes, this is good.
I should be able to put that
confidence interval
in as well.
Because I just want to compare
their correlation.
Then I just draw the line.
So if I draw the curve,
I can have a better
that
better than
better
measure to see
their performance.
Yes, that's what I think.
Because I think if you have an error bar,
you can clearly say this is better, this is worse.
Yes, but
if you just want to show features,
it looks like they all work.
And they all work pretty good.
I think.
OK, got it.
Because the way I compare here
is that every time
I go to see the correlation
of different methods.
And for different people,
I compare their correlation
and then
conclude which method
is better.
This is my current approach.
It's simpler,
but it might not be the best.
Hello?
Yes, if we have a better
I'll ask you again.
OK.
We can discuss later.
OK, thank you.
OK, I'll continue.
OK, so just now
I used the correlation to see
different methods
and their overall performance.
Here I just put all
the subjects I tested
together.
Just now Shaoming mentioned
that my data increase
will be good.
So I went to test
if the size of my database
just now
is different.
The way I did it
is that I cut off
some data
from my database.
Randomly cut off some data
and use the subject as a unit.
I'll see if my method performance
will increase
when the subject increases.
Y-axis is the average
correlation coefficient.
Blue is the traditional method.
Use your own data
to train a model.
Red is our
method of subject transfer.
Grey is the same
subject transfer, but without
our baseline activity
to choose those models.
You can see that
our method
will increase
when the size increases.
But if you don't use
the baseline correction,
it will be a little worse.
A little worse.
Then continue to talk about
the next picture.
I will compare
if we do this,
will the calibration time be reduced?
Traditionally, you have to
record your own data.
If we want to record
the alertness to become drowsy,
it takes a long time.
Traditionally, it takes a long time
to get the data you need.
This will cause
a long calibration time.
Our new method is to
use baseline activity.
It's easy to get baseline activity.
Just don't move.
Less than two minutes of data
The past method
is about 18 minutes.
There is no difference.
My conclusion
is that I can reduce it
from 18 minutes to
less than two minutes.
In terms of calibration reduction,
subject transfer can give us this effect.
In this case,
we really need to use our brain
to predict alertness.
It will be much better
if we use our brain to
predict alertness.
There is another question
that people often ask.
This hat looks like this.
No one wants to wear it.
Is there a better way
to measure our brain?
I was thinking
that when we measure our brain,
hair is a big problem.
If we avoid hair,
we can use some simple devices.
We can also use
these sensors
on our skin.
If we can use these
to measure our brain,
more people will be willing to use it.
You don't have to damage your hair.
It won't be uncomfortable.
I tested that
if I only use the front ear and
these channels next to the ear,
there are only six channels.
Can I use these six channels
to make a comparison
with the two heads
with 32 channels?
I found that
if you only use the channels
without hair,
the classification accuracy
can be the same
as the classification
with all channels.
There is no significant difference.
So we can actually
use the BCI
on alertness
or these channels
with no hair.
This way,
our device can be more convenient.
Here are some problems
that we need to solve
when we really want to use it.
The first one is
to reduce the calibration time
by using subject transferring.
Here we verify that
we don't need to use so many channels.
We can do this
with only one channel.
Here is a demonstration
of how our future
system will work.
We just mentioned
that we use response time
as a ground truth
for our alertness.
To be more precise,
I plan to use the distribution
of response time
as alertness
to define our alertness.
So if your distribution is shorter
and the peak
is shorter,
the y-axis is
the response time
and the unit is the second.
So if this is a very narrow distribution,
it is a better alertness.
If the distribution
is very wide,
it is easier to have
a longer response time,
which is a bad alertness,
and then
here is
a demonstration
that my black line
is my now,
and then I use
the previous
brainwave data
to predict that
from now on to 90 seconds,
the distribution of
response time
is a
thing that
will change
over time.
Then
when this time
passes, I can use some
offline tests
to see
if my response time
really falls
at a relatively high rate.
These white dots
are the response time
that we draw
based on
this, and you can play it a little bit.
OK, so you can see
that now this is
its distribution is
narrower, so the color here is
also more obvious, and then this is
the response time we actually recorded.
It is easier to fall
within this range,
in a better state of
alertness, and then
as time goes by, we can see that
this person's
distribution keeps drifting
and then finally becomes wider,
which means that
he is not in a good condition.
I'm starting to
sleep.
Like this,
it's
like this,
its distribution has become wider,
and then this side is also blurred.
Then you can also see that
there are some
long response times,
which means that
our prediction is roughly
real data
to verify that this prediction
is correct.
It will keep going.
This is a bit
like a weather forecast,
we go to its learnings to make a forecast.
Does anyone have any questions here?
Sorry, this forecast is
a few seconds ago, I might have missed it.
OK, this black line is now,
so I'm going forward
to predict 90 seconds,
and within 90 seconds, its probability distribution is here.
Yes, so let's see
that I predicted like this in the front,
and then the real response time
is it just below the one I just predicted?
OK, OK.
This is the distribution I just predicted.
Then I
plan to continue
to do it.
I hope that this thing can really
be used in
many applications.
In addition to driving,
many jobs that require
attention and focus
may be able to use this thing.
In addition, I also want to
use this thing to see
if there is a way to
actually see if our brain
uses
the change of
learning
to see if it has anything to do
with learning.
Or we can look at
ADHD or other
more specific people,
are they different
from normal people
in this part of
learning?
Take learning as a tool
to see if
different groups
have different differences.
I would like to thank
many people and the lab
and my funding is mainly
sponsored by Lu Jun.
Thank you all.
Thank you, thank you.
And applause, great.
Do you have any questions?
You can ask now.
Questions.
There are some comments.
The first one is a small question.
You said it was sponsored by Lu Jun,
is it the United States?
The project sponsored by
Lu Jun in the United States.
I'm just curious.
Are you an American?
No,
this project
is not sensitive.
So it can
have a project
with many schools
to help Lu Jun do things.
He donated money to many schools
to help him do things.
This project mainly wants to
look at the brain interface
and how to use
sound science
in some situations.
I see.
At least in physics
or astronomy,
if there is
military sponsorship,
they usually have a lot of
work to do.
Who is your nationality?
What is your nationality?
What is your background?
Yes, they have a lot of projects
that require citizenship.
The unit that gave us the money
requires you to be a citizen
to work there.
Even PR is not allowed.
I see.
I have something
that I find interesting.
I think
if I were to do something
in the future,
for example,
this person has started to hallucinate.
We all have this experience.
You sit next to a co-driver
and the driver starts to hallucinate.
You say, hey, don't sleep.
But the idiot
wakes up and brakes.
It's actually very dangerous.
So I think
the reaction of Awakening
to make this whole thing
a complete and useful thing
is a very important part, I think.
Yes, well said.
Yes, we also saw
that if it was
during sleep,
we used sound to wake him up
to see if it was useful
after waking him up.
But we didn't really see
what you said.
Braking randomly.
Yes, but I think it's possible.
Yes, it's possible.
Yes.
That's my suggestion.
I have two questions.
Okay, I have two questions.
The first question is
related to your hardware.
You mentioned that
if you only use a few channels
without covering the hair,
the effect is the same.
Do you use dry electrodes
to measure signals?
In my research,
I use the same electrodes
for all of them.
They're all wet electrodes.
I just look at the results
from different locations.
Because I have to compare,
I still use the same method
to measure.
Because I actually
went to San Diego a few years ago
and he showed us
his lab
using the dry electrodes
for baseball caps.
Baseball caps?
Baseball caps are the most primitive form.
But they mainly
turn electrodes into dry electrodes
so they don't need to be covered.
So I'm curious
about your current experiment.
Is there anyone
still using dry electrodes?
Or most of them are still covered?
In fact, dry electrodes
are becoming more and more popular.
Because people find it useful.
It takes less time.
And
subjects like it more.
But it's not necessarily more comfortable.
Because dry electrodes
usually need
some special design
on the hair
to pass through the hair.
So a lot of dry electrodes
make some corners,
deep corners,
and longer hair.
So it's not comfortable to wear for a long time.
So I specialize in
the part without hair
because there are a lot of
choices for the sensor
because it doesn't need to deal with hair problems.
And for the
adhesive type,
it's better for
long-term measurement.
Because most people
wear dry electrodes
and they start to feel pain
after a few hours.
Okay.
My second question
is a bit of a disaster question.
Most of the BCAAs I've seen
are taken signals from the brain
and transmitted to the computer
for related processing
or other applications.
But is it possible that
in the future, or is there anyone
who is already doing it?
It's a bit like the opposite.
So the BCAAs are being taken signals
and transmitted to the human brain
to try to manipulate human behavior.
Yes.
There are a few non-BCAAs.
I'm talking about non-BCAAs
because BCAAs are directly
transmitted to the computer.
Non-BCAAs
have a kind of TMS,
which is a pass-through magnetic field.
It uses a very strong magnetic field
to try to
trigger
brain activity
in a certain area.
At the moment,
we know
that
the doctor
can look for
the magnetic field
in a certain area
and your hand will move.
But
this thing
hasn't been
fully studied.
So what changes
can it cause?
There is not much
relevant evidence at the moment.
So it's still under development.
Can I say something?
Yes.
Someone in our lab has done this.
I haven't done it myself.
But basically,
it's close to a one-to-one response.
For example, if you stimulate
the visual cortex,
some people will see crossfade,
which is a flash.
As mentioned earlier,
if you stimulate the motor,
it will move in a certain area.
You can find out which finger moves.
For example, if you stimulate a certain area,
it will map out
which finger moves.
For hearing,
relatively few people
have done it.
For example, compared to EEG or MRI,
a group of people
have been doing TMS research.
There are also TDCS, TACS, etc.
Do you have any other questions?
I'm going to ask a question.
Wait a minute.
I don't have a question.
I just want to say
I want to stop recording.
But you can
continue.
OK, no problem.
I'm sorry.