Welcome everyone to today's TerraTalk. We are approaching the end of the year, so we may not have a speech next week.
Today, we are honored to invite Dr. Yang Yaolun to tell us about his doctoral research.
Dr. Yang Yaolun is now a doctoral candidate for the Department of Astronomy at UT Austin.
In fact, he is about to graduate.
When he was in college, he graduated from the Department of Astronomy at UT Austin, and then came to the United States to study astronomy.
His specialties and research interests include early-phase star formation, including observations and simulations.
In his doctoral research career, he has used various telescopes such as Herschel, ALMA, and SOFIA to do his research.
What is interesting is that he is also the host of Astronomy on Tap at UT Austin.
What kind of event is this?
They will regularly give speeches to the public on astronomy at the bar.
They have now grown to more than 250 people attending each time.
Dr. Yang Yaolun is the host of Astronomy on Tap at UT Austin.
Today, he will talk about the topic of the birth of solar-like stars and the inseparable entanglement of dynamics and chemistry.
Let's welcome Dr. Yang Yaolun to give a speech.
Thank you.
I have been involved in this project for a long time.
I am very happy to have the opportunity to talk to you.
Over the past few years, I have been doing research on star formation at UT Austin.
I am a 6th-year PhD student at UT Austin.
My main advisor is Neil Evans.
We mainly do various observations on star formation.
We use models to explain the physical and chemical phenomena observed in early star formation.
Dr. Yang mentioned SOFIA observations.
What is SOFIA?
SOFIA stands for Stratospheric Observations for Infrared Astronomy.
It is an astronomical observatory for infrared.
Why do we use SOFIA for infrared observation?
Because there are a lot of water vapors in the atmosphere.
These water vapors emit a lot of infrared rays.
When we observe on the ground, we only observe the water vapors on the earth.
So, many times, we use a telescope, such as Spitzer or Hubble, to observe infrared rays.
If I remember correctly, we can avoid 95% to 99% of water vapors by using a telescope.
This is SOFIA.
You can see that SOFIA is a modified Boeing 747.
You can see that there is a bulge in the middle section of the tail of the plane.
It is not very clear here.
It is a hole in the middle section.
A 2.7-meter telescope is placed in the hole.
When the telescope flies up, the door will open.
This is how it is observed.
Astronomers and technicians discuss how to make the observation easier to achieve and adjust the strategy in time.
This is how my advisor and I are going to get on the plane.
It is very different.
This is a military airport.
When you enter the airport, you will go up the stairs.
There is a B-2 bomber in the same airport.
This is the inside of SOFIA.
The blue part is the instrument.
The other side of the closed cabin is the telescope.
The other side of the telescope is the mirror.
The other side is the instrument.
There is a balance on the weight on both sides.
Different instruments, telescopes, and mission operators monitor the observation on these stations.
This is a very complicated task.
NASA considers every flight of SOFIA as a mission.
There is a mission director.
There is a mission briefing before departure.
This is the route we flew that day.
We flew from Palmdale, California, about an hour and a half north of LA.
You can see that the route is very strange.
Basically, the route is determined by each arc.
One arc is for a target.
Here we have six or seven targets.
The longer, the longer you stay on the celestial body.
Let's move on to today's topic.
Today's topic is mainly about star formation.
How do we understand the dynamics of early planetary orbits and the corresponding chemical changes?
This is a picture of our galaxy.
You can see a lot of these black irregularities in the middle.
This is what we call Darkland.
It has a lot of dust.
It is also a higher density place.
It is also an area where stars are forming.
If we zoom in to one of them, the Molecular Cloud,
It is mainly a star-forming place.
These black areas are also the so-called dust gathering areas.
It is a place where stars form early.
If we switch to infrared light,
You can see that there are a lot of these pillars or even what we call filamentary structures.
These are from what we imagine as a celestial sphere on Earth.
It's like a sphere in the sky, but it's not a ball or even a block here.
It's more like a texture or a filamentary structure.
Then through these filaments,
The gas and dust will be pulled to the middle through this filament.
Then pull to the middle and then reach a high enough density.
Then trigger the activity of this star formation.
This is when the star formation occurs.
You will have a lot of.
Basically, the density will be from 10 to 3 or 10 to 5.
This is the mole per cubic centimeter.
It will be quickly multiplied by 10 to the power of 9 to the power of 10 to the power of 4.
This is a very large number of changes.
In the process, if you have, um.
At the beginning, um.
When the collapse, um.
You're going to have a little bit of, uh.
The angular momentum is in the outermost part.
If you have this smaller angular momentum, it's in a very small area.
It's going to be a lot of rotation.
At this time, the degree of rotation is likely to make this.
The collapse of the star formation is not very effective.
That is to say, your, uh.
The gas becomes itself to rotate there, not to continue.
Continue, uh.
It's sucked into the middle of the star.
In the process, there will be a lot of.
We call outflow, and then go.
Go to these, um.
The high-speed rotation of the matter is released.
And then go in to reduce.
The angular momentum of the whole system.
You see the green ones here.
The matter that looks like a jet is the outflow.
Now, this is a simulation.
That is, um, a simulation.
Roughly describe that we are from a filament.
And then slowly, uh, develop into.
It will start with a filament, and then zoom in.
And then you'll see a star.
The early shape of the star.
The situation is a lot of molecules.
Very, very fatal molecules.
How to be in that state.
And then, um.
Collapse and then erupt.
That's what you saw in the picture just now.
This kind of outflow.
OK, so you can see this whole process.
Is very, very.
Very big change, and then, um.
It's going to take a lot, a lot, a lot.
Irregular structure.
So.
We also found in observation.
That's what it is.
You can see here, this one.
The picture behind this black and white picture is.
Uh, the distribution of molecules.
This is.
And then the different symbols in front of it.
It means that we are directly observed.
Early star.
Uh, where it appears.
You can see most of it.
Early stars are in, um.
These molecules.
Uh, it's also a more fatal place, so it's produced.
So, um.
We can probably get one of these.
Uh, scenario is to say that you first have a lot of very fatal clouds and dust.
And then through.
Um, these clouds and dust may slowly or even quickly.
Um.
It will collapse to the middle and then become.
Uh, a star or a few stars, I don't know.
So in this process, a very important thing is to say.
Oh, this is probably a very simple one.
Uh, cartoon pattern to express the words is that we have a, uh, a core at the beginning.
We call pre-stereo core.
Simply put, it's the core before the stellar.
So it's called pre-stereo core.
And then you start to collapse.
These core collapse to the middle and become, uh.
Uh, in the early days, it was called pro-star.
So we called this core pro-stereo core.
At the same time, it may, uh.
Um.
It produces a lot of, uh, these.
These flow, this orange side is called the flow.
What about the evolution?
These substances.
The surrounding matter is either sucked into the middle and becomes a part of the star.
Or.
It will be affected by a lot of feedback.
And then it just.
It's just slowly, uh, dissipated.
And then the rest of you are left with a disk.
Because.
There's still a lot of matter, um, in the middle.
The middle part of the high-speed rotation.
There's no way it's very direct.
It's sucked into the middle, uh, on the planet.
So there's a disk.
What about this side?
This disk is, um, planet.
It's where the stars are produced.
So gradually, this disk will slowly evolve into, uh.
Generally, we recognize the planter system.
Just like.
Our solar system, we may be somewhere here.
Okay, um.
So we, uh.
There's a pretty important one.
Uh, the question is, is this.
In the early days of this info, from this.
When you want to produce a pro star.
What?
Uh, it's like a process like this.
How much is his time scale?
Okay, um.
In the pre-status evolution, it's not quite certain now.
So basically.
Um.
If a core starts to collapse.
Production process to become, uh.
Just from, uh.
Core pre-status.
This is probably.
2 million years.
Relatively short.
Then it disappears from disk to disk.
It's probably 10 million years.
So.
And then one, one, for example, like our sun, our sun.
About 10 million years.
So this is probably their time.
It's 1% and 1%.
Then I have another question.
Uh, that's it.
That's one of these.
Uh, how do you say this?
One of these processes.
With the limit, for example, is the model universe.
Or, for example.
Z equals 3, z equals 5.
Or something like that.
Or these things will only happen in the near future.
So there is no difference.
I'm talking about the near future.
Well, the near future is actually.
It's just that it happens, but it happens in the early days.
That even has a lot of.
A lot of active research areas are doing the so-called first star.
It's the first star that starts the earliest.
That's one of the biggest differences.
Uh.
It's in the core.
Um.
This core, a dance core, he wants to collapse.
He doesn't need to, uh.
It doesn't have to be dynamic.
If he is, uh.
The temperature is very high, he is very.
His thermal motion is very strong, so he.
His thermal pressure, he can.
It's easy to be greater than this.
This gravity gives him this middle attraction, so.
Um, when the temperature is very high, it's not easy to collapse.
That's why he has to be cold enough to collapse.
What about in the early universe?
Um, I should say, um.
Um, how do you make this?
This core becomes very cold.
Usually a very important mechanism is called, uh.
Basically, uh.
Your energy, uh, is absorbed by molecules, and then molecules.
Decay.
Decay, and then it becomes radiation.
The radiation goes out, and the energy leaves the system.
So you, you will slowly become cold.
That molecule or.
Um.
It's just more.
In addition to hydrogen, these atoms are more useful for cooling.
That's relative to the early universe.
This cool will be weaker.
So, in the early universe, everyone will think that your core can become.
It can grow very big, and then.
And then it's easy to form a super big quality.
And so on.
I believe that now we have not yet observed anything.
But there should be a lot of simulation to do this part.
Ok, thank you.
Ok, so, um.
So, from an observational point of view, we want to know.
Hey, how does this collapse happen?
What kind of mold does this material go through?
From the outside of this core.
The outer region is transferred to the inner region.
That's like in this simulation, which is simulating.
How does this core collapse?
And then.
In the end.
You can see that the middle of this collapse is very, very short at the beginning.
Compared to the time after that.
So, you can see the same thing as the previous one.
You can see that it is very irregular.
And so it means that there may be a lot of structures in it.
Different structures, different modes.
It depends on the angle you look at.
It may be outflow.
Other places may see it as info.
So, um.
For the measurement of this info.
We mainly want to know how this info started.
And then how he did it.
For example, how far is he?
How big is the size scale?
How do you start?
For example, how big does this core need to grow at what temperature?
He will start to have info.
How is his process?
How fast does he increase as the radius gets smaller and smaller?
Or even not increase, so the radius gets smaller and smaller.
It may be slower or faster.
So how did he evolve in the end?
This rotation dominant region.
It's more like a disc.
An early disc.
A region like that.
How did he go from the original radio motion to the rotation?
So, um.
Through this view, we want to know.
What is the model of this info?
We have a way to write a very good model.
To simulate this part.
And then there's the chemical change.
How do you change with this info?
I'll talk more about this later.
Let's talk about it now.
And then in a bigger structure.
Um.
This info is actually.
For our so-called initial mass function.
Very important.
What is the initial mass function?
It's a bit like.
Um.
We're going to build a galaxy now.
Build a star system.
My inside.
Various quality stars.
What's the ratio?
This is called the initial mass function.
There may be smaller mass stars, smaller mass stars, more.
That's one.
Uh.
Mass distribution is the initial mass function.
That.
But these initial mass functions are mainly refers to.
Uh, already generated stars.
So we.
In the early days, in the space travel, we really want to know.
Okay, if we have.
This kind of big and small.
Different sizes of core.
What kind of stars will these cores become?
Between them.
Core mass distribution and initial mass distribution.
Uh, what is the mass distribution of the star?
Change.
So we hope that in the future, through this understanding, this info model can.
Can.
There are some hints that say, OK, if we have a core, it may be.
A solar mass.
That may be how many percent will become.
Uh.
How much will the middle star be?
Is that what we want?
I can go through this model.
This research.
Go to approach.
Ultimately approach this problem.
How do we go from this blue core mass function to this?
Dashboard, all kinds of different dashboards.
Uh, initial mass function.
The other thing is that we are now in the early days.
Uh, these are also seeing a lot of binary systems.
And in the general, uh.
Already formed a star, we also know.
Uh.
Most of the stars are binary, that is.
Uh, double star or more.
Uh, multiple system.
Then we also saw this situation in the early days.
That.
You want to know how this early star.
Uh, how can it form such a binary system?
Then this.
This binary system is for this info or what impact.
Or say, what kind of criterion do you want to reach for the mass of your info?
What kind of threshold will trigger such fragmentation?
Fragment into.
Different 2 or 3 or more sources.
So we want to know.
Uh.
This initial condition, what is it?
How big is it?
Then it is, how much is its quality?
Then I hope we can get to know how much.
How much mass will be in the middle?
How much will be retained in the middle?
OK, this is another, uh, this is a very.
The system has three, three, three stars in the middle.
So we still don't know why it's like this.
OK, the other part is.
Hey, we're like this, this.
MWC480, this, this disk, you see a lot of this kind of structure.
But in addition, we also see a lot of different.
Uh, more complex, like this.
Or this is different.
Um.
Uh, more large molecules of organic compounds.
That, uh, we were in the early, uh.
Uh, the core stage also saw a lot of these, uh.
Organic chemicals, these.
Organic chemicals, because organic chemicals, ultimately, they will become.
It will enter the interstitial atmosphere, and then it may be.
Trigger, uh.
The main part of the life cycle, because these organic chemicals may be.
In addition to speaking more broadly, it may even be the first step of life.
Or even the seed of life.
So we want to know that in the early stage of this core evolution.
How do these chemicals change with the information?
Um, the same, I'm going to do a lot of explanation in the back.
OK, so our goal is to find out how this information happened.
Then we are in the way we are currently using it.
We are, uh, trying to measure, uh.
To measure, uh.
Uh, the performance of, uh.
Kinematic structure is simply through his.
The shape of the line to analyze that in the end, his.
Uh, we look at this line of sight inside.
What is the path of the movement of the gas?
So.
Here, if we look at it from this antenna,
On the left, this is a very simplified one.
Core of the information.
One of the more common models is the middle of the information.
The velocity is higher than the outside of the information.
So you can simplify this thing.
Like this picture on the right.
This, uh, red is, uh.
We look at the path.
Because he only has this radio motion.
So you can, uh, you can draw a circle like this.
And then they, uh.
The line of sight above the two points is exactly the same.
It means that you will have two, you will have two groups of gas.
And then they, for you, his, uh.
What is it called?
Uh, the cutoff speed is the same.
Uh, but they are in different places.
Then this will cause, uh.
Simplified, it will cause a double profile like this on the left.
That.
Um.
Right, that's it.
And then you have this middle absorption.
This is from a relatively cold gas on the outside.
Maybe it's a cold gas in front of you.
And then the stronger radiation that comes in behind the absorption.
Because you're cold in front of you.
So you're easier to get excited, and then your radiation is absorbed by this colder material.
You look at this.
So, um, if you have a higher resolution.
You can see, uh, like this, like this, if this purple area is our telescope beam.
Uh, you can see the cold gas out there, but it's still moving to the center.
It's still falling on to the center.
So, uh, this kind of, uh, cold gas will give you one.
It's not in, it's not in, uh, source velocity, an absorption.
It's a redshift because it's far away from you.
And then it's going to cause this redshift, this absorption, and it's going to change like this.
So this is basically the profile we want to see.
We want to measure a profile like this.
And then, um.
And then when you, uh, in the back, we have this in the middle.
There's a, um, continuous source in the middle of every collapsing star.
It might be, uh, the hottest part of the disk.
The temperature is very high.
It might be a few thousand degrees.
And then it just gives you a very strong blackbody radiation.
So if you put it on, this radiation, this, um.
Radiation, continuous radiation will also be absorbed by the colder material in front of it.
It's going to be absorbed.
So in the end, you're going to get something like this.
Continuous originally your continuous may be flat, but in the middle of the part.
Uh, because you have a material that's far away from you, you're in this velocity, so you're going to be absorbed by a part of it.
So what you actually see, uh, observation in your telescope, observation of the profile will probably look like this.
Just simply add the two just now.
So when you, if we're in, uh, according to this, uh, two.
The front and back of the continuum, the level to correct it, uh, take the continuum away, you'll get this.
A strange one, uh, line profile is simply that you, we'll see, uh, the middle absorption is less than 0.
You have two radiations less than 0.
That's not really because we assume the continuum in the middle.
Still, uh.
It's the same level as other places, but it's actually partially absorbed.
So, uh, we basically want to measure a line profile like this, and then analyze the line profile like this.
To understand that we, uh.
I've seen this line of sight before.
Uh.
What is the model of the gas movement?
I want to ask a question.
Hey, that.
Why is that profile?
That is, these profiles are not symmetrical to that.
Okay, okay, this is the part I just skipped.
Uh.
Okay, if we go back to the two circles on the right, this picture.
Um, in the middle, I write this high high temperature, which is more central.
And then on both sides, which is, uh.
Large radius is the place where the temperature is lower.
Then you can think of it as, um, in this.
Uh.
In your foreground, in front of you, your foreground is your red foreground material, which is red shift.
It's just that it's falling to the center, so it's red shift to you.
But in this red shift, this part.
You will have, uh.
High temperature in the back, low temperature in the front.
It means that you are more like you have a cold thing in front of a hot thing.
So this cold thing will absorb the back.
The hot gas gives you the radiation.
Uh, but in the blue shift part, which is on the back side of the envelope.
You will, you, you don't have this situation.
It's just that the cold stuff is behind the hot stuff.
So you don't have this kind of self-absorption.
So that's why the red shift peak is lower.
Then continue.
Why is it the same shape over there?
Because the continuum is in the middle.
Imagine a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1, a 1.
So continue.
Only in the red part.
It's going to be absorbed because the front of the continue doesn't have any blue shift.
Oh, I see.
Ok, thank you.
Um.
Yeah, so about 20 years ago, people started measuring this kind of profile.
And then this is usually measured with a wireless telescope.
That was usually used in the past.
It's like this.
Uh, we usually think of this little ear or bigger.
Maybe it's a 10 meter telescope or a 10 meter dish.
Then go to measure these different molecules, and then try to measure the profile.
But you can see here, the first one, in addition to the sensitivity.
Uh, it's not very good.
There are a lot of different structures.
He has a lot of this kind of broad line.
Or even you don't have a very obvious absorption.
Even the most important thing is that you don't have less than 0.
So no less than 0.
The most important thing is that this absorption is very likely to be.
Uh, you're in front of this source.
Other completely unrelated to you.
You have no way to say.
Um, this absorption is not true.
It belongs to what you see now.
If you can see this absorption.
Uh.
Drop to 0.
It becomes negative.
You can find a way to move your telescope.
And then you can say, okay, if I move away from the middle, this has a continuous source.
See if there's any change in this absorption.
You can be more.
Uh, sure.
Make sure that this absorption material is really associated.
The key is that it really belongs to what you see.
This kind of course.
So, because of the relationship between Resolution and Sensitivity.
Uh, this question was broadly studied about 20 years ago.
Maybe 5 to 10 years later, everyone thought, okay, it's almost done.
You can't do it yourself anymore.
So just wait.
Um.
Uh, the new generation of this Auma wireless wave array.
Uh, there's no way to have a better observation result.
So what is Auma?
Auma is, uh.
Uh, Akitama large millimeter sub array.
It is a wireless wave array on the Akitama desert plateau in Chile.
And then.
It's mainly.
There should be 66 antennas.
It's probably like this bigger antenna on the outside.
Each antenna is a 12 meter antenna.
There's a smaller one in the middle.
Another, uh, separate array.
Uh, it's 7 meters.
Then it is.
Uh, it's basically a collaboration around the world.
The United States is NRAO.
Oh, that's not NRAO.
That's NRC.
NRC is Canada's National Research Council.
And then Japan's NLJ.
Europe's ESO.
Taiwan is A, uh, the Chinese Academy of Sciences.
Uh, there's participation.
And then there's Chile.
And then this is open to the world.
Um.
Astronomers can apply to observe.
That he mainly.
Uh, the biggest bonus is that he can have a very, very good resolution.
His.
He can see very, very small things.
So basically the array is.
Uh, the telescope is, uh, your resolution is proportional to the wavelength divided by.
Uh, you.
The diameter of your telescope.
The wireless wave array is simply a mirror.
Cut.
Cut into a lot of little ones.
Uh, a different telescope.
So you can pull the two telescope very far.
As a telescope to use.
So this is the biggest.
This.
Uh, baseline is called baseline.
Simply put, his diameter can be up to 15, 15 kilometers.
Yeah, it can be analyzed to a very small area.
Ok, so at the beginning of this, we started with two more similar profiles that we just drew at the beginning.
Like the left side, this is a.
This is a, uh.
Organic molecules.
Uh, what is the Chinese name?
The English is.
Uh.
This, this.
You can see if we take it off, you can see this.
Go below 0, and then you can see that his absorption is in the red.
You've lost it.
And then the same thing, in this other source, and then we've seen something similar, but in these two cases.
These are all relatively small, because the first one on the left is an organic molecule, so his.
He may be in those early stars.
Uh, the abundance is not so high.
Uh, not much, so the image is relatively weak.
Then, like the one on the right, this is a relatively dark source, so it's not so high, so its absorption is relatively small.
That's what I'm doing, and I'm mainly using it, uh, to give another source, which is this.
And then go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go.
Uh, uh.
And then go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go, go.
It's all about, uh, different different dust and gas.
Uh, in the infographic, you can see he has a beautiful outflow, radio, you can see the beautiful outflow.
It actually has two sources in the middle.
So, here, we're just focusing on irs1, which is the main source.
Okay, so when we were in alma cycle 4, we proposed, and then we got our data.
It looks like this on the right.
It's very much like the way it was drawn before, especially this hcl plus.
This curve is basically the same as the one you saw earlier.
Then you can see here, although, um.
This absorption is very wide, but you can see that he's actually in, uh, redshift.
Velocity still has more absorption, which means that he's actually part of it.
It comes from, um, the gas that's falling in the middle.
Absorption.
Um.
Okay, so to analyze this curve, we actually need to use one.
We can't just read it out of this.
Okay, this absorption is in, maybe it's in 0.5 kilometers per second.
And then you'll know.
Uh, you might know there's something in 0.5 kilometers per second falling in.
But you don't know if he's in the place where you're looking at this line of sight.
That's because you have absorption and emission mixed together, so we have to, um.
Use a very common technique in astronomy, which is ready to transfer the calculation to find a way.
Um, to model the way we see it.
That's a simple way to say, uh, if I'm here every time, this is a function.
It's a, it's a gas.
You might have radiation coming in on the left.
So what about the radiation?
It's going to be in this gas.
He may be absorbed by the gas.
You're going to become weak.
Or after you've been absorbed, or you've been in this gas, it's actually very hot, so he's got some.
Uh, he's got some black radiation, or he's got some of his own radiation, so he's probably going to have an emission.
So, in the transition of these energies, he's probably going to be part of it.
It's the temperature of this gas, or, uh, it's the level population of different molecules in the inside.
He's probably going to turn it from a high-frequency state to a high-frequency state, and then it's going to be a high state.
The high state will even put some molecules, just break up the molecules into smaller molecules, or even into atoms or even into particles.
So you can do this in your mother's face.
And then you can go in and say, I've got a line coming in, and it's going to cause some kind of result to my gas and dust, and then you go to the end.
In the end, you put each of your mother's from the beginning to the end, and then you can know what comes out of it.
Uh, radiation to the end, uh, we observed what it should look like, and then, uh, through, uh.
The process of more than once, and then to get a better model to explain what we saw in front of us.
So, in fact, what we do is very tedious, but it's also, um.
Um, it's actually okay, it's actually not that tedious, but it's a lot of iteration, uh, a lot of iterative process.
Basically, after we have a model, we can get it, we can say, okay, our, our.
What does it look like? Um.
Info this, uh, velocity should look like.
We can throw it into, uh, different radio transfer models to do, uh, here we put gas and.
Separate because basically.
Um, first of all, we use, uh, uh, continuous part of the rain.
To go to, uh.
To constrain this whole envelope structure, for example, this envelope.
Um, his, uh.
What is the density, so what changes with the radius, how much of his outflow area, his, uh, angle is, how much is his angle.
Then, when we determine this envelope structure.
Let's put it in and then calculate it.
Okay, if we follow this structure, follow this kinematic, what should the spectrum we get look like?
Okay, so, um, this is what we did before, uh, the model.
Here, uh, you can see this is, uh.
This is.
The spectrum behind this.
The gray line is the spectrum, and then this is about.
Uh, 2 microns, 3 microns, up to 1 millimeter range.
Then.
Fang, uh.
The blue circle is our model, and then the red square is observation.
You can see that most of us are going to fit through this, and we're going to fit our model to this observation.
And then we'll get a better model to describe this envelope.
For example, like I'm drawing here, but in fact, how do we construct it like this?
What is the angle of his outflow?
What is the density distribution of the envelope?
Okay, so you don't want to show off.
It's more like it's coming out of the outflow, and then it's coming out of the envelope.
Okay, so, um, I mentioned earlier that we're going to take this envelope structure, and we're going to add kinematics, and we're going to figure out how to model this.
Uh, but in fact, one of the very, very important, uh, factors is chemistry.
So chemistry is not.
Uh, well, so chemistry is not just thinking, okay, what molecules are you going to have in there, but molecules like this.
Is it possible to exist in that condition?
In the atmosphere, you can see it, especially in.
Um, these dense core, the density in the middle is very high, and the temperature is quite low.
So it's possible to be frozen on top of these dust.
If it freezes, you, you, you, you, you can't see it in the atmosphere.
So here's the different chemical abundance profile.
You might be out there, you might have, uh, the radiation from other places.
Uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh.
You might have to separate it and make it two different things, or maybe he's in there, and he'll be that ice will be frozen on the dust, or he'll be in here.
It interacts with some electrically charged molecules, and then it generates other particles, and then it disappears.
So you don't measure it.
And in the middle of that, we're going to go to the main thing I've been doing a lot of time lately, and then we're going to say, what do we want to do?
A better abundance profile to explain our data.
So, uh, basically, we need to understand this info profile.
Uh, we're going to take our dust model to get density, temperature, and velocity, and then we're going to add our chemical bonus.
Uh, we're going to find a way.
Uh, get a hat spectrum, compare it, if you don't feel good, we'll go back and change it. So this is a very.
Uh, a long process.
Uh, this is us.
Uh, hey.
Um, uh, yeah, that's good.
My question is, um, like this, in this kind of small system, uh, that kind of info or the final outflow of the gravity distribution is all considered.
Is it just normal?
That matter is good.
If there's a dark matter, he can't say anything about it.
It doesn't really matter.
And.
I'm not sure if it's going to be in the early universe.
But at least in the modern universe.
Uh, the general assumption is that dark matter is mainly in the outer galaxy.
So I rarely.
I heard that.
Uh, dark matter will affect the evolution of these, at least in the region.
So I don't think there's much of an impact.
Because that's what I think.
If today, in some kind of dark matter, with their own strong interacting, then there will be some small structures.
For example, it's a clumpy phenomenon.
Maybe it's possible, but I don't think I can see it.
Yes, it should be impossible to see.
If you have a dark matter, it should be a very, very small scale.
That might be something like microlensing.
So, uh.
So, in a system like this, it should be impossible to see.
The current observation should be very far away.
Maybe there will be, but it's hard.
Okay, thank you.
OK, so, uh.
This is like this, this is like me.
This is our latest profit.
The latest model is actually about two days ago.
Uh, on the right side, uh, blue is our data.
Orange is our current model.
And then you see our model.
Roughly captured data.
The feeling but you can see, for example, in Russian, we still miss a lot of emissions.
So, uh.
This is actually our status now.
In the future, we should continue to do more.
Uh, different tuning, and then even to understand that there is no way to make up for this part of the missing mission.
And then.
To understand that it is possible to say, um.
Well, of course, our current model is very, very symmetrical, so basically it is a symmetric model.
That, um.
The first one is to understand that, OK, if in this very strong assumption, we have no way to make this model.
Make this model better.
What if it doesn't work?
How do we break this?
This assumption.
And it's not going to create too much freedom.
And it becomes, OK, you can say whatever you want.
Um.
So, uh, this is probably the main thing I'm going to do in the next month or two.
And on the left side of the show, this picture is.
Uh, basically, it's like.
Uh, if you look.
This is a map.
Then if you take the middle continuous source, it will be like this.
This dark place in the middle is the continuous source.
After being removed, it causes a very strong absorption.
It's like you see this very strong absorption on the right.
So when you get close to it, it becomes negative.
And then the two bright spots up and down are because you have an outflow, so the outflow is up.
Uh, up and down in this direction, so there's an outflow.
Uh.
Uh, the density is relatively low, so it's easier to be heated, so it's brighter.
OK, so why does this info affect this chemistry?
That is to say, uh, simply put, if there's a group of gas, now it's going to come from the outside of this envelope.
It's travel, you're affected by the infogravity, and you can't travel to the middle.
And then falling to this star or disk.
It will pass through different temperatures in the middle.
It's getting hotter and hotter in the middle.
Basically, it's getting hotter and hotter because there's a pro star in the middle.
Pro star is emitting a very strong emission.
So, but this info can manage is determined by saying, OK, I have this group of gas.
This gas will take a long time in different temperature ranges.
If it's very slow, it might take a long time in every place.
Well, or even if it's in a relatively low temperature, it takes a long time.
Or in a relatively high temperature, it will take a long time.
That will affect, uh, at different temperatures, it will affect, uh.
It should be said that at different temperatures, the chemical reaction that you can generate is different.
And the time scale of each chemical reaction is different.
If you're in a low temperature, although you have a lot of low temperature chemical reactions,
But if you only spend a short time in a low temperature,
Then those reactions won't cause any changes to the chemical state of those molecules.
So, another way to see is to say, uh, we're actually using these molecules.
The radiation to track the dynamic in this envelope.
Well, if we don't know where these molecules are going to be,
our interpretation is going to be incorrect.
So, the other thing I was talking about earlier,
these, uh, these dynamic evolution will also affect the chemical reactions that you can produce.
So, these two are a bit like interaction.
It's like being bundled together.
It's hard for you to separate one from each other.
So, here's what I'm talking about.
For example, in the first question, you might have a lot of free.
You know, you have a lot of deterioration.
Your H will become very low.
And then, in the so-called medium tension,
you're going to have a lot of different chemical reactions on the surface of this dust.
And that's going to cause the chemistry, the chemistry, the chemistry model.
People will tell you that this is going to produce a lot of different species.
And now, when it's high temperature, when it's 100 Kelvin,
uh, you're going to have a lot of different species on top of this dust.
Maybe it's because the temperature is getting higher, so it's coming out.
So, it's going to affect what you're seeing.
These different bonds are going to be at different temperatures, and there's going to be different changes.
So, basically, uh, in the early days, there were two.
So far, we've observed that there are two different kinds of, uh, source.
One is called Hocker.
You know, and then there's Warren Carpenter Molecule Source.
Uh, Warren Carpenter Molecule Source is a, uh,
uh,
uh.
Warren Carpenter Molecule Source is, uh,
t8..
t9.
E
E E
f