Hello everyone, welcome to this week's Terra Talk. I am today's host, Zhang Yanyong. I am currently studying high-energy physics experiments at the University of California.
Before we officially start, let's first introduce what kind of organization Project Terra is.
In fact, as we wrote on the website, our goal is to establish a timely cross-national academic information sharing platform,
connect Taiwan's academic talents from all over the world, exchange results and trends in Taiwan's academic circles overseas,
and provide each other with a platform for effective communication.
To put it simply, we hope to establish a platform that helps Taiwanese from all over the world engage in research and work to communicate with each other quickly and timely.
We will hold a webcast like today every week.
The speakers are basically our members, and the audience can sign up online.
The topic of the speech is based on the results of the speaker's research, review his current development in his special field,
and share new ideas, plans, or opportunities for cooperation.
Project Terra is currently a fully self-funded, fully volunteer organization.
Our staff are basically all doctoral students and post-doctoral students.
You can see the About page on our website.
Now I'm going to post the link to our website on the chat room next to it.
I want to add that we recently added a lot of staff who may not have been updated to the website.
The most important purpose of a project like this is to fully open up, share and cooperate.
The more friends who are willing to join us, share and help each other,
we can move towards the goals we all want.
I also hope that it will be helpful to Taiwan's academic circle and everyone's research career, or to transfer jobs in the future.
Now I'm going to post the link to our website on the chat room next to it.
If you feel that you support our ideas, or are passionate about sharing your very passionate research,
you can consider joining our members, and you will continue to receive our speech and activity information.
Of course, you can also go to our Facebook fan page and continue to follow our news.
We also want to emphasize that we have no profit at all.
If you are willing to share with other Taiwanese, it will be the biggest reward for us.
It is also the biggest help to other friends who work in the academic circle.
This is the introduction of TARA.
Next, I want to introduce our speaker.
We are honored to invite Zheng Yunting today.
Zheng Yunting is currently studying physics at the California Institute of Technology.
He is currently a doctoral candidate.
Yunting graduated from the Department of Physics in 2014 and joined the Caltech Research Institute.
He is currently studying his doctorate.
His special field is observational cosmology.
He will introduce to us today that he is doing a data analysis project.
It is a rocket project.
There is one more thing to remind everyone.
In order to let the speaker feel our enthusiasm,
the microphone must be turned on when applauding, so that he can hear the voice.
Let's applaud and welcome Yunting to give us this speech.
Thank you everyone.
I am Zheng Yunting. I am studying my PhD at Caltech.
Thank you to my office mate, Zhang Yanyong, for the introduction.
The topic I am going to talk about today is
Measuring Extragalactic Background Light at Optical and Near-Infrared.
This is a project I am doing.
I am doing its data analysis.
What I am going to talk about today is more focused on
the background in this field.
What do we want to measure?
What do we want to understand?
What is a signal?
Let me start by introducing the history of our universe.
This is the universe we know so far.
We can start from the left.
The left is the earliest period.
We have inflation and Big Bang.
Inflation is the theory of explosion in Chinese.
Big Bang is the beginning of the universe.
In the very early period,
the universe is very small and hot.
Everything inside is very hot and oily.
As the universe expands,
the gas will expand.
At a certain point in time,
the temperature in the universe is low enough.
The electrons and protons in the gas
will combine to form hydrogen.
This process is called recombination.
After recombination,
there are a lot of photons in the universe.
Photons are easily scattered with free electrons.
After recombination,
there are almost no free electrons in the universe.
These photons will not become long.
We can see the photons emitted at that time.
This is called a cosmic microwave background or CMB.
This is the earliest signal we can measure in cosmology.
After recombination and CMB,
a lot of protons and electrons combine to form hydrogen.
During this period,
the universe is full of neutral hydrogen and hydrogen.
This period is called the Dark Age.
Because it is very dark,
there are no photons like the CMB at that time.
However, there are no stars and galaxies yet.
The universe during this period is completely black.
During this period,
there will be some density fluctuations in the universe.
These density fluctuations are because of gravity.
As time goes by,
there will be more matter coming in.
The main component is dark matter.
These dark matter may form heavier and condensed structures.
We call this dark matter halo.
Because there is a strong gravitational potential in the halo,
the background gases such as hydrogen will also gather here.
When the gathering becomes compact,
it will cause a fusion reaction and form the first star or galaxy.
After a period of time,
the universe begins to form stars and galaxies.
After these stars and galaxies form,
they will release a lot of photons.
If the energy of the photons is strong enough,
the energy gap between the hydrogen and the gas will be strong enough.
The gas will separate the hydrogen nearby.
You can see that there are some separated areas on this map.
We call this ionizing bubble.
This process is called reionization.
As time goes by,
there will be more and more stars and galaxies in the universe.
It will ionize the hydrogen nearby.
At the end,
if you have enough galaxies,
you will separate all the hydrogen in the universe.
The gases outside the galaxy are all ionized.
This is our current universe.
This is the history of the development of the universe.
What I'm going to study now is called an extra-galactic background light.
I have a question.
What if I put a traffic light on my screen and it disappears?
Oh, okay.
I see.
So, what if I put a traffic light on my screen and it disappears?
Can you see it clearly like this?
Actually, I think it's pretty clear.
Okay, then I'll do it like this.
I also think traffic lights are more convenient.
So, what I'm going to measure is the extra-galactic background light,
or EVL.
In the universe, the word galaxy is used to refer to our own galaxy.
So, extra-galactic is outside our own galaxy.
Background light means everything outside the galaxy is called background.
So, the EVL we measure is the time and space that happened in the universe.
So, from the earliest meter, you can see C and B and the Dark Age and many stars.
The frequency along which posters were laid out is locked on through that spectrum.
We call this spectrum the EDL.
Specture on different wavelengths or language.
These data are gathered so far.
You can see that different wavelengths have different EDL measurements.
Let's talk about what each wavelength does.
We can look at the highest and lowest energy.
The highest energy is gamma ray and X-ray.
The main source of these high-energy photons are
active galactic nuclei.
These nuclei have a large black hole
in the center of each galaxy.
Sometimes these black holes may suck in
all kinds of messy gas and then
heat them up and release some radiation.
These radiations will have very strong energy.
These high-energy photons are called
active galactic nuclei.
The main source is from the galaxy cluster.
The center of the cluster has a large black hole.
The cluster itself has some very hot gas.
It has a very strong gravitational potential.
This is the main source of gamma ray and X-ray.
The main source of X-ray is gamma ray.
The main source of gamma ray is gamma ray.
At the same time, the source of very low-energy radio
is also from something like AGN.
I don't know if you've heard of synchrotron radiation.
This is also when gas is heated
or accelerated to a very high speed.
This is also when gas is heated or accelerated to a very high speed.
Next is UV.
We didn't measure a lot of data for UV.
It's hard to see UV data
because it's a higher-energy photon
than 912 Armstrong.
In our own galaxy,
it's easy to absorb
the UV photons.
So it's hard to see the background
of the UV astro-galaxy.
The strongest peak is in the microwave.
The source of the microwave is from the Cosmic Microwave Background.
The source of the microwave is from the cosmic microwave
bakick-de normando radiation.
The source is from the Cosmic Microwave Background.
One is in the optical and the other in infrared.
These two are mostly stars pieces
emitted in different galaxies.
Star emission is in optical.
In infrared,
There's dust emission in the galaxy.
These dusts will suck
stellar lights
They will emit thermal radiation
and it's in the infrared
You can see
This star's light
is emitted from as equal from the opposition
of the star to the star.
The wavelengths I will talk about today
are in the optical area.
If we zoom in
we can see a lot of different data
This is the far-infrared
You can see a lot of different data
I will focus on this area
You can see a lot different data
and these data change
up to different values
You can see data changing
These data are inconsistent
because they are used in different ways
in Constraint EDL
There are 4 ways
I will introduce them
The first method is called Galaxy Counts
These data are from Galaxy Counts
Galaxy Counts means
I want to measure
in the near-infrared or optical background
I will use a telescope
to look at a field
I can measure many galaxies in this field
I will add the light from the near-infrared
I will say these are the extra-galactic backgrounds I measured
You can only contain low-LE in EBL
You will only get the brightest galaxies
You can only get a few of them
You will only get a few of them
I also place multiple
You will only get a feliz
You will only get a few of them
I also explained the number of colors
I also explained the name
the second method is Absolute Photometry
Absolute Photometry
Resolve the gas and measure the total intensity
Measure the total emission of the sky
Fluctuation
Correlation function
Flare transform
Fluctuation
Fluction
Galaxy