Q&A SESSION
Hello everyone, welcome to today's TAIRA speech.
Today's speech topic is very special and I like it very much.
The speaker is Liu Junlin.
He is going to talk about LATEX and DINNER today.
I will briefly introduce the speaker today.
The speaker got a doctorate in electrical engineering from Caltech this year.
His main field of research is digital signal processing and statistical signal processing.
This is a brief introduction of the speaker.
Without further ado, let's welcome the speaker to talk about today's speech tool.
Please turn on the microphone and let's clap together.
Let's start the speech.
We'll leave the time to Junlin.
Thank you.
I need to turn on the microphone.
You can turn it on, I'll turn it off.
Then I'll turn it on here.
Okay, thank you.
Thank you for the invitation from TAIRA.
I am honored to give a special academic speech today.
Today's speech topic is mainly about LATEX.
Another tool called TIKZ and DINNER.
How to use these three tools in academic reports.
Before talking about this topic, I want to mention why I want to talk about this topic.
First of all, when I received the invitation, I also thought about whether to talk about my special research topic.
Thinking about it later, I think it's too professional.
It may not be useful to everyone.
Then I turned to talk about some tools in the academic world that I have a little experience with.
These three tools.
By the way, let me share my experience with these tools.
Next is my speaker.
The speaker will first do a brief introduction.
Then I will focus on these three tools.
Then show some of the presentations I made.
Presentations made with these three tools.
Finally, a little summary.
Before starting the whole talk, I want to show you a picture.
I believe everyone should have at least a little experience in academic research.
In fact, academic research can be divided into several stages.
Suppose you want to do academic research.
First of all, you need to have the most primitive research idea.
According to this idea, you have to make a corresponding plan.
For example, how much funding to apply for, how many students to receive, and how large your lab needs.
After these things, you are responsible for managing people or managing the progress of the plan.
After having people or progress, you may need to design experiments and collect data.
Then make a corresponding conclusion based on your data.
The last step, I personally think it is a very important step.
When you have the results of your research,
You may have to publish it to the appropriate conference and magazine.
Make the right oral report and promote your results to let others know.
I believe that many research topics are related to this research cycle.
The topic of my report today is related to this research cycle.
But I'm not going to share with you how to find new research topics.
I'm not going to teach you how to do research.
Of course, it has nothing to do with the following topics.
Of course, it has nothing to do with my research topics.
The topic of my report today is related to the sixth topic,
Publication and Presentation.
It has a little bit to do with these two topics.
But I'm not going to teach you how to write a paper or how to do oral expression.
This is another topic.
My main focus today is to show you a picture.
This picture...
Because of copyright issues, I didn't put the original picture on the screen.
I'll just put a copy and I'll show it to you.
After I click on it, I have to change to share, right?
This one.
I don't know if you can see this picture.
If you know Ph.D. Comics, it's actually a...
When you read the textbook, you can draw a picture like this.
I'll show you.
This is a pretty close ecology in the academic world.
When you finish writing the paper, you show it to the boss.
The boss will change it for you for the first, second, and sixth time.
Or later...
According to what he wrote, I don't know how many times.
49 times, right?
Okay.
This is actually something that happens quite often in the academic world.
Because everyone wants to adjust the quality of the paper to be very perfect.
After it's very perfect, it will be sent to the magazine
or find a way to try to publish it.
In this case, you can see that this student is in great pain.
The reason for the pain is actually...
There are several reasons.
The first one is that he changed it back and forth many times.
You can see that the file name is different every time.
Suppose you look at this Revision 8, Common File.
Do you know what the boss changed?
You probably can't tell.
You don't know what the boss did just by looking at the file name.
There's another one. You can look at the photo.
He also wrote a track change.
After you open the file, he might say,
Oh, what did he change in this file?
But if I want to compare this Revision 18 with Revision 2,
it should be quite difficult in this situation.
I'm actually using this comic as a motivation today.
We can use LaTeX to deal with this situation more effectively.
It won't be so painful to change the paper.
I'm going back to the original...
This is my story.
My report today is mainly focused on LaTeX.
I believe that everyone has a little background on LaTeX.
Someone calls it LaTeX.
I personally like to call it LaTeX.
Because the word LaTeX has another meaning.
It's actually a text layout system.
I will introduce a tool called TIKZ later.
It's actually a interface that can display images in LaTeX.
Finally, I mentioned what Beamer is.
It's mainly used to make videos.
Okay, then...
Okay, then I won't talk too much nonsense.
I'll just go straight into what LaTeX is.
LaTeX is actually the most primitive version.
It's called TeX.
It was actually designed and published by Professor Donald Knuth.
It's a layout system.
The so-called layout system means that
it designs the text you want to type
with a text file.
Then, through the layout system,
it can design the font size and distance of the text
and then prepare it into a final version of the file.
This is the so-called layout system.
The version of TeX is very interesting.
You can see it's a strange number.
There's actually a story behind it.
Professor Knuth was quite confident in the text he wrote.
So he felt that the text he wrote had very few bugs.
So if someone found a bug,
he would give a corresponding check as a reward.
Then when TeX was revised,
the number would be added,
but the way it was added was not the usual software,
which is to add 1 and add 2.
It's the number of decimal places after pi.
This is the current version.
The little story is that
if Knuth can't maintain it in the future,
the final version will be changed to pi.
So it's still a prime number.
Then it might become pi at some point.
This is the TeX system.
What we often use in LaTeX
is to add some additional instructions to TeX.
These instructions allow us to
efficiently arrange a file.
For example, in a academic document,
it usually has a title and author.
Then you may want to control the size of the page.
You have to add a password.
LaTeX will wrap these functions
into some very simple applications,
so you don't have to worry about
what the format of the title, author, and password is.
You just need to focus on what your content is.
If you have any questions,
please feel free to interrupt me at any time.
Let me ask you here.
You turned on your microphone,
that is, your speaker.
So if everyone is talking, you can hear it.
I'm not sure if you turned it on or not.
Oh, right.
Okay, that should be fine.
Oh, yes, I just muted it.
Okay, I'll move on to the next page.
I'm sure you all have experience with LaTeX.
I'll just quickly talk about it here.
LaTeX mainly inputs a text file
and then goes through some layout systems.
After going through the layout system,
you can output the final file.
Usually, the text file name is .tex.
After going through the layout system,
there are a lot of different options here.
I just mentioned .tex and LaTeX.
There are other different ones later.
They are used for different layout situations.
The final result of the layout
may be this kind of different file names.
The most common is to arrange the file into a PDF file.
This is the LaTeX system,
which is the most basic concept.
Okay, in the next page,
I'll briefly introduce
the basic structure of a LaTeX file.
I'd like to ask
if you think this is too simple.
You may think it's too simple.
If you all have experience.
No, no.
No?
So do I need to explain a little more?
Yes.
Okay.
I said no, no.
Does that mean you need to skip it?
I think it's just right.
That's it.
Let's talk about it quickly.
Okay, let's talk about it quickly.
A standard LaTeX file is probably...
First, it will have a command
called document class start.
Then the GuaHu part will specify
whether I want this file to be an article,
a report, or a book.
It will first define
the approximate size of this file.
Then usually after this document class,
there will be a part of the area
called use package.
That is to say, this file,
some of the commands it will need,
for example, more complicated math,
or some special font,
or some other functions,
such as if there is a hyperlink,
or some special color,
or drawing.
These enhanced functions
are usually introduced with this use package.
This is the second part of this file.
The next part is that
these commands will specify
what the title of this file is,
and then its author,
the author's name at the back,
and then the date of this file.
It's very simple to use.
You just type in this command
and change this part to say
what the title is,
what the author's name is,
and what the date is.
This part is usually called preamble.
The real file starts
with the beginning document,
the end document.
The latex command is
that most of the commands
are processed by the beginning and end.
The beginning means
that I am now at the beginning of a certain environment,
and the end is the end of this environment.
So from the 10th and 15th lines,
this means that
between the 10th and 15th lines,
I will describe the content of this file.
After defining the file,
we can see that the 11th line
is a command called makeTitle.
This command means that
based on the title author date I specified earlier,
I will make a corresponding
title shape.
The important part of this part is that
when you do this,
you don't have to worry at all
about how big the title font is,
how big the author font is,
or how much the date font should be.
This part of the latex
will help you
to arrange it according to the specified command.
So all you have to do is
focus on your content.
For the 12th to 14th lines,
I will simply show an example.
It can arrange some mathematical parameters.
Here I use a command called
beginAlign and endAlign
to insert a mathematical value
with a whole width.
This command will also add a
function number behind the function.
This is a very simple one.
Of course, there are a lot of commands behind it.
I don't want to mention so many time factors.
This is a standard example.
Next, I will show you that
if you are really interested in
making real latex files,
there are some that I have used,
and there are some editors
or some interfaces that I recommend.
There are usually two types of editors.
There is a type of editor
that I call Latex Specific.
This type of editor
will automatically
compile the compiled file
and sometimes compile the PDF
to the same interface.
So you can
click some quick buttons at the same time
and you can quickly see
the contents of the compiled file.
Then there are often used
text maker, text studio, textworks, etc.
I just had a discussion with the host
that there are some web page interfaces
such as Overleaf or ShareLatex.
These interfaces mean that
you don't need to install anything at all.
Your stuff is stored in the remote server.
As long as you open the web page, you can edit it.
You don't have to worry about
which editor to use to edit it.
It has done a good job of compatibility.
As long as you focus on the content of the file,
the format of the file
will automatically arrange it for you.
This is one type.
I call it Latex Specific.
There is another type.
I call it General.
Basically, as long as you can open the text file,
you can do this.
I often use things like
Vim, Emacs, etc.
I personally like to use Sublime Text.
You can also use Windows Notebook.
It depends on your preference.
As long as you can open the text file,
you can edit and save it.
As for the layout system,
if you use a single board Latex,
you need to install a larger system.
This system includes
the editing interface I mentioned earlier.
I often use things like
TechLive, MiKTX, or MacTek.
These are used separately.
TechLive can be used for Windows or Linux.
MiKTX is mainly used for Windows.
This is mainly used for Mac.
After editing,
you can choose
which PDF monitor you want.
There are many different choices.
This is mainly to give you an overview.
What are the most basic Latex tools?
How do we make a simple text file?
What is the content?
The first is the background.
Next, I will introduce the main focus of this talk.
I think everyone will be more interested in this.
But if you come to listen,
you should already have a good understanding of Latex.
So for this picture,
you might think it's acceptable.
The meaning of this picture is
Latex vs Word.
Horizontal represents the complexity of processing files.
Y-axis represents the time you need.
The meaning of this picture is
when your file is very small,
maybe only one page,
or one or two pages,
not much content,
maybe only text,
when it's simpler,
in this case, you can use Word
to make this file in a very short time.
But when your file is very large,
for example, you want to write a journal paper,
you want to write a book,
some problems will arise.
At present, I still don't know
how to use Microsoft Word
to effectively solve these problems.
But Latex has a corresponding method.
Here, I would like to say
that I will compare Word and Latex.
I personally use Latex more often,
so I might be a little biased.
I might think Latex is better.
The same function,
Word may also be able to achieve.
If you want to discuss with me,
please feel free to interrupt me.
The first point I want to discuss
is the difficulty of mathematical editing.
If you use Microsoft Word,
the tool you often use
may be called a square editor.
Some people may think that
the square editor is too ugly.
They will use tools like MathType.
These tools are mainly
used to edit the square editor with a mouse.
So you need to use a mouse
to click here and there
to select some up and down icons,
to select some root numbers,
some special mathematical symbols.
I don't say this is not good.
This is an input method.
But if you use Latex,
suppose you want to input the following symbol,
you can use Word at all.
You don't have to leave the keyboard.
Just input these symbols with the keyboard
and you can output the following mathematical equation.
You may think
how to convert this equation
to these strange symbols.
This actually depends on
your familiarity with Latex.
For example,
Begin and Align
means that I inserted a row of wide mathematical equations.
The input method
is actually quite similar to the way we read.
It's the same from left to right.
If I need a square,
I will enter a square.
If I need the initial a,
I will enter an a.
This command means
I want the initial a in mathematics.
It's very similar to the way
to input words in mathematics.
I need an initial u, initial c, initial v,
and then a right square.
This symbol means up and down,
and then up and down plus 1.
So this command
is not the final result,
but in terms of reading,
it's actually quite in line with people's reading habits.
It's the same from left to right.
Another advantage I use is
when Latex is in the array,
you can add blanks and arrays at will.
So you can put a very complex mathematical equation
with very effective arrays.
You can insert an array or a blank
to make it easier to read.
So like me,
this equation represents this part.
Then according to the following
different structures of this mathematical equation
to make a relative array.
So when you want to change the mathematical equation,
you can also easily go back
to the relative Latex part
to change its original code.
This is my personal experience.
The first advantage is that
the mathematical equation is very easy to input.
Let's pause for a moment.
Do you have any questions?
I want to...
I guess I should turn this on.
Then you can turn it on.
It's okay.
Then I'll just use your side to talk.
I want to share something with you.
It's a powerpoint plug-in.
It's called Iguana Text.
I'll post it in the chat room for everyone to see.
It's actually...
Because you mentioned that
the Microsoft equation is an editor.
It's actually very ugly.
So someone developed a powerpoint plug-in.
In fact, all the mathematical equations
are still using Latex code.
Basically, it's also
what the author shared on the screen.
It just happens to be a plug-in
that can be placed directly in your powerpoint.
So it's beautiful.
This Iguana Text
is a very, very advanced
Microsoft equation editor.
So I'll post it in the chat room
and share it with you.
Thank you for sharing.
Because I...
My computer is actually Linux.
So it's...
Iguana Text can't be installed at all.
It can be installed, but...
It's very painful.
So I'm just...
I'm not familiar with this aspect of the plug-in.
Okay, so this is...
I personally think the first advantage is
to edit in a mathematical way.
Okay, what about the second part?
This is a personal experience
of sharing.
That is to say,
when you need to deal with
a very large file,
suppose you want to write a doctor's thesis,
and then suppose your research results
are very rich,
you write up to 500 pages.
Yes, write a 500-page doctor's thesis.
If you have Word experience,
that is, you open a 500-page Word file,
what will happen?
I haven't really opened it myself,
but I've heard people share their experience
that usually this situation is...
First of all, when you open the file,
it will be very, very slow
because it needs to scan all 500 pages.
Then next,
if you have some text blocks in the middle,
some blocks you pulled yourself,
it will be slower
because it needs to load these blocks.
Okay, but for our purpose,
these steps are not necessary.
We just need to change
a paragraph in our text.
So the focus of our focus
should be to pick this paragraph
and then modify it.
After that,
that is, to do this,
it should not need to be loaded
into other blocks.
If it's Word,
I don't know yet
how to avoid this problem.
Suppose you have a 500-page thesis.
If it's LaTeX,
it can use a...
It's a bit like writing a word.
Suppose you write a thesis,
you can use a file called
Thesis.txt for your thesis.
Under this file,
you separate the different content.
You may need to separate a file,
Introduction a file,
Topic 1 separate a file.
Under Topic 1,
you can have your own Introduction,
your own introduction,
your own translation.
That is to say,
you make your file
a system plan.
Distribute different content
into different files.
The advantage of this is that
if I want to change
Example 1 of Topic 1,
I just need to open this file
and make a relative modification.
I don't need to
load all the files.
This is the first advantage.
The second advantage is
if I want to see
the result of this part of the translation,
I can translate this
Thesis.txt file,
but I can put
these unnecessary ones,
such as
Example 1,
Introduction,
Topic 2,
Topic 3,
Conclusion,
I can just block it.
I have a simple version.
Thesis.txt only has
Example 1 in Topic 1.
I only do translation
for this file.
So I can see right away that
I changed this thing,
and it will look like this
in the real file.
So this can reach
a very large file,
we make it a system partition,
then we can edit
a small file,
and we can see
the result of the editing very quickly.
This is my personal opinion
the second advantage of LaTeX.
Next is
to continue to the next one.
The third advantage
is the compatibility problem.
If you often use
Microsoft Word,
you may still remember
about ten years ago
there was a
Dock version
to DockX version
a pain period.
Dock version is mainly
I think DockX version
is Office 2007
Word 2007 plus
about ten years ago.
Anyway,
there is this pain period.
Before that,
it was all DOC version.
Like this file format change
there will be some
some trouble.
Suppose you wrote a paper
twenty years ago,
you may now
the format will run out.
This thing,
especially in the academic world
it should not be allowed.
Suppose you have a picture
you run out
then your data will run out.
So it's very troublesome
to maintain anything.
Microsoft has such
DOC to DOCX
history.
So it's hard to guarantee
DOCX may be changed
to other formats.
It's hard to say.
So this is a
history of Word.
Another one is
even if you use the same file
you use DOCX.
If you use different versions of Word
it may run out a bit.
Maybe its line
or font will be a bit
not the same as your original edit.
Suppose some people don't have Word
they use Pages or LibreOffice
it may be different.
This is the same
in academic papers
a very disadvantageous phenomenon.
Another one is
you may use different computers
different operating systems
Windows, Mac.
This file
may not be able to run
in other operating systems.
If you use LaTeX
its editable file
is actually Word.
So Word
you can run a lot of things.
You can run a notebook
and Mac, Linux
all can be run.
The final file is PDF
almost every platform can support PDF.
There are a lot of software
you can use.
This is my
third advantage
from my experience.
The file format is Word
and there is no DOC, DOCX
or other problems.
Next I will
Is there any questions?
All right.
Next I will look at
one of my personal experiences.
Look at the picture on the left.
I will draw it roughly.
Suppose you have a paper
you are writing a journal paper.
This box represents
one of your pictures
it is Figure 1.
Then you are in the text
in the paragraph
you need to mention Figure 1.
Then in a certain place
you need to mention 20%
this number.
Then in another place
you need to mention
X equals 10
this message.
Then this 20%
and X equals 10
it may actually be
one of the Figure 1
some data points
the conclusion.
I use red here
means
red means
my experiment data.
The file is here
there is no problem
Word or LaTeX
can reach this function.
Now suppose there is a situation
suppose your boss is not satisfied with Figure 1
he is not satisfied with the parameters
he thinks you change the parameters
to see if these numbers
become more effective.
So in some cases
you may need
after you finish writing the paper
you need to update your data.
Maybe you need to run again
run to a new set of data.
In terms of updating
in concept
the red part
needs to be updated together.
Because you run a new result
your Figure content changes.
So this Figure 1
it
you may also
in the process of text editing
this Figure 1 becomes Figure 2.
So this
this
Figure 1 also needs to be relatively modified.
This number
needs to be modified
according to your experiment data.
If you use Word
you can think about
if you use Word
how to achieve this?
Maybe you just
run MATLAB again
generate another picture
and then
after the picture is generated
you put the picture back
back to Figure 1
put the picture back
then you have to remember
you need to change 20%
you may now become 15%
and now X may not be 12
X may become 12
So
a job
you need to change Figure 1
at the same time you have to pay attention
you have to change 20%
with X
all these things need to be changed.
When your file is complicated
this thing will appear
more times.
So if it appears
100 times
then you change 95
you have 5 forgotten to change.
Then your data is wrong.
Okay, then LaTeX has a solution
that is
first you can use
Label and Reference
to update
your Figure numbers.
If you use LaTeX
to write paper
this value should be used often.
This is my own
experience
that is
20% and X is 10
These two data points
are actually related to Figure 1.
So before you use LaTeX
you can
when you write MATLAB
you generate two text files at the same time
output 20% and X is 10
that is, the city directly input these two numbers
it is for two different files
when you write paper
you directly include these two files
right
so you
when you write a file
you have to pay attention
that is
what value
is related to what
then put all these things
together
then it is convenient to update
this is one of my
experience
because
I also studied for a while
then I found out that
LaTeX has this
quite convenient function
that
the last one I
this picture I
showed you before
that is
final.doc
if you use Word
you will keep changing
and then
change the name
then you may track
do not know how
this can track
but it may be
very difficult to say
the difference is very far
version to track
that if LaTeX, then
first I have to state that
LaTeX itself
it does not provide
that is the file tracking function
it needs to add some other
software
then
I often use my own
software called GIT
that if you have written
that is
a relatively large software
project
GIT is actually a management
that is
a program code
version control system
it can control
that is to say
this program code
at what time
by which
program designer changed
what part of who changed
then
these changes
it will have a relative record
then
between different users
to do
these changes
record
it integrated
in the same project
so
this
GIT is actually
a pretty
I personally think
pretty great invention
because it can
like that
software engineering
some super big project
it can use
a lot of people together
that is
a lot of engineers
to do the same software
then it can ensure that
different engineers
will not change
other engineers
the result
so
that
this function
it actually
needs to use
LaTeX file
plus GIT
to achieve
that
I only simply list
a few keywords
if you use
GIT
this software
to monitor
that is
LaTeX file
file
change
text
you wait
to come up
and say
you can control
that is
your file
at what time
to change
what place
you
usually
commonly modified
that is
you add text
or delete text
then
right
then GIT
has a feature
that is
every time you modify
you can do
something like
change block
it can
send a simple report
that
in this version
which file was changed
then
you can do
very detailed
so
that
with this feature
you do not have to
that
change content
it forced
because
this is not easy
to read
that
use GIT
can also be
very easy to
reply to the changes
before
then
you can do
a lot of people
in this
cooperation
that
this is
my personal experience
that
finally show you
I mentioned
the first five
advantages
that
probably
the second
with
this
with this
second
and the fourth
is my personal experience
that
good
later if
we use more advanced
there are some other
features
like
we can
write a paper
in
is to use
reference
when
it can
automatically
help you
form a format
automatically
help you
arrange
that
you write
paper
you want to
change
that
good
this is mainly
that I
currently
include the
part of
that
you have any
questions
or want to
discuss
it
is very
welcome
that
I will
continue
good
that
next
I want to
discuss
a called
TIKZ
I'm sorry
I have a
small problem
that
you said
you can
output
a certain
or a certain
number
when
that
side I do not
understand
you say
I can
picture
picture, then
I can
understand
that I
output a
picture
and then
I just
reference
to that
picture
and then
feature
will not
change
but you
is to produce
a picture
you are using
tools like
MATLAB
or something like
that
you are using
RR
good
that should
also be
the same
meaning
good
I mean
that
because
this is just
a reference
picture
if my
feature 1
is a
long
picture
I did not
draw
then this
20%
represents
that
the second
data point
is the first
of 20%
it represents
this
question
and then
in the file
I
especially
use
a number
20%
to
represent
is
particularly
emphasize
this picture
of a
feature
like this
here
integrated
that is to say
when you output
this picture
has included
20%
of this information
in the
inside
Oh
right
that
good
so now if you want
to update data
you run
the experiment
20%
becomes 15%
in this picture
looks like
15%
but you
you become
you have to go back
to your paper
part of
the 20%
manually changed
to 15%
so
your
figure
is not a
that it actually
contains another
thing I do not know
what this
is called
because this
I have not used
but your
figure is not a
example of a
.eps
such a file
I
look at
my back
there is no
case
Oh
I
that
but I can
that I
take as an example
suppose
now this is
what I want
to be
good
then
he
he is
this strange
picture
and then
suppose
I wrote
later
when I
specifically
mentioned
that
this function
is the lowest
point
0.2
I
that
now
suppose you
teach
you to run
another picture
this function
of the picture
that you become
you later
in that
article
when you
do not
0.2
this place
you have to
follow your
picture
to do
relative
modification
that
OK
?
I guess
his question
should be
that
I will mention
the next section
I personally
prefer to
use
latex
to
draw
that
of course
I know a lot of users
will save
EPS
right
that I just
mentioned the
problem is
that he
is with you
picture
is not
directly
related
so
should be
said
if you are
in the
picture
this
can achieve
this thing
but I
want to mention
that
latex
can also
do
control
these
things
that
I
want to
say
this page
is that
you
file
some
part of
the data
with
some other
other
part of
the data
they are
related to each other
that if
you
are writing
files after
you did not
put this thing
into consideration
that you have to
manually update
figure 1
this 20%
and manually
update this
three parts
because you
write files
when you did not
pay attention
to you
is to write
separately
when you
update
you become
because you
know that the
red part
is actually
these data
points these
values are
related to each
other
so if you
have this
concept, then
you can
put
figure 1
these
or these
values
are output
into three
different files
figure 1
maybe you
figure 1.
EPS
is a file
and then this
20%
you may
output
a data
1.
TXT
and then
this place
you may output
a data
2.
TXT
and then this
data 1 and
data 2
you have to
use your
MATLAB
or R to
generate
when you
are drawing
a good calculation
at the same time
you put
20%
and 10%
it out
output
into two
TXT
EPS
and then you
input data
1.
TXT
and data
2.
TXT
so
this is
ok
I know
this is
a personal
use
I think this
is very practical
and if you
want to change
a lot of things
at once
you have to
remember this
thing
I
wrap up
a little bit
now this
20%
but
when I do
figure 1
I do
another thing
called
data 1
equals
measure
right
thank you
ok
this is mainly
practical
and
this
doesn't seem
to have a book
talking about
this
this is
more of a
writing habit
here
to remind
the distance
is
time
I
will
talk about
TIKZ
and
Beamer
TIKZ
is a
language
that can
draw a
picture
and
it can
directly
do the
drawing
in
Lighttime
and
I
personally
like it
because
this is a
basic introduction
so I
jump to
some basic
things
that
I
just
mentioned
is the
EPS file
so I
think you
have some
basic
knowledge
of the
file
basically
a
file
can be
classified
as a
quantity
file
or
a
dot
file
a
quantity
file
different
lines
different shapes
different words
and their
color they
are stored
information
so when you
enlarge the
picture
when it
can be
based on
these
shapes
colors
to do
the same
proportion
so you
will not see
these
sentence
phenomenon
that
dot
picture
means that
that
special
academic report
academic research
it
actually
quantity picture
is a better
choice
because
back to the
beginning
is that you
have to do
academic report
you have to
say that
the precise
and concise
is that
you describe
things to be
precise
like this
is not
acceptable
like this
is not
acceptable
these
pictures
is
TIKZ
What this
suite
you might
be more
probably
standard
because
the
good
caution
TIKZ
is
a
process
called
TIKZ
picture
and
TIKZ
picture
to
describe
his
description
is
a
point
he
designated
coordinates
like this
is the
seventh line of
this
point
represents
the
beginning of the
point
has been drawn
to 0.50
so I
meant to draw
this line
and this
bar arrow
represents
I want to draw
a line
and the arrow is
close to the
second
point on the
right
this
reference
means that
I'm
at 1.50
this
coordinate
I want to
put a node
and the
node content
is x
on the right
so it is
this
node is
put a
text command
and then
the back
Chinese number
can specify that
I put the text
after it has some
relative position
or color
can be
a lot of details
can adjust
your arrow
that symbol is
which line
is the first line
of the Chinese number
is
right
so your arrow
is this
is drawn
is
a
the
seventh line
is only
drawn arrow
that
the eighth line
is
only draw
x
that
nine and
ten lines
is that
it can combine
the command
I can draw
arrow
while drawing
text
command
can be connected
so it
means that
from 0.5
draw to
1.0
draw a
arrow
after
I want to draw
a y
so
I can draw
x-axis and y-axis
and then
some other
example
I can draw a
rectangle
is that
I specify
four
four points
one of the
points
I
minus 1
this point
draw to
1.1
this is
two relative
points
and then
I want to draw
this 0.0
is the origin
and then
the radius is 1
Green
means that
I want to draw it
in green
that
14-16
means that
I want to draw
draw a line
and then
the format of this line
it is to
draw a line
and then
it is this
curve
thick and
dash
it means
the curve
and then
these things
mean that
the turning point
so I
draw a line
and then
this turning point
here I use
a cartoon
cartoon
means that
the front
is the
coordinate
0.0
is the
coordinate
its grammar
is the
first value
angle
with
degree
and then
the second value
is the radius
so I
equal to
equal to this
point
start
and then draw
the angle
is 330
and then this
cycle is to say
back to the original
point means
that I have specified
these turning points
I can draw this
triangle
that
this simple
some instructions
to introduce
good
that I
here mainly to mention
is that
you use this set of
tools
you can be very
accurate to draw
the picture you want
because of
these numbers
you can see
that
this circle
it with this
rectangle
is cut
you can imagine
if you use
PowerPoint to draw
this picture
you can draw
that rectangle
and circle
cut
may be
you need to adjust
quite a long
should be able to draw
but to adjust
quite a long
and then because you specify
this set of tools
you can
very
can ensure that
this
triangle
is the
inner circle
and you can
be sure that
this point
on the circle
simply put
I want to say
that you use
TIKZ
this set
is very accurate
you can draw
the picture
very accurate
that
this comparison
I skip
good
because of
time
next
I will introduce
a
called
PGF
PLUS
that
it is actually
based on
TIKZ
a set
of
pictures
that
it is mainly
it can draw
such a picture
and then it
has a very good compatibility
with
LaTeX
and then
it
is also I thought
because it is
text
so you can
use
GIT
to do
that version
control
so
simply put
you draw
a picture
you can
ensure that
my picture
changed
because
if you
adjust the position
you adjust
a pixel
you may be in
Word
is more difficult to see
the change
but if you use
text
you use
TIKZ
to track
the word
you can see
the change
in the number
that
this
because of
time
so I
give you a
simple
example
is good
this is also
my
picture
and then
stick to the
paper
inside
the usual
workflow is
I use
MATLAB or
Python
or
suppose
to use
R
write a
script
after writing
it
out of
the corresponding
picture
and then
save as a
picture
file
to see
you want to
save
PNG
to see
the
first problem
is that
these words
are too small
but the
size of the
word is actually
depending on
the ratio of
your picture
if you put
the picture
in some
words
in
some words
in some
words
actually look
like it is
okay
but when you
put it
big
words
look
very
small
because
the
size of the
word is actually
related to the
file
so
control the
size of the
word
this thing
should be
in the
LaTeX
to deal with
it
and not
directly
save as
EPS
because you
save as
EPS
after
the
size of
your word
is
too
small
you
should
put
the
picture
in
some
words
in
some
words
in
some
words
in
some
words
in
some
words
in
some
words
in
some
words
in
some
words
in
some
words
in
some
words
in
some
words
in
some
words
in
some
words
but
in
the
code
can
submit
a document
may be
a different document
is said
some
words
exercises
to say
length
is how much
08 with
the
appearance
of what
should be
saved
when we have
another file
have these two
files separate
whether it
is divided
directly from
habit
Sut
corresponds to
the TIKZ
relationship
with this
right
and then
use these codes
when you add
directly to your
LaTeX file
inside
you have to use
you have to
file 1, file 2
have to add
that
after doing this
you have to
slightly adjust the
size of the
image
these of course
is to adjust
the appearance of
this line
this is
you have to do
relative adjustments
according to
your file
this
I personally recommend
this workflow
is because when you want to run
another picture
you just change
the raw data
you can
run again
you do not change the
picture you just change
the raw data
so you
this data will
be equal to
running another picture
that you do not have to worry
about the size of this
word
Equation20
or other
places
this is my
recommended workflow
so I
personally
use
the
right
I
10 minutes
OK
I
do not have much
left
if
Bimmer
it
is good
I finally mentioned
Bimmer
is actually
based on
LaTeX
it is
a set of
video
system
like
my video
is made
with
Bimmer
that
I personally
think the
first
time I
use
Bimmer
is
after
the
first
time I
use
Bimmer
it
is
actually
the
first time
I
use
Bimmer
but
the
second
time
I
used
TiX
to
do
this
.