First of all, I would like to welcome everyone to our Chira Talk on August 4th.
We are honored to have Jason Hong, a student from Hong Shi An University, to give a speech on his latest research.
Today's topic is Coherent Exotonic Effects in 2D Materials.
Before we start, let me briefly introduce Jason.
Jason graduated from the University of Taiwan in the Department of Physics.
He did his Ph.D. at UC Berkeley and the Lawrence Berkeley National Lab.
He is currently working as a postdoc in Michigan.
His current field of expertise is the application of super fast light in solid matter.
His main research topics include graphene optical sensors,
coherent exotonic effects in 2D materials, and cavity exotonic polaroids.
In today's talk, he will introduce some basic principles and applications of super fast light.
He will use super fast light and light-matter interactions to understand the dynamics of electrons in solid state physics.
He will also discuss related research in super fast light and exotonic effects.
If there are no further questions, let's welcome Jason to start his talk.
Hello everyone.
I am very happy to be invited to Chira Talk.
Today's topic is Coherent Exotonic Effects in 2D Materials.
This is today's outline.
In the beginning, I will talk about what super fast light is, the history of super fast light, and a very important technique called pump probe measurement.
On the other hand, I will briefly explain what is special about the acetone in the coherent exotonic materials.
Finally, I will talk about my recent research.
In the coherent exotonic materials, there are not only acetone, but also biacetone effects.
I will start with super fast light.
The so-called super fast light is actually a super fast phenomenon that uses light to study the extremity of time.
Generally speaking, the definition of a super fast phenomenon is the phenomenon between a femtosecond and a picosecond.
We call it a super fast phenomenon, but there is no clear definition.
Femtosecond is 10 to the power of negative 50 square seconds, and picosecond is 10 to the power of negative 20 square seconds.
However, we will briefly introduce the extent of time later.
The main reason why we use light to study these super fast phenomena is that there are many super fast phenomena that cannot be observed in other ways.
For example, the general method of electrolysis.
Everyone knows that electrolysis is basically to charge.
The charging time is actually around nanoseconds.
For example, the switch speed of these computers is about gigahertz, and gigahertz is about nanoseconds.
Even if the electrolysis is done well, the time you can observe is only about nanoseconds.
There is no way to do better.
If you want to observe these super fast phenomena with a shorter time period, you have to use light.
At this time, we have a technique called pump-up technique, and we can use it to observe these super fast phenomena.
Basically, in my own concept, light is basically photography, which is the art of capturing light.
For example, when we usually shoot small objects, this is called micro light.
When we turn a black and white camera into a color camera, what we are actually doing is photography.
We can study the reaction of a object to a different amount of light with different energy.
This is called photography.
The meaning of super fast photography is actually high-speed photography.
For example, when we watch TV, when a baseball player throws a ball, he basically uses high-speed photography to do these things.
Super fast photography basically uses high-speed photography to the extreme.
What is photography?
There is a picture here.
Basically, photography is that you have a light source, and the light source shines on your object, on your model.
The model will reflect light or penetrate light.
People don't penetrate light, so this is reflected light.
In the end, the reflected light is taken down by the photographer with these cameras.
This is called photography.
Sometimes you need something else.
For example, you need another assistant to remind your model to remember to smile.
When you add all these things together, this is called photography.
When it comes to super fast photography, I have to talk about the interesting history.
A long time ago, people had a question.
When a horse is running, is it possible that when the horse is running, the four legs will float in the air for a moment?
It may not seem like a problem now, but you may think it's not useful at all.
This was in the 1870s.
These people were very passionate about racing horses.
This was a very interesting question at the time.
People wanted to know how the horse ran.
But you can't see it with your eyes.
You can't record it and tell everyone how the horse ran.
At that time, there was a man named Leland Stanford.
He was the governor of California.
He thought that when the horse was running, the four legs might float in the air for a moment.
But no one believed him.
Leland Stanford was very rich.
He asked Edwin Muybridge, who was a photographer, to research how to capture these fast things.
He gave him a $25,000 research fund.
I think it was a huge amount of money at the time.
After several years of hard work, Muybridge invented the shutter.
The picture on the left is the shutter he invented.
Basically, it's a few boards.
He used a mechanical method to make the board fall.
When the board falls, it blocks the light.
When the light does not pass, it means that the camera will not continue to expose the light.
The shutter speed can be up to 500 microseconds.
This is where he did the experiment.
Basically, it's a racecourse.
The horse will run from here to here.
There are 24 cameras.
Each camera has a shutter.
When the horse runs like this, it will take pictures like this.
Then he got a picture like this.
Basically, you can see that there are 12 pictures here.
This is the continuous process of the horse running.
You can see that these two pictures clearly show that the horse's four legs are in the air.
But it's definitely not like the picture above.
This is a very wrong concept.
When the horse is in the air, it's definitely not the state of the legs.
It's probably the situation where the legs are shrunk.
This is an interesting story.
In that era of super fast light, the method was to take a light source and take a picture of the object you wanted to take.
How do we choose which time to take a picture?
Use a mechanical shutter.
The shutter switch is very fast.
At this time, we can take a picture that is short in time.
But everyone found that the mechanical shutter has a limit.
Basically, you can't do it faster than microseconds.
The next time is nanosecond.
How to enter this nanosecond?
An important invention is the light bulb.
The light bulb was invented in 1880.
So it was before Moonbridge.
What is a light bulb?
Light is produced by electricity.
Of course, ordinary light bulbs can't do this.
But the next invention is this.
We can use electricity to produce light.
So we can adjust this electricity.
The light we produce is a form of pulse.
You can turn on this light at a certain time and turn off this light at another time.
You can use this pulse to hit your object.
When the object is reflected back to the camera,
you just need to turn off the shutter when the pulse stops.
In this way, you can measure the time it takes for the pulse to stop.
This method is called frequency-shift observation.
The main concept is that we can't quickly adjust the shutter of the camera.
So we change it to adjust the light source.
Here are some photos of stroboscopes.
This is basically what you see in many photo studios.
On the left is a woman waving a golf club.
This speed is also very fast.
Basically, every frame is your flashlight hitting the woman.
Then it reflects back and you take a picture.
At the next moment, the next pulse hits the woman and you take another picture.
This inventor is a professor at MIT named Edgerton.
He has a nickname called Papa Flash.
Basically, Flash is Flashlight.
It's the light source you need for frequency-shift observation.
This method was invented in 1931.
The picture on the right is an example.
You can use this method to take a picture of the state of the bullet in the air.
We use frequency-shift observation to reach the level of nanoseconds.
How do we get to the level of picoseconds and femtoseconds?
The first thing is why we are particularly interested in picoseconds and femtoseconds.
It's because there are many physical phenomena that occur at this time.
For example, phonon vibration.
The vibration of the metal in this material is actually at the level of picoseconds.
There are also a lot of electrons in this material.
The events of activation and relaxation are actually at the level of femtoseconds.
This is why we want to get to the level of picoseconds and femtoseconds.
The main discovery that can break through nanoseconds is the discovery of magnetic laser.
Laser is basically a game media.
When the light passes through the game media, the light becomes stronger because of the feedback of the game media.
If you put the light in an optical cavity,
The optical cavity is basically made up of two high-reflection mirrors.
At this time, it becomes a laser.
Of course, we want the laser to output, so we use a semi-transparent mirror on one side to let the laser pass through.
At this time, you have a laser.
Another interesting thing is that when you have a cavity,
What frequency of light can become a laser?
The important thing is that when the light passes through the cavity,
How to make it a coherent line?
The condition is that when the light passes through the cavity, the light-returned phase is the same.
This is the condition.
We can convert it to frequency.
At this time, you can see that the allowed optical mode is actually a positive integer.
Multiply by c divided by 2L, where L is the length of the optical cavity.
I have a question.
What kind of material is the game media?
There are many kinds of game media.
We can see all kinds of lasers on the market.
For example, there are semi-transparent lasers, CO2 lasers, and hydrogen peroxide lasers.
These are the game media.
Semi-transparent lasers are used as game media.
CO2 lasers are used as game media.
There are all kinds of game media.
As long as there are four lasers, there are two conditions.
The first condition is that there should be game media.
The second condition is that there should be an optical cavity.
All lasers are indispensable.
There are many ways to do it.
Can you give more details about the output coupler?
What is its main function?
Does it allow light to pass through?
The output coupler is actually a mirror.
It's just a semi-transparent mirror.
The first thing is that when the light travels through the cavity,
the gain should be greater than the loss.
The reflection rate should not be too low.
If the reflection rate is too low, the loss will be too high.
The gain should be greater than the loss.
The output coupler can also leak some light.
This creates a laser that can be used.
It means that half of the light can pass through the cavity.
This is the basic structure of a laser.
The current laser looks completely different from this one.
You can still point out what is game media, what is mirror, and what is its cavity.
The frequency of light that can be allowed is the frequency mode of the equality space.
Let's see what happens.
The picture above is a simulation of an optical mode in the cavity.
This is the output of the laser.
There is only one mode now.
The difference between the two modes is c divided by 2L.
You can see that the frequency of red and green are slightly different.
If we add these two modes together,
you can see that there is a beating effect.
You can see that there is something that looks like a pulse.
When there are four modes, this is more obvious.
These four modes are c divided by 2L.
You can see that the pulse of the output of the laser is more obvious.
Now we can keep adding until there are 30 modes.
You can see that there is a very obvious pulse here.
The general ultrafast laser has hundreds or thousands of modes.
This will make the pulse very obvious.
Another thing is why this thing is called a lock mode laser.
This is because when you add a lot of modes,
there is a condition that their phase must be fixed.
Then these pulses will be formed.
This blue line above
means that when the phase of these modes is locked,
you will see that there is a pulse.
However, when each optical mode has a different phase,
when they have a random phase,
you will see that this is probably a general CW laser.
The invention of lock mode laser is surprising.
The invention of lock mode laser was in the 1960s.
It was Charles Townes.
They made Mesa or something.
The first invention of lock mode laser was in 1965.
Five years after the invention of lock mode laser,
everyone has already discovered this lock mode laser.
After a period of time,
everyone tried to shorten the pulse of the laser.
In 1980,
a method called CPA was invented.
It's called True Pulse Amplification.
Basically, it stretches the laser pulse,
amplifies it, and compresses it.
At that time,
it took about 6 femtoseconds to make a die laser.
It was in 1985.
Another technology was invented.
It's called Tie Sapphire.
It just changes the laser gain media.
There are many reasons why Tie Sapphire is good.
Basically, it is a semiconductor laser.
At that time,
the technology of Tie Sapphire made rapid progress.
In 2000,
it took about 4 femtoseconds.
This is equivalent to a light oscillation.
A light in a visible oscillation.
This is a limit.
There is no way to continue.
The application of lock mode laser is very wide.
The first application is to use the laser's pulse.
It can be used for a short time.
Basically, it uses rapid pulses
to study atomic physics, solid physics,
chemical reactions, and so on.
It can also be used for light communication
and higher harmonic generation.
Another direction is
because the pulse laser
collects energy that does not have a pulse time
in the time that there is a pulse.
This means that in the pulse time,
the laser beam will be very strong.
Generally, you can get the power
to 10 to the power of 8 or 10 to the power of 4.
This can be used to do a lot of interesting things.
If you have super strong light sources,
you can use it to do non-linear light studies.
Recently, some people want to do nuclear fusion.
There are also laser cutting or cosmetic surgery.
You can see that the picture on the right
is basically the laser's peak power.
It is the laser beam within the pulse time.
It is also a very fast-growing laser.
It can now reach the power of 1 terawatt.
Of course, you can use the laser as a light source.
Because the pulse time is very short,
you should be able to take very short pictures.
But there is a problem here.
The time is too short to figure out
how to trigger an event.
How do you know when the event will happen?
If you don't know when it will happen,
you can't take pictures at all.
So the next question is
how to find the event you want.
The general approach is like this.
The picture on the right.
We are using a pulse laser.
It will emit a pulse.
The red dot is a pulse.
When the red dot reaches the beam splitter,
the pulse will be divided into two parts.
One part will go through the pump beam.
The other part will go through the pull beam.
The pump beam will hit the sample first.
After the pump beam hits the sample,
the pull beam will pass the sample
and reach the detector.
What is the purpose of doing this?
We use pump beam to trigger the sample,
such as electrons or electrons.
Anyway, no matter what we do,
we generate an event.
After a while,
we use pull beam to observe the event.
Another thing you can do is
to adjust the time difference
between the pull beam and pump beam.
You can adjust the time difference
You will put the pull beam on a delay stage.
When you adjust the delay stage,
the pull beam will start to change.
Then you can see
the evolution of the event over time.
For example,
this is a pump probe measurement on a pull beam.
This is how it works.
Basically,
a pull beam with a wavelength of 800 nm
hits the sample.
Then you use a wavelength of 100 nm
as a probe.
When the probe passes the sample,
you use the detector to observe the pull beam.
To simplify it into a dynamic picture,
it looks like this.
First, you use the pump beam
to stimulate the electron.
When the electron decays for a while,
you use the pull beam
to observe the graphene absorption
under the current situation.
The experimental picture looks like this.
When the time is zero,
the pump beam and the pull beam
are in synch.
This is when you get the biggest reaction.
As time goes by,
the electron slowly relaxes
and decays back to its original state.
I have a question.
Sorry.
Why does the curve
have a different direction?
This is the experimental detail.
Okay.
This is not what I want to talk about.
But this is an interesting thing.
This is what the paper discusses.
The blue line is graphene in charge neutral,
which means it is not doping.
You can see this.
This should be the absorption increase.
I can tell you that
this line represents the absorption increase.
It means that when you hit an optical beam
to stimulate the electron,
you will produce more carriers,
resulting in a higher conductivity of graphene.
When the conductivity increases,
the absorption increases.
The red line is graphene in doping state.
Why is it negative?
It means that the absorption is decreasing.
The reason is that
when you hit an optical beam,
you will increase the temperature of the electron.
When the temperature of the electron increases,
the conductivity will decrease.
Because it has more scattering.
When the conductivity decreases,
the absorption decreases.
Do you mean that it will produce photons?
Yes.
Okay. Thank you.
Basically,
this means that
there are a lot of things to study
in the super fast speed.
Very interesting.
Thank you. Please go on.
On the other hand,
I want to talk about
the two-dimensional semiconductor.
The first two-dimensional material discovered is graphene.
As you know,
graphene is made by the method of exfoliation.
Basically, you take a tape
and put the graphite on it.
Then you stick the tape on the substrate
and tear it up.
Then you will find that
there is a layer of graphene on the substrate.
It looks like this.
Then you look under the microscope
and you can find these
only one-dimensional flakes.
This is the band structure of graphene.
Another thing is
this is the band structure of graphene.
There are two Dirac cones.
There are two different Dirac cones.
The reason for these two cones
is that
graphene has inversion symmetry
and time reversal symmetry.
As a result,
this conduction band
and valence band
will always have
a intersection point.
Basically,
this thing
means that
graphene is always a metal.
It is always a metal.
Metal is often bad
and can't do what we want to do.
Another thing is
because it has two different values,
there is another degree of freedom
called pseudo-spin degree of freedom.
This means that
you can put these messages
on these two different values.
If you can manipulate this value,
you can treat it as 0 and 1.
For example, 0 is the k-value
and 1 is the negative k-value.
The advantage of this thing is that
we used to use
Electron's degree of freedom
to make computers.
Basically,
the current computer
uses charge.
When you turn on the transistor,
the charge will flow.
When you turn off the transistor,
the charge will not flow.
One of the things
we want to do in the future
is to use spin.
When you turn on a switch,
the spin-up electrons can pass
and the spin-down electrons
cannot pass.
There is a proposal
that we can also use
Electron's degree of freedom
in the k-value
or negative k-value
as 0 or 1.
However,
the first thing is
that metal cannot do anything.
We have to find a way
to open a gap.
This is a saying.
We want to find a semiconductor.
One of the semiconductors
is called
Transition Metal Dichotronate.
Basically,
its lattice
is similar to graphene.
One of its atoms
is transition metal,
which is probably
Mo or tungsten.
The other
atom site
is sulfur
or selenium.
At this time,
you will find
that this lattice structure
does not have
inversion symmetry.
You can't find a point
where the inversion symmetry
returns to its original state.
This means
that it will open a gap.
It turns out that
the basic structure
of this lattice structure
looks like this.
It has a gap.
There is no state
in the middle.
This is a gap.
However, it still has
k and negative k-value.
You can still
use it
to make valetronics.
However,
you still have a semiconductor.
Because you have a semiconductor,
you can still
study electrons.
Sometimes,
you can study electrons.
you can reduce
Fermi energy.
Fermi energy
is in the middle.
At the same time,
electrons and holes
form acetone.
Acetone is a particle
where electrons and holes
form.
These properties
lead to
Transition Metal Dichotomy.
Transition Metal Dichotomy
is one of the popular
research topics.
We hope
to use it
to make valetronics
or other
optoelectronics.
Our question is
that we are
using valetronics
to make valetronics.
Another interesting thing
about valetronics is
that
we mentioned acetone.
Acetone is an electron and a hole.
You can imagine
that an electron and a hole
have coolant in them.
They are heterogeneous.
That's why they are heterogeneous.
When they are bound together,
they release their energy.
That's why their energy
is a little bit low.
How much energy do they release?
It depends on
how strong
the electric field between them is.
In the three-dimensional
semiconductor,
there is a hole
and an electron.
Because of this,
the electric field
goes through
many other backgrounds.
These backgrounds
cause the electric field to go down.
The coolant interaction
between them is not very strong.
The binding energy goes down.
In the two-dimensional material,
you will find that
the electric field
between them is in the air.
In the air,
the electric field
is not screened.
After the electron and hole
are bound together,
a very good
acetone is formed.
This is one of the reasons
why people want to study acetone.
Acetone is
similar to
the concept of
hydrogen.
You may have
found acetone
in Galileo Arsenal.
Basically,
this is
basically
an electron
and a hole.
They are not bound together.
They have a continuum.
The continuum is here.
Under this continuum,
you will have
the electron and hole's
bound state.
They have 1s, 2s, 3s,
just like the hydrogen atom.
Under this spectrum,
you will see
the spectrum of 1s, 2s, 3s.
In the
Transition Metal Dichotomy,
there is the same thing.
However,
the effect is very strong.
You can see
the energy scale
in the left picture.
The binding energy
is about
3-4 MeV.
In the Transition Metal Dichotomy,
we can't even see
the continuum.
The reasonable
prediction is
that the binding energy
is about 300 MeV.
You can only see
the first state
and the second state.
The next question is
that you have these values
and these acetones.
What is the question?
The question we want to ask is
whether we can
break the value degeneracy
We just mentioned
the value degeneracy.
We just mentioned the value.
However, the energy of
these two values is exactly the same.
So,
the question is
that if you store
the information in the value,
but you don't
touch
the energy of the value,
the information
will not change.
The final result is the same information.
This is basically
meaningless.
What we want to do now is
that if you have a way
to store the information
in these values,
if you use
some methods
to change
the energy of the acetone,
then
you can read
the final result.
The final result will be changed.
Depending on
the energy of the value,
the information will change.
This is called manipulation.
One of the ways
is to use the magnetic field.
Using the magnetic field,
you can pull
the energy of the value
on one side up
and the energy on the other side down.
Then you will see
that the red line
and the blue line
represent two values.
When the magnetic field is zero,
the two values are exactly the same.
When you add a strong magnetic field,
the energy of the two values
will be slightly separated.
At this time,
you can use
the magnetic field
to do valetronics.
Another thing is that
we want to ask
whether light
can do valetronics.
Another thing is that
in the valetronics,
the acetone has
very strong valence.
Will the valence
affect the behavior of the machine?
The reason
why I ask this question
is that
we have found similar things
in Galen-Arsenal.
In Galen-Arsenal,
you will have
various free electrons
and holes.
It is called plasma.
Then you will have some acetone.
When the density of acetone
is high enough,
biacetone will appear.
Biacetone is
two acetone bonds
together.
It is a bit like a hydrogen atom.
When you have more
density,
it will form a droplet atom.
There are many acetone bonds.
These
biacetone
quasiparticles
also have
some applications.
In Galen-Arsenal's
quantum darts,
you can use these biacetones
to make entangled photons.
You can also
use optical control
to change
the behavior
of acetone.
Next,
I want to answer
two questions.
The first question
is...
Sorry, I have a question.
Can we go back to the last page?
You just said
that
if you want to break
the valley degeneracy,
let's say
your sample is
molybdenum sulfide.
If you want to break
the degeneracy,
if I am an alloy
or some doping,
will it break the degeneracy?
If the material is not...
OK.
If you want to break
the valley degeneracy,
there is a
symmetry condition.
The symmetry condition
for the valley degeneracy
is time-reversal symmetry.
If your material
has time-reversal symmetry,
it will have valley degeneracy.
Then,
time-reversal symmetry
will break the time-reversal symmetry.
For doping,
it is not exactly break.
Doping is not.
So, apart from the magnetic field,
do you know any other factors?
Light.
Is that all?
If so...
I don't think so.
And the current.
The current is...
If the current is long,
it will break the time-reversal symmetry.
So, if it has a lot of charge,
the current...
The current is...
The current is flowing.
So, for example,
when you are measuring,
if you apply a bias to it,
it may...
This will slightly break.
This is the valley hole effect.
OK.
Thank you.
You can continue.
OK.
The answer to the first question
is yes.
But this thing
is about optical stock effect.
Now,
let's look at a very simple model.
You have a...
a...
a material.
It has a state.
It has a black state called state A.
It has a red state called state B.
At this time,
if you apply a light,
it is non-resonant.
Then we
control the light's
frequency
under the
AB resonance.
Its energy will be under this.
At this time,
state A will produce a
virtual state under state B.
state B
will also produce a virtual state
above state A.
If you
consider these
dipole interactions,
if you
consider the two corresponding states,
these two states
will repel each other.
Usually, if you
write a matrix,
you add...
The matrix's
cross-section represents two energies.
The off-diagonal
represents
two...
represents their interactions.
If you turn on the interactions,
these two energies will be separated.
The following
is the same.
At this time, you will find that the red state
will move up and the black state will move down.
When
you apply light,
the transition
from black to red
will increase
its energy.
It will blue shift.
The quantity
of
the
blue shift
will
be determined
by this formula.
Basically, this formula
tells you that
it is equal to
how strong the light
is.
It is equal to
detuning.
Detuning is the energy difference
between the AB resonance
and the light.
This is called detuning.
However,
there is one thing.
If you take these things
into numbers,
you will find that
this change is very small.
Therefore,
it is true that you can use light
to change the energy of the machine,
to change the energy of the acetone.
However,
because this change is too small,
you need to adjust the intensity
very, very strongly.
The intensity of light is very, very strong.
Therefore, at this time, you need to sell
the laser to do this thing.
Of course,
someone has done this before.
You can see
that this paper
was published in 1986.
This is
basically
demonstrating
the optical star effect
on the gallium arsenide.
Basically,
you take a piece of gallium arsenide
quantum well.
The pump is 806 nm.
Its energy is lower
than
the energy of acetone.
Then,
you use another beam of light,
which is a probe.
Its function is
to see
if your spectrum
is changing
when the pump is on.
You can see that
here
at negative 2 picoseconds,
negative 2 picoseconds is this line.
Negative 2 picoseconds
means that
when you hit the probe,
your pump hasn't come yet.
Therefore,
its original spectrum
is two peaks.
One is heavy acetone.
The other is light acetone.
This is acetone in gallium arsenide.
When it's 0 picoseconds,
it means that the pump
and the probe are
hitting the sample at the same time.
You can see that
the resonance of acetone
is getting smaller.
The resonance of acetone
It means that its energy
is getting bigger.
When you turn off
the pump,
when the pump
is at 1.2 picoseconds,
the resonance
of acetone
moves back.
This is an interesting effect.
When you hit the pump,
when you hit the pump,
the resonance of acetone
moves slightly.
When you turn off the pump,
the resonance of acetone
moves back.
What's the situation
in Transition Metal Dichotomy?
The interesting thing is that
in Transition Metal Dichotomy,
the two values
correspond to
different helicity.
We can use
the left and right
to distinguish the two values.
What we can do
is this.
We choose
the left light.
It only
couples to K-value.
Of course, we need
a light which is
less than the resonance of acetone.
When there is light,
the resonance of acetone
will slightly blue-shift.
If we send
a probe
of the left light,
we will see
a blue-shift.
If we send a probe of the right light,
the resonance of acetone
will slightly blue-shift.
By using this method,
we can break
the VAD degeneracy.
Let's try
to see if it's right.
This is our sample.
We choose
to use Moebillion Dicillinide
as our sample.
We have
encapsulated
Moebillion Dicillinide
in these two H-BNs.
It's in boron nitride.
The reason why we do this
is that
there is a study
that says
in boron nitride,
the quality
of Moebillion Dicillinide
is very good.
This is the reason
why we do this.
Do we need
low temperature
in this kind of measurement?
Or can we use
room temperature?
You mean
in this kind of measurement?
Yes, in room temperature.
We can see
this kind of phenomenon
in room temperature.
But some of them
are invisible.
Some of the things we want to see
But
if it's Moebillion Dicillinide,
we can see it
in room temperature.
Yes.
I don't know much about this.
There is an important thing here.
The light we emit
is always lower than the energy of acetone.
So
the light
won't be absorbed
by the material.
It will pass through the material.
So
there will be no phonon.
This is a very important
question.
Thank you.
This is
the reflectivity
of this sample.
Basically,
the reflectivity is the absorption.
This is Moebillion Dicillinide
in room temperature.
When we
lower it to low temperature,
the peak
becomes narrower.
The intensity of the peak becomes larger.
The width
of the peak
is about 5 MeV.
Compared to
before,
we didn't
use boronitride encapsulation
or CVD sample.
CVD sample
has a line width of
about 30 MeV.
The sample without
encapsulation is about 10 MeV.
We
only have 5 MeV
in this sample.
This means that the quality of the sample
is very good.
Another interesting thing
is that we can see
the absorption
from 30 MeV
to
very large.
We can even make it
100% absorption.
There are
other interesting questions.
But I won't
talk about it today.
You can discuss it if you are interested.
I have a question.
Have you compared
CVD sample
with
exfoliated sample?
Have you measured the result?
The quality?
Yes.
We have compared.
Is exfoliated sample better?
Yes.
Much better.
Much better means
if we measure
absorption or PL,
the line width of
CVD sample is
about 5-10 MeV.
But CVD sample
is about 30 MeV.
Is it because of defects?
Yes.
The reason is that
in CVD sample,
there are many
inhomogeneous broadening.
The source of inhomogeneous broadening
is the defects.
Yes.
Thank you.
This is
pump probe setup.
This is a sample.
On the left,
there is a laser.
We divide it into two parts.
One part is called pump.
Pump
Because the laser
has a wide bandwidth,
we use a spectrometer
to divide the light.
We only take
about 2 MeV
and put the pump
on the sample.
The other half of the light is called probe.
We run it to a delay stage
and put it on a
sapphire.
The function of sapphire
is to make the probe light
produce nonlinear effect.
It will become
basically
the color of the light
will change.
It will become
the light of broadband.
The light of broadband
can be put on the sample
and used to study the sample.
Finally,
we put the probe light
into a spectrometer
to divide the light
and put it on the detector.
Basically,
on the right,
we use a picosecond
laser light.
It has a very sharp
light,
and we put it on the sample.
At the same time,
we send a probe
with many colors.
The probe is very short,
and we put it on the sample
to study what we want to study.
The result is
like this.
First,
look at the middle picture.
In the middle picture,
the x-axis is the delay,
which is the time
between the probe and the pump.
Then,
the y-axis is the delay,
and the x-axis is the energy,
which is the energy
of the probe light.
Then,
we see
the difference
between the pump
and the non-pump.
Let me explain
the meaning of this picture.
The first thing is
that all the effects
occur within
negative 1 to 1 picosecond.
This means that
only the pump light
has this effect,
and only the non-pump light
has this effect.
This means that
it is a coherent effect,
which is basically
what we want to see.
If you draw a line
within 0 picosecond,
you will get this.
Basically,
when the pump and the pump probe
are combined,
the reflectivity
changes.
We also have
the normal reflectivity
of the sample.
We can measure
the reflectivity
of the sample
when there is no pump.
Basically,
when there is a pump,
the reflectivity
increases in the red part,
and the reflectivity
decreases in the blue part.
Basically,
it is a shift.
In the red part,
the reflectivity increases,
and in the blue part,
the reflectivity decreases.
This means that
the peak is a blue shift.
To draw a picture,
we use a
ready-tuner light,
a sigma plus light,
and we probe
the k-value.
At this time,
the energy of the k-value
is blue shifted.
This is what the picture
tells us.
The other thing is
that
we have done this
before.
This is our group
in Berkeley.
There is another group
in MIT.
They have actually
done this before.
This measurement
shows that
when the intensity
of the pump
is very high,
the blue shift
is about 3 MeV.
This means that
this 3 MeV
is already...
We talked about
using magnetic field
to break the value degeneracy.
If you want
the energy
to change 3 MeV,
you need to add 60 Tesla's
magnetic field.
This is basically impossible.
In the world,
it is impossible
to do 60 Tesla's.
However,
we can
find that
we can indeed
break the value
degeneracy
and make the energy
shift very large.
However,
the previous research
showed that
the k' value
is not a couple.
Therefore,
it has no effect.
However,
we found that
the k' value
has some strange effects.
The k' value
curve
is the opposite
of the k' value curve.
This means that
this is a redshift.
When we add
the k' value,
the k' value is redshifted.
The next thing
we want to know
is what happened.
What happened?
OK.
In addition to
this,
we can also
do one more thing.
We can change the energy
of the reflected light.
Just now,
we showed that
the detuning value
is about 50.
It is like this.
The omega x
is about 50 Mv.
We can see a redshift.
However,
when we increase
the photon energy
of the pump light,
the detuning value
will decrease.
We can see that
the peak becomes splitting.
If we
adjust the photon energy
very close to
the resonance of acetone,
we will find that
the curve is completely reversed.
It is a blueshift.
What does this mean?
In fact,
when you see
a blueshift from a redshift,
the first thought is
is this a new resonance?
Next,
we will ask
how to explain
this phenomenon.
Let's go back
to the beginning.
At the beginning,
we said that
you have a light state
k' acetone.
When you add
a sigma plus light,
you will change
k' acetone
to redshift.
to blueshift.
Therefore,
when you send
a sigma plus light,
it will be a blueshift.
However,
there is a problem.
Why?
In theory,
your light state
will also be a blueshift.
This means that
your k' acetone
will also be a blueshift.
Why didn't
anyone notice this?
This is actually
a wrong picture.
In fact,
when we are
considering the Arpio Stark effect,
in addition to
considering the light state
and the k' acetone,
we also need to consider
more states.
For example,
this is a two-acetone state.
Basically,
after you excite an acetone,
you can still
excite another acetone.
If you
add a sigma plus light,
you will have a k' acetone.
You will have an acetone in k' value.
However, if you add
a sigma plus light,
you can have two acetones
in k' value.
You can also
add a sigma plus light
and a sigma minus light.
You will have an acetone in k' value.
You will also have an acetone in k' value.
You can also have
an acetone in k' value
and k' value.
These states
are actually
in your
transition.
They all need to be considered.
If you consider
this way,
you will find that
the energy of k' acetone
does not change.
Because you have a ground state
that affects it.
However, you have
a two-acetone state
that pushes it down.
It will actually
stay at a fixed energy.
However, your ground state
will move down
if you have a two-acetone state.
At this time, you will find that
if you add a sigma minus light,
the degree of downshift
is the same.
Therefore, you will get
a sigma that should not change.
The next question is that
in addition to these states,
we know that there is another state
called biacetone.
As I just explained,
biacetone is the interaction
between two acetones
to generate a bounding energy.
This bounding energy
will push the energy
of the state down.
This state will also affect
the k' value.
We claim that
the experimental results we see
are from these biacetones.
How do we explain this?
Let's go back to the
experimental data.
We can see that
this is the dependence of detuning.
From left to right,
it is redshift to blueshift.
In redshift,
the photon energy is very small.
The photon energy is relatively small.
Therefore,
the pump
will have this effect
in addition to this effect.
This effect
will cause a virtual state
above the k' value.
This will push
the energy of the k' value down.
This will cause
a redshift
in the probe value.
When you
move the photon energy
of the pump
very close to the acetone,
the virtual state
generated by
the biacetone
will be
below the k' value.
If it is below the k' value,
it will move
the acetone state
of the k' value
up.
At this time,
we will see a blueshift.
This is how we explain our data.
In the middle,
the photon energy
matches the transition
of the biacetone and acetone.
When these two
energy matches,
the state will split.
We can see that
this is a split.
According to this method,
we can determine
the difference
between the two acetone states
and the energy
of the biacetone state.
The energy difference
is the binding energy.
According to the detuning result,
the binding energy
of the biacetone state
is about 20 MeV.
This is similar to
the effect of
the biacetone
on TMDC.
These effects
are consistent.
The last thing we do
is to write
the theory
of effective state.
We are experimental scientists,
so we can't write the complete theory.
However,
we try to write
the interaction
of all these states.
Basically,
we only consider
the transition
from ground state
to k' value.
The state related to
ground state
will change
the k' value
and the ground state.
This is a 2x2 prediction.
The state related to
k' value
is related to
free acetone
and
biacetone state.
This is a
3x3 prediction.
If you solve this 3x3 prediction,
you will get
this prediction.
The picture on the left
is our experiment.
As you can see,
the experiment is very consistent with the theory.
I want to emphasize
that this is an effective theory.
Many things are fitting.
If there is a theory,
I hope
this theory
can help us
figure out
how these parameters
come from.
This may involve
many-body theory.
This is the conclusion.
Today, I talked about
the history of super-fast light theory
and the technique of
pump-off.
I also showed you
the effect of acetone
in the two-dimensional
semiconductor.
The value of
valetronics
is the
value of
valetronics.
In the end,
we demonstrated
that we can use light
to adjust
the value of valetronics.
We can also use
our sample
to observe
the effect of
valetronics.
What's left is
what we didn't talk about today.
I'm currently
doing research on
ultrafast optics.
I'm still
studying
2D material.
I'm doing
photon-echo spectroscopy.
Another interesting thing
is the
optical star effect.
It's a photon-dressed
acetone,
but it's very weakly dressed.
There are other ways
to
place the
semiconductor
in a optical chamber.
If you make the chamber
very small,
you can strongly
couple the photon
with the acetone.
This is called acetone-polaroton.
This is my
recent research in Michigan.
I hope you can see
the effect of acetone-polaroton.
We also
did some applications.
One of the
concepts is that we can use
graphene.
Basically,
if you add voltage to graphene,
the absorption of graphene
will change.
We can use this method
to make optical sensors.
One of the things we've been
doing recently is
placing neuron cells
on graphene.
Neuron cells
emit electrical signals.
Is it using love to emit electricity?
What?
What does it mean?
Is it using love to emit electricity?
That's right.
In our experiment,
we used
the heart of a chicken.
But the heart of a chicken
doesn't look good on the picture.
Basically,
we just
put some
electrical signals
on it.
Basically, you need to study
your heart cells or neurons.
Neurons
use electricity
to send signals.
When these
electrical signals
send signals,
they also change
the absorption of
graphene.
If we turn on the light,
we can see
if the neuron
is emitting electricity.
Using this method,
we can detect
the signal
of the brain cells.
This is
an application
for biophysics.
These are
my main collaborators.
In Ann Arbor,
Hui Deng is
my boss.
In UC Berkeley,
Wang Feng.
We worked together
to create
the Artifical Star Effect.
Thank you.
Thank you,
Joseph.
Do you have any questions?
Yes.
I just asked some questions.
Wang,
do you have any questions?
I have a question.
You can
go back to
the previous slide
with sigma plus
and sigma minus
of the pump probe.
On resonance,
you can see the X-split.
In the middle graph,
the two states
of the split-up
have a parity difference.
In theory,
in this quantum
optically split state,
the parity difference
should be different
by the selection rule.
These two states
should not...
We wrote
effective theory,
but
according to
effective theory,
there should be
no change.
The reason is
basically
this is
sigma plus
from here to here.
But
when you
add up the
up-do-step effect,
the remaining
is still sigma plus.
So basically
these two states
should not change
for this state.
This is my understanding.
But of course,
in reality,
we didn't do this experiment.
If you probe
with sigma plus,
you will...
This experiment is not easy.
It's not easy
because if you send
a probe with sigma plus,
the most important effect
will be from ground state to k-value.
This is just
a very small change.
So of course,
it's possible to do this experiment,
but
I'm not sure
if I can see the significant effect.
Thank you.
Because today's time
is a little over.
So we'll stop here today.
I'll
pause the recording for now.
Thank you, Jason.