Hello, everyone. Welcome to this week's TerraTalk.
I am the host for this week, Lin Yu-Wei.
I am very happy to invite our speaker today, Zhou Zhijie.
He obtained a master's degree in electrical engineering at NTU,
and is currently a doctor of electrical engineering at the University of California, Lincoln.
Under the guidance of Professor Dai Yu-Chang,
he has been conducting research on wearable devices and biomimics for medical purposes.
Today's topic is the application of wearable technology and personal health management.
Let's give a round of applause to welcome Zhijie and his speech today.
Remember to turn on the microphone.
Now let's give the microphone to our speaker today, Zhijie.
Thank you, Yu-Wei, for the introduction.
Hello, everyone. I am Zhou Zhijie.
Today's topic is the application of wearable technology and personal health management.
Without further ado, let's get to the topic.
First of all, I would like to introduce to you
why wearable devices have become a hot topic in recent years.
Basically, it can be divided into several aspects.
The first is the concept of non-invasive.
The concept of non-invasive means that the device does not need to enter our body.
You may have been to the hospital for injections or blood draws.
Once something enters your body, the first reaction is pain.
In addition to the pain, the immune system will also react to foreign bodies.
For example, some white blood cells or other immune cells will attack foreign objects.
Basically, it will cause a lot of inflammation, swelling, pain, and heat.
Therefore, wearable devices basically avoid such risks.
Many technology giants like Apple and Fitbit
want to study non-invasive devices first
and see where their limits can be pushed.
Then they will consider the so-called minimally invasive devices.
In fact, there is a huge barrier between non-invasive and minimally invasive.
Whether it is from the perspective of devices or from the perspective of government agencies like the FDA,
the biggest barrier is still entering the body.
Once you enter the body, there is a lot of risk.
Stay outside the body is a very low-risk device.
Basically, wearable devices have become so popular recently.
Next is the so-called big clinical data.
I believe everyone has heard of big clinical data.
The meaning of big clinical data is that this device can provide some diagnostic information.
This diagnosis is also a bit tricky.
How can we determine the value of the diagnosis?
What metrics are really useful?
The third part is the so-called Autonomous Sensing.
Autonomous Sensing is not as complicated as you think.
Just put the wearable device on your body and it will automatically start to measure.
Then you don't need to intervene.
Then it can continuously send this data out in a wireless way.
The advantage is that even if you are not conscious, for example, when you are sleeping,
this device can still continue to measure and send the data out.
So it can let us see some things that we couldn't see before.
For example, when you are sleeping, it can help you measure the cycle of sleep,
or the heartbeat when you are resting, and so on.
The fourth aspect is that it is very easy to compare with portable devices,
such as mobile phones, smartphones, or even tablets.
Basically, these portable devices can be used as a relay station.
You can imagine that your wearable sensor is a bit like a place to send signals.
Then store these signals in the portable device.
Basically, the computing power of these portable devices is relatively strong,
and the bandwidth to upload data is relatively high.
On the one hand, it can be used as a relay station, and on the other hand,
it can be used as a place to send signals.
There are a lot of benefits that you can think about.
Next, I will talk about the logic of why we want to use wearable devices
to monitor the health of our body.
There is a study in Stanford,
which is called digital health.
It is a comparison of regular visits to the hospital
and digital health.
The so-called digital health is actually
collecting all the data that should be collected at the hospital,
digitizing it,
and then processing these digitized data.
This study is actually very simple.
There are only two main variables.
One is to measure the skin temperature,
and the other is to measure the heart rate.
If I put the sensor on the patient
for a long time,
the patient will inevitably get sick.
The heart rate and skin temperature
when the patient is sick
are basically the same.
The heart rate and skin temperature
The wearable sensor has some information in it.
How do we get this information out?
We have big clinical data.
When do we get this data?
It's basically 24 hours a day.
You can get some useful information
such as your body temperature, heart rate, etc.
It's basically 24 hours a day.
Can we tell if a person is healthy or sick?
We can tell from the data from the sensors.
For example, a disease has a certain distribution in the data space of the sensor.
So this is a very interesting question.
Before this disease appeared, our data space was completely blank.
But there are actually some privileges in this sleep stage.
For example, when we sleep, our body does not move.
Because there is a lack of noise in our daily life.
For example, motion noise.
Or when we do other things during the day, our heartbeat suddenly changes.
But when we sleep, it doesn't change.
At present, some wearable sensors are already measuring heartbeats during rest and sleep.
I will show you some data later.
Location.
The main thing is to see where our sensors can be placed in the body.
Research related to motion impedance.
First look at this picture.
You can see that its range is a bit different.
You can see that the place where wearable devices are often placed, such as a bowl, is actually a good place to put it.
Because it doesn't have too many...
This is a matrix.
It tells us what sensor is most suitable for measuring when placed in a certain place.
For example, the red block is used to measure whole body motion.
Basically, it is used to measure the movement of the whole body.
You can imagine that your limbs, hands and feet are often moving.
But if you want to track the center of the whole body, the red block will be more accurate.
And so on.
For example, the extension of the joint stretch, of course, depends on the elbow and knee joint.
So...
The last one is the place where the sensor is really placed.
This is interesting. You can compare it with the two pictures just now.
For example, many devices are placed at the wrist or ankle.
Next, I will discuss the future prospects of wearable devices.
Basically, it is like this.
From the era of personal computers, the market trend is to try to make the size of the computer smaller and smaller.
From personal computers to knee-shaped devices and wearable devices.
The so-called computing unit is the center of the data, which is closer to the body.
The advantage of doing this is that you don't need too much delay from your sensor to get the data.
You can do the operation directly.
This is the size of the entire market of wearable devices.
The size of the entire market of wearable devices is the largest at the beginning.
However, as soon as Apple Watch appeared, it appeared around the middle of 2015.
As soon as it appeared, it immediately ate up the market share.
Then, until recently, 2016 to 2017, you can see that the largest has become Apple Watch.
Then, on the contrary, Feizui started to decline from the highest point.
This is a very interesting phenomenon, and you can think about why.
The last is my own imagination.
From the beginning of the 2000s, the so-called smartphones began to appear.
By 2010, the first generation of wearable devices began to appear.
It has PPG, which is a method of optical heart rate detection.
Motion is basically an accelerometer.
It can see the motion of your entire body.
ECG is a heart rate map.
Blood pressure.
Basically, these are some of the information that is easier to get.
However, its application is actually limited.
In the next ten years, there may be some new wearable devices.
For example, FUET, which measures biomarkers in sweat.
LP is ocular pressure.
CGM is Continuous Glucose Monitoring.
Basically, these devices may need to use minimally invasive sensors.
However, it still has great advantages.
Because it basically gives us some information that the previous wearable sensors cannot provide.
Of course, it is more difficult for the government to get FDA approval.
Because it is a relatively high-risk device for patients.
My prediction is that after 2030, it depends on how the market reacts.
Because there is the first and second generation of wearable devices.
If the market reacts well, there may be new minimally invasive devices.
Then let the market continue to grow.
Or like personal computers or smartphones, it will start to saturate.
So you can wait and see what the future of wearable devices will look like.
Next, let's move on to the next topic.
I will introduce the wearable sensors on the market now.
First, let's talk about Fitbit.
Fitbit is the first company to launch a smartwatch.
At first, it only gives you some heart rate information.
Heart rate information is based on optical detection.
The principle is simple.
It uses a green light LED to illuminate the threshold under the skin.
When your blood flow changes, it will affect the intensity of the reflected green light.
When the green light shines fast enough, for example, this is a 25Hz frequency.
The heart rate is about 1 to 2Hz.
The 25Hz light can be modulated by the heart rate.
You can get heart rate information by processing digital signals.
This is the first generation of Fitbit.
Recently, they have added some new features.
They are interested in sleep tracking.
The reason is simple.
First, it is easy to measure.
Because you don't move much when you sleep.
So there is little noise.
You can see the picture on the right.
Fitbit uses EEG to divide the sleep cycle into 3 to 4 types.
The most famous is REM.
Rapid Eye Movement.
This is the sleep cycle when you are dreaming.
There are other types, such as pre-sleep and deep sleep.
It can show you the percentage of each sleep cycle.
Although it is a sleep cycle, it does not use EEG.
It only uses heart rate and acceleration to measure data.
You can see that the cycle is fast.
Some people complain that there are some false signals.
Let's take a look at the EEG.
EEG measures the electric field on the head and nose.
Different sleep cycles have different brain waves.
Stage 1, Stage 2, and Stage 3 correspond to the sleep cycle of JELLO and DEEP.
Fitbit does not measure EEG.
It only uses heart rate and acceleration to measure data.
This is the sleep cycle of JELLO and DEEP.
Let's take a look at Apple Watch.
Apple Watch is a little later than Fitbit.
The reason is that it has a lot of functions that are not related to clinical information.
Apple likes to make things fancy, so it adds a lot of external functions.
In the latest series 4, Apple tried to add ECG.
You can see that there is an optical heart rate sensor on the back.
This part is the same as Fitbit.
But there are two more electrodes.
One is the crystal electrode on the back.
The other one is the electrode above the circle.
When you want to measure ECG, you have to touch the dial with your right finger.
This way, you can form a circuit to measure your ECG.
But this ECG only has one channel.
You can think about it. It measures the electrical field from the left to the right of your heart.
But this also requires FDA clearance.
Because it claims to be a device that can assist with medical care.
Any device that claims to have this needs FDA approval.
Once you have this ECG, you can do some irregular rhythm notification.
It can see if there are any abnormal frequencies in your ECG waveform.
The so-called abnormal frequency is a signal like a heart beat or atrial fibrillation.
Once the ECG is detected, it will give you an alarm.
The so-called class 2 is not the simplest medical device for FDA.
But it's not as invasive as class 3.
This device can't be used for diagnosis.
This is a point that FDA emphasizes.
The last feature is the accelerometer.
When you fall, it will tell you if you need to call an ambulance.
This is a very fancy feature.
The next product I want to introduce is Omron.
You may think of it as a blood pressure monitor.
Or a stopwatch.
What I'm going to talk about today is a blood pressure monitor.
The traditional blood pressure monitor has a cuff.
You have to tie it to your arm.
Then it will start to add pressure.
Then it will measure your heart rate.
When you can't hear your heart rate, it's a cuff.
When you can hear your heart rate again, it's a cuff.
Where is this intervention?
You can see the watch on the right.
It's actually made very small.
You can wear it on your wrist.
If you press a button, it will stop the process.
But it's made on the wrist.
The advantage is that you can wear it all day.
The advantage is that you can wear it on your wrist.
When you want to measure your heart rate, you can press it at any time.
But you still need to operate it manually.
Ideally, this device will measure your heart rate every fixed time.
Even when you sleep.
This is what I think is ideal.
So there are still some improvements.
And it's still under development.
So it hasn't been released yet.
Because it still needs FDA clearance.
Next is the Freestyle company.
This is actually a British company.
In the United States, I know Metronic and Dexcom are doing blood sugar testing.
Why do we need to measure blood sugar?
In fact, this device is not for ordinary people.
It's actually for diabetes patients.
Why do I want to let diabetes patients measure their blood sugar?
The reason is that their body can't produce insulin.
So they have to inject insulin into their body to control their blood sugar.
If their blood sugar is too low, it will be life-threatening.
So they want to keep monitoring their blood sugar level.
And keep it within the normal range.
This device is already very small.
Because the needle is only 0.4 mm.
It can be regarded as a wearable device.
After the needle is inserted into the skin, it can stay on it for about 14 days.
Just two weeks.
Then you don't have to take it off.
It's basically like a patch.
It's a bit like a sticker.
You just stick it on your body.
If you scan the sensor, it will send the glucose reading to your scanner.
Then the scanner can pair with your phone.
It will send the glucose reading to your phone.
The advantage of this device is that if you want to measure blood sugar, you need to poke a hole in your finger.
Then squeeze the blood out.
You can imagine that the process is very painful.
Basically, you just need to poke a hole with this device.
You only need to poke it once every two weeks.
And the advantage of this device is that you don't have to poke it yourself.
This device continues to measure blood sugar.
So basically, it can measure blood sugar even when you sleep.
OK.
The last one is a company called Emotiv.
It's actually doing EEG.
You can see this in the upper right corner.
It's a bit like a headgear.
There are actually more than ten electrodes on it.
This is basically a device that is not really used for medical diagnosis.
It's more like a device that monitors your brain waves.
In addition to measuring EEG, it can also measure...
For example, if you say a command in your head, it will translate it for you.
This is actually pretty cool.
It can also detect facial expression changes on your face.
This device has a EEG system with Clinical.
You can see that this is basically very consistent.
Clinical's EEG is actually very expensive.
It's about 60k.
They developed Emotiv themselves.
It's only a few hundred dollars.
OK.
Let me give you a brief introduction to how EEG came about.
Everyone knows that the brain has various cortex.
This EEG...
You can see these...
Have you ever heard of alpha or beta?
All kinds of brain waves come from the cortex.
It's just that it's not the same as the nervous system.
The reason is that this is not the real action potential.
It's actually a change in hyperpolarization and depolarization.
This cycle is actually very long.
You can see that there's a scale at the bottom.
This is one second.
The action potential is usually only a few dozen milliseconds.
So this is not the action potential.
This is actually a change in hyperpolarization.
After this is produced in the cell,
it actually has a local field potential.
It's measured near the cell to the junction point.
Then this junction point goes all the way through the medium between the cells.
Then it's passed on to the cortex.
So you can see that the cortex is actually just a depolarization of the nerve.
Of course, the EEG hasn't been declared to be able to measure while sleeping.
So I don't know what happens if it really wears this device when it's sleeping.
I think it should be quite interesting.
Okay, let's move on to the third part.
The third part is mainly some relatively new technologies.
There are mainly...
The first one is continuous blood pressure monitoring.
As I just said, it still needs you to measure it yourself.
So its measurement speed can't be that fast.
Continuous blood pressure is a new device.
It uses the ultrasound to track the blood pressure in the blood vessel.
This is the normal distribution range of blood pressure in general.
This is the basic structure of the device.
The main signal source is the piezoelectric material.
It's sealed in epoxy.
Then some electrodes are applied to the surface.
At the same time, the piezoelectric material is actually in two directions.
One is when you give it electricity, it will generate a current.
The other is when you have a current, it will generate a signal of electricity.
So it's actually in both directions.
The principle is that you give a pulse at the beginning.
So the piezoelectric material will generate a pulse.
Then it presses the blood vessel.
So it will see how the blood vessel is changing with the blood pressure.
According to the time-of-flight, it can reverse the environment of the blood vessel.
Then this signal can be reversed into blood pressure.
The two positions are in the pulmonary artery.
So it's just a little patch on top of it.
There are some sensor arrays in this patch.
Maybe there are a few sensor arrays on top of the blood vessel.
It can measure the blood pressure.
The next one is actually quite interesting.
This is actually a device that can measure sweat.
So why are we interested in sweat?
The reason is that a lot of metabolism will come out with sweat.
Such as glucose and lactate.
They all show up in the sweat.
And their concentration is quite similar to the concentration in the blood.
So sweat can be thought of as a substitute for blood.
Then you don't really need to put a needle into your blood vessel.
So it has the advantage of non-invasive.
Then it can measure the concentration of electrolytes, such as sodium and potassium.
I'm curious about the time difference between glucose and lactate in sweat and in blood.
I would say about ten minutes.
They actually did a similar research.
Look at the concentration of glucose in your blood.
Then you will see that if there is a spike in the blood, there will be a delay in the spike in the sweat.
That delay is usually about ten minutes.
So it's a delay, but the timing resolution is higher.
So even if it's a very short spike, you can still see it.
It's just a delay, right?
If it's a very short spike, it's not very certain.
Because the spike I'm talking about is usually like a step.
For example, after you eat, your blood sugar will suddenly rise and then slowly fall.
So it's actually not a really short spike.
It's actually a step up and then slowly decay.
This device is actually made like a wristband.
Its principle is basically to detect your target with a variety of different coating electrodes.
Like glucose and lactate, it uses enzymes to detect.
It basically puts the enzyme on the permeable film.
Then let it react with the target.
After the target is reacted, the enzyme dissolves the target and releases the electron.
Then the electron is picked up as a voltage signal.
The other part is the concentration of sodium and potassium.
It uses ion-selective electrodes.
It uses a variety of coatings on the surface.
This improves the professionalism of the ion.
So there won't be any interference problems.
It's the same as converting it into an electrode.
Finally, it's sent to a wireless ECB and sends the signal to the mobile phone.
This is what it actually measured when it was running.
You can see that there are five different data.
The temperature on the skin, lactate, sodium, potassium, and potassium.
It also has a collaboration with the device.
This collaboration is very good.
Because it matches the commercial device.
The only bad thing about this device is that it needs to let this person sweat.
Basically, you can see that there is a period of time after the exercise.
Then he started to sweat to get this reading.
The last one is the pressure in the eye.
It's actually measured...
It's different for each eye.
Jump to the structure of the eye.
This is the structure of the human eye.
Basically, the pressure we're talking about is the small part in front of the eye.
It's called aqueous humor.
In Chinese, it's called aqueous liquid.
Basically, it's the space between your mucous membrane and the crystal.
There's actually a little bit of aqueous liquid in it.
It's only a few microliters.
In fact, these microliters determine the balance of pressure in your eyes.
Because the vitreous body in the back is a glass body.
Basically, the volume won't change.
So if the pressure in the front increases, it will start to compress the mucous membrane and blood vessels in the back.
That's why it's called this disease.
This disease is called glaucoma.
OK.
So we want to monitor this 24-hour eye pressure change.
Can you imagine the same thing?
It's actually hard to sleep.
And there's an interesting phenomenon.
In fact, when you sleep, your eye pressure is the highest.
So, in fact, ophthalmologists are very interested in eye pressure changes when they sleep.
So we started to think about whether or not we could put a wearable device on your eyes and measure the eye pressure change.
Someone suggested that you could actually use this wearable glasses as your platform to measure eye pressure changes.
This is actually a new company's idea.
It actually uses existing wearable glasses materials.
Then they added a strain gauge to measure the change in the curvature of the mucous membrane.
They claim that this can be connected to intraocular pressure.
In fact, FDA has also approved this device.
It can actually be placed on the glasses and continue to measure 24 hours.
OK.
Then the main target is still these patients with light eyes or patients who are about to get light eyes.
As you can see, the structure of this device is very simple.
There is a coil.
It is actually used to receive power and send information back to the microcontroller.
There is also a small microcontroller here.
But its function is just to help modulate the signal and measure the strain gauge itself.
As you can see, this device does not have a battery.
It actually needs a larger coil outside the glasses to provide this power.
This power is also a receiver coil.
It can digitize the signal and send it to the recorder.
I personally don't really appreciate this.
Because it feels a little strange.
You can actually make it like a blindfold device.
You don't have to make it so complicated.
And this wire is not very convenient when you sleep.
Then back to Glocoma.
This is what I just talked about.
When you sleep, the eye pressure is actually higher.
The black one in the middle is actually the eye pressure when you sleep.
Generally, the standard eye pressure for Glocoma is 21 mmHg.
It's about this line.
21 is here.
The upper line is actually the real Glocoma patient's eye pressure.
The bottom line is normal.
In fact, there is a big difference between standing up and squatting.
Because when you stand up, there is a pressure difference caused by the height.
It even has something to do with standing or lying down.
So when you lie down, your posture changes.
Basically, the eye pressure will be a little higher.
Compare with when you stand up.
They maintain the same posture.
If you stand up, it will be colder during the day.
The last new technology is the battery technology.
I just talked about so many wearable devices.
If they put batteries in, they will basically use lithium-ion batteries.
The reason is that its energy density is the highest.
Of course, this is also why smartphones and laptops use lithium-ion batteries.
You can see this picture.
This is the current structure of the mainstream lithium-ion battery.
It has two levels, one level and a separator in the middle.
What's the bad thing about this?
It's very fragile.
The reason is that when the lithium-ion battery is charged, it will heat up easily.
Once it reaches a certain temperature, it will start to affect the electrolyte inside.
After the electrolyte breaks down, it releases gas.
The gas is more serious because it causes internal pressure to increase.
After the internal pressure increases, the structure of the separator is destroyed.
Once the structure is damaged, the battery is like a short-circuit.
A short-circuit is a positive feedback.
It will cause more heat to be released.
The whole thing will break down.
If you insert a nail into the lithium-ion battery, it will start to ignite and explode.
We don't want this scenario to happen to wearable devices.
It's basically wearing on your body.
If there is a problem with the battery, it will be a big problem.
Recently, someone proposed a new design.
It uses the same structure as the solar panel.
The structure is on the right.
It uses a 3D structure.
Basically, the structure of the battery is changed to a solid-state silicon.
So there is no weak and easy-to-puncture problem.
The traditional lithium-ion battery has a very fragile structure.
It's easy to break through.
But if you change it to a solid-state substrate, it's not easy to be affected by external forces.
On the other hand, you can use the photolithography method to pattern the structure of the two-stage and one-stage.
It can increase the density a lot.
On the one hand, it is safer.
On the other hand, the density of its unit has also been increased.
In the future, it is very likely to see this new lithium-ion battery being used on wearable devices.
In the last part, we will discuss the problems that wearable devices may encounter in addition to this technology.
The first one is privacy.
When a sensor starts to collect very personal data,
and there is a lot of data,
there will be a question mark.
What kind of people can access this data?
What kind of people can't access it?
You may have heard of Google Glass before.
The reason why it was scared was because it was collecting data.
If the camera is not approved by other people,
it will randomly shoot everywhere.
It violates other people's privacy.
The same goes for wearable devices.
It collects personal data all the time.
If it is not approved,
for example, you wear a wearable device today,
and the watch is lost.
Can other people easily access your data?
This is a privacy issue.
The following table is a survey on wearable devices.
On the left, you can see how people react to wearable devices.
Most people are very happy.
There is a new toy to play with.
But when it comes to trust,
people start to have questions.
The most trusted people are doctors, hospitals,
or health insurance.
These people are more trustworthy.
The following categories are cell phone providers,
entertainment providers, etc.
People's trust suddenly dropped.
This is also a trend.
If you want to collect data,
it is recommended to start from hospitals or doctors' offices.
Traditionally, people are more confident in health care providers.
They know they won't use these data.
The second discussion is about business.
This is an interesting issue.
Everyone sees that wearable devices have a good market.
But it is difficult to enter this market.
The reason is that it requires a lot of investment.
First, if you want to use wearable devices for diagnosis,
you need to get FDA approval.
Basically, whether it is class 2 or class 3,
you need to invest in research and development,
or even apply for a patent.
Then you can get FDA approval.
But consumers care a lot about the price of wearable devices.
You can see the following.
Whether it is fitness band, smart glasses, smart watch, or smart clothing.
The first thing everyone cares about is the price.
The second is that you may not use it.
Then there are others.
The first is that the cost of investment is high,
but you can't lower the price.
The last one is the difficulties that wearable devices may face.
There are five points.
The first is that consumers don't know why they need to use wearable devices.
What can wearable devices do?
As mentioned earlier,
for example, sleep tracking.
Even if I know that my sleep is divided into these weeks,
what are the possible applications?
For example, can it assist me in diagnosing what diseases I may have?
Or when I go to see a doctor,
can it give the doctor some judgment criteria?
The second is that wearable devices are easy to lose.
This is the same problem as mobile phones or other portable devices.
And it's quite troublesome to lose it.
Currently, wearable devices do not have ID settings.
Basically, it's wearable.
It won't be linked to your account.
The third is that
is it attractive or comfortable to wear?
This is a question worth thinking about.
When we don't know what function this device can do,
there is no reason to want to wear it.
For example,
if you don't wear glasses,
you may not want to wear glasses.
Wearing glasses only provides you with some minimal benefits.
The fourth is battery life.
Currently, most wearable devices only last 7 to 10 days.
Some people may complain that they can't last longer.
The fifth is about syncing.
Can it pair well with your smartphone?
This is a technical problem.
It's easy to solve.
But if you want to design a new wearable device,
you need to read.
This is the last video.
If you have any questions or experiences with wearable devices,
please feel free to ask.
If you have any questions,
Thank you.
Thank you, Zijie.
Let's give him a round of applause.
Please turn on your microphones.
Let's open the Q&A session.
Do you have any questions?
I have a question.
Can you hear me?
Yes, I can hear you.
Let's say 10 or 15 years later,
everyone wears a certain wearable device.
Your data will be uploaded to a data center for 24 hours.
The manager of the data center is basically a group of MDs.
They can see the data and know where the person's body may have problems.
In other words, this system can replace the current GP.
After the initial diagnosis,
the GP may be suffering from a skin disease.
The GP will be transferred to the relevant department.
In other words, this whole system will become the first line of defense of the medical system.
Imagine this society.
If this society really exists,
what do you think is the technical problem?
I can imagine other problems in society or politics.
But what do you think is the technical problem?
Now there is a fundamental question.
How far can this wearable device go?
If you don't want an invasive action,
it's actually very limited.
So I think the first technical problem is
how to measure all the data you need in a minimally invasive situation.
Then your data can distinguish between different diseases.
I think this is the first problem.
And it's a must-solve problem.
If you want to get into the ideal scenario,
you have to be able to do it.
Hello, I have a question.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
Hello, I would like to ask.
You just said that there are some minimally invasive devices.
I do cancer research.
I know that some of the current scientific cancer fields
are already targeting some cancer prevention methods.
For example, there are some so-called tumor DNA in the blood of cancer patients.
I wonder if this technology has been applied
or is already being developed on this wearable device.
How will it develop in the future?
OK, thank you, William.
Basically, yes.
Someone is already doing this.
I didn't mention it just now.
In fact, many people are doing so-called lab-on-a-chip.
Basically, using a single chip,
you can do what a whole lab can do.
For tumor cells, yes.
But because it needs to use a protocol.
Basically, it's still a protocol.
Because it basically looks at the circulating tumor cells.
So it needs to first design a filter
to filter out these tumor cells.
After filtering out,
it will look at which tumor cells belong to which cancer.
For example, doing DNA sequencing and so on.
If you want to turn it into a wearable device,
you still have to solve the invasive problem first.
Because if you want to take a blood sample,
the trouble with blood is that it is easy to coagulate.
Coagulation occurs.
So how do you get it from your bloodstream
to the cancer cell?
At the same time, it doesn't coagulate.
This is actually a problem that needs to be solved.
But if you can get this blood sample,
it's technically feasible.
So now in this wearable device,
there is no way to make this breakthrough, right?
If you don't want human intervention,
I don't think it's there yet.
But if you can do it like a blood sugar machine,
you poke a hole and squeeze the blood out,
and then drop it on the lab arm chip,
it can actually be done.
So the difference is whether it can be automated.
So the difficulty now is that
the coagulation situation you just mentioned,
that is, in a long-term surveillance,
instead of a single-point,
time-point time to detect.
That's it.
Thank you.
Hi.
I'm from the Taiwan University Student Association.
Thank you for your wonderful speech.
I'm the president of this year.
I'm also from the Electrical Engineering Institute.
But I'm studying electrical waves now.
And then in this regard,
maybe it's related to you.
Maybe it's like Energy Harvesting.
And then I'm doing the topic now.
It's UCLA.
They're developing how to make the antenna satellite.
It's possible to do the level of micrometer.
It should also be related to wearable.
But I'm pretty curious.
Like in the topic you're studying,
now it's more of an application.
What are the more common
or specific hardware bottlenecks?
For example, the most common is of course the battery.
Or is there anything that is still difficult to overcome?
Or is it just that you need to find a better application?
Thank you.
OK, thank you for your question.
Yes, you just mentioned the battery.
It's already a big concern.
In terms of hardware.
The reason is because, think about it.
If you want to put a battery inside the body,
the size has a big limit.
Because the bigger the size,
the stronger the immune response.
Of course, we want to make the battery smaller and better.
Even without the battery.
Just use the wireless power transfer to provide energy.
So the battery is a concern.
In fact, everyone has been thinking about
how to give the power to the device.
Either by inductive coupling.
Or even using ultrasound.
In fact, I have been doing this kind of wireless power transfer project before.
Then I studied how to use ultrasound to provide this energy.
So everyone is also brainstorming
how to make this power better.
Because you don't want the battery to get into the body.
There is also a biocompatibility.
So basically all the batteries you need to use in the implant.
Like your pacemaker battery.
It also needs special design.
It must be placed in a good enclosure.
It must ensure that the electrolyte will not leak out.
And it won't short-circuit.
Because FDA has a lot of concerns about this.
Then you just talked about hardware.
There is another question.
Because you are doing antenna related.
So I would like to talk about communication.
How to get the signal out with the minimum energy per bit.
This is also a problem.
Because your body.
For example, if you use gigahertz.
It actually has a lot of energy damping.
It is actually wasted in your interstitial space.
Because your tissue is also for power supply.
And in the gigahertz range.
Whether it's water or ion.
It actually absorbs a lot of energy.
So if you want to use wireless.
If you send this data out.
It will waste a lot of energy.
So how to use this.
Maybe you want to find a frequency band.
Optimize your energy.
This is also a research question.
Then, of course, other things.
Like this sensor design.
Because now we can use the sensor on the left.
In fact, it is also limited.
Then how to improve this sensor design.
Then make it energy efficient.
Or this.
The smaller the bone factor.
So basically.
Let this patient.
When you put these devices in your body.
You almost don't feel pain.
This is also a direction.
So yeah.
These three aspects are actually Howard.
Especially in our lab that does this kind of device.
In fact, I have been working hard.
Hello, I have a more naive question.
But you just talked about the battery.
Then I thought at the beginning.
Hey, since the battery has its limitation.
Then why don't you use something like solar cells?
In this way.
To work hard in this direction.
You talk about solar cells.
Does it mean that you harvest energy from the environment?
Correct.
OK.
Yes.
Someone is also doing this direction.
But basically.
The current problem.
Because everyone.
May say.
If you want to harvest energy from the environment.
Where is your source?
The first one is probably.
Temperature.
But your body temperature is only 37 degrees.
So with you.
The room temperature is 25 degrees.
There is only a dozen degrees difference in the middle.
So this temperature may not be enough.
You use it to generate electricity.
Then the second one may be.
Is the motion produced by the body itself.
But there is a problem here.
The first one you are.
To make sure this motion is.
Is.
It has been happening.
Not like this.
For example, your muscles move.
Then it's gone.
You may want to.
For example, heartbeats.
Or breathing.
This kind of motion that has been happening all the time.
Then use this motion to generate electricity.
Someone is doing this.
Then the third type.
Is from chemical chemistry.
For example, glucose.
Someone is studying how to use glucose to generate electricity.
But this is still in the research stage.
There is no real commercial device.
The reason is that.
Its conversion efficiency is still too low.
There is no way to provide this.
The lowest power needed by the sensor.
So most of it is still.
It's all about providing power to the outside world.
What about solar energy?
Solar energy.
The first problem you encounter is the problem of light.
Because once the light enters the tissue.
For example, the skin.
It begins to diffuse.
After the diffusion, you can really penetrate the depth.
Only a few millimeters.
So after a few millimeters.
Basically, you can't see the light.
So there is no way to use solar energy.
Unless you put it directly on the surface of the body.
There is still a possibility.
Hello.
I am currently doing.
Biological research.
Then I am also studying.
I want to ask some questions about animals.
For example.
Now these devices are being developed.
Although I don't think so.
But still at some stage.
Because of safety factors.
Like traditional experiments.
Do you use experimental animals?
Or say.
These devices are for.
Because we know that animal experiments.
It is also necessary, for example, to draw blood every day.
Or measure blood pressure every day.
Or look at some of their physical changes.
Does anyone already use these devices?
Do some applications for animal experiments.
Thank you.
In fact, there is.
Basically, we.
These sensors.
Especially implant.
Is the device that is really placed in the human body.
Basically, all have to go through animal experiments first.
So actually animal experiments.
It is also a very good platform.
Can these sensors really work?
OK.
Like I have a colleague.
He is doing this.
I just talked about intraocular pressure.
This is the device for measuring eye pressure.
He basically puts it in first.
For example, to study in the eyes of rabbits.
Then look at his sensor.
Is it a good response?
Because basically.
The advantage of animal experiments is.
It's easy.
So.
Generally, if you are really doing implants.
Will use animal experiments first.
Then you just talked about.
Is there a device?
Really used to measure animal.
That.
For example, blood pressure or the like.
In fact, there is really a company doing this.
Is specifically for animal experiments.
Then.
It basically provides a.
A whole set of complete wireless.
This measuring system.
For example, blood pressure.
Then.
I forgot the other parameters.
But it can measure a lot of.
Basically very similar to people.
It basically can measure.
Because the lab often uses mice.
So it can measure the mouse's blood pressure.
Then, for example, heartbeats and the like.
Then it can put this.
Integrated into a platform.
Then give the lab people a reference.
So what you say is actually done.
OK, thank you.
Hello.
Hello, I am Red Stone.
Now at the University of Michigan.
As a postdoc.
Then I have a.
I have two questions.
The first one is that I heard before.
Is to use Fitbit.
These products.
They usually use it for a year or two.
Will be broken.
I want to know.
These are the devices.
Is the problem solved?
I didn't mention these questions.
OK.
Durability.
If the problem is.
In fact, I have been using Fitbit myself.
Its durability.
In fact, the main thing is.
Mechanical durability.
Its sensor itself is not broken.
But he.
For example, his wristband.
With this sensor.
The junction of the wristband.
There is actually a problem with the connection.
For example, you often go to this.
Exercise.
Then stretch it.
It is easy to produce mechanical fatigue.
Then the place where the fatigue is easy to break off.
OK, but this.
It has nothing to do with its sensor itself.
Because the sensor itself uses this optical method.
So unless you go on purpose.
To break it down.
Otherwise, it is actually very difficult to break down.
OK, so in fact.
This problem has already been solved.
So basically.
In fact, you just solve it.
Mechanical strength is OK.
So this is actually with the sensor.
It is not related to the problem itself.
It's just that it's designed.
I don't think so much.
OK, then the second question is.
About that EEG.
I want to know that.
When you use this.
EEG device.
You have to wear it on your head.
That is the helmet.
But you still have hair.
Those EEG.
Can't directly touch your scalp.
Then these.
In this case, those EEG.
Can still work?
Oh, yes, that's a good question.
They actually have a special design.
For this EEG.
It's not like what you think.
It's just a flat EEG.
It's actually a bit like an octopus's foot.
It has this.
For example, a few.
This helmet.
It's actually a bit like.
Add a little pressure.
On that EEG.
It can actually.
Go through your hair.
Then directly touch your scalp.
That EEG.
It's actually a special design.
Yes, thank you.
Hello.
I would like to ask a question.
Related to materials.
Because these wearable devices.
Relative to the skin.
Or any part of the body.
So their.
Capability is relatively better.
I can imagine.
Consider some mechanical properties.
If you consider these properties.
Biocompatible.
Bioresorption.
So it will be weaker.
Based on these.
Material selection.
What kind of material do you use most often?
Or is there any.
Already commercial.
Or is it special.
To synthesize these.
Polymer or organic.
To be able to do these things.
This is also a good question.
Basically.
Currently.
Whether in this.
The medical world.
Or this.
Medical equipment.
Everyone uses this most often.
PDMS.
That is.
This.
Silicone.
It's a bit like silicone.
Its advantage is because.
First of all, its material is very soft.
Second.
Its extensibility is very good.
You can pull it.
For example, more than 200%.
It still won't break.
Flexibility is also very good.
It can confirm.
Confirm to your skin surface.
Then it is.
Water and air.
It actually has this inside.
Porosity.
It has this nanostructure inside.
These small molecules.
Structure passed.
So basically.
Everyone's first choice is to use PDMS.
Then.
If you don't want to.
Let these.
For example, water vapor.
Or something else.
We will be outside PDMS.
Outside.
Coat a thin layer.
Polymer to protect it.
Like our lab.
A kind of.
Polymer material.
It can.
By chemical.
Then directly.
On top of PDMS.
It's a bit like.
Two-layer structure.
It's just that the outer layer is very thin.
It won't affect.
Overall mechanical property.
Then.
And this material.
It's actually a biochemical.
Then.
It's basically.
It's a bit different from PDMS.
Because it doesn't have this inside.
Nanoporous.
So it.
So it won't let this.
Water vapor to pass.
So if you want.
If it's a barrier.
In fact, you can add this outside.
Polymer.
Then you can ask.
What kind of standard.
Biofluid barrier.
Because we know these.
Protocols or biological.
It may be an electrolyte.
If it's on both sides of EEG or ECG.
These will not form noise.
Or other concerns.
OK.
Basically.
Of course, it depends on you.
What about the process of adding this material?
Like PDMS, it's almost.
If there is no process.
Just a few microns.
Just a few micrometers.
It basically won't have any.
This transparency.
So basically.
That's our criteria.
Of course, he started.
When commercialized.
At first.
It's actually used to protect the circuit board.
Is to protect the circuit board.
Not corroded by this water vapor.
So.
Their initial criteria.
It's about 10 or 20 microns.
Then we.
If you take it.
If you do this, it's probably the same thickness.
So it won't be much different.
OK.
Thank you.
I would like to continue the last question.
That is, why would you choose Perlin?
Don't choose PolyMNL.
Oh.
Actually.
There are a few reasons.
That is.
The first one is.
The two of them.
The physical nature is a bit different.
The first one.
PolyMNL is.
It's a bit like.
Semi-transparent material.
Then Perlin is completely transparent.
So if you want.
For example, optical.
If you want to use an optical device.
Perlin is a better choice.
Then the second one is.
PolyMNL.
That is.
Glass transition temperature.
Higher.
So basically you heat it up.
For example, 200 or 300 degrees.
It still won't deform.
Then Perlin.
It's when you heat it up.
200.
Around 200 degrees.
It's kind of like a semi-melted state.
So it's easier to shape.
If you need to shape.
Because.
Generally speaking, when we do Perlin.
There are usually two layers of Perlin.
So how do you put these two layers of Perlin.
Just put it together.
I usually use this.
Is the heating method.
To put it together.
PolyMNL.
I don't know if it is.
Easier than Perlin.
So generally.
We usually choose to use Perlin.
When the temperature is relatively low.
Yes.
So these are two.
More different places.
Of course.
Some people use PolyMNL.
His life.
It won't be as long as Perlin.
Some people in our lab.
Is the same.
Circuit.
The same circuit.
One is using PolyMNL.
The other is using Perlin.
He found that PolyMNL.
It can only last about a month.
And then the top ones.
Layout is starting to melt.
Is to be dissolved.
Then but.
Perlin.
Because it has a very poor water permeability.
So basically the water is not easy to pass through.
If there is no water.
Basically your ion can't work.
So his device.
Yes.
Thank you.
Do you have any other questions?
If not.
Then our speech is here.
Then I will turn off the recording first.