Hello everyone, welcome to today's Taira speech. I am today's host, Lin Bo-xuan, and today I am very happy to invite our speaker, Huang Jiao-yan.
He is now the first EQ in North Carolina to serve as Environmental Consultant.
This speaker's self-introduction is actually quite cool.
He has been in the air-conditioning environment research for more than ten years.
Recently, he gave up atmospheric chemistry research and started to be a policy analyst civil servant.
Today he will share with us the story of Taichung Power Plant.
The slogan is very simple, if you are afraid of death, you must listen carefully.
Then I will leave the time to Jiao-yan, thank you everyone.
Before we start, I would like to applaud and encourage everyone to remember to turn on the sound so that the audience can hear.
Huang Jiao-yan is so handsome.
Thank you, thank you.
Jiao-yan, please start your speech.
Today, I would like to talk about the impact of certain fixed pollutants on the downstream or the overall health risks of Taiwan.
Why do I want to mention Taichung Power Plant?
The main reason is that Mr. Zhuang Bin-jie published an article a few years ago.
He used his own air pollution model to run the Taichung Power Plant PN2.5.
The PN2.5 is a model that shows the impact on the overall health risks of Taiwan.
However, I think his analysis has some errors or bugs.
The main reason I want to talk about Taichung Power Plant is that in the past two months, we have been discussing whether Taichung Power Plant should be converted to a natural gas or maintain the current super-nearby coal-fired power plant.
Mr. Zhuang Bin-jie and Mr. Zhang Chang-chuen from Taichung Power Plant have done a lot of analysis.
I would like to discuss with you what these studies tell us about the real content or the story.
First of all, we need to discuss what air pollution is. Mr. Zhang Chang-chuen discussed what air pollution is in May.
Simply put, any material that is unbearable in the atmosphere is air pollution. The U.S. Department of Environment now defines six standard pollutants, including carbon dioxide, SO2, PN2.5, and NOx.
There are 187 harmful pollutants.
These pollutants will be released into the atmosphere through man-made or natural emissions.
Natural emissions include forest fires, VOCs, and chemical or physical reactions.
At the end, the pollutants will descend back to the ground, causing the human body to breathe in the pollutants.
There are two main levels of air pollution risk. One is inhalation, and the other is exhalation.
Inhalation is very simple. For example, when you stand next to a car and the engine is turned on, NOx and particles are released, and you breathe in these pollutants.
Most of these pollutants are not harmful to the human body, but they are long-term.
Another type of air pollution risk is intact.
Intact pollutants are harmful air pollutants that are released into the atmosphere and descend back to the ground.
These pollutants will be released into the air through biological accumulation, such as milk, fish, or fruits.
Most of these pollutants are not heavy metals, but they are organic.
Today, we will focus on the inhalation part.
We are currently discussing the PN2.5 and ozone part.
Before discussing the Taiwan part, I would like to discuss the current distribution of global air pollution.
This graph shows the global distribution of PN2.5 in 2013.
In this area, there are mainly deserts, so there are relatively small particles.
In China, it is mainly human-made pollutants such as fuel cells and mobile pollutants.
In northern India, it is mainly human-made pollutants.
In the Amazon, it is a natural pollutant, but it emits a lot of VOCs, which is volatile organic matter.
These pollutants will be released into the atmosphere through light reflection to produce secondary particles.
We will also see relatively high PN2.5 in non-rainforest areas.
In the US, PN2.5 is relatively low.
This is a graph of global air pollution in 2013.
This graph shows the highest value of PN2.5 emissions in three months.
Since 2005-2016, the U.S. has introduced a variety of control and regulation.
The U.S. has introduced a variety of control and regulation.