Hello, everyone. I'm the host for today. I'm Lin Yuwei from UC Irvine.
Our guest for today's TerraTalk is Lu Kefan, a Ph.D. student at Fairbanks University of Alaska.
His field of research is very interesting. It's about Arctic Ocean Sea Ice.
He also worked as an intern at the Department of R&D at Fairbanks University of Alaska.
He also taught for 3 and a half years.
He is expected to graduate next spring.
You can visit his defense course and watch the aurora.
Let's welcome Lu Kefan.
Thank you, everyone.
I don't want to bore you.
Plus, no one knows about this field.
So, I'll introduce the Arctic Ocean Sea Ice.
I'll talk about my field of research.
I'll also talk about my field of research.
At the beginning, we saw a video.
It's a popular video on social media.
It tells us how to reduce this year's sea ice.
It's about how to save the Arctic, the Earth, and the environment.
It's a similar title.
For me, the video's demand is correct.
But every time I see a similar video, I have to be careful.
What does the color in the video represent?
You may think that the white part is the size of the ice.
But in fact, this video is from NASA's Scientific Visualization Studio.
It calculates the age of the ice.
That is, the length of time the ice stays in the ocean.
Why do we look at the age of the ice?
Generally speaking, we will divide the ice into one-year ice or multi-year ice.
One-year ice is the gray part.
You can see that it fluctuates a lot every year.
Because it melts in summer.
When the sea water reaches the freezing point, it freezes again.
In fact, the thickness of the sea ice has nothing to do with its age.
The average thickness of one-year ice is about 2 to 3 meters.
Multi-year ice is the ice that has not completely melted in summer for more than a year.
Its thickness is actually about 3 meters.
The thickness of one-year ice or multi-year ice may be more than 5 meters.
So when you see a video like this, especially a large-scale video,
Because the thickness of the sea ice is very difficult to measure in the air.
So if you see such a large-scale video,
It is usually not discussing the thickness of the sea ice or its size or volume.
Next, let's look at the winter of 2016.
Take a closer look at the gray part.
For example, as I just said,
One-year ice is also 3 meters.
Multi-year ice is also 3 meters.
Then you will see that the whole piece is white.
Even the east coast of the United States still has sea ice.
Then visually, you will not feel so deeply that our sea ice is declining.
You will not feel that terrible.
But NASA made this video is not to intimidate everyone.
This video has several points.
The first is that we can see that most of the sea ice will flow out of the Atlantic coast.
This is the first point.
The second point is that if we look closely at the gray area,
Or look at the statistics next to it,
In the summer, the gray area is the part of one-year ice.
Indeed, there is a gradual decrease in the trend.
I will say that it is a decrease in the trend,
It's not that it's really decreasing every year.
It's because it's really decreasing every summer.
But overall, it has been gradually decreasing in the past 40 years.
The countries that are concerned about the research of the Arctic Ocean
There are mainly neighboring eight countries, including the United States, Greenland, Iceland,
Then the Nordic countries and Russia.
In addition to these neighboring eight countries,
There are some countries such as Europe, Germany, France, East Asia, Japan, South Korea, and China.
The reason why they are so concerned about the research of the Arctic Ocean is because
Everyone wants to take advantage of the summer when there is no ice.
Take advantage of the fishing rights and navigation rights in the Arctic Ocean.
So these distant East Asian countries,
Once they can use this red line,
This red line is the Arctic Ocean's North East Line.
It is now being used.
If East Asian countries use the North East Line to travel by sea,
If you send something to Europe,
Its navigation will be about one-third of the way to the south.
So for them, the melting of the summer ice,
Or the gradual decrease in the area of ​​ice,
For some countries, it's not entirely a disaster or a bad thing.
Or something you want to avoid.
Not to mention the United States, Norway, and Russia.
There are very large drilling projects along the coast of the Arctic Ocean.
Or mining natural resources.
It's not like what you see.
Greenpeace has tried to ban drilling in the Arctic Ocean.
And then they won.
It's not like that.
The reason why Shell stopped drilling in the Arctic Ocean
It's because they hired a lot of scientists to do research.
And then they found out that if they were to deal with the subsequent oil and gas problems,
And to strengthen the ecological balance,
They didn't lose any profits.
That's why they decided to withdraw.
But in addition to Shell,
There are a lot of oil companies in the United States.
Like ConocoFlips or BP.
They continue to drill along the coast of the Arctic Ocean.
Not to mention that the entire north coast of Norway is a drilling platform.
What about these countries?
Their attitude towards the reduction of sea ice is
Treat it as a natural phenomenon that is already happening and is almost impossible to reverse.
Their research focuses on how to deal with what has already happened.
For example, researchers from Alaska and Norway are now working on improving the shape of the oil platform.
Because we see that if there is less sea ice, the flow of the sea will be strengthened.
But there will still be some floating ice stuck on the coast.
These floating ice will be affected by the strong flow of the sea.
And then it will hit the oil platform.
And then it could cause a public safety accident.
So they want to improve the oil platform to reduce the slowdown of floating ice collision.
Or like the East Asian countries I just mentioned,
They are constantly studying when to enter the Arctic Ocean.
Which route to take to avoid aftershocks and shipwrecks.
For example, Alaska's King Crab is very famous.
As the sea ice retreats, the water temperature will change.
So we find that the King Crab is gradually moving north.
At this time, they have to consider whether to change the target species or change the area and timing of the King Crab.
These are all countries that are now working on Arctic research.
They are not completely treating it as a disaster to avoid.
Or try to recover to the original sea ice situation.
From this animation, we can get a lot of information.
A lot of sea ice is flowing out of the Atlantic Ocean.
This can be seen from the ocean flow cycle of the Arctic Ocean.
There is a lot of Atlantic Ocean water flowing from the Atlantic Ocean of the Arctic Ocean.
Because of the force of gravity, the King Crab will move along the right bank of the Arctic Ocean.
The Atlantic Ocean has an opening, and the Pacific Ocean also has an opening.
Why didn't the King Crab flow out of the Pacific Ocean?
This is because the opening of the Pacific Ocean is very narrow.
The width of the opening is about 100 to 200 kilometers.
The depth of the opening is about 30 to 50 meters.
The depth of the opening of the Atlantic Ocean is about 200 to 300 meters.
So once the Atlantic Ocean enters the Arctic Ocean, it is difficult to flow out of the Pacific Ocean again.
At the same time, there is also water flowing from the Pacific Ocean.
So the King Crab will continue to move along the right bank of the Atlantic Ocean.
The King Crab will continue to move along the right bank of the Atlantic Ocean.
This is the first reason.
The second reason is that we can see the picture of the King Crab.
The first reason is that we can see the picture of the King Crab.
Continue to the third reason.
The third reason is that the King Crab became very wet from the air.
Continue to the fourth reason.
Continue to the fifth reason.
Continue to the sixth reason.
Continue to the seventh reason.
Continue to the eighth reason.
Continue to the ninth reason.
Continue to the tenth reason.
Continue to the eleventh reason.
Continue to the twelfth reason.
Continue to the thirteenth reason.
Continue to the fourteenth reason.
Continue to the fifteenth reason.
Continue to the sixteenth reason.
Continue to the 17th reason.
Continue to the 18th reason.
Continue to the 19th reason.
Continue to the 20th reason.
Continue to the 21st reason.
Continue to the 22nd reason.
Continue to the 23rd reason.
Continue to the 24th reason.
Continue to the 25th reason.
Continue to the 26th reason.
Continue to the 27th reason.
Continue to the 28th reason.
Continue to the 29th reason.
Continue to the 30th reason.
Continue to the 31st reason.
Continue to the 32nd reason.
Continue to the 33rd reason.
Continue to the 34th reason.
Continue to the 35th reason.
Continue to the 36th reason.
Continue to the 37th reason.
Continue to the 38th reason.
Continue to the 39th reason.
Continue to the 40th reason.
Continue to the 41st reason.
Continue to the 42nd reason.
Continue to the 43rd reason.
Continue to the 44th reason.
Continue to the 45th reason.
Continue to the 46th reason.
Continue to the 47th reason.
Continue to the 48th reason.
Continue to the 49th reason.
Continue to the 50th reason.
Continue to the 51st reason.
Continue to the 52nd reason.
Continue to the 53rd reason.
Continue to the 54th reason.
Continue to the 55th reason.
Continue to the 56th reason.
Continue to the 57th reason.
Continue to the 58th reason.
Continue to the 59th reason.
Continue to the 60th reason.
Continue to the 70th reason.
Continue to the 80th reason.
Continue to the 90th reason.
Continue to the 91st reason.
Continue to the 92nd reason.
Continue to the 93rd reason.
Continue to the 94th reason.
Continue to the 95th reason.
Continue to the 96th reason.
Continue to the 97th reason.
Continue to the 98th reason.
Continue to the 10th reason.
Continue to the 11th reason.
Continue to the 12th reason.
Continue to the 13th reason.
Continue to the 14th reason.
Continue to the 15th reason.
Continue to the 16th reason.
Continue to the 17th reason.
Continue to the 18th reason.
Continue to the 19th reason.
Continue to the 20th reason.
Continue to the 21st reason.
Continue to the 22nd reason.
Continue to the 23rd reason.
Continue to the 24th reason.
Continue to the 25th reason.
Continue to the 26th reason.
Continue to the 27th reason.
Continue to the 28th reason.
Continue to the 29th reason.
Continue to the 30th reason.
Continue to the 31st reason.
Continue to the 32nd reason.
Continue to the 33rd reason.
Continue to the 34th reason.
Continue to the 35th reason.
Continue to the 36th reason.
Continue to the 37th reason.
Continue to the 38th reason.
Continue to the 39th reason.
Continue to the 40th reason.
Continue to the 41st reason.
Continue to the 42nd reason.
Continue to the 43rd reason.
Continue to the 44th reason.
Continue to the 45th reason.
Continue to the 46th reason.
Continue to the 47th reason.
Continue to the 48th reason.
Continue to the 49th reason.
Continue to the 50th reason.
Continue to the 51st reason.
Continue to the 52nd reason.
Continue to the 53rd reason.
Continue to the 54th reason.
Continue to the 55th reason.
Continue to the 56th reason.
Continue to the 57th reason.
Continue to the 58th reason.
Continue to the 59th reason.
Continue to the 60th reason.
Continue to the 70th reason.
Continue to the 71st reason.
Continue to the 78th reason.
Continue to the 79th reason.
Continue to the 80th reason.
Continue to the 71st reason.
Continue to the 87th reason.
Continue to the 88th reason.
Cause of IncidentEu regrowth.
Continue to the 84th reason.
Continue to the 85th reason.
The 37th reason.
Continue to the 87th reason.
3rd Reason.
The bottom of the ice water is a large layer of ice with a very high salinity of about 33 degrees.
The reason why it is called winter water is because when the sea water freezes, it releases a lot of salt.
After the salt has melted, it enters the sea water, which makes the sea water very heavy.
After the sea water freezes, it sinks to the bottom, leaving a large amount of high salinity and very cold water.
The water temperature is close to 1.8 degrees in the sea water.
This winter water stays at the bottom of the Arctic Ocean for a long time this year.
The bottom of the ice water is a very salty water with a very low salinity.
The function of the universal heat transfer is to differentiate heat conversion in a large scale.
My name is Oscar, I am a marine biologist.
Any other questions?