All right, so today's speaker is Fang Sichun, MD.
So Fang Sichun is actually one of my friend
back to college from entomology department.
And he's doing PhD in University of Texas, Austin.
And he's going to introduce some story about ants to us.
So just give the time to Andy now.
All right.
Thank you, Oscar.
Thanks for the introduction.
So today I have four things that I want to share with you.
The main idea is to show you the embryo development
of one of the live callers, one of the antennae ants,
and we also call it live callers.
The species name is Ada texana.
And since my childhood,
I bet everybody watched Lion King before.
And this is one clip from that movie.
That scene was fascinating.
That was actually the first time I knew,
oh, there are some ants with a couple leaves
and bring them back.
But at that moment, I didn't know what they were doing
or not even saying what is the social insects.
So I'm going to show you
what are the typical, like a true social insects around us.
Termites, honeybees, ants, and wasps.
So the typical pictures for social insects
is that they have hierarchical level.
For example, they have workers, they have queens.
Sometimes they will have big soldiers,
like a larger body size.
And also all of the characters I mentioned,
they're all females.
For those sexual reproductive system social insects,
they do have males.
So how do we distinguish the male and the female
social insects?
Oh, by the way, termites, it's kind of awkward.
The sexual determination for termites,
it's different as honeybees, wasps, or ants.
And we're not going to explore too much
about termites today.
Okay, so when we talk about the sex determination
for use of social insects, let's take ants as the example.
This is the word that people will see.
We call the haploid diploidy.
So haploid means one set of chromosome
and diploid means like two sets of chromosome.
Take us human being as the example,
we are diploid.
Okay, that means we have two sets of chromosome.
And the way that human being decides the sex
is based on X or Y chromosome.
But the story is different in ants world.
For the males, for the male ants,
they actually only have one set of chromosome,
which is haploid.
And for the females, including queens or workers,
they do have two sets of chromosome.
So let's say if the egg got fertilized,
that will become a future queen or future worker,
which is a female, right?
If the egg didn't get fertilized successfully,
can be a trophic egg or it can be a male, right?
So as I mentioned that Disney influenced me a lot
since my childhood,
but actually sometimes they make some mistakes.
So this is the clip from the Bugs Life by Pixar Disney.
The left hand side,
that's supposed to be a male worker in that movie,
his name is Flick.
And the right hand side is the princess Ada,
a female version queen that Flick fall in love with.
One thing, the first thing Pixar made like wrongly
is Flick can never be a male worker.
There's no male worker, okay?
And a second, if we consider the real situation
in the field, talking about Ada,
this genus, Ada Texana,
the queen, the size of the queen
is way bigger than the worker.
So if we want to correct Pixar in the movie,
it should be like this.
So that's a queen and a worker, okay?
And what's the real situation?
Here is the Ada queen and here is the worker, okay?
So how do you decide?
How does the egg decide to be a queen or a worker?
Since both of them,
they are deployed like a fertilized eggs.
It's still a mystery, okay?
So here I have a simple cartoon figure to show you.
Question marks on the slides means
there's still something like the mechanism
that we don't know.
So back to 1990s, Diana Wither and other groups,
they thought juvenile hormone plays an important role
at the late level stage to determine
whether that individual will become a future queen
or just a worker.
The more juvenile hormone got expressed,
the higher possibility that individual
will become a queen, okay?
And till 2015, another group, they figured out,
oh, EGFR, which is the epidermal growth factor receptor,
gene, plays another important role
during late level stage,
may involve in caste determination.
But the other group from Canada, Ahab's lab,
they published a series of paper back to 2008 and 2010,
and they brought up really interesting
and important finding as they thought
the caste determination may be determined
at a very, very early stage during oogenesis, okay?
Oogenesis means before the egg being laid,
i.e. the egg still in the ovary.
Due to some gene regulation,
their final character, like either queen or worker,
will be determined, okay?
And how about the embryo development?
Do people know anything about embryo development?
The answer is no before I start to have my PhD.
And that was actually quite surprising
because people study ants a lot.
For example, like fire ants, like how to kill them, right?
But or some interesting ecological concepts
or behavioral studies,
like ants are one of the hottest species
when you study insects
that people will just use as a material.
But surprisingly, we don't know too much
during the egg stage or the larva stage
or the pupa stage, okay?
People apparently care more about the later on stage
like the adult, like what's their behavior.
So when I look back to those references,
we left so many question marks, okay?
No matter like how many people study ants,
we still don't know too much about egg stage.
And there was the paper back to 2006
and they show some footage
of the embryo development of two ants.
The left-hand side, this one is Argentine ants,
which is the huge pest.
And this one is the Ferroni ants,
also a pest and it's quite common.
We also have that in Taiwan.
In the whole paper, there's only six figures
to show how does the embryo grow,
but to me, it's not informative enough, right?
Because I want to see like the start and the end.
Based on the figure, people thought like,
maybe the ants embryo development
is similar to Drosophila based on figure D.
Okay, why do people think like that way?
So there are three types of the embryo,
the insect embryos, okay?
Based on the size of the germ band,
we call it insect fate map, okay?
Here represents three types of the embryo,
long, intermediate and short, okay?
The color part is the germ band,
which will become a future embryo, a future larva, okay?
For the long germ band species,
you will have the head, thorax and abdomen part, okay?
If you are not too familiar with insects,
that's one, the three of the majority part of the body
of insects, head, thorax and abdomen,
well, and wings and legs.
For the intermediate germ band species like beetles,
at the beginning, once the egg being laid,
you won't be able to see the abdomen part,
you will see head part and part of the thorax, okay?
So that's the short germ band species like crickets, okay?
So I put a wasp here.
For social insects, lots of scientists,
they study honeybees and wasps,
and they compare the Drosophila,
one of the most famous model species
that people study embryo development.
They compare the wasp embryogenesis
and the honeybee embryogenesis with Drosophila,
and they figured out, oh, actually, they're pretty similar.
Those social insects, the wasps and the honeybees,
embryogenesis are pretty similar to Drosophila.
So people didn't pay enough attention to ants
and they just referred to, based on whatever they knew,
and they thought, oh, maybe ants,
it's similar to honeybees or wasps,
because they belong to the same order, okay?
And today, I'm going to show you that's not the truth.
That's not the whole story.
So four things I want to show you as the first,
well, I will talk about the ant embryogenesis,
but I will involve two different species,
except the Adatexanthum.
I will also include Microsaparus methi,
and I will explain what is the high
and lower agriculture mean later.
That's the first part.
And the second, I want to compare two types of eggs.
One is laid by the foundress,
one is laid by the mature queen.
Foundress means the new daughter queens
just fly out from the nest and have the mating flight
and start to build their own kingdom, their own colony, okay?
The fresh queen, okay?
Like the one you saw from the Pixar on the Bug's Life.
That's the foundress.
That's the virgin queen.
And the third part, I'm going to use
two genetic staining evidence to prove
that the ant embryogenesis is not the same
as honeybees or wasps.
And the last part, that's kind of like a side project
that I was lucky enough to figure out.
We found out some new story about the trophic egg,
and I will go deeper after.
So here's the first part.
The difference of embryogenesis
between low and high agriculture ants.
Here are the two species I include.
The Ana texana, the leaf color ants,
is the high level agriculture
based on the phylogeny tree.
And I will show you in the next slide.
And M. smithii is the low agriculture ants, okay?
And there are several features I want to point out
to show how different these two ants
are in different perspectives,
like the ecology or even the reproductive system.
First, Ana texana is sexual.
They do have the male,
but M. smithii, microcephalus smithii, they're asexual.
People also call them pathogenesis.
And the second feature is if you go to the fields,
you will figure out there are different size
of the workers of Ana texana.
There are some small workers, there are some big workers,
but for M. smithii,
they are no difference between worker size, okay?
They're almost identical.
Well, they're clonal, right?
They're asexual.
And so that's the size.
It's pretty similar.
So what is the high and low agriculture mean?
It's based on the position of the phylogeny tree, okay?
Here is the low agriculture ants,
the microcephalus smithii,
and Ana texana is the high agriculture.
In the fields, the low agriculture ants
not only use some dead leaf parts
or roses or branches to cultivate their fungus,
but also they collect caterpillar poops
to grow the fungus.
And the Ana texana, they basically cut the leaves
and bring the leaves back to the colony,
use those leaves as a nutrient to cultivate the fungus,
grow the fungus, and they eat the fungus.
So overall, we call them Antennae ants, okay?
Antennae ants means the ants will grow the fungus
in no matter what perspectives,
like in different ways,
and they eat the fungus and they live in the fungus.
So they are farmers, okay?
So when we look at the life history
for those two different Antennae ants,
they're on the two sides of the phylogeny tree.
We may think, oh, they're so different
based on their behavior, based on their ecology,
even their morphology, they look so different.
But surprisingly, they spend their egg stage,
it's almost identical.
So what does that mean?
That means they spend most of the,
I mean, sorry, they spend,
both of them spend about 20 days for hatching.
And how about those details
during the embryogenesis, the features, okay?
So the next slide shows the complete,
the first complete development table
for the Adatexana, okay?
From day one to day 15,
the eggs were from the foundresses,
from those nude or the queens, okay?
So there are lots of information here,
and I'm going to show you one by one,
explain one by one.
So the egg is about 300 micrometer,
and day two, you will see lots of nuclei
showed up on the surface of the egg.
We call it blastodon, okay?
Once you see that, the future embryo nuclei
will start to gather to the posterior part
of the egg and form a heart-shaped embryo, okay?
So first stage will be blastodon,
and the second stage will be the heart-shaped embryo.
The third stage will be the elongation stage, okay?
When the heart-shaped embryo, the germ band formed,
the embryo will start to elongate
and form gradually day by day when it gets older.
So the elongation stage
was from day four to day eight, okay?
And insects, they're autopods.
They have axoskeletons, right?
And they have different segments.
So segmentation is the final step
that's when the embryo grows.
So day nine, you can start to see those lobes forming,
the segments forming,
and till day 12, you can see,
compared with day nine, day 12,
there are more and more lobes adding up.
Day five, it's almost like lava.
And then the next day,
or within the same day, it will hatch, okay?
That's the overall concept of embryo development
of adatexana.
How about microcephalus methi?
It's pretty similar.
Sorry, the footage is,
some of the images are kind of foggy.
That was the image I took almost three years ago,
and we are recollecting the data for M. smethi.
But on day five, you can see the heart shape,
the future embryo formed,
and then the elongation happening,
and then segmentation happening,
just as same as what you saw from adatexana, okay?
So if we look at those four stages of two ants,
of these two Antennae ants,
higher agriculture ants, adatexana,
and lower agriculture ants, microcephalus methi,
those really similar feature, okay?
So the first part, the conclusion is,
even on the ecology, ecological or behavior perspectives,
they're so different,
but when we look at their embryogenesis,
they're actually quite similar.
All right.
The second part is the differences
between the adafoundraces and the mature queen laid eggs.
So why is it interesting to compare this two?
For a long time, people who study ants found out
that for those foundraces laid eggs,
they will usually hatch faster.
Oh, sorry, not hatch faster only.
For those foundraces,
usually they will have the first broods of workers
earlier than the mature colony, okay?
But for ants, there are different stages,
egg stage, lava stage, lava stage,
pupa stage, and then worker.
We don't know which stage got speed up,
or every stage got speed up evenly, okay?
For a long time, we just know,
for those new queens,
they will have the first broods of workers faster
than the regular queen,
but we want to know more details.
So since I have the expertise in studying ants' embryogenesis,
the egg development,
I examined the eggs laid by the foundraces the past summer,
and we found out something interesting.
So I hope you still have the concept
for the whole developmental series
in your mind of Antitech Center.
If we compare the eggs laid by those foundraces
and the eggs laid by the mature queens on the same day,
we can actually see the segmentation happens
faster in the foundrace-laid eggs, okay?
This is on day nine.
Three mouse part segments, the lobe formed,
and the future thorax segments formed already
on day nine of the adenue.
Adenue means the foundrace-laid eggs, okay?
But nothing happened except the future head lobe formed
in the mature queen-laid eggs.
How about day 12?
So if we compare day 12,
we can see actually from the new adenue,
the foundrace-laid eggs, sorry, the phrase is so long.
The foundrace-laid eggs will form multiple segments
at this stage, but not the mature queen-laid eggs, okay?
But does that mean there's no gene expression
involved in segmentation at this stage?
No, that's wrong.
So even there's no obvious morphological lobes formed
from those mature queen-laid eggs embryos at this stage,
there's some conserved genes.
For example, windlass here already has the expression.
And I will go deeper for those gene expression later.
At this moment, I want to point out that
we firstly saw that actually during the egg stage,
the accelerations got speed up already, okay?
How about the larval stage?
How about the pupa stage?
That we don't know yet,
but they are different at the beginning, okay?
That means those foundraces-laid eggs got speed up
when the egg being laid.
So those are the four stages,
blastorym, heart shape, elongation, and segmentation,
and then labeled at which date each stage happened, okay?
And so why do we have to know that?
Actually, that brought some interesting concept
about maybe we should exam some aging genes
involved in elongation or segmentation at this stage.
We want to figure out what's the causation
for that acceleration, for that speed up.
It's quite interesting, and that will be our next step.
All right.
Okay, in the third part,
I want to explain the germbane type of the ants, okay?
Recall what we just discussed.
The honeybees and the wasps,
their germbane type is the same as Drosophila.
It's pretty similar to Drosophila.
Drosophila is a fruit fly, okay?
They're a long germbane species.
And I want to know whether ants has the similar germbane,
or actually ants follow different development pattern.
And when people study the germbane,
we use conserved genes, okay?
What does conserved genes means?
So conserved genes means you can see the same genes
showed up for similar purposes in different species.
In the textbook example,
people compare the hawk's genes
by fly, Drosophila, and the mouse, okay?
Both of those two very different species,
they have hawk's genes.
And they have similar principle in embryo development.
Even the outcome is totally different.
So the hawk's genes expression
involved in segmentation formation in insects, in flies,
but in mammals, in mouse,
it involves in the backbones or somites formation,
or somites formation.
Like if you consider backbone,
it's also kind of like segment-like concept, okay?
So the take-home message for the conserved genes
means, okay, no matter how different the species are,
they share the similar genes involved in similar principle.
And how do they utilize those conserved genes
in studying the germ bin?
So here is quite a little bit complicated.
I hope that can recall your high school biology
or college biology.
First, I want to say is from DNA to RNA to protein,
there are different procedures, not procedures, sorry.
So DNA will be transcribed to RNA
and then it will be translated to protein, okay?
That's how it works in the world, right?
For sometimes, not every DNA
will successfully being translated to protein.
Sometimes it will just end at the transcription step,
like they will stop at mRNA
and no more protein will be made, okay?
And sometimes, yes, you will see DNA RNA
and then find a product protein, okay?
For those genes, for those conserved genes,
which will stop at mRNA stage,
we have to use in-situ hybridization.
And for the genes will successfully
being translated to protein,
we use immunohybridization, all right?
So let me explain it slowly.
For in-situ hybridization,
we have to make the RNA probe
by using a DIC-labeled nucleotide.
So DIC-label is just like a price tag, okay?
Attached to those nucleotides.
Nucleotides are the code for your sequence,
for our DNA or RNA, okay?
What are those codes?
Those are ATCG and for DNA, AUCG for RNA.
So we assemble those RNA probe
with the DIC-labeled nucleotide.
That's the first step.
And the second step,
we treat the sample with anti-DIC antibody.
So that's another concept.
Back to your high school or college biology.
What is the antigen?
What is the antibody?
So during spring, there's lots of pollen, right?
And you will sneeze
and you will have some immunoreaction.
The reason why you will sneeze
is because those pollens you sniff in,
those are the antigen.
And your body, you have your immunosystem.
Your body will recognize that out here
as a bad thing and start to generate,
start to make antibody.
So when the next time you face the same antigen
like the pollen,
your body will have enough antibody
to make that reaction
so you can sneeze those bad things
which are pollens out, right?
The bad things that is bad to your body.
So this is the same idea.
The DIC-labeled, the DIC,
is the site that the anti-DIC antibody can bind to.
It's like making different layers of sandwiches.
And we also have the alkaline phosphatase
attached to that antibody.
And then we use chemicals, MBT and BCIP,
to make the color.
Okay, that's the reason why we can see
with this successful binding
between the DIC-labeled conjugated probe,
the RNA probe we made with the DIC,
and the successful binding of the anti-DIC antibody
attached to it,
we can, and then the next layer is the MBT-BCIP.
We can successfully see those colors, okay?
I hope I explained it clearly.
So three layers.
The first is the MRA, okay?
The MRA expression exists in the embryo at somewhere,
but how do we see that, right?
We need to see some color, right?
So we know where does it happen.
And how do we know?
First, we make the probe, the MRA probe,
to anneal with it,
and then we treat them, the antibody,
the antibody attached to a non-detect,
and we use chemicals to trigger that colorization
so we can see the color.
When we see the color,
we know where does the MRA got expressed.
That's the big story in short.
That's in-situ hybridization.
Immunohybridization, same idea.
We also treat them with different antibody.
First layer is the antigen.
You can consider as a protein.
There are some binding sites on the protein
that the antibody can recognize, okay?
So two layers in this picture.
The first antibody will bind to that protein, right?
And then we treat the sample
with a second layer antibody
which attached to a fluorescent tag
so we can see the color
after the tag got excited by the laser, okay?
Well, same idea, okay?
I hope you don't get confused at this moment.
So for in-situ hybridization,
as for those expression stops at MRA, right?
Because there's no protein.
So no protein can be reproduced
so there's no way you can use the immunohybridization
to see the colorization.
But for the immunohybridization,
since you can easily make antibody attached to the protein,
then we don't have to make the probe.
Right.
And what do I want to see?
There are two conserved genes involved in segmentation
that you can see it in even really different species.
So this is the example
for grasshopper embryo development.
Witless is the first gene.
Engrailed is the second gene.
In each segment of the insect's embryo,
witless MRA will be expressed
at the anterior part of each segment.
Engrailed protein will be translated
at the posterior part of each segment.
So in the real sample,
you will see witless, engrailed, witless,
engrailed, witless, engrailed,
just like the cartoon that I showed you, okay?
For the mouse part, for the thorax,
for the abdominal segments.
How about those expression in ants, okay?
And why is it important
to see those two genes involved in ants?
For Drosophila, for fruit fly,
those segmentation gene expression
showed up in the same time.
That's the typical feature for long-germband species.
So people study honeybee embryo development,
they see the same pattern,
those bands showed up in the same time.
Sometimes depends on the species.
Sometimes it's like 14 stripes,
sometimes like 16 stripes.
Depends on whether it's a wasp or honeybees, okay?
But if you see all the bands showed up in the same time,
that's the typical feature for a long-germband species.
But not for a short or intermediate germband species.
That's the reason why I use those two genes
to see whether ant embryo is similar
to honeybees or not, right?
So with the concept of the whole story
of the ant development pattern, the embryogenesis,
I can, we can easily figure it out
when is the proper time for us to apply those probes,
like the wingless or the engrossed antibody, right?
We definitely don't want to apply those probes
at a very early stage before any segments formed, right?
Like the heart-shaped stage, no matter how hard we try,
there's no way we can see the signal, right?
We got to apply the probes or antibody at the right time.
That's one of the important reason
why we have to know the developmental table first.
So with that idea, with that concept,
we know between day nine to day 12,
like when the segments starting to pop out,
are the good timing for us to apply those conserved genes,
probes or antibody, okay, to see the signal expression.
So for wingless on day nine, as you can see,
there's no obvious stripes formed yet,
but started by day 10,
you can see three stripes over here,
the top row and this bottom row,
there are the same data,
but just use different way
to show the bands to the audience, right?
And when the embryo gets older,
more stripes are adding up, okay?
Those are the stripes number.
Day nine, you got zero.
Day 10, we see four.
Between day 10 and day 11, we see 10.
And until day 12, we got 12, okay?
So that's the evidence to prove that those segments,
those stripes are actually adding up.
They didn't show up simultaneously.
How about the engraved?
Let me recall that wingless and engraved
will be expressed at the same time.
One is at the anterior,
one is at the posterior of the segments, right?
So we should be able to see the similar pattern
when we examine the engraved gene expression,
engraved protein.
So the day 10 embryo,
you can see there's only eight stripes, okay?
But when the embryo gets older,
the stripes number get adding up.
So that's the second evidence to show,
all right, actually embryogenesis
follow different development pattern
as other social insects, okay?
So they're actually not long-term band species, okay?
They're more similar to like tribolium,
like the beetles or the crickets.
That's a really interesting and surprising finding.
How about other social insects
that is not similar to honeybees or wasps?
Yes, we do find the evidence.
There's another wasp show a different,
show the similar pattern,
development pattern as the ants,
which is either we can call it a short-term band
or intermediate-term band development.
So the green signals are the engraved protein,
like the one you just showed.
You can see when the embryo grow from A to H,
you start to see the signal adding up.
C, you only see one band, one, yeah.
You see, well, this is the first band got formed.
It's not the actual band yet.
But D, you see like three stripes,
and E, you got more stripes,
and till H, like before,
you see like 16 stripes, 14 to 16 stripes.
Okay, and the red dots over here,
those are another different gene called VASA.
We're not going to explain too much.
I'm not going to explain VASA today.
So not just in ants, but also other social insects,
different wasps show the short-term
or intermediate-term band embryo development pattern.
All right.
So can we say that the ants
has identical development pattern as crickets,
because they're not the same as flies or honeybees?
No, we can't say that.
I used the embryogenesis figure from two papers.
First, we know, okay,
based on the adding up stripes feature,
ants are not like flies or honeybees.
But the embryo, the germ band formed completely.
Imagine the germ band is the hot dog,
and the yolk, the rest of the embryo is the bone, okay?
The ant embryo formed the hot dog first,
like completely, and then segments formed gradually.
But in the short-term band species like crickets,
you don't see the full hot dog first.
You see part of the hot dog,
and then more segments adding up.
So when the embryo gets older,
the hot dog, the germ band gets longer and longer, okay?
In ants, you see the germ band formed completely,
then segmentation.
But in crickets, well,
you don't see that four complete developed germ band.
You see the segments and the germ band elongation,
like it happens in the short-term band.
Germ band, sorry.
You see the segmentation adding up
and the germ band elongation in the same time, okay?
So we think at this moment,
based on our DAPI standing morphological data
of the development table,
and the two conserved gene expression data,
the ants' embryogenesis is more like a mixture
of long-term band and short-term band, okay?
And the next part will be the trophic egg.
So trophic egg means the nutrient, okay?
And for a long time,
for those entomologists who study ants,
trophic eggs are considered
as one of the nutrients to those babies, okay?
Here's the picture I took that the workers,
the worker of Adatexana guards those eggs,
her future sisters in the fungus garden.
Usually the workers will chop off the trophic eggs
and feed those larvae when the fungus start to grow,
I mean, in the founding colony, right?
In the founding colony,
the queen only has small piece of fungus,
so there's limited food resource.
Therefore, the queen has to lay some trophic eggs
and use those nutrients, the workers,
either the workers will use the trophic eggs
to feed those babies,
or before the first broods of workers come out,
the queen will chop off those trophic eggs
and feeds them as a nutrient,
feeds to the first broods of baby as a nutrient, okay?
And the life history trade for a fungus growing ant
is the queen lay eggs,
and also she brought a small patch of the fungus
from the mother colony
and use her feces, poops,
to cultivate the fungus.
Meanwhile, take care of those broods
and make them, help them to grow up successfully,
and those workers, once she has those workers,
enough workers, those workers will take care of her
and also start to make the fungus garden be bigger,
like this, right?
And one interesting thing that I discovered,
like luckily, a few months ago,
is we found a new type of trophic eggs, right?
So when I first look at that,
I just thought, why the eggs,
the morphology of the eggs is so different,
they're so bizarre,
it looks like two eggs attached to each other.
And then I did multiple different sampling.
I figured out, actually, here are the fertilized eggs,
like here,
and those two are the huge, massive trophic eggs
that anneal to each other,
and even deform, okay?
So I sampled, like I got more samples
from those funguses,
and we can clearly see that those funguses,
they do lay trophic eggs,
like those massive trophic eggs
and the fertilized eggs in the same time, okay?
This is not the same you can see from the mature garden.
For the mature garden,
that we have, like four or five years old garden,
those queens only lay fertilized eggs.
So only during the foundries,
only during the foundry level,
like when they start to establish the fungus garden,
you can see those trophic eggs.
And here is their cartoon figure
to show three types of eggs.
The first one is the fertilized eggs,
like regular egg, the 2N egg,
and the second is, we call it trophic A,
and the third is the trophic B.
Here's the actual figure for fertilized trophic A
and trophic B, okay?
And I'll have more footage to show you
how do I distinguish whether that egg
is a trophic A or trophic B.
So let's focus on trophic B first.
One interesting feature for trophic B is
the egg is just like a water balloon.
It's so massive.
And when you place it on their solid place,
solid surface, it will deform, okay?
And if you place it on the fungus garden,
after 24 hours, it will be liquefied or deliquent.
Okay, what does that mean?
Why is it important to see,
like, why is it interesting?
So trophic eggs, for a long time,
people just think, people think,
or observe that either the new queen
or the new workers will use them to feed the babies.
But this is the first evidence,
first discovery to see that actually
trophic B egg can also be one of the nutrients
for the fungus garden, okay?
The fungus garden started with a small patch,
like a really small piece,
when the new queen fly out from their mother colony.
And the fungus garden ants,
the fungus garden ants, the leaf collar ants,
they cannot live without fungus.
No matter how many workers they got,
once they lost the fungus,
the whole colony will just die, okay?
So it's really important to make sure
that small patch of the fungus
the queen brought out from the mother colony
can successfully be cultivated
during the first or second month, right?
Okay, so we hypothesize that
the trophic B, the egg laid by the queen
has the evolutionary benefits
to make sure the fungus garden
can obtain, receive enough nutrient.
This is another replication that we did the collection,
and you can see after two hours,
in the first footage,
you see three trophic B eggs.
After 24 hours,
we clearly see that the trophic eggs
got deliquid, liquefied, okay?
So would the egg be liquefied
by the fungus only,
or it will be liquefied just by itself?
I mean, without the fungus,
we're really interesting to know that.
The next step we did
is we put the trophic B egg
on the compost slab
in the close to 100% humidity environment.
In the petri dish they've created,
after 24 hours,
the egg will be deliquid by itself, okay?
So it proves that
this is a really nice
co-evolutionary evidence
to help the fungus,
to help the queen,
like on both parties, right?
So the queen needs the fungus,
and she will lay those trophic eggs
to help her to maintain the fungus,
to grow the fungus to be better, okay?
And the egg itself will deliquid,
so it will provide the nutrient
or the water to that small fungus
and help them to grow well at the beginning, right?
We have more image to show the difference
between the fertilized eggs,
trophic A egg,
and trophic B egg.
For the fertilized eggs,
usually the eggs will be guarded by the worker,
and after 20 days,
depends on the temperature,
or 15 days,
it will hatch to larvae,
and will grow up to worker.
And those fungus,
the mycelium cannot intrude to those eggs,
cannot harm those eggs, okay?
On bigger B,
you can see the mycelium grow
on the surface of the egg,
but the egg's still pretty good,
in a good status.
And bigger C,
you can see the egg's still really,
it's not damaged.
But how about the other two trophic eggs,
the trophic A and trophic B, okay?
For the trophic A egg,
the mycelium will start to absorb
the nutrient from inside,
and cause the dent,
and eventually it just sucked up
all the nutrient by days,
like after 13 days.
And the trophic B egg,
it will deliquest by itself, okay?
Just like the way I explained to you,
and why it is important
to help to cultivate the fungus garden.
Okay.
So besides the image evidence,
I also fixed the trophic A egg
to prove that
we have two types of trophic egg.
So for the fertilized egg,
day five,
you can see the embryo start to grow,
like during the elongation.
This is the future head lobe,
here's the future body.
But the trophic A egg,
there's only a single nuclei,
and nothing happens,
and eventually the fungus garden
will absorb the nutrient.
Okay.
The last part of my talk will be,
let's go back to those males, okay?
So I briefly explained
how does the embryo grow in ants,
and the differences between lower
and higher level agriculture ants,
and no matter how different they are,
they show the similar development pattern
of their embryos.
And also, we found out a new type of trophic eggs
that people never discovered before,
and we had the hypothesis that
trophic eggs can also be the nutrient resource
for the fungus garden,
not just for the babies, the larvae.
And one interesting we found out is,
do you remember that I mentioned
the haploid diploid of the insects?
Some haploid eggs laid by the foundresses
will become a male, okay?
But usually that won't happen
when the foundresses started
to establish the colony, right?
Because only female workers are useful
that can help her to maintain everything.
The male individual is totally useless
at that stage.
They do nothing.
They basically just waste the energy,
and also they are not helpful, okay?
Ideally, that won't happen,
but we did find a weird nanotech male
from those founding colony, okay?
And those males are really small.
We call it nanotech.
Nanotech means like lack of nutrient
and body size is really small.
We found out that they have weird,
like fairy wings.
The wings are not well-developed,
and they were just crawling around
in the fungus garden.
Once the pupa occlusion happened,
like became an adult,
the queen will kill that within 48 hours, okay?
Oops, yeah.
So here's the complete vision
for the nanotech male of Eta texana.
The morphology is totally different
as the regular female workers.
We don't know the queen can recognize
the weird nanotech male by vision
or by the smell.
More studies we have to do,
but at least one thing we can assure is
during this stage,
the egg, the larvae, or the pupa stage,
here's the nanotech, future nanotech male.
Before pupa stage,
the queen will still take care of them
as the way the queen takes care of the workers.
But once they become the weird,
crawling around male,
they'll be killed,
like literally ripped off by the queen.
So that's also a new finding
that we're excited to publish
on Insect Social
of the behavior
so the queen knows
those are not actual helpful workers
and they will just kill them.
But the stories behind them
is like how does she receive the signal,
how does she know by vision
or by other smell cues
are really interesting to do more research.
All right.
I hope you guys don't fall asleep.
It's a long talk.
And overall,
I finished the four parts.
And thanks for your listening.
And please ask me if you have any question.
Thank you.
Okay.
Thanks for Andy's talk.
Let's give him a applause first.
Thank you.
Don't look at me.
All right.
So if you have any questions,
please just go ahead and ask Andy.
How many people we have?
Now we have six, including you.
Okay.
Sorry, the talk was like too long.
I was starving.
No, I think you're fine.
But your talk is pretty kind of professional.
And even I don't understand,
I would say half of the sites
because I don't study embryo genesis.
Anyway, the development of embryos, right?
Yeah.
But actually I do have one question.
Why do we care about?
So that question,
so first let me ask,
what is the germ band though?
Oh, so the germ band means the embryo.
The embryo itself.
Okay.
So the embryo has the yolk and the future larva.
And the germ band is just like the hotdog.
And the yolk is like the bond.
The overall, the two things,
we call it an egg, right?
Yeah.
So the future larva grow from the germ band.
Okay, start with the small heart
and then start to grow bigger and bigger
and then segments and then form the future larva.
That's the germ band.
And why do we need to care the difference
between long and short germ bands?
We actually don't have to care about that.
So, no, that's not true.
So that doesn't matter.
That actually doesn't matter.
Like, okay, yeah, it's long or short.
But the reason why I want to study this
is because the very first few slides
I mentioned cast determination.
So actually at the beginning,
I really want to know what are the genes
involved in cast determination in ants
if that actually happens during early stage.
But without knowing the complete development table,
I can barely can do anything, right?
I don't have the tool.
For example, for like flies,
people know how the embryo grows.
So I can see different gene expression
at different stage.
With that knowledge, I can do some prediction, right?
So if Ahab's theory is not saying it's wrong.
I mean, if his theory is correct,
we should be able to see some gene expression
during the early embryo development.
But how do I apply those probes?
How do I apply those genes
without knowing the development table?
We can do nothing, right?
So I got to study like how does the embryo grow first.
And surprisingly, we figured out,
oh, okay, so actually they have different pattern
like other social insects.
So we divide them into different categories.
So my finding just like to point out,
oh, ants, they are more like grasshoppers,
like crickets, not like honeybees or wasps.
Okay, so that's just a step
before you can move on to your further research.
Exactly, that's the foundation.
Yes, yes.
But if you ask like why does long or short matter?
No, that doesn't matter.
It's just like a prescription, right?
Okay, okay, okay.
Got it.
All right, are there any other questions?
Hi, I have two questions.
So I'm Jason.
I'm from, I'm Jason Hong.
I'm like a physics postdoc.
So, you know, I have no prior knowledge about the ant
and like I have no limited knowledge about biology.
So I have like one pretty simple question.
So you mentioned that for male ant,
it only has like one set of chromosome
and for female, there are two, right?
So like what determines that?
So for human, we know that it's,
so you have two kind of sperm.
So one is with X and one is Y.
And like that determines the sex of your like birth.
So like what determines that in the ant colony?
Right, so the egg has a single set of chromosome.
And if the egg got fertilized,
the sperm will bring another set of chromosome
into that egg, right?
So if the egg got fertilized,
it will be a two ant individual.
Like it has two sets of chromosome.
If the egg didn't get fertilized,
it will be a male supposedly from a mature colony.
Okay, I see.
Yeah.
So even not fertilized egg can be hatched in ant egg?
Theoretically, yes.
But there's some, like you don't see that,
you don't see male ants come out from the founding colony.
Founding colony means the colony just started to grow.
You only see the male ants come out from the mature colony.
Yeah, so that's also a topic like people want to study
the reason why.
Okay, so we don't know why yet?
We don't know.
We don't know why yet.
Okay, so I have another question.
So you mentioned that for the foundress ant
and the mature queen egg,
they have a different hatch time.
Right.
Right, so also like I guess you show the data,
but I don't remember you explain why that is the case.
And is there any method we can understand why?
So is it due to chemicals or due to some biological processes?
Okay, so we don't know the real key factors
involved in that acceleration.
And for now, we guess it's because of methylation.
So, all right, let's put it in the easy way.
So when, think about you're the new mom
and you have to start your colony
and there's so many birds or frogs trying to eat you
and you got to face those pressures in the field
and start like also having babies
and start to build your nest.
So you want to do that ASAP, right?
You want to do that as soon as possible.
Yeah, and that's the reason why we think that makes sense
that those foundresses broods will grow faster.
Okay.
Right, but what's the mechanism behind this?
What's the reason for causing that speeding up process?
We don't know.
Okay.
Oh, I also...
Oh, sorry.
Oh, maybe it's okay.
So I also heard that in humans,
it's actually like the first birth song,
you will have a higher probability for like early birth.
Is that the...
I mean, that might be like a very far away,
but is that something also similar?
Oh, I have no idea.
Really?
I actually don't know.
Okay, yeah.
So I guess you can check.
I don't know what it is.
It's a legend.
It's a rumor kind of thing.
Okay, okay, cool.
I will check it.
Wait, doesn't it mean the first born
will be larger than the others?
It will be faster.
The pregnancy period is shorter.
Oh.
In what animal?
It's more like the rate for early birth is higher.
Interesting.
Yeah, I would check it.
Okay.
I haven't heard about that as well.
I'm not very sure.
So you should double check.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
But that's interesting.
All right.
So are there any other questions
or other concerns or suggestions for Andy?
All right, if not,
I'm going to stop recording this talk.