Hello everyone, my name is Wu Mengchang, and I am a student at Mata University.
What I want to talk about today is about 4-way mixing and squeeze light.
If you have any questions at any time, you can ask, just turn on your microphone.
My field is in the field of atomic physics, which is relatively low-energy physics.
Our research unit is JQI, which is the United States Department of State.
It is a rather special institution, which is under the Department of Commerce in the United States.
Although they don't sound like they are doing this kind of specialized research,
they have actually won four Nobel Prizes in atomic physics.
So it's a pretty special national standard.
My instructor is Paul Leitz.
Our main source of research funding is from the Air Force in the United States.
At the beginning, I want to let everyone know what squeezing means.
We want to compress all the information into a better measurement.
After watching the video, let's get down to business.
The experiment we are doing now is using laser light.
The characteristic of laser light is that it is a coherent state.
What is a coherent state?
I don't know if you've heard of it.
I'm sure you've heard of the non-coherent principle.
The non-coherent principle tells us that we can't...
We used to think that the results of delta x and delta t must be greater than h-bar.
We can imagine that our laser light has a so-called non-coherent property.
Non-coherent property means that it has its government amplitude and its horizontal axis.
Both of these can't be measured very accurately in practice.
That is to say, it has its limits.
You can see that when our laser light is in coherent state,
Basically, it's always in coherent state.
When it's in coherent state, you'll see its...
Its FN or phase fluctuation is actually...
Its result is in...
That is to say, the curve on the left represents the line that meets the non-coherent principle.
Mathematically, we know that when your delta...
My y-axis is delta e, and my x-axis is delta phi.
If these two variables are in the minimum value,
When the two are equal, they are actually in their so-called minimum value.
Laser light is when these two values are equal.
Then it presents such a coherent state.
So what is Squeeze state?
Squeeze state means that you can...
That is to say, we don't need to measure all the information of laser light very accurately.
We can say that we just need to measure the phase very accurately.
Or we can measure our government very accurately.
When you see that your phase is measured very accurately,
In fact, it still meets its non-coherent principle.
Then it will lead to the inaccuracy of your government.
It will become very large.
Then your phase can be measured very accurately.
So a while ago, probably the year before last,
Isn't there a gravity wave measurement experiment?
It is to use this Squeeze light to throw away your impurities.
I will talk about quantum impurities.
Because you are in coherent state.
Then go to the limits of quantum mechanics.
Then push it to compress it so that you can measure the phase very accurately.
Then they may have a so-called interferer.
Then the interferer can measure the phase of something.
If the gravity wave passes over the earth,
Then you can measure the phase of this gravity wave.
There will be some changes.
As long as you have a way to enter this Squeeze state,
You can let a certain frequency of the phase be able to measure it very accurately.
Because the gravity wave passes through like this,
So its frequency will be very weak.
If you are very weak, your impurities will be very strong.
You need to have a way to get rid of this impurity.
Then measure to the phase you want.
But what we did in the experiment,
We did another one.
We are so-called Two-Mode Squeezing.
Two-Mode Squeezing is to say,
I'm producing two intangles of light.
That is to say, I now have some special light and non-linear effects.
Then produce two intangles.
What about these two intangles?
Some of their signals are exactly the same.
So if I input a light,
That light is called Probe.
Then it will produce its oscillation.
It uses a Twin Beam.
These two lights have each other.
For example, there is quantum co-relative.
That is, quantum co-relative.
Quantum co-relative.
So when I can put these two lights together,
I can get another one called Intensity Difference.
That is to say, I can let my Intensity Difference,
to measure the noise of this two-mode intensity is the lowest.
This may be a bit abstract.
I'll show you some data later.
If you don't quite understand, you can ask me again.
The preliminary introduction is,
I spent 20 minutes to introduce what happened.
I have introduced the background knowledge needed at the beginning.
If no one has any questions, I will continue.
OK.
How do we make this?
Excuse me.
You just said that the intangles,
How is it produced?
Is it also produced by something?
Is it produced by intangles?
We don't use intangles.
We use Rubidium Vapor.
Rubidium is a 2A group.
The Rubinium Nitrate.
Rubinium Nitrate.
We will hit a very strong laser beam.
This strong laser beam will have a non-linear interaction with a very weak beam.
Then produce another conjugate,
another intangle beam.
How are they produced?
I will introduce a little later.
How do they produce this twin beam?
I want to talk about 4-Way Missing.
4-Way Missing.
Total is 4 beams.
But we only put 2 beams in.
Then 3 beams will be produced.
There will be a more detailed explanation of the pattern later.
How is this produced?
Thank you.
Can I ask a question?
What is 4WM?
4 is 4.
W is 4-Way Missing.
Or translated into Chinese,
it is 4-Way Missing.
4-Way Missing.
I should say that it is the abbreviation of this.
My standard abbreviation.
Does it mean that 4 waves are mixed together?
Yes.
But you only have 2 beams.
I will show you a picture of the conjugate later.
Then everyone will be confused.
Did you just say that these 2 beams are added or subtracted?
Added.
Because they are...
Actually, they said that the intensity of the beam is 1.
Then the intensity of the beam will have a magnification ratio.
The magnification ratio is G.
So the light coming out is G.
Then the other conjugate beam is G-1.
So they even put that...
Originally it was Coherent State.
If it has a magnification effect,
it will become Thermal State.
That is to say, it is no longer the original laser beam.
It is a very messy light.
After the two conjugates are subtracted,
you will see the effect of the twin.
They become very messy together.
But when they are subtracted,
they will see that they are actually very beautiful and become messy together.
OK, thank you.
May I ask a question?
So what is the power of these laser beams?
My pump power is about 750mW.
It's quite big.
Of course, it can't be compared to super fast light.
We are continuous wave.
OK, you also answered my second question.
Sorry, let's continue.
The result we did is...
There is a relatively influential improvement.
Our previous records have always been in the range of Kilohertz.
When you want to look at the magnification compression,
the lower the frequency,
the greater the interference in other environments.
For example, you walk over there.
Or you have a call coming in.
These may have some interference in your system.
Then it will cause you to be unable to see the so-called squeeze light at a very low frequency.
That is, the compression of the magnification.
Even if there is a car driving on the main road,
it will have a great impact.
So our lab is doing experiments in such a deep basement.
Our result is...
Anyway, our previous records have always been in the range of Kilohertz.
In recent years, we have broken through the following three orders.
From Kilohertz down to about 1,000 times to a few Hertz.
You can see the effect of the magnification compression.
Especially like the gravitational wave measurement I introduced at the beginning.
It must be seen at a very low frequency.
Because theoretical mathematicians have calculated the magnitude of the gravitational wave.
So if you can only see the squeeze light of Kilohertz,
you can't use it to do these gravitational wave measurements.
So in the past ten years,
this squeeze light has been developed in such a way that it can still have this effect at a very low frequency.
In the future, it will be possible to measure the gravitational wave.
In the result of our experiment,
there will be some applications in image processing.
Because you want to see if you can pass the image through a very weak light.
Then maybe you can do some biological experiments.
A lot of low light hits your sample.
Then you can get rid of these impurities.
Then you can see the signal very clearly.
So it has some applications in biology.
Then it can even do some correction.
And it's a quantum correction.
Then I will continue to introduce it later.
This is our 4-way missing.
So on the right, we are.
This is our wafer cell.
I drew the picture like this.
The length of this wafer cell is about two centimeters long.
Then the diameter is about an inch.
Anyway, it's a very small cell.
Then you put a very strong pump beam in.
Then the strength of this pump beam is about 450 mW.
Then it will interact with the other very weak beam.
Then you look at the link map on the left.
There are a lot of links in it.
But we only care about the link that we will call.
This lambda type link.
It should be quite common to do quantum computing.
There may be something very famous in quantum computing.
It's called EIT.
Slow light storage technology.
Basically, it's quite similar to that.
For example, you hit a very strong pump beam.
Very strong pump beam.
Then it will interact with your probe beam.
Then this very strong pump beam.
It also interacts with the ground state on the other side.
Then because of energy conservation.
So it releases the fourth conjugate beam.
So you only hit two beams in.
But in a continuous operation.
It actually acts like there are four waves interacting with each other.
Two of the four waves are the same pump beam.
So this pump beam is at the same time as these two ground states.
What you want to see is that.
In addition to energy conservation.
It actually has to meet the other momentum conservation.
Then we usually don't talk about momentum conservation.
We also talk about phase matching.
In other words, this wave pump beam.
In addition to interacting with the probe beam.
The momentum inside.
That is to say, the pump beam and the probe beam have a very small angle.
About 0.3, 0.4 degrees.
Then we have four waves.
So the total momentum of this pump beam.
There will be two.
Then it will produce another conjugate beam.
So it's in the other direction.
Then you see.
When you have any phase fluctuation.
Or any frequency fluctuation.
It has to meet this.
Momentum energy conservation rate.
So any fluctuation has to make it consistent.
So this is a bit.
This is a more general way to explain.
Because they have to be energy conservative.
Momentum conservation.
So any fluctuation.
The fluctuations must be consistent.
In order to meet this condition at the same time.
That's how it produces the twin beam.
This is some of our experimental conditions.
Then you will see this delta.
Big delta.
This big delta is about 1.3GHz.
It's a pretty far detune.
Because of our experiment.
In fact, our entire group is called.
Laser cooling and tracking.
Our group is called.
Laser cooling and tracking team.
Research team is like this.
One of us.
Our big boss is.
We have a big boss.
Then there are four teachers below.
Then I did this.
The only thing is to do it with heat source.
This heat source is about 120°C.
We have to heat it up.
Then let it become a vapor.
So at the beginning, someone just asked.
Are we using crystal or what?
We are not using crystal.
If you use crystal.
There are other.
Also doing.
Or doing that kind of twin beam.
In fact, they are doing single mode.
Anyway, crystal can also be used to do that.
Squeeze line.
But.
Anyway, some principles are still a bit different.
We might use.
K3 is the third stage.
If it is crystal, it may be K2.
There are some differences in nature.
That's right.
Then the next one is.
We are several.
This one is about ten years ago.
Experimental results.
That.
You will see that.
Ten years ago.
We actually used TESAFA laser.
To do this experiment.
That.
TESAFA laser is.
Its feature is that it is very expensive.
That's about.
One or two decades ago.
We.
Buy a TESAFA.
About.
More than 200,000 dollars.
Then now it is more than 200,000.
Or its.
Power becomes stronger.
That's right.
You see.
The company is doing this experiment.
You need to have one.
Very expensive.
TESAFA laser.
More than 200,000 dollars.
This.
This is not practical at all.
So.
We started to develop.
Cheaper.
Then again.
It is a dilutable.
Laser light source.
That's it.
What about the TESAFA laser we used at the beginning?
Go again.
When doing this low-frequency quantization.
There is a.
Ah.
Should I talk about this first?
Experimental map.
What does it mean?
That is.
Here you will see the blue line here.
The blue line here is the so-called shot noise.
Then I just started.
Not to say.
Laser light.
It is coherent state.
What about coherent state?
In fact.
One of its features is that.
Its impurities.
Will not change.
According to the frequency of your measurement.
That is to say.
You are measuring.
You are now inserting a light.
This.
This picture has pink.
This light.
Insert.
Then you use this photodial.
To detect this.
Then send it in.
Spectrum analyzer.
That is.
Spectrum.
Spectrum analyzer.
That.
This spectrum analyzer will tell you.
This.
How much is the impurity of the frequency of this light?
If you insert this light.
It's a laser.
It's a coherent state.
Its impurities.
Will not change.
According to the frequency of your measurement.
Just like this blue light.
The blue.
The curve is like this.
We insert a light.
Then use a beam splitter.
Divide this light into half.
Then divide it into half.
Then subtract these two.
Then do the measurement of this impurity.
Then why do these two subtract?
Because.
You can also.
You can only measure one light.
That is.
You can also get a similar answer.
It's just the impurity power.
If you measure one light.
The impurity power will be halved.
If you measure two lights.
The impurity power will be doubled.
That's it.
There is another one.
The reason we want to divide it into two lights.
That is.
In fact, although the laser light is a coherent state.
But it's in the low frequency.
There are all kinds of impurities.
Will come in.
If you don't use two lights.
You can't put those.
The so-called classical impurity.
Or the technical impurity.
Eliminate it.
So you have to use.
Use one light.
Divide it into two.
Then do the subtraction.
Then measure the impurity.
This is the so-called.
I will talk about it later.
It is the so-called shot noise.
It's called the mega shot.
Its frequency.
It should always be flat.
This is a.
Our field is a very.
Ah.
I didn't know this was a common thing before I came in.
Then now.
Okay, this is the coherent state.
The impurity must be.
The so-called.
The so-called two-color frequency has changed.
So it's the so-called shot noise.
What about the red light?
This is what I just produced.
Glow beam.
I am not.
I am now.
To be more specific.
The setting of our experiment is to say.
I hit a pump beam.
Then.
Hit another glow beam.
Then these two.
Intensity.
The pump beam.
Its intensity is about 10,000 times as strong as the glow beam.
Yes.
Then it goes through this non-linear.
Element.
The element plus.
After the effect.
It will produce this glow beam.
This glow beam is amplified.
Yes.
Then it will also produce another one.
Conjugate beam.
So they are a twin.
Then after these two lights are cut off.
I call it.
Intensity.
Difference.
Squeezing.
Or in other words, it is squeeze.
In other words, it is squeeze light.
Then these two lights.
That is to say.
We will.
To control the light of this input.
Then let the power of the output light.
With these two lights.
The power of these two shot noise lights is exactly the same.
Then you will see.
When we.
If I have the so-called.
Squeeze light.
My two intensity.
Difference.
This is weaker than my shot noise.
Sorry.
Let me ask.
So the frequency of your four lights should be.
What is the range?
Because.
So the frequency below you should be.
The frequency of the big noise.
Right?
Ah.
It should not be called big noise.
Because these two.
The frequency of these two lights is different.
Yes.
You look at the left picture.
Have you seen this cross-section?
Yes.
So you have two pink lights.
Is it a wave of visible light?
He.
In fact, he is a distant infrared light.
Light of 795nm.
Ah.
Yes.
So that.
That is also right.
A few hundred terahertz.
Right?
Yes.
So you.
So you just.
The next page.
That one.
Um.
The following frequency is kilohertz.
Is it the difference between the two?
My.
The problem is.
Is.
The frequency on both sides.
You.
You want to see.
You have a side wave now.
Correct.
Then this side wave has a side wave frequency.
Right?
But I.
I am now.
I.
I'm talking about.
These noise.
To do.
Negative analysis.
Of.
Noise frequency.
Not to say.
My whole side wave.
What is the frequency?
Not this frequency.
But this noise.
He has his own frequency.
He has.
So.
So you just.
Your next page.
The noise.
Spectrum is.
These noise.
Spectrum.
Not the light itself.
Yes.
That is.
His noise.
Just make sure.
Um.
Good.
Thank you.
Continue.
Because like.
Light.
Light has his.
His distribution.
So.
Anyway, he.
He actually.
He.
There will be a.
Distribution of noise.
That.
If it is.
His distribution of noise.
That is to say.
His frequency.
The noise.
The power should be the same.
This.
That.
Uh.
Here.
For missing noise.
That is.
I.
I do.
Intensity difference.
When.
The noise.
That.
Uh.
That red.
This.
The noise of the customer.
Only left.
The original.
Only 17%.
His.
His noise is.
It's actually very weak.
That's right.
The focus here is to say.
You can see.
Hey.
When it's low.
There are some small peaks.
In fact.
This small peak.
That is.
This.
Very expensive.
There are very stupid.
The disadvantages of TESLA.
Because.
There will be cavities in it.
That.
This.
Cavity will.
Causing him.
Will have these.
The noise.
Run out.
So.
When you are in low frequency.
Will receive these.
Cavity noise.
Affect.
You can't see it.
Very low frequency.
Mass noise.
Compression.
Right.
That.
Assuming that.
Uh.
We are.
When doing experiments.
Sometimes put the laser.
Will lock the laser.
What does it mean to lock the laser?
Just let.
Its frequency is fixed.
It won't float around.
Or let.
Its width.
Narrow.
That.
The meaning of the line width narrowing.
That is to say.
I have a sine now.
That.
Your.
Is your sine a very simple sine?
Or.
Your sine.
Sine.
Or.
There is a plane.
The sine.
That is to say.
This plane.
I'm talking about.
Right.
This plane.
That.
Okay.
That's about it.
So.
There is a picture here.
That is to say.
Let's measure.
TESLA.
This.
When we lock the laser.
You will find that.
This.
The blue dash 9.
Is.
That is.
When we do time.
We just.
Anyway, just hit the light.
Hit in.
Fiber.
Then go.
To measure its.
Line width.
Right.
You will see that it is probably.
Maybe a few.
A few hundred.
Or a few dozen.
Kilohertz.
The blue dash 9.
Its width is probably.
Maybe a few dozen.
Kilohertz.
So.
Narrow.
It's pretty beautiful.
But.
It's getting worse.
This is.
The disadvantage of TESLA laser.
That is to say.
You lock up.
In fact.
Your frequency is fixed.
But.
The quality of your laser.
It's getting worse.
Right.
Then you have to.
Put it.
Line width becomes narrower.
In fact.
It will be quite complicated.
Then we look at another.
Red curve.
This red curve.
Is.
2D laser.
Then.
When you haven't locked up.
It's like this.
It's dash 9.
Red dash 9.
It's.
About a few.
Megahertz.
So wide.
But when we lock up.
After.
This red line.
It becomes very narrow.
It's probably a few.
Probably.
Even less than.
A kilohertz.
So narrow.
Line width.
So.
For 2D laser.
It may.
Our laser.
2D laser.
About.
Only 20,000 to 30,000 dollars.
So.
So it is also.
Relative to.
It's a lot cheaper than.
TESLA.
About.
One TESLA.
You can buy.
About nine.
2D laser.
Like this.
But.
2D laser.
It's actually.
Its.
Light is weaker.
Correct.
Then this is another team.
In.
Australian.
Experimental research.
Then he is.
I just forgot.
Who asked.
That is.
They are using.
Crystal to do.
Then their method.
It's not called.
4-way missing.
Then their method.
It's called.
What is OPO?
Ah.
Important.
Correct.
This is.
This is another kind of use.
Ah.
In the way of opening.
To do.
Squeeze line.
Then they.
This.
This picture on the left.
You will see this black.
This.
This straight line.
Is the so-called.
Shot noise.
I just said.
Laser light noise.
Then you will see.
There are other.
Very messy line.
There are red lines.
Blue line.
Red line.
Black line.
Blue line.
Then you will see.
There is a power here.
That is to say.
His power.
From 6.
Microwave.
Down to.
0.7.
Microwave.
Down to a few.
Power.
When.
You will see.
His.
Miscellaneous.
Low frequency.
When.
Getting weaker and weaker.
Correct.
That.
In fact, this piece of paper.
He.
I don't know.
Why.
Will be like this.
Anyway, they are.
They are a record.
That is to say.
It's at 280 Hz.
That.
In fact, we already know.
Why.
That.
He.
Because.
It's his own problem.
So there will be some.
Some.
Peak.
Noise.
Is particularly strong.
But.
These are not important.
The point is.
He can be very low.
Very low frequency.
More than 200 Hz.
Can still.
See.
The effect of the noise reduction.
As long as it is below zero.
Is.
The effect of the reduction.
That.
Blue line.
With black line.
Oh, no.
The red line and the black line.
Is.
At low frequency.
There are a lot of.
Classic noise.
Basic noise.
It's hard to see.
Noise reduction.
Effect.
Especially when.
It's very powerful.
When.
That.
This.
Next.
These are.
That.
Is.
To.
Thank you.