Welcome everyone to today's Taira speech, and I am the host today, Bo Xuan, and I am very happy that this is the first Taira history speech today, and the speaker today is Hong Qi Ting, who is currently a doctoral candidate for the history of Santa Barbara.
And now the main focus is American history, Asian American research, as well as the Cold War and Taiwan-US relations. I think these studies are quite important.
And today Qiqi is going to talk about the traditional Taira people, so let's not talk too much and let Qiqi start the speech.
Hello everyone, it's an honor to be here for the first time, and I feel a little sorry for everyone, because I didn't do much.
And my position today is that I personally hope that everyone can give me some feedback.
In fact, the topic I am going to talk about today is a part of my paper, because my paper mainly wants to study the role and importance of Taiwanese Americans in Taiwan's democratization and current Taiwan-US relations.
This topic is about the traditional Taira people, and I think it is a very important part of my paper.
The reason is that the traditional Taira people are in May, the whole month is a day to commemorate the multi-ethnicity of the United States.
And every May, it seems that the Jews and the Asians are all in May, and there will be a lot of commemorative activities related to the culture of the Taira people throughout the month.
This event can be said to be the most important event in the year of the Taira community, so I think this topic is very important to my paper.
It can be seen as a small fragment of how the Taira community mobilizes, organizes, and designs such activities to promote themselves internally and externally.
From this process, we can understand how the community of Taira people is formed, so it is a very important part of my paper.
Before I get to that point, I would like to mention that there is a national newspaper in the United States called the Pacific Times, which has a history of about 30 years.
It is the most influential Chinese newspaper in the United States or the entire North American region.
Their editor-in-chief asked me to write a topic like this, so I think this opportunity is very rare.
After I finish sorting out the information, I will publish it in the Pacific Times.
If I have time, I might turn it into English and see if I can post it in other newspapers.
For example, in May, when many Taira people started to promote traditional Chinese activities, they could take this information and introduce it to members of Congress in the United States or local communities, such as high school students.
If the audience of the article is different, the angle of discussion will be different.
So my current position is that how can I get the Taira people who are organizing this event and the Taiwan Committee to review the history and think about how we can improve in the future.
I have participated in two presentations as an audience, and the speaker has been talking about a very complete topic, which is his own research.
I'm not sure what my argument is, so I hope that if you have any questions, you can always ask me.
Because I think that way I can make my own thoughts clearer and I will know what is important and what is interesting.
This way, my article will be better written, so I hope to interact more and I hope to have a lot of questions, which can be a variety of questions.
Hello, I have a question.
Zhang Yan has a question.
Okay, go ahead.
So about this, I will ask a very basic question. What is the definition of Taipei people?
That's a very good question.
The definition of Taipei people is that you are a descendant of Taiwan, your parents are Taiwanese, or you are a Taiwanese immigrant.
Then you have an American nationality, and your wife is American, and she marries you, and she becomes half Taiwanese American.
Or you are the fourth generation, and your grandfather is Taiwanese.
They are all considered Taiwanese American.
Anyway, you are the same as the black man, as long as you have a drop of blood, you are Taiwanese.
They all count.
Then you have the right to be an American citizen, and you can be praised as a Taiwanese American.
But there is one thing that I think must be included in it, which is your own identity.
Because this thing is also related to Taiwan's history.
Although Taiwan is not mainstream, but some people think it is Chinese, it is not Taiwanese.
And I'm talking about the Chinese, it's not that I'm Chinese, I'm Taiwanese.
Some people think he is a member of the People's Republic of China.
I will not draw that kind of person in the range of Taiwanese American.
And the other thing I want to talk about is this holiday.
In fact, he has, I think, behind my own research, more and more, I found that he was behind the politics with the Taiwan government.
The political component of the US government-Taiwan-US relationship is actually there.
For example, in the eight years of Ma Ying-jeou's administration, the Taiwanese American society in the United States.
Basically, they hold a traditional week every year.
But they didn't take money from the Taiwanese government, and they didn't ask the Standing Committee for help.
Many of the elders I'm visiting now, they just say that we don't need to take the money from the Kuomintang.
Yes, and now that Tsai Ing-wen is in power, some people think, ah, forget it, we can still work with the government.
So I think behind this, he's actually not just a very pure cultural thing.
He also has some political identity of Taiwanese people.
And the Taiwanese American as a very special group of people.
When I talk about Taiwanese American, I think of Taiwanese American.
Because from my research, from 1950 to 19, there are a lot of people coming from Taiwan to the United States.
But not everyone thinks they are Taiwanese American.
About half of the people think they are Chinese American.
So this thing is a very important difference.
So to answer your question, I would say that the first thing is related to blood.
Your family, your gene, there is such a link between Taiwanese people.
Then you are now an American citizen.
Then another thing is identity.
I think it must also be considered.
So in other words, if you are actually in the Taiwanese American, identity can also be allowed in many ways, right?
Because it is possible that Lin Shuhao, although he is related to Taiwan,
but he does not necessarily feel that Taiwan is his home or something like that.
If this is also considered Taiwanese American?
This question depends on which context you are discussing.
For example, Lin Shuhao, his parents, his great-grandparents seem to still be in Taiwan, right?
So he will travel to Taiwan.
Then he will go fishing in Taiwan.
He will go to Taiwan to eat dumplings.
Fishing is a very open event.
He was not asked if he was Chinese or Taiwanese.
He just came to that place because of his great-grandparents.
So when he has a vacation, he will want to go to that place.
I think in that context, he is Taiwanese, there is no problem.
But if today is a very special occasion.
For example, he was asked if he was going to play in China.
Then you have to admit that you are Chinese American and he is Taiwanese American.
At that time, I think it is a totally different story.
And this kind of contradiction, this kind of entanglement is actually not just Taiwanese Americans.
Taiwanese people will also face this kind of problem.
Now there are 31 meetings in Taiwan.
I don't want to make any judgment.
Everyone has their own way to survive, right?
It's just that when he's on that occasion, he's bound to change his identity.
Then it won't be a topic for me to discuss.
Because when I say that Taipei people are a highly political issue.
It's because in my paper, I want to make an argument.
That is to say, my question, my paper has a very big problem.
Taiwanese Americans as a person who immigrated to the United States under a very special Taiwan-US relationship during the Cold War.
Their experience is very different from Chinese Americans.
If you have read the book Asian American History.
If you read Chinese American, his story, his argument is all the way from this 19th century.
Chinese workers came to the United States to help the plantation workers.
Then help to build the railway.
Then in the 20th century, it was a slum movement.
Then everyone is hiding in Chinatown.
Then they all have long braids and then they eat rat meat.
Very, very different image.
Then after the 1950s, the Chinese American image is that they are a group of refugees from the Communist Party of China to the free world.
Then I got to Taiwan.
Then I got to Hong Kong.
In that sense, Taiwanese immigrants were placed in this whole line from the 19th century.
Chinese workers, then the slum movement, then the refugees.
To understand Taiwan in this context.
I think it's very problematic.
Because the first thing is that in the 19th century, we didn't have anyone.
At that time, we were still in the Qing Dynasty.
We moved from China to Taiwan for the second time.
We are not discussing the context of Chinese Americans.
Then in the second to 20th century, the group of people who lived in Chinatown because of the Paihua Act.
Also with our impression, our memory is different.
Because in the 20th century, Taiwan was ruled by Japan at that time.
Most people want to immigrate.
For example, my grandfather went to Japan to study, not to the United States.
The United States is not the main immigration place in Taiwan.
The United States has become the most important place for Taiwanese immigrants.
And even in the 1960s, the most important immigration country.
It started after the Cold War.
So Taiwan's immigration to the United States is actually a very modern, very cold war story.
If you don't emphasize this, you will become a Taiwanese-American, Chinese-American.
I think a lot of people think that if you read the textbooks, or you read the textbooks.
A paradigm that has been established seems to be unbreakable.
You will take it for granted.
Yes, we are Chinese-Americans.
We are like that.
But I think this is the first thing.
The first thing is that he simplifies the story.
The story is not that simple.
Second, identity in American society is a self-claim.
You can say what you are not.
You can say what you are.
No one can force you to say who you are.
This is the case in American society.
So I think because we have this space, we should go even better.
Even if Taiwan and China are in a very complicated situation in Asia,
it doesn't mean that you are already in the United States.
You have become a Taiwanese-American citizen in the United States.
You have no right to say that you are a Taiwanese-American, not a Chinese-American.
So I think behind this, this Taiwanese-American,
he is what I want to use, my argument.
There is a very important argument in my paper.
I want to bring up the Taiwanese-American, independent of the Chinese-American.
And why can this Taiwanese-American be independent of the Chinese-American story or argument?
In fact, it is a very special experience of Taiwanese-Americans immigrating to the United States during the Cold War.
And what is that very special experience?
That is, under the martial law of Taiwan, many people came to the United States in order to oppose the Kuomintang.
Then, oh, no, it should be said that they came to the United States under the martial law of the Kuomintang.
After they accepted a lot of liberal ideas, progressive ideas,
they began to oppose that authoritarian rule and then to promote Taiwan's democracy.
The most obvious example is the Paris era.
After the Melita incident in 1979,
where can those refugees like Xu Xinliang be accommodated?
Most of them came to the United States.
Then you can also know that every time something happens,
money and international aid are mainly provided in the United States and Canada.
One argument is that because of the experience of Taiwanese-Americans immigrating to the United States,
there is a connection with the opposition to authoritarian rule.
After you connect them together, you will find that this is very different from the Chinese-American context.
You should not mix them together and say that they are all Chinese-American.
Then the second one is that when studying the democratization movement in Taiwan,
in fact, the role of overseas Taiwanese is not given enough attention.
It seems to be just a side story.
But I don't think so. I think it is actually very important.
And this importance, especially after the Democratic Progressive Party came to power,
I think it should be emphasized more.
Yes, I'm a little far away now.
OK. Hello, is everyone still there?
We are all still there.
OK, OK, OK.
Are there any more questions?
I would like to ask if you are sharing the screen now or have not started yet?
I haven't started yet.
OK.
If you want to share the screen, you can confirm it.
Because I'm afraid you won't be able to share it.
OK, I'll press share first and then press my screen.
Can you see it like this?
Not yet.
But I'm already on my screen.
Now you...
Let me think.
My computer is now on my screen.
Then you jump back to BlueJeans.
Then BlueJeans, you slide down from the middle.
You should see a share screen at the bottom.
A rectangular blue button.
Yes.
OK.
Then...
You should be able to choose after you press it.
Yes.
1 or 2?
Now we can see it.
Then you can press play.
OK.
I'm recording.
Is it recording now?
Yes, yes, yes.
OK.
So the topic I'm going to talk about today is Taiwanese traditional porridge.
My PowerPoint is actually very simple.
Just four pages.
So you're welcome to ask any questions you have.
My structure is also very simple.
What I'm going to talk about is...
What is Taiwanese traditional porridge?
And why is it important?
Before we start, I'd like to ask if anyone has participated in a traditional porridge event in the U.S.?
We have three people here.
Hello?
I'm going to help with the traditional porridge next week.
Where are you going to help?
There's a circus troupe coming from Ann Arbor.
Are you going to Chicago or Michigan?
They're probably going to perform in Chicago.
But the elders have brought them to Ann Arbor for a one-night show.
So there's a show in your city, too?
Yes, there's a vacancy here.
So you're going to see it and help with the venue?
I'm going to help with the venue.
Oh, OK.
I interviewed Professor Li Xianglan from your city.
I think he's in charge of the committee in Chicago.
He told me about the event in your city.
I haven't participated in it myself.
I'm going to participate this year.
I'll post a link to the event in LA.
Let's take a look at the event.
This is the LA schedule.
You can see from April 21st to June 16th.
It's been over a month.
LA is special because it has the most Taiwanese in the U.S.
So there are a lot of circus troupes here.
If there are a lot of circus troupes, there will be a lot of shows.
So you can compare it to Chicago.
There are a lot of Taiwanese, but not as many as there are here.
So what I know now is that there's an event in Chicago.
There's a local singer from Taiwan.
There's a show from the committee.
There's a teacher from the Taiwan Food Association.
He's in charge of a food event.
There are a lot of circus troupes in LA.
So there are a lot of activities.
If you look at the schedule, you can see there are a few types of activities.
The most popular one is the food tour.
It's on May 20th in LA.
It's in a park in Montreal Park.
It's a whole day's event.
In addition to the food tour, there are also live performances.
In the major cities I know, including LA, San Diego, Chicago, and DC,
there are also food tours.
In addition to food, you can also see in LA.
I think it's a special event.
It's not just about performing, eating, and playing.
There are also community service events.
For example, today in LA, there's an event to clean up the LA River.
It's to contribute to the local community.
I also know that there's a dentist in Taiwan.
Some doctors provide free dental services.
I also know that there's another thing to do with the local community.
In many places, other than LA, there's also one in San Diego.
When there's a bridge, they'll donate money.
At the opening of the traditional week, there's a high school scholarship.
It's not limited to Taiwanese children.
It also includes people of other ethnicities.
For example, in San Diego, they give six places every year.
It's stipulated that four of them must be foreigners.
Last year, they gave an Arab.
It seems to be a refugee.
He came to the United States and applied for a scholarship to support his financial needs.
I also know that there's another one in San Diego.
It seems to be from Syria.
When you look at the traditional week in Taipei,
you'll see that it's not just about promoting Taiwanese culture.
This is a very important goal.
At the same time, there's also outreach.
It's connected to the local community.
It allows the local community to know more about Taiwan.
There are three different activities in the traditional week.
I'll talk about this later.
Let's take a look at what the activities are about.
Why is there a traditional week?
In 1992, President Bush announced that May was the traditional month of the Asian-Taiwanese in the United States.
In fact, the traditional week in Taipei is put in the context of the Asian-Taiwanese traditional month.
The main purpose is for the U.S. government to praise the Taiwanese and Asians for their contributions to American society.
Why is it chosen in May?
May has a very important relationship with the history of the Asian-Taiwanese in the United States.
There are two reasons for choosing May.
The first reason is that the first wave of Japanese immigrants arrived in the United States in May 1843.
The second reason for choosing May is that the cross-strait railway was completed in 1869.
More and more people believe that the cross-strait railway in the United States was built by Chinese laborers.
For example, the 101 in Taiwan was built by Taiwanese laborers.
The 101 is our icon, but it was built by foreign laborers.
Sorry, I have a question from the audience.
I want to ask how you define culture and what is Taiwan culture?
My paper also discusses relevant issues, so I want to discuss it.
This is a question from Annie.
This is a very good question.
Because I actually have a question mark where I look at the end.
So, when we get to the end, when I talk about the wrap-up,
I will discuss my own observations of the activities of traditional music.
Actually, it will be there soon.
Because I only have four PowerPoint slides.
So, I will write down my question.
I will answer it together at the end.
So, this event was chosen in May because of its contribution to American history with two Asian ethnic groups.
Because of the history of Japanese and Chinese, it was decided to be held in May.
In 1992, Asian traditional music began to be played.
In 1999, during the Clinton administration, the US Congress, in order to praise Taiwanese for their contributions to the United States,
decided to separate Taiwanese from the United States.
So, in May, you can choose a specific state.
Now I know that a lot of people will choose the state of Mother's Day as Taiwanese American Heritage Week.
This has become a trademark.
It is Taiwanese American Heritage Week, not Chinese American, not Asian American.
It has its own independence.
This is very important because it is related to the organizer's outreach to the local community.
When there is a Taiwanese American trademark, it can promote Taiwan and China in private.
So, there is a diplomatic connection behind it.
I will talk about this later.
So, this is Taiwanese American Heritage Week.
But there is an exception.
I know that there are a lot of Taiwanese in D.C.
But they did not come out of the traditional state of Taiwan and the United States independently.
Instead, they celebrated the Asian American Heritage Month together.
I think this is an exception.
I don't know why they don't particularly emphasize Taiwanese American Heritage Week.
Maybe because it's in D.C.
It's more political sensitive.
So, they don't want to cause trouble.
So, they put it in the context of the traditional state of Taiwan and the United States.
It can avoid some tensions.
But other places, other than D.C.,
Taiwanese communities in other places, when they celebrate May,
they put the Taiwanese American Heritage Month in the context of the traditional state of Taiwan and the United States.
So, why is this important?
There are three levels.
For the American society,
the reason why they set up this month to commemorate
is to praise the contribution of American minorities to American society.
In addition, they want to promote multiculturalism.
So, for the American society,
this is their main position on this event.
For the Taipei community,
it is an important event to establish,
gather, and strengthen ethnic identity.
I want to share this.
When I was writing this article,
I wanted to understand the different dynamics in different places.
So, I visited different areas, different generations, and different positions.
Some people are just participants.
Some people have participated in many events,
and they are the main organizers.
From the perspective of different people,
I wanted to understand the different meanings of this event for different people.
I found it very interesting.
Older people,
people who came to the United States in the 1960s and 1970s,
the first generation,
when the traditional state began,
they were the founding fathers.
For them, this month,
this kind of commemorative event,
of course, it is important to let the mainstream society know them.
However, because their English is not good enough,
it seems that the younger generation of Compare
is not able to fit into the mainstream society.
How can we use the language that is familiar to the mainstream society
to talk about this culture,
to talk about this tradition?
Their ability is relatively lacking.
So, when they organize this event,
they tend to serve the people in their own community.
For example,
when I visited the organizer in the Bay Area,
he said,
his name is Cai Hejie.
He is a second-generation American.
He grew up in Illinois in the Midwest.
He is very special.
He does not speak Chinese at all.
He often goes to Taiwan.
He is an American,
and he is not studying Humanities.
He studied Engineering in college,
and now he is a physician.
He is a second-generation American.
Anyway, he is such a person.
I asked him,
why do you want to participate in this event?
What is the significance of this event to you?
He said,
he used to be a white person in the Central Department.
So, he had an identity crisis when he was young.
He felt that
in American society,
either you are a white person,
or you are not a white person.
What kind of person is not a white person?
He was born in the 1970s.
He said that
when he was a teenager,
the mainstream American society
did not have enough nutrients
to tell him what kind of person is not a white person.
He was confused.
I asked him this question
because I know a lot of second-generation Taiwanese.
I know a lot of second-generation Taiwanese.
Although their parents are Taiwanese,
their grandparents are in Taiwan,
but their interest in Taiwan
is very superficial.
They say,
I will go back to Taiwan to see my grandpa.
Taiwan has pearl milk tea.
Pearl milk tea and stinky tofu are delicious in Taiwan.
Other than pearl milk tea and stinky tofu,
he has zero understanding of Taiwan.
Many people do not speak Chinese.
I know a lot of people
who are more concerned about Taiwan.
The United States is the place
where they choose to settle down.
Although Taiwan has a Taiwanese
ethnic concept,
Taiwan is a foreign country
and is not important.
I know a lot of second-generation Taiwanese.
Many people are white-washed.
When they look at the identity,
they are more concerned about
their professional career.
For example,
I am a doctor.
I have a lot to do with my community.
I don't care if I am Asian
or if I am white.
Ethnicity is not something they care about.
There are a lot of people
who choose this option
in the Taiwanese community.
Cai Hejie is very special.
He made me feel that
he made me feel that
he understands Taiwanese people.
He doesn't blame them.
He thinks that
Taiwanese American identity
is important
and he is willing to spend a lot of time
on this issue.
a completes your choices
doesn't matter
because it is your choice.
He started in Ilino
then moved to San Francisco
He has been participating in various activities
but he is more concerned about the activities of Taiwanese
He even has an online website
called Taiwanese American.org
I read a lot of things
I think it is great
If you are interested
I will give you his link
since opening
grandparents
governor
doctor
processed
sent
send
Sapporo
Now these young people
generation after
there is a big change like me
For example, I went to visit the organizer
in Portland. He said
that his previous activities were
usually held in a high school
and then in the auditorium of the high school
he felt like that
he was not so satisfied he felt
he could do better
so he last year and the year before
when the general recruitment
he rented a venue in the city of Portland
Yes, but he is very advanced
and that venue because he is a
mainstream society everyone wants to go
to see the show to listen to the concert will go to that place
so you are holding an event in that place
you can use his platform to promote
to do a lot of promotion
and outreach work
so his visibility
suddenly increased
from this example you can reflect
for the older generation
of course, on the one hand, they have their own
limitation and then on the other hand
because
they are not fit in
so it seems that one of the purposes of this event
is to serve their own community
so in the end
it becomes a community
but the new generation
of the younger generation
because of their ability to adapt to culture
or the ability to interact
with different cultures
so in addition to being able to
internalize
and also to build
this Taiwanese American identity
to do such a
cultural construction
it can actually outreach to the
mainstream society of the United States
so that the mainstream society of the United States can understand
what is the Taiwanese American Heritage Week
so I think
this is a different generation
they are organizing
such an event
they have a lot of different ideas
this is different
at the same time the reason is
different generations
have the ability to interpret
culture and have the ability to
interact with different cultures
and then it also reflects
different generations
what is the positioning of this event
my own observation is
now the young generation
in fact, their main ideas are
hoping to make the mainstream society
of course, because I am more leftist
so what is this mainstream
I will criticize a little later
this is also a question mark
but their idea is
we are going to the White House
we are going to Union Square
we can let the mainstream society
know what we are doing
what is Taiwan
what is Taiwanese American culture
so there are different generations
will reflect a different
way of thinking
and this reflects
when they are organizing
there will be a lot of differences
for example, in San Diego
it is mainly the older generation
who are organizing
the most important thing is
there will be delicious Taiwanese food
and I heard that
there is a mom in San Diego
who is very good at making zongzi
the zongzi will disappear
so she started making zongzi
about 3 weeks ago
she can make more than 1000 zongzi
and it seems like
it will be sold out in half a day
so the traditional week
they want to participate
because they want to visit
their hometown
to see
where they grew up
so for us
it is a group of Taiwanese
they will feel
so nostalgic
I will go there
and share with other Taiwanese
how to cook
so for us
how to strengthen
their feelings
for Taiwan
but for the younger generation
of course there is
I will go there
because I want to eat Taiwanese food
I think there is a reason
but for the young Taiwanese
organizers
this event will be
how we use this occasion
to talk to the mainstream society
to discuss
or to promote
what Taiwan is
and the importance of Taiwan
so I think
I see a
very different place
and the third
I think is very important
this event is very important
I interviewed
the director of
L.A.'s church
and I talked to him
about the role of the church
and I found
for example
in Chicago
every year
the church
will have two groups
to the U.S.
East Coast and West Coast
East Coast will go to
10 different cities
to perform
West Coast
will perform
in different cities
this is the work of the church
and they will pay
to invite these groups
and the food and accommodation
of these groups
will be paid by the church
but the church
has a very limited budget
so it is impossible
to invite
for example
Yunmeng Wuji
and secondly
they can't
go to too many cities
for example
more than 15 or 20 cities
because they can't afford
and when it comes to local
they don't really
have the human resources
to support
local performances
so the director
told me
a very important concept
which is the diplomatic issue
he told me
in the U.S.
the church
is just an auxiliary
they are very grateful
to the U.S.
Taiwan Bridge
because the Taiwan Bridge
these groups
when they go to the local
although the church
will pay for the food
but the local
for example
celebration
these groups
are not hosted
because the U.S.
network
is not enough
so you can see
this is not
like we are
helping the Taiwan Bridge
assisting
the Taiwan Bridge
I think it is the opposite
is very important
for Taiwan
but the church
is not enough
and they can't
do it well
so we need to rely on
the Taiwan Bridge
like I interviewed
a person
he said
the church
pays for the local
the local
they pay for the local
he said
they don't ask for money
from the government
they pay for the local
for example
this year
there is a cooperation
with the Taiwan Bridge Committee
but I know
the main
teacher
he is not
from the Taiwan Bridge Committee
he is a Taiwanese
living in the U.S.
he likes Taiwan
he wants to help
the U.S.
so he used
his own money
to pay for the local
everything is his own
so I think
this is what I want to
develop
in Taiwan
like my friend
in Portland
every year
there is a committee
to discuss
to raise funds
in May
they bought the tickets
for 5 months
but usually
they need to pay
for the tickets
they usually
buy the most expensive
tickets
they didn't go in
so a group of Taiwanese
because it's
12.52pm
there is still
10-15 minutes
so let me remind you
sorry
I can't finish
so I think
I want to develop
but I don't know
where to go
so I want to emphasize
Taiwan's government
is in a difficult situation
and needs Taiwan's help
I want to emphasize
Taiwan's organization
is very strong
so I want to
answer the question
what is the problem of culture
I observed
so many different places
doing this
I found a few problems
these three questions
I think they all answer
what is culture
how do you define it
and what is Taiwan culture
the second question
I found it very interesting
I read the Taiwan public opinion
in the Taiwan-US traditional week
just started
not long
there was a discussion
the Taiwan-US traditional week
the American people want to promote Taiwan culture
and write books
and cut paper
what is the difference
this is a very interesting question
this problem still exists in Taiwan
so we say Taiwan culture
Taiwan is different from China
but where is the boundary
where is the boundary
if we are in the US
we want to promote Taiwan culture
if our agenda
is to distinguish Taiwan from China
how should we navigate
to make the boundary
very obvious
so people know
this is different
my observation
I don't think this is a good way
but I found
we don't do it
what is left of Taiwan culture
isn't Chinese culture
a part of Taiwan culture
I think this is a problem
even in Taiwan
you can't make it clear
this continues to the US
I saw some people
for example
they invited Taiwanese aboriginals
this is different from Chinese culture
these kinds of attempts
are to make the boundary
but my question is
what is the higher priority
what is the main agenda
to make the boundary
first
is the solution the best
second
is the boundary
that important
isn't Chinese culture a part of Taiwan culture
second
this is related to culture
I myself
I saw a lot of
photos of the traditional week
and their annual activities
a lot of people would record
a lot of times
I would find it funny
I had a discussion with a friend last year
he was in San Francisco
he was in Union Square
he was passing by
he wanted to see
because I'm Taiwanese
he saw a big
dragon
with three dragons on top
his face was shaking
and he left
he was like what is this
Taiwanese culture
my second question mark
to promote
Taiwanese culture
this kind of festival
you will find a lot of times
if the organizer is not self-aware
he will end up
repeating
the American
mainstream society
and the superficial
image of Taiwan
the patriotic
image
Taiwan is bubble tea
Taiwan is stinky tofu
Taiwan is inviting aboriginals to perform
and inviting
Taiwanese to sing
Taiwanese songs
this is Taiwan
but if an organizer
is organizing a cultural event
his imagination
I would
I would feel
scary
because
you are
inside
what is this
what is his influence
what is he
when you are doing this
when you are organizing
does he make you know yourself better
or does he
just
restrict
your imagination
I think this question
is important
I am not
from
many events
I can see
some hope
some people
I talked to
they told me
for example
Dr. Tsai
he does a lot of
events
and he feels
in his events
he wants to
emphasize this
show what is
Taiwanese culture
he cares about
events
he invites people to
spend a lot of time
researching
what stories
are unknown
to Taiwanese
Taiwan's latest research
on history and culture
and new discoveries
new debates
he is willing to
include these
he does not want to
to a superficial event
Taiwan is stinky tofu
Taiwan is Xiao Long Bao
Taiwan is traditional dance
we drink bubble tea
we are Taiwanese
he thinks
this kind of
cultural imagination
is a pity
and superficial
I have seen this kind of attempt
another attempt
this is Taiwanese American
heritage week
not Taiwan culture
I tried to ask them
this is Taiwanese American
heritage week
not Taiwan heritage week
how do you draw the boundary
and distinguish it
of course
on the one hand
Taiwan culture is part of
Taiwanese American
you do not need to
clearly say
which part is Taiwanese American
which part is Taiwan
this problem may not exist
for the older generation
this problem may not be an issue
on the other hand
I heard some young people
willing to think about this
they will say yes
I think Taiwanese American
is a little different from
Taiwan's culture
how should I
in such a cultural festival
to show the difference
they will start
some people
they were born in the United States
and then use English
to write their memories
of Taiwan
what is their imagination of Taiwan
draw or write
some short articles
use that way
to present
Taiwanese American
as a very special
he is not Chinese American
he is not Taiwanese
a very special existence
to see such a common sense
it exists
to respond to
what is the culture
I think I still think
that point
Taiwan culture
how do you distinguish
Taiwan culture from Chinese culture
I think this will be an issue
the second issue
you can apply
to a bigger issue
when doing the creative industry
you have to think
how can I push further
to let
deeper understanding
or imagination about culture
not just to copy
the imaginations of the mainstream society
I don't know
if I have answered
your question
for me
my question is
I believe most people
can agree that
Taiwan culture
even Taiwanese
are trying to define
in such a situation
we are in the US
actually abroad
to hold a Taiwan culture
promotion
in 1998
we have been promoting
calligraphy, pen and paper
xiaolongbao
in the next 8 years
we have been promoting
calligraphy, pen and paper
in the next 8 years
it is not stable
we are still
searching for
identity
to hold such an event
is it positive
or negative
I would say
identity
this concept
is always flowing
so I don't think
it has to be
stable
but we have been
talking
there may be
conflicts
finally we found
a consensus
we all agree
I think
it is
so you can find
for example
indigenous people
you can say
it is politically correct
but it is
kind of
after 30 years
we have been
discussing
it has become
an important
cultural icon
or heritage
so I would say
identity building
identity
it is not
a consensus
it is
a process
a process of discussion
it is not
a clean
it has many
grey areas
but finally we found
a consensus
we all agree
there are many
these things will
continue to move forward
I don't know if I answered
your question
thank you
because of the time
you can
wrap up for 3 minutes
thank you
so
my point is
when I look at
a cultural
traditional week
for me
there are two important things
one is
three
why it is important
I think
we should not
give up this opportunity
to introduce Taiwan to the US
because it is
not only
important for
diversity
it is also
a tool
to promote
Taiwan
so
if
I become an organizer
it will be
an important
part of my agenda
so
the second
is
how to
encourage
and organize
how to
gather our
fellow citizens
to have
more
interaction
to know
who we are
I think
these are
two important things
the third is
how to help
Taiwan to
promote diplomacy
because
the US is still
the place with the most
Taiwanese
if we can do well
I think this model
can be applied
Taiwan has a lot of
important work
and meaningful
things to do
anyway
thank you
for the wonderful speech
before we end
I want to ask
if there are any questions
we can chat
if there are
any questions
we can chat
Emma left
but she said
LA and Mazu temple
yes
she also
invited
the master
what was his name
anyway
is it Oscar
yes
I don't know if this is a question
or an idea
when everyone
is promoting the traditional state
and the theme of Taiwan
I think
the biggest difficulty is
young people in Taiwan
don't want to
come out to help
rely on the old people
old people are pushing
is that enough
I don't know
I think my question
is more like
how to make more people
willing to promote this
instead of these Taiwanese
I will say
remind everyone
you are sharing your Gmail
you can turn off
the sharing screen
luckily I didn't
post it on Facebook
remind everyone
you can answer
yes
I think this is
a good question
I talked to some elders
because the Taiwanese community
has a very important crisis
the elderly have retired
they are old
it's like
there are generations
of problems
different ideas
so I will say
young people
don't come
it's not just young people
it's also
old people
for example
I can't accept
the elderly
who talk to me
we grew up
in the era of
martial law
we are the generation of
sunflowers
even if you are a
pro-democracy
you talk to me
like an old green man
I can't accept
the anti-KMT
the KMT is very
sexist and racist
I can't talk to them
will it be recorded?
will they hear?
hello?
yes
but
if you have
something you can't talk about
wave your hand
and tell me to cut it
I don't know if we have a name
the answer is
young people don't come
because
young people and old people
have different ways
of doing things
I know many young people
they are willing to
do things for free
but they
will leave
they are not happy
because they don't think
they should be treated like this
so I think this problem
is the internal organization
of different generations
young people
I am very busy
you want me to do a lot of volunteer work
it depends on my ability
I have to work
I have to write papers
I have to do unpaid work
if I have good physical strength
I don't have to worry
one of my worries
I will be willing to commit more
but at this stage
there is no way
let alone those who have children
young people don't come
I think our job is
to create a space
this space is very friendly
a very warm space
it's ok if you cannot join now
it's ok
we understand
but I will tell you
this space is always welcome
if you have time today
you can come
as an organizer
I will position myself
I am not saying
why don't you come
why don't you love Taiwan
I think this is too harsh
because everyone's life agenda
different time points
their tasks are different
yes
understand
thank you
thank you Oscar and Qiqi
for your answers
I want to ask
one last question
if not
we are ready
to end today's speech
do you have any feedback
let's ask if there are any questions
yes
I will count to three
feedback
do you have any
points to add
I have a suggestion
I think you asked
a lot of questions
these questions
are actually
related
but
I think
these questions can exist independently
so if you
say them all
like a group
without a specific
order
connect them all
actually
the most important question
you have to ask
is not that clear
so I think
you may have to
make a choice
these materials
the question you want to ask
at least
in this article
you may want to ask another question
but you can answer
from these materials
and you want to use this question
to ask the question of the paper
that's another question
but I think for a presentation
like you want to write to the newspaper
you may have to think about
a very clear question
and you have to give up some
secondary but these materials
can also answer the question
otherwise the structure
will not be so clear
there are a lot of materials
you have to tie up
the most important thing
very good advice
I think
this research is very interesting
because actually
I had a few Taiwanese friends
who came to the US
they had a meeting in the US
and they did business in Taiwan
they wanted to promote
Taiwan's exquisite agricultural products
to the world
such as milk and coffee
and fruit jam
the exquisite processing of fruit
of course they are very
recognized by Taiwan
but we talked about
what is the Taiwanese culture
for example
a group of Chinese
went to New York
and made a Chinatown
are these cultures
American culture
if so
how do we define
Taiwan culture
I think this is
a very important issue
of course I have no answer
and I'm not an expert
but I think this kind of research
is very important
to all Taiwanese
so I think it's great
I can understand
that kind of
in a hurry to cut
the workers
the traditional Chinese
Chinese characters
I can understand
their anxiety
because you are
doing a political battle
you want to establish a
discourse as a weapon
for your political agenda
you have to be very careful
anything that can weaken your argument
you have to figure out a way to get rid of it
so I can understand their anxiety
and their persistence
but
but I think
I can accept
and I can understand
and I think it's a process
when Taiwan is really established
these things can all come back
now
you can only let it be
vague
you don't have to mention it
you don't have to talk about it
you can talk about it
assimilate
with the English
family
process
as an organizer
as a political organizer
it will be
considered as a
can throw away
can
can use, can not use
depends on different context
when it's useful, you use it
when it's not useful, you keep it
no need to build a
unbreakable
Taiwan culture is what
I think you don't have to
set yourself to death
you don't have that flexibility
to swim in different
different context
Oscar
seems to have a question or not
seems
no, I just think
this question, I also think for a long time
then I think
uh
should say that in my experience
is
I think
it is more likely to
make Taiwan into a
speaking
uh
is a little bit of an
assimilated society
to let people know that Taiwanese people are
what people have, for example
for example
last week we just
held a speech
and then our theme
is to put all kinds of people
in the picture
he is a Japanese
so he has his own
Japanese elementary school students
and his grandmother is Chinese
and then his
anyway, there are all kinds of people
different races over there
and then our theme at that time
is to define it as Taiwan is
everything
because we are
an island, it is impossible to have only one thing
everywhere
this is the influence of many cultures
so you see a certain
aspect of Taiwan, like you said
Mazu, in fact, it is also the people of the south
Mazu is also from Meizhou
that is not Taiwan, of course you can
seriously say that the real Taiwan is also the indigenous people
that you are in the indigenous people is actually from the south
to the Yuxin side, it is also the real Taiwan
that is not
so I mean
instead of going to find a
fact, like you just said
is to find a majority
then I think instead of
finding a very clear
subject, it is better to be very honest
so that everyone knows
Taiwan is everything
you see is not a whole
and then we have
elements of Chinese, we have elements of Japanese
even the Dutch
and Spanish
really
just an
impression
I agree with this
this is the controversy of the textbook
although the KMT has been saying
that the KMT is going to China
but in fact, the KMT is hoping to
you can't say
that the KMT brought in something wrong
right?
How do you navigate that direction today?
You look at the world
from a different angle, if you look at Taiwan
from a diversified perspective
you will find that it
is not just a Han society
it is not
just the history of the past
great China
made it into a
history written from the perspective of the Han people
that
are there any other questions?
because I think the time
is actually almost
that
looks like everyone
should have learned a lot today
like me
I heard a lot of things
at the end of the speech
I want to talk a little bit
because I was listening to your speech
I suddenly thought of a little story
I started from high school
I participated in the
indigenous tribe service
I basically go there every year
we are in the camp
every time it is about a week
every time we go to the camp
there will be a show
and then I was
the first year I went up the mountain
I was very shocked
because the first year we let the children
decide what to play
and then they played the theme
I think it's amazing
although they are all
very playful
but you can see the context of their life
for example, there is a play called
Grandpa is drunk
or the sister who sells incense
or father beats sister
you will go
although they are very
if they are free to play
they will talk about these things
so I thought
every year to hold a traditional week in Taiwan
is like an identity
a time point
so if you see
activities or slogans used
in this traditional week
more or less
reflects the identity of
our subgroup
I think it's very interesting
after listening to your speech
when they write their own things
they will say
as long as the topic they write is
we let them decide
what to play
we don't care
let them play
so it can be imagined
that those children
from Taiwan National High School
what they can think of
must be the most direct theme in life
they can immediately think of
who the grandpa beats
or who the father is drunk
you can imagine
although you can't see
but these are their life
and they are exposed to these things every day
this sharing is great
just like I just mentioned
a question
if you don't reflect
will you just repeat
what the mainstream society
imagines of you
I think
the culture they can imagine
is very different
from the story
you have heard
and I think
this diversity
should be brought out
but I think
I have organized
things
and when you are
very busy
sometimes you can't think
just like the past
just let it be
it's simple
there is a network
you can't be sure
whether it will be popular
there are all kinds of considerations
so I think
you will continue
the imagination of the past
but this is very dangerous
because it simplifies a lot of things
and what's worse
if it just reinforces
it doesn't help
the mainstream society to understand Taiwan
it's harmful
so
that's it for today
thank you
I'm looking forward to it
I feel like
I'm the type of person who keeps talking
now I have more inspiration
keep writing
that's it
thank you for your participation
that's the end of the speech
you can leave the chat room
good night
next time I will talk about
the South China Sea issue
and the Chinese
good luck
you too, bye
good night