Hello everyone, and welcome to our Terra Talks on Wednesday afternoon.
Our speaker today is from Germany. Her name is Candice Zhu.
She is going to talk about two topics today.
The first topic is related to the American medical education and training system,
including some information related to hospitalization and doctor application, and some background.
The second topic is her personal doctor's course main research topic, which is related to the topic of chronic kidney disease.
Please feel free to type your questions in the chat box.
I will check the chat box to see if there are any questions.
Before we get started, I would like to introduce our speaker Candice Zhu.
Her personal bio is from the University of Taiwan,
and she has a Ph.D. degree from the Institute of Biological Sciences,
and she has already passed her candidacy.
She has a Ph.D. degree from the Institute of Biological Sciences,
and she has a Ph.D. degree from the Institute of Biological Sciences,
and she has a Ph.D. degree from the Institute of Biological Sciences.
Thank you Candice for being here today.
My original topic was to share one of my Ph.D. projects,
but I realized that most of the members of TARA are related to engineering or engineering,
so I wanted to talk about a more interesting topic,
which is veterinary education.
First, I will talk about my Ph.D. project,
which is a program called DVM, Doctor of Veterinary Medicine.
Then, I will talk about my Ph.D. research.
Let's get started.
First of all, veterinary education in the U.S. is different.
We apply for a veterinary degree after graduating from high school.
In the U.S., you need to go to a four-year university,
take a course, and apply for a veterinary degree.
After four years, you can take a national exam.
If you want to pursue further training,
you can spend a year as an intern.
Intern is a term used to refer to a student who is already a veterinarian.
After the internship,
some people choose to apply for a veterinary doctorate.
Some people choose to apply for a veterinary doctorate.
After the internship,
you can apply for a veterinary doctorate.
There are 30 veterinary medical schools in the U.S.
There are only one veterinary medical school per state.
Some states have more than one veterinary medical school per state.
Texas A&M is the only veterinary medical school in Texas.
Here is the ranking of veterinary medical schools in the U.S.
There are different rankings.
UC Davis and Cornell are in the front.
Texas A&M is a good veterinary medical school.
Everyone is called DVM,
but if you are a UPenn graduate, you will be called VMB.
Texas A&M University