Welcome everyone to today's Terra Talk.
Today is the whole summer vacation of Terra.
Because we did not plan for the summer vacation at the beginning of this year.
Because there are a lot of people joining this year.
So we arranged a new session during the summer vacation.
Today is the first speaker, the speaker of the summer vacation program.
Today's speaker is Chen Xinhao.
He graduated from the Department of Atmospheric Engineering of NTU.
He is currently a doctoral student in the Department of Atmospheric Engineering of NTU.
He is about to graduate.
Wait a minute.
His interest is mainly in the hot zone area,
which is near Taiwan.
This is the analysis and simulation of the diagnosis of the weather phenomenon to the mid-level.
Then there is a special thing that everyone in Taiwan is very familiar with.
Disastrous weather such as typhoons or heat currents after noon.
In terms of method, it is mainly used for numerical and weather forecasts.
Then he can provide this simulation to give a fixed amount of precipitation forecast and assessment.
In addition to the research part, Chen Xinhao is a very good friend of mine for more than 10 years.
We were classmates of the Taita Bicycle Club.
He had a very famous feature when he was on the club.
He is a human weather forecaster.
It is very important to the bicycle club.
So let's listen to him today.
How did he become an atmospheric scientist from a human weather forecaster?
The method of numerical simulation.
The topic he often tells us is
Medium-Range Cloud Resolving Typhoon Rainfall Ensemble Forecast for Taiwan Through Time-Lagging Approach.
This topic is very long.
So I hope Xinhao can tell us what his Chinese vocabulary is.
Without further ado, let's applaud and welcome him.
Hello everyone.
I am Chen Xinhao, the speaker today.
You can call me Guige.
Maybe because when I report to the police,
The main setting is related fields of research.
So if there is something in the middle that you can't understand,
You can interrupt and ask.
Because today I will report to the previous seminar.
Then I will explain the name a little bit.
The topic I want to talk about today is
Medium-Range Cloud Resolving Typhoon Rainfall Ensemble Forecast for Taiwan Through Time-Lagging Approach.
This is what he came up with after I came in from the PhD class.
For Taiwan, there is a new typhoon forecast strategy.
Okay, I don't care.
Let's start with the first one.
In our country, typhoon and rainfall are extremely low.
Every year, there will be a large loss of all kinds of life.
Typhoon is the main cause of Taiwan's drop in water.
This is the typhoon in 2016.
From 26th to 29th.
This is the drop in water for 26 hours.
The amount of wind and rain they bring can be compared to Taiwan.
Anyway, the typhoon is an important drop in water in Taiwan.
In addition, Taiwan is different from other places.
Taiwan is not a high mountain.
When the typhoon passes, it will cause a terrible drop in wind and rain.
Taiwan also has a lot of people living in the mountains because of the underground population.
The map is a map of Taiwan's geography.
The black spot is the location of the Yuliang Station in Taiwan.
Because of the high mountains and the people living in the mountains,
These two characteristics of Taiwan cause the typhoon forecast.
The maximum drop in water will be higher than other places.
For example, mainland China.
These big countries will have a higher drop in water.
In the past, it was thought that the forecast limit was about three days.
It is generally thought that the area model forecasts more than 72 hours for numerical weather.
The following results are low in reference value.
Wang Teng conducted an 8-day drop in water forecast in cloud analysis mode.
We evaluated five typhoons in 2002 and two typhoons in 2013.
There are a total of six typhoons.
We found that the drop in water forecast is different from the above past.
We found that the drop in water forecast may be in 8 days or 4 days, 6 days, or 3 days.
These 10 days make a reference value drop in water forecast.
There is a conclusion in this paper.
Our path is different.
However, the drop in water forecast is still useful.
This paper is to break down the past.
Let me briefly introduce the current detailed forecast method.
The blue dot is the start time.
The method of forecasting more than 10 years ago is to forecast 72 hours before the start time.
The current detailed forecast method is based on different physical parameters.
Based on different physical parameters, there are different rules.
Then make about 20 to 30 conditions and forecast for 3 days.
The drop in water time for this target will be about 20 to 30 days.
The picture on the bottom right is a detailed forecast result for the 2013 Kaohsiung typhoon.
The blue dot is a detailed member.
The forecast is different.
The middle is a detailed black line.
The result of the current detailed forecast is like this.
Let me briefly introduce the difference.
As mentioned earlier, they divided all the calculation resources into 20 parts.
The concept of the difference in detail is that I put 20 parts of the forecast resources in the same place.
Then I increase the frequency and increase the forecast range.
I only run single mode.
And I have a forecast of 8 days.
Then every 6 hours, the start time will increase by about 6 hours.
In this way, there will be more than 20 members for the target time.
This is the difference in detail.
It's a little different from the current forecast.
Because it's regional mode, the maximum level is the same.
There are also 24 members.
The forecast range is about this.
Then the X-17 forecast.
The cloud analysis X-17 forecast.
The forecast range is about the red box.
Then the distance between the two networks.
Its resolution is higher.
The forecast range is larger.
The length of the forecast is also longer.
I forgot to show my little arrow.
The members of Ensembl will be used in a while.
And the calculation resources they use are about 1500 core systems.
It's all about 1500 core systems.
In other words, it can do this.
I raise the resolution.
I raise the forecast range.
The length of the forecast is also longer.
Then there are about the same number of members.
Then use the same data.
In the model, we use the Japanese National University developed
X-17 forecast mode.
It is a non-linear model.
The key is that there is no linearization.
The original physics is the same process.
On the right is the conversion method of its six waterfalls.
There are all kinds of models.
Hello, Gui, can you hear me?
The first example I explain is that.
In 2013.
The bottom left is the final path of the Central Meteorological Bureau.
The red box is the original X-17 forecast range.
The top right is the observation waterfall from August 29th to 30th.
The bottom right is the forecast a few days ago.
It's about this time, the observation time.
The color bar is the waterfall.
You can see that after the meteorological conditions are strong.
The path is very similar to what it did a day ago.
Its strength is weak.
But it is a strong deterrent.
This picture is the forecast from August 22nd.
For the target time, from August 29th to 30th.
You can see that the forecast can be calculated from August 22nd.
When the meteorological conditions are weak.
You can tell the disaster prevention unit.
There may be more than 311 waterfalls in the south.
Maybe you don't know 311.
311 is about the same size as Yanda Waterfall in Pingting.
Because the weather conditions are different.
The weather forecast is different.
So the result is good or bad.
Some results are better.
Some results are not the observed weather forecast.
So the meteorological conditions will be observed.
After August 24th, the meteorological conditions will be observed.
The meteorological conditions will be observed.
This method is based on.
Before a lot of days.
It can provide the meteorological conditions of the disaster prevention unit.
Provide meteorological conditions.
Then it will be on August 26th.
On August 18th.
It will be 5 kilometers below zero.
24 members.
It will provide.
This is their detailed frequency.
The detailed frequency of 24 members.
After 24 reports.
Add their water.
Then.
They are like this.
The other is the poured water.
Although the progress is similar.
But the results are different.
Then.
Yes.
Add.
Hello.
Then.
In the last few days.
Add water.
More and more.
Then this is.
Meteorological weather forecast.
For a strong typhoon.
On the 29th and 30th.
Then the lower right corner.
This is.
You can see.
No. 22.
Black.
No. 23.
Green.
Different time.
Hello.
Did you hear that?
Typhoon warning.
Then black.
This is.
Joint.
With us.
Complete.
They made it.
Best warning.
Before.
Then.
The above group.
Is.
No. 22.
Their.
Forecast.
For this forecast.
The water situation.
Ok.
Then.
You may say.
Ok.
Give me so many situations.
Then how do I use.
The water system.
Ok.
From the water system.
We can see.
This refers to.
The leftmost.
This is the leftmost.
Then this is the leftmost.
Then the largest.
Then.
Typhoon.
Out.
There is also.
The most famous.
There will be the most famous.
Then.
There is also.
Of course.
Through Taiwan.
That is.
The epidemic situation.
There is no flood in Taiwan.
Then.
There will be.
With.
With the government of the United States.
He is.
In.
Five days.
Or.
Five days ago.
He will provide.
Such.
The water situation.
For example.
If this typhoon.
If it is.
On the left.
He will.
Taiwan.
May.
Pingtung.
Erlangbi.
In.
Such.
The water situation.
If it is.
On the right.
The water.
May.
Occur.
On the north coast.
If.
I.
Fortunately.
Landed in Taiwan.
Then.
Zhongfu Mountain Area.
Dangerous.
Will be in Zhongfu Mountain Area.
If.
Go.
Is.
He will.
Will.
There will be different.
Paths.
Then.
Provide.
The most dangerous.
Of course.
No. 22.
No. 8.
Because.
These two.
The water situation.
Will be.
Free.
Then.
As time goes by.
The water.
Because.
Not sure.
Typhoon.
What is it called?
Butterfly effect.
Is.
The longer.
Then.
The error will be magnified.
The closer the time.
The error.
Is getting smaller and smaller.
So.
This typhoon.
Road.
Handling.
Then.
The water situation.
Handling.
Then.
You can find out.
Oh.
He.
Road.
Handling.
Then.
Just.
Begin to.
The trend.
Will be.
Proceed to.
Oh.
Probably.
Will.
Water situation.
This.
The whole.
Good.
Then.
On the left.
It is.
Five kilometers.
24 members.
The result of the forecast.
That.
On the right.
It is.
X-ray forecast.
Is.
Then.
He is.
On the 26th.
When.
For this time.
He will have.
So many.
The water situation.
That.
Five kilometers.
He will also provide.
So many.
The water situation.
Then there are not 24.
Isn't there 24?
This is.
Then.
This is their.
Water issue.
Oh.
Is.
The X-ray.
no.
Typhoon.
Black Haze.
Of the.
Typhoon.
Oh.
Actually, it can be seen.
A little.
Is said.
Oh.
Them.
This is.
Five kilometer resolution.
24 members.
It's like.
Five kilometer resolution.
24 members.
They.
Several members.
Their.
Water.
Is.
Their.
Path.
Because.
Their.
How to say.
My.
Their.
Their,
Alternative,
Alternative, alternative takes,
Alternative takes,
Other alternatives,
Other alternatives.
Other alternative takes,
Other alternatives have
needed
CARE free
女生
Other than
This.
Because the left side
expect it to have a
trend
other than
the left
5km
24 layers
Every importance
Besides
We just mentioned
Temperature drop in 24 hours
If I put the drop in time
up to 48 hours
In fact, the Kangrui Typhoon
Drop in 48 hours
Then we color bar
300 to 1500
Then its value is about
700 or so
That
I don't know if this typhoon
Do you have any impression
This typhoon is
Lai Ching-Ting's mayor
When he was the mayor
He was in Tainan
He used to
Before this typhoon
He was called God Lai
Then
His god place
It's written on it
I think I'm going to take a vacation
Then Ching-Ting said
I don't want to take a vacation
Then
Then the next day
No wind, no rain
He became God Lai
What about this typhoon
He did the same thing
Then he fell from the mountain
I don't know if you have any impression
On this matter
This typhoon
Then this typhoon in Tainan
It's raining a lot
Then salt water
Then
Lai Ching-Ting insisted
You have to go to work
So
It's pretty bad
it is good
That
So
The precipitation in 48 hours
It's the same on August 23
That is
Six days ago
He can have
Precipitation
Then
Of course
Some precipitation
Have been grasped
The one who ran away in the middle
Did not grasp
Precipitation
But he had a trend
Uh
Excessive at first
Then again
Uh
The big environmental trend is
This typhoon may not affect Taiwan
But gradually came back
Tell him
Oh, this typhoon
May really affect Taiwan
Then
A day ago
Three days in advance
And tell you
Uh
Typhoon
It looks like this
Then
Typhoon
Here
More than 200
That
His shortcoming is
Your mechanism
Can't grasp
Then he can't
In many days
Provide
Uh
The trend of precipitation
It's raining
Gradually
Uh
One by one
It's raining
I think the model
Should go in this direction
I think he
He can't provide such
Uh
That two days
Result
Can
That is
Five or six days ago
Provide such precipitation
Then
The typhoon
Three or four days
Provide such precipitation
One or two days
Uh
Collect
Should be
Five kilometers per hour
Twenty-four meters
He
There is no way to go
That
If for
It will rain for three days
Uh
The example I chose here is
Typhoon Morak
That
Morak is a typhoon
He actually
In 2019
Typhoon
The typhoon
Uh
The most famous thing
Is
In the small village
Right
That
What about this method
Uh
But
Let's talk about it first
This technology
There was no such thing at that time
And
Calculation resource
Now this
Gradually increasing
He can use this way
That
If
I
I am
Only three days
If this typhoon
Just three days
That is
He can't provide
Everyone is
Oh
He must be
After it started
He told me
Oh this mode
Three days
He rained
Will
Become
How
This typhoon
Observed in
Taiwan's Zhongpu Mountain Area
More than 1,500 kilometers
The value is about 2,000
But
If I forecast eight days
There is a way
For the next three days
Preliminary forecast
That
Because my show in front
He is a weather forecast
With five kilometers
That now
I can't fix it
Because they
Can't do it
If he only forecasts three days
Then
Here's a little conclusion
Is
In general
He is a weather forecast
Can be called
The current weather forecast
Earlier
Provide
Damage
That's it
If the rainfall
The rainfall time
Longer
One day
Half a day
Two days
Three days
So if the rainfall time is long
It increases the possibility of dust
That way
Just call
Current
More useful
Then
I want to talk about another typhoon
Is the Subing typhoon
That
Hello
The typhoon
In
Because
I
Can you hear me
This is a strong typhoon
Then
Observation room
24 hours
Then he is very powerful
Is in
Uh
Hsinchu Miaoli Mountain Area
About 1500
876 meters
About water
That
This typhoon
His strength is stronger
Then he can be in 20 hours
More than 800 meters
Water
Then
What's next
Just tell everyone
Uh
His name is
M01 M02
Is
Uh
Uh, let me mention it first
Because we
The laboratory also provides
TTFR
Typhoon flood research center
Then they
In charge of running this
Typhoon forecast
They have members
Then
Every school has to provide
Not every school
Must provide
Some schools are interested
Will provide some
Typhoon results
Then put it in this
Then for everyone's reference
That
Simply put
This is the typhoon forecast
M01
M02
Then
Uh
Shida also provides a member
M17
That
Basically he
Every member is
5 km
But only M17
With me below
This is the typhoon forecast
Made
Typhoon forecast
That can be seen
Uh
In fact, every result
The situation is different
Then my red box
Is
Means
Uh
Typhoon
More than 700
Because
I'm in a lot of
I also talked about it in my video
Taiwan because of heavy rainfall
Mountain area
So
The water level
Exploded
Very serious
For example, if my water level
Exploded 310
That
Everyone knows
That is probably
Go down
Go down the mountain area
But if the mountain area
700-800 meters
Down
Water
That might be
A disaster
That is
That
5 km resolution
Can be calculated
That is
About 24 members
More than two-thirds
Did not explode
Uh
Water level
But in 2.5 km
Members
Just
There is a way to explode
That is also for this typhoon
Just change different timing
Then my initial time
Is always
In
Close
This observation time
So
You can see that
Is
The result will be more and more
Closer observation
But one thing
Has not changed
Uh
5 km resolution
Members
N01 N02
And so on
Then in addition to N17
They explode
This kind of
possibility
Not so much
Then he
This explosion
Strange
I do not know why it looks like this
It looks like this
Then the time of the experiment
The same is 2.5 km
He can master the water level
That
5 km members
There is no way
But the time of the experiment
Everyone is getting closer
But
Now there should be half
Explode the water level
That
Then everyone thinks
Oh
We may
Really
Will be so much
Then I am here as a lady
Is
There are two sentences
I said before
That
Because my understanding is improved
Can explode the water level
That
These things are
Uh
What I did a few years ago
That
He is
Will be a
Effective way
But he also has a
Uh
The problem is
Say
Hey
That
I just talked a lot
That is to say
Oh
If it's on the left
The water level is
That
On the right
The water level is
That
Before I have this black observation
Before
How do I know
The path is right
Which path
Your reference value is higher
Then you tell me
Say
Oh
So recently
The trend is
The more to the middle
The more to the back
The closer the time
The water level
The closer
Will be more like
So
I'll just watch the last one
What I'm doing now
That is
Uh
If the observation comes in
I use
Machine learning method
He can judge that
Hey
On the left
These exposed
Observation
Far
So they
Uh
The machine will learn
Oh
Their credibility
Lower
That
These on the right
The credibility is lower
That
The method I use now
Can give
He
Every
Pre-report member
His
Uh
Water level score
That is to say
Hey
I 2618
This report
His water level score
May be
70 points
This may be
60 points
That
May be too far
Because he is too far from the observation
So he
Water level score
With
2 points
Something like this
Let's make an example
That this is
What I'm doing now
That
Uh
Because
Because machine learning
He needs more
Cases
So
I have run a lot of
Is
Recently
Keep running
Run more cases
Want to give
Uh
Computer
More things to learn
Recently
Keep doing
Such a thing
That
That why
Uh
What is that
Why
The machine's forecast can't do this
Because they
No
Six days ago
No five days ago
No four days ago
The captain is three days
So they can't
Use this method
To support the forecast
Then give out
Each
Score
That
The last one
Is
Because we
This method has
Past
Forecast results
So we can use
Objective method
To
Guide us
That
My report today
Is
Probably this
About this
Then
Uh
Just
Report to everyone
I don't know if everyone has any questions
Like this
Can you hear me
Can anyone hear me
Oh
Can hear
I found a very serious problem
Because
Without turning on
He didn't
No
No sound
So I just
If you didn't speak
I didn't hear it
Oh ok
So you can hear it now
Yes yes I can hear it now
I don't know if you interrupted me in the middle
Have
I tried a few times
But it doesn't matter
I just want to ask a question
That
Ok
Does everyone have a question
If there is no problem
I ask one first
Just
You are running this
Ensemble time
You said you ran
More than 20
More than 30
Their
Initial conditions
Is it all
Is it exactly the same
Or
You will use some
For example, observe
The actual inaccuracy
Go
That is to say
To slightly disrupt
His initial conditions
Then let him run
You said that way
Is it
Oh
Uh
In that way
The difference is
Different
The initial time is different
Because
Uh
To put it simply
For example, this is the 7th
Assuming it's the 22nd
Okay
After 6 hours
He will have different
That is to say
I
8 o'clock in the morning
Start forecasting
Then
This is
2 o'clock in the afternoon
The initial conditions of the two
Is different
So
The result they caused
Is the same
He didn't
Add any
Disturbance
Like this
Oh so you won't say
To slightly disrupt
I mean
For example, for example
What is your air pressure
What is the temperature
Then
For example, your air pressure is
Oh no
No no
The temperature is 30 degrees
You are 30
Then add a
Random constant
That constant is
Is
For example, minus 0.2
Something like that
Then let the random number add
because
Originally you measured
There will be
Uncertainty
Still not
You are
These things are fixed
Is a very certain number
Enter
Yes
What is the number it predicts
I put it in
Just like this
Because
Because because
Because one
Run a round every six hours
So i don't need
Do
Such action
That
Typical ensemble
He
Can use this technology
That
The result
The result is
Some of them
Members are
Use this method
This method
Made
Uh-huh
Then
Yes
I have another question
Just
There was a show in front of you
Say
You are now
Typically running these things
Are using
One or two thousand cores
right
Correct
OK
That
You think
This
Computation
This hardware
Restriction
Is
Main
Accuracy
Restriction
Just say
For example, I will give you 5000 cores
Can you do it
Obviously better
Uh
Mainly
Maybe this model
He wrote
Is that
He
Must be distributed
After parallel computing
He has to combine again
Just take it apart
And stick it up
Is that he will divide
These two actions
Uh-huh
That
Core
When you want to stick it up
Is actually
It also takes a lot of time
Uh-huh
Let's say it becomes 5000
Maybe he is
Parallel computing
He will double
But he is stuck
May increase
Much
So actually the biggest difference
OK
Still your
That
The logic behind that thing
Is your algorithm
Like you want
How do you sign your grid
Then what do you want to resolve
Then how do you arrange your time
I
I think
Just now
Because i don't
I have no ability to change the mode
Then
So my current use
Test result
Probably use this
Core number
He is
Uh
In the forecast result
With
The time of use
Is
Is balanced
Because actually
The number of days to forecast
He
Must be
Must be effective
You can't be
Uh
For example, I can
20,000 core
Then run
The range is global
Then the efficiency is super high
But he ran
The typhoon is not raining
Yes yes yes
Then there is no
No problem
He
Uh
Is my
My design is
Uh
Stabilize time and efficiency
Then
Uh
Stabilize resolution
Then
Stabilize strength
Then he is
I think
After evaluation
Very balanced
A more balanced design
Then increase or decrease
I think
That's what I just explained
Say
Because he needs you
After evenly distributed
He has to be united
Then when united
because
Japan
Japan National University
Their design
Use a core
To do
Combination action
That
Maybe in the future
Will also
I am
I want to say
I want to talk to them all day
You
It seems like
No
I
I want to talk to them later
OK
Hurry up
Any other questions
I can do
I see
Does anyone have
Any other questions
Because I
In fact, I can ask a lot of questions
I think it's quite interesting
I have a lot of questions
But
Let's let others ask
Does anyone have any questions?
No one has a problem?
Or
Or you still can't hear me
Because I can hear it
Yes, because I can hear it
OK
Then I have another question
My question is
About machine learning
Yes
I'm not sure you
You are
Someone has a problem
But
You speak
I didn't hear you
The microphone is on
But
necessary
The more necessary
In fact, I don't know how to read
OK
Yes, we didn't hear your voice
You can type it
I heard it
I can't hear it again
No sound
I think you can type it
His question is
He asked
Double typhoon forecast
What is the difference between single forecast and double typhoon forecast?
You said in a forecast
Will there be two typhoons?
I think that's what it means
Yes, he said that's what it means
For the model
It's just that the complexity will increase
The forecast time will be a little longer
That
I don't think there's anything wrong
Because
There will be two in the model
Rotating
Then they have to
Say
They
The water will rise and move
The air rises and moves
It's going to freeze
It will rain after freezing
After the rain
It will rise and move
Then the water will rise and move
They have been
Calculating this kind of thing
Because there are two typhoons
Inside
So the model is more complex
The forecast time will be longer
but
Almost a little bit
About 10% or so
6 hours
That
Will there be any difference?
Yes
OK
He said
I see
Thanks
OK
Does anyone else have any questions?
If not
Today we
Wait a minute
Yes
OK
Please say
He said
The satellite measurement resolution
About how much
Because of the satellite
Simply put
How many satellites are there?
One is
Earth satellite
Another one is
Satellite orbit
That
I don't know
What is the difference?
What about the satellites?
That is to say
The Earth is here
Then he is
Keep going around the earth
Then he
Because it keeps going around
So he flew a long way
I don't know why
Anyway, he
Because of this design
He flew a long way
Then there is another satellite
That is the earth
When the earth is here
He is going to
The earth follows
He keeps going around the same place
Then
This one flies higher
Because according to what gravity
Then rotate and so on
This one is higher
That resolution
I personally
In the image
How far back to the satellite
Probably
To
It's pretty thin
Then it depends on
When was it produced?
Because like the earth head satellite
Previous
For example, China's wind cloud
Satellite
Then
With the latest
Australian space
Is it Australia?
Let's call it the sunny track 8
Then
Their resolution
It's not the same
You have to ask me
That number
I personally
Because I am
Touch mode
I didn't touch the satellite
My resolution to them
To what extent
I am
No impression
But if you need
Just
What do you want to see my painting?
I can only insert it for you
But my impression is not too low
That is
Uh
Is there a few hundred meters?
Then their resolution is probably a few hundred meters
100 meters or 40 meters
Super cool
So the next question he asks is
So as the initial condition
Data input
Will the resolution be higher than the simulation?
Uh
Right
Oh
Correct
Because this is actually with me
What I was thinking was a bit similar
What I was thinking was
Because you observe the limit of resolution
So what you know
The limit is actually this big
and so
I think it can be
You input the initial condition
Then put it at this level
Smear it
It's more reasonable
You don't know
Then run a lot of ensembles
Then go and see
Do you have this smear
How much
Influence
But it seems
It will take a lot of time
Yes, there is no way
Do it before the valid time
I guess
Um
What you are talking about
Uh, what the atmosphere is doing is
Data synchronization
Simple
His name is called data synchronization
In other words
This is
It's almost the same as what you said
That is
Uh
At the beginning of atmospheric simulation
There will be a global
Global mode
Its resolution will be about 20 kilometers
About 10 kilometers
Then it forecasts the whole world
Then
After he ran
It will be based on satellites
And then the radars all over the place
Aerial balloons all over the place
We will be on the ground
A small balloon
Then the blue instrument hanging below
Then up
Then they will collect this vertical
Temperature pressure
Wind speed
He will collect such information
Then go
Tell this global mode
Uh, where am I
What is his observation
Then he will follow this observation
Correction mode
Then this global mode
Will be after the calculation
Cut
Send to various places
Then come to the area mode
Like the one I'm using now
This is the area mode
Then his
The resolution will be higher than the global mode
20 kilometers
That's what you just said
I think that's it
Then he put
Observation data transmission mode
This thing
It's called data transmission
Hey
Is anyone talking?
No, no, I'm listening to you
Oh, I want to say my microphone
Is it
Because no one is talking
So he
The system is closed
No, no, no, no, no, no
OK, that
We have 4 minutes
Is there any other question?
Is
Is it just doing numerical?
Or the question of atmospheric
In addition to
In fact, the question we asked should be
Asked almost
So do you have any games?
More scientific questions
Or have their own interests
Just ask
For example, let me show you one.
Just
I am actually curious about one thing.
Is this
This one
Let me talk about the objective prediction.
Have
How big a chance
Will be adopted by the government
Or they are
Anyway, they are
After reading the data, I still have to tell you
There is no problem with this return screen. We want to build a house.
Or they will really refer to professional advice.
Because
Uh
The disaster prevention units are probably divided into
layers
Is generally in contact with the people
Is the Central Meteorological Bureau
The things that the Central Meteorological Bureau releases to the people
Must be credible
To a certain extent
He can only be released
But
But if you want to fight for validity
Is to become a disaster prevention unit
Then he must have a little understanding of the weather.
For example, he knows
The credibility of the forecast a few days ago
Uh, for reference
How about a few days later
I did this set of things.
Is for the disaster prevention unit
Use
I don't seem to have answered your question.
I think
Are you asking
But my question is more like
That
The chiefs who decided to take a vacation
Does he have a weather forecast?
Or is he just looking at it?
Uh
Basically should have
I know Taipei City has it.
but
I don't think it's safe.
Uh, don't keep talking.
Because we are still recording
That one
A very good question
I think it's very interesting
We all know that you want to run this numerical
You have to enter the initial condition
Then let him propagate
To have a border condition
He just came from the global model.
As I just said a few minutes ago
He is running a global model first.
Then the global model
He is another model
He doesn't need a border condition.
Should be round
He is that
Symmetry
Will be connected
But because of the range
Will grow
He is
Then he needs to be initialized
OK
Let me repeat the question he just asked.
Because I just saw it directly.
His question is actually weather simulation
Do you need a border condition?
Because we actually see it now.
It's all a frame and you have Taiwan.
But if you say
This frame is windless
It's not very reasonable, so this is a pretty good question.
I just told you what the question was.
Ok, now it's just 7 o'clock.
Do you have any questions?
If there is no problem
I will announce it again.
When you clap, you have to turn on the microphone.
Only the speaker can hear
Let's applaud again, thank you Xinhao.
Thank you
Stop recording