Hello everyone, welcome to this week's Terra Talk. I am today's host, Zhang Yanyong. I am currently studying high-energy physics experiments at the University of California.
Before we officially start, let's first introduce what kind of organization Project Terra is.
In fact, as we wrote on the website, our goal is to establish a timely cross-national academic information sharing platform,
connect Taiwan's academic talents from all over the world, exchange results and trends in Taiwan's academic circles overseas,
and provide each other with a platform for effective communication.
To put it simply, we hope to establish a platform that helps Taiwanese from all over the world engage in research and work to communicate with each other quickly and timely.
We will hold a webcast like today every week.
The speakers are basically our members, and the audience can sign up online.
The topic of the speech is based on the results of the speaker's research, review his current development in his special field,
and share new ideas, plans, or opportunities for cooperation.
Project Terra is currently a fully self-funded, fully volunteer organization.
Our staff are basically all doctoral students and post-doctoral students.
You can see the About page on our website.
Now I'm going to post the link to our website on the chat room next to it.
I want to add that we recently added a lot of staff who may not have been updated to the website.
The most important purpose of a project like this is to fully open up, share and cooperate.
The more friends who are willing to join us, share and help each other,
we can move towards the goals we all want.
I also hope that it will be helpful to Taiwan's academic circle and everyone's research career, or to transfer jobs in the future.
Now I'm going to post the link to our website on the chat room next to it.
If you feel that you support our ideas, or are passionate about sharing your very passionate research,
you can consider joining our members, and you will continue to receive our speech and activity information.
Of course, you can also go to our Facebook fan page and continue to follow our news.
We also want to emphasize that we have no profit at all.
If you are willing to share with other Taiwanese, it will be the biggest reward for us.
It is also the biggest help to other friends who work in the academic circle.
This is the introduction of TARA.
Next, I want to introduce our speaker.
We are honored to invite Zheng Yunting today.
Zheng Yunting is currently studying physics at the California Institute of Technology.
He is currently a doctoral candidate.
Yunting graduated from the Department of Physics in 2014 and joined the Caltech Research Institute.
He is currently studying his doctorate.
His special field is observational cosmology.
He will introduce to us today that he is doing a data analysis project.
It is a rocket project.
There is one more thing to remind everyone.
In order to let the speaker feel our enthusiasm,
the microphone must be turned on when applauding, so that he can hear the voice.
Let's applaud and welcome Yunting to give us this speech.
Thank you everyone.
I am Zheng Yunting. I am studying my PhD at Caltech.
Thank you to my office mate, Zhang Yanyong, for the introduction.
The topic I am going to talk about today is
Measuring Extragalactic Background Light at Optical and Near-Infrared.
This is a project I am doing.
I am doing its data analysis.
What I am going to talk about today is more focused on
the background in this field.
What do we want to measure?
What do we want to understand?
What is a signal?
Let me start by introducing the history of our universe.
This is the universe we know so far.
We can start from the left.
The left is the earliest period.
We have inflation and Big Bang.
Inflation is the theory of explosion in Chinese.
Big Bang is the beginning of the universe.
In the very early period,
the universe is very small and hot.
Everything inside is very hot and oily.
As the universe expands,
the gas will expand.
At a certain point in time,
the temperature in the universe is low enough.
The electrons and protons in the gas
will combine to form hydrogen.
This process is called recombination.
After recombination,
there are a lot of photons in the universe.
Photons are easily scattered with free electrons.
After recombination,
there are almost no free electrons in the universe.
These photons will not become long.
We can see the photons emitted at that time.
This is called a cosmic microwave background or CMB.
This is the earliest signal we can measure in cosmology.
After recombination and CMB,
a lot of protons and electrons combine to form hydrogen.
During this period,
the universe is full of neutral hydrogen and hydrogen.
This period is called the Dark Age.
Because it is very dark,
there are no photons like the CMB at that time.
However, there are no stars and galaxies yet.
The universe during this period is completely black.
During this period,
there will be some density fluctuations in the universe.
These density fluctuations are because of gravity.
As time goes by,
there will be more matter coming in.
The main component is dark matter.
These dark matter may form heavier and condensed structures.
We call this dark matter halo.
Because there is a strong gravitational potential in the halo,
the background gases such as hydrogen will also gather here.
When the gathering becomes compact,
it will cause a fusion reaction and form the first star or galaxy.
After a period of time,
the universe begins to form stars and galaxies.
After these stars and galaxies form,
they will release a lot of photons.
If the energy of the photons is strong enough,
the energy gap between the hydrogen and the gas will be strong enough.
The gas will separate the hydrogen nearby.
You can see that there are some separated areas on this map.
We call this ionizing bubble.
This process is called reionization.
As time goes by,
there will be more and more stars and galaxies in the universe.
It will ionize the hydrogen nearby.
At the end,
if you have enough galaxies,
you will separate all the hydrogen in the universe.
The gases outside the galaxy are all ionized.
This is our current universe.
This is the history of the development of the universe.
What I'm going to study now is called an extra-galactic background light.
I have a question.
What if I put a traffic light on my screen and it disappears?
Oh, okay.
I see.
So, what if I put a traffic light on my screen and it disappears?
Can you see it clearly like this?
Actually, I think it's pretty clear.
Okay, then I'll do it like this.
I also think traffic lights are more convenient.
So, what I'm going to measure is the extra-galactic background light,
or EVL.
In the literature, the word galactic refers to our own galaxy.
So, extra-galactic is outside our own galaxy.
Background light refers to everything outside the galaxy.
So, the EVL we measure is the time in the history of the universe.
So, it's like this.
You can see CMB from the beginning,
and then there's Dark Age,
and then there's a lot of stars and galaxies.
And then they emit light.
So, next I'm going to introduce the spectrum of EDL.
The spectrum is the light emitted by the different wavelengths.
So, the spectrum is the light emitted by the different wavelengths.
So, next I'm going to introduce the spectrum of EDL.
And these data on the diagram show the subjects all of the EMB measurements.
And you can see that they're all doing at different wavelengths,
and you can see that they're all doing at different wavelengths,
and I'm going to share a little bit about what each wavelength does for you.
So, let's look at the high-energy and low-energy one first.
The high-energy one is GAMMA RAY and X-ray.
The main source of these high-energy photons is called
the Active Galactic Nuclei from the AGM.
The main source of these high-energy photons is called the Active Galactic Nuclei from the AGM.
These are billions of black holes in the center of each galaxy
These black holes accelerate the heat emanated from galaxies
These black holes accelerate the heat emitted from galaxies
These black holes acceleration leads to både  coated with aurorae
These black holes acceleration leads to béocte
These high-energy photons secure the Przybyszane
These high-energy photons secure the Psi
These high-energy photons secure the Phi
We also have low-bout of agaric compounds
which are synchrotron radiation
which is when gas is heated,
or accelerated to a very high speed.
We don't have much data on UV
and the experiment result was mere readings
And the experiment result was mean readings
And the experiment result was mere readings
So we very rarely meet UV in astro galactic.
So we very rarely meet UV in assegalactic.
This peak was the oscillation of Cosmic microwave background in 30s
These are the two small bumps, one in the optical and one in the infrared.
These two mainly come from the star emission in each galaxy.
Star emission is on the optical side.
In the infrared, it is the emission of dust in the galaxy.
These dusts absorb the starlight and emit thermal radiation.
This thermal radiation is in the infrared.
In the infrared, half of the starlight is emitted by the optical, and the other half is absorbed by the dust.
The wavelengths I'm going to talk about today are in the optical.
If we zoom in, we can see that there is a lot of different data here.
This is the fine infrared bump, and this is the optical down near infrared.
You can see that there is a lot of different data here.
Each data is measured at a different value in the same wavelength.
The reason why these data are so inconsistent is because they are used in many different ways.
The first method is called Galaxy Counts.
The second method is called Absolute Photometry.
The third method is called Absolute Photometry.
The fourth method is called Absolute Photometry.
The fifth method is called Absolute Photometry.
The sixth method is called Absolute Photometry.
The seventh method is called Absolute Photometry.
The eighth method is called Absolute Photometry.
The first method is called Air Growth.
The second method is called Zodiacal Light.
The first method is called Zodiacal Light.
The third method is called Zodiacal Light.
The fourth method is called Zodiacal Light.
The fifth method is called Zodiacal Light.
The sixth method is called Zodiacal Light.
The seventh method is called Zodiacal Light.
The last method is called Zodiacal Light.
If you want to measure the total intensity, you need to know how big the objects in your galaxy are.
The next method is called Fluctuation.
The next method is called Correlation.
The first time the data was bad was because they found out that rockets would be hot.
Do you use PowerSpatial to look at the data?
I use PowerSpatial to look at the data.