Hello, everyone. Welcome to today's Tera Talk.
We're honored to have Lin Weikai with us today.
Lin Weikai has been a good friend of mine for many years.
Lin Weikai is now a third-year PhD student at Cornell,
majoring in Computer Science.
Lin's research focuses on cryptography.
His main focus is on Oblivious algorithm.
This allows the algorithm to store data without revealing the content.
He majored in Chemistry when he was a college student.
He majored in Computer Science when he was a master's student.
Before his PhD,
he worked as a software engineer at Chengxin.
He also worked as a research assistant at the Central Academy of Sciences.
What Lin is going to talk about today is the concept of Oblivious algorithm.
But today, he's going to talk about a new definition of
the fairness of multiparty coin tossing.
Let's give him a round of applause.
By the way, remember to turn on the microphone when you clap.
Thank you for such a wonderful introduction.
The title is complicated,
but I assume most of you have heard of the theorem of the game.
Today's topic is
the concept of coin toss.
I'm going to talk about the relationship between coin toss and the theorem of the game.
This work was done by Zhong Kaimin at the Central Academy of Sciences.
Guo Yue, Rafael, and I are both at Cornell.
Cornell Tech is a campus at NYC.
Cornell has a new campus at NYC.
Let's talk about the topic of coin toss today.
The motivation of this research is very realistic.
Although I usually do theoretical research,
our motivation is very realistic.
What is the motivation?
Trump and Xi want to hold a summit.
Where will it be held?
Trump wants to hold it in DC.
Xi wants to hold it in Beijing.
If these two people can't get along,
what should they do?
The easiest way is to make a decision by tossing a coin.
If these two people can't get along,
how can they toss a coin?
This is a tricky question we are going to discuss today.
If these two people can't get along, how can they toss a coin?
Let's not talk about whether the coin toss will be fair or not.
If they can't get along,
if Trump tosses a coin here,
Xi won't believe it even if he doesn't see it.
So what should they do?
If I have a way to toss a coin,
a way to toss a coin remotely,
if the coin tosses out,
Xi is in DC,
Xi is in Beijing.
If the coin tosses out remotely is fair,
everyone will be happy.
Half and half chance.
In the game,
someone will tell you that there is a payoff.
What is the coin toss?
Which side has how many payoffs or utilities?
But let's not talk about this.
In history,
there is a hotline between the United States and the Soviet Union.
Maybe there is also a hotline between Trump and Xi.
If they don't meet, they can talk on the phone.
If there is a question in the middle,
you can interrupt me at any time.
I hope everyone can understand what I am talking about today.
If you don't understand,
don't be afraid.
Try to ask.
The purpose of the hotline is that
you say one sentence, I say one sentence,
and the other party can hear what I say.
Then there is nothing else.
So the hotline can't help you directly
toss a coin.
It's not such a good thing.
But what can the hotline do?
The hotline can communicate on both sides.
After the communication,
the hotline may have an output.
B is equal to 0 or B is equal to 1.
It's the same side.
The hotline can do this.
It can help you create a random variable.
Its value is 0 or 1.
The probability is 0.5 or 0.5.
What I want is to get a random variable.
It's a random variable defined by math.
If you are familiar with the random variables defined by math,
or you've heard of it in class,
I have a way to get the two sides to toss a coin.
How do you do it?
Trump throws a coin first.
The coin is 1.
Then Trump says to Xi on the phone,
my coin is 1.
Then Xi says,
I got it.
Your coin is 1.
Then both sides agree that the coin is 1.
If Trump throws a fair coin,
this method may work.
But Xi is obviously not happy.
If Trump is a bad guy,
and he didn't throw the coin at all,
it's not a good thing for Xi.
He won't agree with the result of the coin toss.
Don't say that Trump made a mistake at the beginning,
and made it unfair.
Even if he made a very complicated LeTouJi,
and recorded it,
and sent it to Xi through a hotline,
Xi won't believe it.
If Trump didn't cheat,
it may work.
But neither side believes each other.
This is a common problem in cryptography.
If neither side doesn't believe each other,
what should we do?
A long time ago,
there was a technology called commit.
Trump first calculated a number X
using SHA.
Then he told Xi.
This thing is called commit.
Xi said,
you calculated X, I calculated Y,
and then E.
Then Trump said,
my X is below E,
and then he made a mess.
In order to hide the E at the beginning.
Then these two sides,
X and Y, XOR,
is the result of the coin toss.
In cryptography,
these two things are simplified
into commit and open.
That is,
he wrote an X,
and then sealed it in the envelope to Xi.
After Xi received it,
he opened the envelope.
The purpose of the envelope
is to prevent the person
who wrote the envelope from changing.
The person who received the envelope
can't see it for the time being.
This is called commit and open.
In the past...
I have a question.
Does this hotline
have a rule
that you have to do it one by one?
Can't you say it at the same time?
If you say it at the same time,
everyone says 1, 2, 3,
and I say 1 or 0,
and everyone says XOR.
This is a very good question.
But because everyone doesn't believe it,
they might say it slowly.
So...
This hotline
has a rule
that you have to do it one by one.
You can't say it at the same time.
I should say that
I didn't assume
that this hotline
had to do it one by one.
But Trump and Xi agreed
and...
If someone says it slowly,
what should you do?
Do it again?
Yes, yes.
Then it will be endless.
Okay, good.
Also,
when we imagine a hotline,
we can't judge
who says it slowly.
Because of the message delay,
we can't be sure
who says it slowly.
If we do it one by one,
we can be sure of the order.
Okay, got it.
So,
at the same time,
on the internet,
it's hard to judge.
This is a good question.
Let's say
all the protocols
are one by one.
And the order is...
Okay,
then,
this thing,
this commit and open,
if you have a good commit,
when you commit,
the other side can't be opened.
And the other side of the bus
can't be tampered with.
Then this thing,
this coin toss thing,
can be done fairly.
Because when it commits to x in advance,
it doesn't know what will happen to y.
And when it commits to y,
it doesn't know what x is.
So,
the result will be
fair.
And
we can be sure
the other side can't tamper with the result.
Then,
this thing,
we've been talking about fairness.
What kind of fairness
do we want?
The formal definition of
mathematics is
the expected value is 0.5.
The result of the commit is only 0 and 1.
And the probability is 0.5.
So the expected value is
0.5 times 0 plus 0.5 times 1
equals 0.5.
I want the expected value
to be exactly 0.5.
Then,
if you look at this thing carefully,
it's not exactly 0.5.
I'll talk about this later.
So it usually adds
a very small fraction,
negligible.
But let's leave it alone.
I just want 0.5.
Then,
this thing,
unfortunately,
in the
previous result,
a long time ago,
about 30 years ago,
what can't we do?
This
adversary,
like Trump or Xi,
can end
earlier.
This protocol is not finished yet.
He said I'm not going to play like this.
And
this adversary
is
only when there is a limited
computing power,
this
protocol,
this is easier for the protocol
to do.
Let's assume that Trump and Xi
have limited
computing power.
It's all polynomial time
algorithm.
This polynomial time,
you may not be familiar with it,
but
you can make a decision
within a few seconds.
Then
any
protocol like this,
in the result of this cliff,
it can design
an attacker to crack
any protocol.
So
to achieve the expected value
is exactly 0.5,
no protocol can do it.
The result is
such a strong impossibility.
That is to say,
no protocol can do this.
In this way,
let's take a look at this example.
Just
commit and open this example.
Here,
we are using the
new hash function.
It's not new, it's about
more than ten years.
So far, everyone still believes that SHA-256
is difficult to crack.
For example,
Bitcoin is still in use.
How to
crack it?
If
Xi's
computing power is
infinite,
he can easily
decrypt SHA-256x
which is equal to a certain number.
As long as he violently
tries all the x,
he can decrypt the x.
After Xi knows
the value of x,
he can choose a relative y
so that the result is what he likes.
For example, he likes 0.
0 represents Beijing.
So when he sees that the value of x is 1,
he chooses a y
so that the result is Beijing.
Trump doesn't know
that he was fooled.
He can only delete 1.
The result is what Xi wants.
This is
if
one of them
has
infinite computing power,
something may happen.
But
what I said last time
is even stronger.
Even if Xi only has
limited computing power,
he can still attack.
How effective
this attack method
can be?
It can make the expectation value
deviate
to any
deviation
1 in three rounds.
So
The number of attacks
is about 1 in three rounds.
This is a very powerful attack.
For example,
the attacker
has infinite computing power.
He can make
his expectation value
deviate to 0.5.
He can choose
what he wants.
But if he only has
limited computing power,
he can't
make the expectation value
deviate so much, but he can
deviate to a certain number,
which is 1 in three rounds.
I just gave a random number,
but according to this protocol,
it is about 1 in three rounds.
The expectation value is 1 in three rounds.
From 0.5 to 0.5 plus 1 in three rounds
is 0.8.
So
the result of
cleave is very strong.
You can't make a fair copy.
Because no matter what protocol,
it can create an attacker.
Then
make an effective attack in a limited time.
here
There is another thing
to talk about this attack.
This
What kind of
impact will it have at the beginning and end?
For example,
at the beginning, I talked about the simplest
protocol.
Trump threw a copper plate,
and Xi Jinping received it and
admitted that it was a copper plate.
He admitted the result of the copper plate.
This thing
has a fail-stop.
If one of them
can end early
and not late,
it is difficult to achieve
a fair result.
For example, Trump threw a copper plate,
and he saw this copper plate
was not what he liked.
He said, then I won't play.
Then
this
If you don't play, Xi Jinping
So far
we still assume that he is
honest
to follow the game rules at the beginning.
He received
a copper plate message
and then he
admitted that the message of the copper plate
was their consensus.
But
one of them is not late,
what is the other party's consensus?
This is
difficult to say.
In order to have a consensus,
we usually have to define
one of them
is not honest and not late.
What should the other party say?
Xi Jinping
threw a copper plate
and it was 0.5.
Or he has to
fix the output
0 or 1
It's hard to say.
Trump
can see what he is doing
honestly
and decide
when to end
and when not to end.
The entire output
is completely controlled
by the dishonest
party.
Then
there is no fairness
or
security.
The result of this copper plate
output
its fairness is the security
I want.
So
the focus here is
this
computationally bounded
the attacker's
computing power is limited
and it can end early
these two things.
If one of them is missing
we all know
it can be done
If I assume
the attacker will never
end early
then this copper plate
can be played
up to 0.5
but these two conditions
these two computationally bounded
and failstop
when these two conditions exist at the same time
we can't do it.
And the proof that we can't do it
is to really build a
attacker
and then target
any protocol
to attack.
So
but
when you look at the first page
you may find it
strange
if Trump can't end early
then Xi Jinping can
say I like to be in Beijing
then I will be in Beijing.
This is
another definition
of
the focus
Hello
Is my connection broken?
I can't hear you.
Ok
So
Can you hear me?
I can't hear you.
I can hear you.
But
I can't hear the speaker.
Ok
So the connection is broken.
Let me contact him.
Hello
Can you hear me?
I can hear you.
How are you?
I can't hear you.
I am scared.
So
I call you
because
I can't hear you.
Can you hear me?
I can hear you.
I think my internet is down.
I don't know where I am.
I just
talk about
the commit and open
protocol can
protect
good people.
And
why this protocol
can protect good people?
If
one side
can't finish early,
the other side
will be happy to say
the other side is bad
so I can
protect my own interests
to protect the interests of good people.
So I will
produce the result
that good people like.
Because
the other side can't finish early.
And
this
is just
one example.
Of course, you can also
let the other side finish early
and Trump
will choose the result he likes.
This is another case.
In short,
the commit and open
protocol
can
guarantee
the
previous definition.
Even if
one side is attacking
and the other side's expectation
is still over 0.5,
the payoff is still over 0.5.
Because
the basic idea
is simple.
If one side can't finish early,
the other side will be happy
to choose the result he likes.
He can choose.
So
if one side can't finish early,
the other side is
a good person.
If a good person chooses the result he likes,
his expectation value will not be
reduced by bad people.
Is it okay
to go this far?
If it's okay,
it will be a little more complicated later.
But
the most important thing to define here
is to protect the expectation value of good people.
And the payoff
is the most important point.
First,
we need to define
what a good person is.
Second,
what a payoff is.
The payoff is
the protocol.
After running the result,
I look at the result and decide
how much benefit this result will bring me.
Then
I define
that I want to protect the interests of good people.
The expectation value is greater than a certain number.
Of course,
if I say a little more here,
the payoff
is completely
restricted to
the payoff function
defined by this example.
The payoff function itself is very simple.
But
in Game Theory,
there are many strange payoffs
that will make
these results strange.
But we won't discuss those today.
Even in my paper,
there is no way to discuss so much
because there are too many strange payoffs.
But the simplest
payoff function
is the focus
of this paper.
Okay,
next,
well,
what you see here
is that there are only two players
and two parties
playing.
The two parties
can achieve
the fairness
in this
fairness in interest.
The result
may not be fair,
but the interest is fair.
Then we start.
But a very natural question is
when
you add one more person,
is there any way
to achieve
the fairness?
So we just
add one more person.
Then
I don't know if the third person
is Jin Xiaopang or
Putin.
Anyway, it's A, B, C.
Then
we assume the simplest
is
what kind of output
do these three people like
is public.
It's also public
who aborts early and
doesn't play early.
So if C aborts early
and doesn't play,
A and B will not play
sooner or later.
So let's assume
all the messages are public.
Maybe you can imagine
three hotlines or something.
Or
now this very popular
blockchain
messages are all public.
So if one of them doesn't play
or if one of them sends
a message, the other two can
know at the same time.
One of the possible applications
may be
eating dumplings and tigers
on the blockchain.
But how do these three people define
eating dumplings and tigers?
You can also say
the result of
eating dumplings and tigers
is 1.
If the person who chose 1
is 1,
then he won.
If the person who chose 0 is 0,
he also won.
Of course, this payoff is not
0.3. So in some cases,
the seller of
eating dumplings and tigers may lose money.
And the loser is not ABC.
It's the one who
opened the casino.
This is just
one example.
But
in terms of game theory,
there are many
forms of this game.
But for now,
let's focus
on this
simplest example.
I just want to
ask
to protect the
real
interest.
Can we do this?
Then
this definition
we call it Maximin.
Maximin is also
a terminology borrowed
from game theory.
In the game,
Maximin means
everyone
maximizes
their own
interest.
I want to
minimize
my own interest.
Basically,
it means
when others maximize
their interest,
I want to maximize
my own interest.
Why is it called Maximin?
Because if one side is maximized
and the other side is minimized.
Anyway,
intuition
means
I want to protect good people.
Good people
are people who play according to the rules of the game.
The interest of good people
should be greater than or equal to 0.5.
This is the expectation value.
After this thing is defined,
the first question we ask is
whether it can be done.
Of course, there are other definitions
of Maximin.
Some are very natural.
Some may seem
unnatural in some scenarios.
But we'll talk about it
later.
For now,
let's focus on
the definition of
protecting good people's interests.
Let's pause here.
Is this definition clear?
My definition is
that my protocol
should protect good people's interests.
This is my definition.
Then I ask
whether this protocol
can be constructed
to protect good people's interests.
I have a question.
You said
we should protect
according to the rules of the game.
This is a starting point
of your research.
I can understand this.
The concept of
protecting good people's interests
is translated to
greater than or equal to 0.5
for the expected payoff
of honesty.
You said your game
is not zero-sum.
Is greater than or equal to 0.5
greater than or equal to 0.5?
You asked
a good question.
I don't write
a quantifier here.
For example,
A, B, C are all honest.
They all follow the rules of the game.
Then
everyone's
expected value is 0.5.
So you will ask
the total expected value is 0.5.
So I
don't have a quantifier here.
It's just that
every honest is greater than 0.5.
Oh, I see.
I define
it as
A, B, C
all follow the rules of the game.
But they
may not
care about each other.
They may not like each other.
But they all follow the rules of the game.
They are all good people.
So the better way
is that
if I follow the rules of the game,
it's my best choice
among the players.
This question
will become another definition.
What you just said will become another definition.
So we'll
discuss it later.
OK, thank you.
OK, so
if
this definition
is not a problem,
then we can
discuss
a simple example.
When everyone
wants the result to be
1, or everyone
wants the result to be 0,
then
this thing
is extremely simple.
This thing
As long as
everyone sees
the same side number,
then everyone outputs
the same side number.
As long as everyone sees
the same side number,
then everyone outputs 1.
Then everyone is happy.
For example,
if everyone wants the result
to be 1,
then everyone outputs 1.
The dealer
in the casino is not happy,
but the rules of the game
are set.
The players are happy
because everyone can win.
But this example is not very interesting.
Because
if
Trump, Xi and Putin
all want to go to DC,
then
they don't need to discuss this thing.
They are happy to go to DC.
So
this case is not interesting.
Let's change to
a more complicated one.
If one of the players
has a different side number,
he is a minority.
But
I assume
the bad guy who doesn't follow the rules of the game
can only do one thing,
which is
he can't play earlier.
I also have
a slightly more complicated
rule of the game
that can protect
the interests of good people.
How to do this rule of the game?
It's very simple.
Let the minority throw the coin.
After throwing the coin,
he tells the result of the coin
to the other two players.
Then the other two players
are very happy to receive the coin.
Then the game is over.
Why
can this rule of the game
protect the interests of good people?
Because
this game only forces
one person to speak from the beginning to the end,
which is the minority.
If the minority
speaks,
he follows the rules of the game.
If he wants to speak,
he must follow the rules of the game.
Otherwise, he will shut up.
If he speaks,
it means he follows the rules of the game.
This coin is also
fair.
After the other two players
receive the coin,
they follow the rules of the game.
Because
everything is fair
according to the rules of the game.
If the only person
who speaks
does not follow the rules of the game,
how can he not follow the rules of the game?
He can only
shut up.
He does not say what he should say.
This is his only way
not to follow the rules of the game.
When A and C see B
do not follow the rules of the game,
they are happy to decide that B is a bad person.
A and C can be happy to say
that we do not care
about the loss of the bad person.
We just follow our happiness.
So
what I just
talked about
is to prove
that the rules of the game
can easily protect
the interests of good people.
So
if the only thing
bad people can do
is not to play,
this thing is also easy to do.
Just
as I just said,
throw a coin, send a message,
and it's over.
But
these examples
of Trump and Xi
or Putin
are not like this.
They may
not follow the rules of the game,
not throw a coin,
so
the previous one, B
threw a coin and sent a message,
this thing is
that the bad guy
may not follow this rule at all.
And
if he doesn't follow this rule,
then
he can't protect
the interests of good people.
This is what we call
random
input.
This is what we call
random input.
Everything is not fair
when it is tampered with.
And
the main difficulty
of this project is
to discuss
whether this case
is fair
to Maximin.
And
We
spent a lot of time
We spent a lot of time
discussing whether he can do it or not.
We can't think of a way
to really do this thing
to protect
honest players.
But we can't prove
that he can't do it.
So we can't do this thing.
At the beginning,
we thought he could do it.
The reason is
When bad guys
are restricted,
there is a solution.
There are
many technologies
on traditional documents
that allow
a simple example
that allows a simple example
to resist
the restricted bad guys.
And then,
we get a
cryptographic operation
and get a
protocol that
the bad guys are not restricted
but still safe.
This is called the game rule.
Because
there are a lot of experiences in our documents,
we can upgrade
this security
in different situations.
So when we first
saw this problem,
we can upgrade
the security
with what we already know
or what we already know
in the documents.
But
later on,
we moved more documents
and finally proved that
it can't be done.
And
especially
the bad guys
can't be done
like
what I said earlier
about the result of cleave.
We really built
a
limited time attacker
a polynomial time attacker
to attack
any
protocol like this.
And
the middle proof is more complicated.
I won't talk about it.
But
the point is
these protocols
can't be done
in a lot of situations.
And the proof
is
the proof
taught in high school or
university math class.
The technical details
in the middle
are skipped.
But I think
this
thing
should be
conveyed.
I defined
a
so-called
fair board
for a
specific payoff function.
This is very specific.
I have countless payoff functions.
Only this
payoff function
can't be
fair.
Maybe other payoff functions can.
Because
some payoff functions
are easy to do.
For example, if everyone's payoff looks the same,
it may
degenerate to a
case I just discussed.
And
the so-called
profit of the city
is defined
in this way.
So there must be
some way to define
the profit.
But even in such a simple way
to define
the profit,
there is still
no way to
protect the profit.
This is the message
I want to convey.
And
one more thing.
Even if
the attacker has limited computing power,
it still can't be protected.
If your attacker
has very limited
computing power,
you still can't
protect the city's
profit.
So
what I just said
is back to the first example.
Where should
Trump and Xi meet?
They can decide.
But
when one person becomes the third person,
and Putin is added,
there is no way to
protect the city's profit.
This is the
biggest message
I want to convey.
There must be
one or two people
whose profits will be damaged.
And
the witness here
is very complicated.
But
it's just a simple
expected value calculation.
But there are a few more turns.
But
I won't
talk about
the details.
So
to sum up,
more than three people
can be grouped
into
a larger
organization.
For example,
if I have
ten people,
I can group
them into
three large groups.
If
the three large groups
correspond to
what I just said,
they still can't
do it.
Or if I can
correspond to two people,
I can tell you
the result of
Cliff earlier.
So
this...
Actually I was going to ask
if you keep saying
you have three parties
and you want to generalize
what N-Party will do.
Intuitively,
it makes sense.
If you can group them
into three parties,
you can reduce the problem.
But if you say
the bad guys
can be grouped
into a group of bad guys,
you still have to assume
the bad guys
are good to each other.
They are honest.
So the shared information
is what they are doing.
They know
each other is breaking the rule.
Yes.
Your question is very good.
So I will
jump a little bit
to talk about
high-level.
I assume
the bad guys
I mentioned
are
good guys
and bad guys.
The bad guys
have
a common...
What is it called?
For example,
they have
a bad guy
controlling them.
So your question is
maybe
the bad guys A
and bad guys B
have different interests.
So they
control each other.
So far,
I assume
the bad guys A
and bad guys B
have a bad guy leader.
Maybe he is not
in the game.
But he is the leader of the bad guys.
He controls all the bad guys.
All the bad guys
cooperate with each other.
So
for the
bad guys
or good guys
two or three
should be
easy to explain.
Did I answer your question?
Yes.
It's the same as I thought.
OK. Thank you.
I will talk about
the bad guys A
and bad guys B.
Sometimes,
the bad guys A and bad guys B
don't always
have the same leader.
But
to sum up,
most examples
can't be used
to protect
the good guys.
Unless
the problem is simple.
Only one
person has different preferences.
And the bad guy is very limited.
He can only
play. He can't do anything else.
Only a small piece
can be
justified.
The justification defined
under Maximine
can only be justified
by a small piece.
The rest can't be justified.
It's quite sad.
Just now,
the host
asked
some good questions.
For example,
I defined
that the good guys' interests can't be damaged.
My starting point is to protect the good guys' interests.
The other starting point
is more like
game theory's
Nash Equilibrium.
The so-called bad guys
or corrupt parties
must have
a certain economic motivation
to do bad things
to break the rules.
This is
another
definition.
This definition is very natural.
For example,
I defined a set of game rules
in a certain game.
Even if
there is a
bad guy controlling
certain people,
he becomes a bad guy.
But the bad guys
controlled by the boss
don't have to
listen to the boss.
They have to
listen to
the boss
to increase
their own interests.
Then,
Nash Equilibrium
requires
the boss
to increase
the interests of the bad guys.
This is
very difficult
for the boss.
Especially,
for example,
what I said
from the beginning is that
the output is only 0 or 1.
Your preference
is only 0 or 1.
If the boss
controls both
0 and 1,
the boss
can't
satisfy
both sides.
Because
one side's interest increases,
and the other side's interest decreases.
So,
this definition is
called Strong Nash.
Strong Nash is borrowed
from Nash Equilibrium.
But in fact,
this definition is easier
to achieve than Maximine.
Because the boss
can do less
and receive more restrictions.
So,
it's very easy
to be fair
under this definition.
I don't know
if the boss is a bad guy,
or a good guy.
As long as the two sides
have different preferences,
let them play
what I said at the beginning.
One side commits
X,
the other side
decides a random Y,
and the other side
commits at the beginning,
opens the envelope
and decides what X1 and X2 are.
Everyone
listens to them.
No matter how many people are there,
10, 100, 1000,
as long as two people
are working.
This thing
is easy to prove.
Just list all the conditions
and it can be proved that
this game rule
can achieve
Strong Nash.
The boss can't
increase
the benefits of the boss.
Let's go back to the first page.
If you think about it,
you will find
these two definitions
are exactly the same
in 2Party.
Because in 2Party,
there are only two people.
In 2Party,
under this payoff,
it is a completely zero-sum game.
The situation of the two people
is symmetrical.
So the payoff of the bad guy
is equal to
the payoff of the good guy.
This was established
in Zero-sum.
In the case of two people,
there is only one bad guy
and one good guy.
So these two definitions are exactly the same.
But in 3 or 4 people,
or more people,
these two definitions are completely different.
One is
almost impossible.
The other is
almost possible.
This is a big difference.
In addition to these two definitions,
in my paper,
I will consider
other definitions.
Maybe more natural, maybe more complicated,
I don't know.
The first one is
the benefits of good people alone.
In the case of Group,
I don't consider the benefits alone.
I consider the benefits of all good people
to be added.
The benefits of good people
to be reduced
or the benefits of bad people
to be added.
There may be different
situations.
For example,
when the boss controls
a group of bad guys,
he may add all the benefits of the bad guys
and divide them.
This may be
a suitable
model for discussion.
For example,
the feasibility of these two
is between Maximin
and StrongNash.
These four definitions
are a bit complicated,
so I won't talk about them all.
Anyway,
in the case of
only two people,
these definitions are equivalent.
In the case of two people,
the total is equal to the individual.
In the case of zero-sum,
the increase of bad people
is equal to the decrease of good people.
So these four definitions
are the same
in the case of two people.
However,
they are completely different
in the case of more than three people.
If you have learned
or seen
some game theory,
you will
immediately think of
the question just asked by the host.
There are
various settings in game theory,
such as the payoff function.
Maybe the payoff function
I just gave is not the most natural.
In some cases,
the payoff of zero-sum is more natural.
Or in some cases,
what kind of outcome
does everyone like?
What kind of outcome
Where does Trump like to meet?
Where does Xi like to meet?
Maybe
the payoff function
is not the most natural.
Maybe it's private.
Everyone doesn't know.
This is a more natural setting.
In some cases,
it may be like this.
Of course,
from the beginning to the end,
I only talked about
throwing a coin.
Then this coin has only two sides,
0 or 1.
Then the coin becomes a dice.
0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
Or I want to do something more complicated.
For example,
Trump and Xi want to
add their salaries together.
Something like this.
These are all questions
that can be discussed in depth.
But there are a lot of questions
that can be studied.
This paper
only discussed a small part of
the blue ones.
So this is
the coin toss I talked about today.
Thank you everyone
for taking the time to listen to me.
Thank you.
Please turn on the microphone.
Let's give a round of applause
to our speaker today.
Do you have any questions?
No.
Let me ask you a question.
This question is not
related to the content of the lecture.
Did you publish this paper?
Or did you throw it away?
Do you want to
write down the title of the paper
and some other information
that we can find,
such as the date of the paper
and so on.
Then it will be recorded.
If you are interested,
you can look for it.
How can I write it?
I don't know.
You can jump back to your PowerPoint.
Okay.
Just type it here.
We can see it now.
Wait for me.
Text box.
Okay.
Now we are typing the text.
Do you have any questions?
Do you have any comments?
You can ask some basic questions.
For example,
what do you study
and so on.
I have an interesting question.
Of course,
this is the most fundamental
scenario.
Then we can
think about
a special example.
But now you...
Let me think.
So what you just said
is basically
your maximum
and the two parties below
are two extremes.
They can be discussed.
But those in the middle
are in, for example,
how many parties do bad people have?
Are the interests of bad people
completely the same?
In these cases,
your conclusion
is related to
N,
how many good people and bad people
are assigned to each other.
What is the relationship between them?
Will it affect your conclusion?
Yes.
I...
I just posted
the conference here.
I will jump back to my PowerPoint.
It is...
In...
In Max and Min,
the simple case
is that
when greater than or equal to 3,
it is impossible.
In the middle,
the group Max and Min
is the same as Max and Min,
greater than or equal to 3,
it is impossible.
It is related to N.
Three people can't do it,
or four people can't do it.
In the middle,
no matter how many people can do it,
it is related to N.
Does this answer the question?
Yes.
Actually, this is just the beginning of my question.
I should say that
I also expect that
this thing is related to N,
and N will affect your conclusion.
If this is the case,
it is closer to
the realistic situation.
For example,
how do you study in computer science?
Do you calculate one by one?
Or do you use
Monte Carlo
to use empirical methods
to conclude
some relationships,
such as the relationship with N,
or what is the solution
under some threshold,
what do you usually do?
So,
the question asked by the host
is more like
I have
a set of definitions
on the left,
a set of
maybe it is the sky,
maybe it is
some
realistic
problem motivator
definition,
a set of
motivator definitions,
how do I discuss
or
the definition on the left
whether it can be done
or not,
especially
in this
current
talk discussion
it is
related to N,
and how
to say
how much can be done
and how much can't be done.
In this
work,
there is
no good way.
In the middle,
every case
where N is greater than
how much can't be done,
is used
to
transform
to make another statement
N is greater than how much can't be done.
For example,
at the beginning,
N is greater than 2,
the first result is
the lower bound of cleave.
The following
is to
extend
the first
cleave's
impossibility
to 3 and 4.
In this example,
there is no good way.
There may be
other examples,
but
these definitions
are
the definitions of
cleave.
We
don't have
these continuous
or
continuous
or functional
mathematical tools
to use.
For example,
I asked
if there is
Monte Carlo
or experiments
to prove
those
experimental
methods,
we usually
avoid them.
Because
experimental methods
are difficult to prove.
Even if there are
only 3 or 4 small numbers,
it is not possible
to prove.
So,
we
rarely use them.
Maybe
we don't know
how to use them
to prove them.
Our
proof
is here.
It is more
comprehensive.
We calculate the probability.
After that,
we use...
For example,
here,
we calculate the expectation
and the probability.
Then, we use the average
to conclude
whether it is possible or not.
I see.
Thank you.
Do you have any questions?
Hello.
I have a question.
Please go ahead.
I still don't understand.
Can you
explain
how to
reduce
3 to 3?
How to reduce
almost
and malicious
to 3?
This
is a good question.
It is very simple.
Let's assume
n is equal to 4.
If n is equal to 4,
in this line,
unanimous
is the same.
Almost is one less.
Only one less.
If n is equal to 4,
it is...
I just type it.
It is 0, 1,
1, 1.
It is 0, 1, 1.
Of course,
it is symmetric.
0 may be in one person.
We don't know.
We don't care.
It is 0, 1, 1.
Then,
you have to ask
whether
there is a rule
that allows 4 people
to protect
the interests of honest people.
Let's assume
there is a rule
that allows
4 people
to protect
the interests of honest people.
What do we do?
We do
that
I don't care
whether 1, 1, 1, 1 is a good person or a bad person.
I tie
the two people
who like 1 together.
It is
a person.
a fatter person.
They all like 1.
The fatter person
likes 1.
If
there is a rule that allows
4 people to protect
the interests of honest people,
I tie
the two people who like 1 together.
Then,
they
play according to the rules of 4 people.
I don't care
whether it is a good person or a bad person.
After
I tie
the two people together,
there are only 3 people left.
Their preferences
are 0, 1, 1.
Their preferences are 1.
So, I tie
their preferences to 1.
If
there is a rule that allows
4 people to protect the interests of honest people,
it is a rule
that allows 3 people
to protect the interests of honest people.
Okay.
It feels like a math problem.
Yes.
It's what we often do.
We don't have a good tool.
Is it the same
for other preferences?
Do you tie all 0s
and 1s together?
This question
is a good question.
We tie
0s and 1s together.
Then, we tie
other 0s and 1s together.
Why do we tie like this?
It's because
Cliff's result said
that
when you play
with two parties,
you must have a way
to make them leave
0.5.
I don't know
if it's from 0.5 to 1
or from 0.5 to 0.
But there must be one side.
I don't know which side it is.
He didn't tell you.
But after
tying 0s and 1s together,
if it's one side,
in my definition of
maximum,
it will definitely hurt
one of the 0s and 1s.
Because 0s and 1s are tied together.
Okay.
It doesn't matter which side it is.
So,
I can get
a contradiction like this.
Okay.
It's amazing.
The thing is that
you can go down
a few pages.
I don't remember.
Go down again.
This is also right.
The method of
strong Nash equilibrium
is that you call a 0 and
a 1 out.
Then they are tied together.
The reason why this method
can't be used in Max and Min
is that you may choose
0 and 1.
One of them is a bad guy.
I'll cut it here.
I sent two representatives
to point at the board.
Why this thing
doesn't work
in Max and Min?
The question is like this.
The definition of Max and Min
is that
the benefits of good people
can't be harmed.
So,
in the definition of Max and Min,
the bad guy doesn't care
about his own benefits.
The bad guy
can lose money.
But the good guy
just wants to harm the good guy maliciously.
For example,
the red one is the bad guy
and the green one is the good guy.
Can you tell the difference?
The red one is the bad guy
and the green one is the good guy.
I can tell at the beginning.
Sometimes the color is not enough.
Because some people
have color blindness.
There are three bad guys
and two good guys.
If the bad guy just wants to harm
the good guy maliciously,
he can point to the bad guy
and the good guy will like him.
Then he will be harmed.
He doesn't care.
The good guy is happy.
But as long as the good guy is not happy,
Max and Min won't work.
So, this thing
doesn't work in Max and Min.
Does it have anything to do with
the question
the host asked at the beginning?
Do I consider
all the benefits of the good guy
or the benefits of the good guy
individually?
My strictest condition
is that I can't harm
every benefit of the good guy.
So, Max and Min
can't harm every good guy.
Yes.
This is a difficult question.
The definition
is tricky.
There will be a lot of groups
after the number of people.
I have a question
that is unrelated.
If
there is
something
that is completely random
and everyone agrees that it is random.
For example,
there is a quantum stack.
For example, the radiation of the sun.
This is also possible.
But you have to observe
the same thing in two places.
Yes.
There is
something called quantum entanglement.
Do you know this?
I know.
There are two examples.
For example,
they have to spin up together
and spin down together.
I assign these two
to two people
who are far away.
They observe this example.
Spin up
means one place.
Spin down means another place.
In this way,
can we solve this problem?
We don't need these protocols.
There will be
some ways
that you can operate.
Actually,
I know entanglement,
but I'm not familiar
with how to do it.
For example,
you mentioned that
you have to create two examples
that have entanglement.
I'm not
familiar with it.
Can we
do this entanglement
in advance
and
bias to
one side?
I'm not sure.
Maybe.
It seems that
we need some proof
to prove that
the entanglement
we created at the beginning
is fair.
I really don't know.
I just heard it.
After creating the entanglement,
you have to give
these two entanglement to two people.
In this
long-distance definition,
it may not be
very suitable.
I don't know if there is a better explanation
that it can't be done.
But you have to
give two bits
to two people,
or give two examples to two people.
Actually,
it doesn't
go well with this
definition.
Why don't I
create an entanglement
and give the result to two people?
OK.
It makes sense.
It doesn't seem that
it can be solved.
But I think
there is room for discussion.
Because some
can prove
that the entanglement
is fair.
Another thing
I want to ask is
at the beginning,
what I said
is that
1, 2, 3,
everyone says a number at the same time,
and then X, O, 2.
Why can't
everyone
say X, O, 2
at the same time
and then
say the number?
If it's
more than 12 o'clock,
you lose.
It's the same with fail-stop.
Fail-stop means
if you are slow,
you lose.
Yes, but
I think
at the same time,
it's difficult in practice.
One is in China,
the other is in the U.S.
The distance is
quite far.
The transmission message
may also have a delay
of 0.0 seconds.
0.0 seconds
plus
on the food,
if the light
is directly
connected,
it may be OK.
But the network on the food
has passed many host
and the delay
may be almost 1 second.
You can't be sure
how much time is there.
59 minutes and 59 seconds.
Is 1 second enough?
Or
too much
will be a bit slow.
It's hard to decide.
At the same time,
this is mainly
difficult to do on the food.
So people think
if you can't do it
or you can't prove it,
you give up.
Failstuff
also requires a time.
Yes, failstuff
is...
Yes, failstuff is...
Let me put it this way.
At the same time,
the rules are tight.
after my message
is sent out,
it takes at least
1 second to send it.
It may not work if I arrive early.
Because if I arrive early,
there will be a relatively slow output.
It won't work if I arrive late.
Is it slow output
or is it
slow? I don't know.
But failstuff
has a relatively large
range.
I can
arrive in 0 seconds
or 10 minutes.
So the range is relatively large.
If I can't wait for you for 10 minutes
and you haven't sent it out,
it's just
1 second
or 1 minute
to send it out.
So the
condition is
strictly
weak.
Very interesting talk. Thank you.
Thank you.
Actually,
it's been more than 10 minutes.
Please turn on
the microphone again.
Thank you to our speaker, Weikai.
Thank you, everyone.
If you have any questions,
you can
go to our website and find
Weikai's page.
It's on the right side of our website.
You can click and see his contact information.
Or you can also search
Weikai or Weikai's paper.
You can also see this information.
If you are interested in his paper,
he just wrote
on our
screen.
You can also see
Weikai's speech
in a few days.
You can also
contact Weikai
and discuss more.
Thank you again.
Thank you for attending today's Terra Talk.
That's all for today.
Thank you, everyone. Bye.