Hi, I'm Yen-Yung Chang, the host of Tera.
We are going to have the second lecture of Tera this year.
Today's speaker is...
Wait a minute, I have to scroll up first.
Today's speaker is Bi-Yao Zhuang.
She is from DC's George Washington University.
She is a fourth-year doctor of mechanical engineering.
She specializes in fluid dynamics and numerical simulation.
She is going to talk about...
Flux Reconstruction Correlation Procedure via Reconstruction in Computational Fluid Dynamics.
Let's welcome her.
Hi, I'm Bi-Yao Zhuang.
I'm a fourth-year doctor of George Washington University.
I specialize in fluid dynamics and numerical simulation.
I recently learned about a new numerical method called Flux Reconstruction.
Oops, I accidentally typed the wrong title.
Never mind.
It's called...
It doesn't have a Chinese name.
It was first proposed in 2007.
The second paper was published in 2009.
Other groups joined the field in 2012 and 2013.
So, it doesn't have a Chinese name.
It's called Flux Reconstruction.
As you can see, there is a typo in the title.
It's a reconstruction.
Some groups thought the name was bad.
So, they renamed it to Correction Procedure via Reconstruction.
It's basically the same.
There are two groups in the UK.
There are three groups.
One group is in NASA.
One group is in Stanford.
One group is in the UK.
In the UK and Stanford, they are called FR, Flux Reconstruction.
In NASA, they are called CPR, Correction Procedure via Reconstruction.
I recently learned about this.
I think it can be used for my doctoral research.
It just started in computational physics.
There is still a lot of room for development.
I just finished learning this.
I read a lot of papers and learned a lot.
So, I have some insights.
I'm here to make a progress report.
I'm here to share with you what this numerical method is doing.
What I'm going to talk about today is...
First, let me introduce some basic concepts of numerical methods.
I'm not sure what your background is.
So, there will be some basic introduction of numerical methods.
To avoid some people who are not doing numerical simulation and don't understand.
Next, I will introduce how to introduce Flux Reconstruction.
Basically, the first part is like a math class.
It's a mathematical introduction.
The last part is how I want to apply it to incompressible flow.
Because my main research is to do incompressible flow.
The group that proposed Flux Reconstruction, like Stanford or the UK.
They are all doing compressible flow.
So, at least so far, if you look for Literature Review.
I haven't seen any group using this method in incompressible flow.
So, I plan to do my research in this direction.
So, I will briefly talk about my future plan.
First, I want to introduce a very important concept in numerical methods.
It's called the Full-Weight Fragmentation Method.
It can infer all kinds of different numerical methods.
It's the foundation of the foundation.
So, I'm going to introduce it.
Today, there is a Full-Weight Fragmentation Method.
At present, many phenomena in the natural world are unified by the Full-Weight Fragmentation Method.
We call it the unified method.
I use a symbol like L to represent the operator of the Full-Weight Fragmentation.
It's the Full-Weight Fragmentation symbol.
An example of L is the so-called heat expansion method.
This is the operator of the Full-Weight Fragmentation.
U is an unknown function that we want to solve.
In the Full-Weight Fragmentation, it may be a temperature field.
The temperature field changes with time and space.
In the fluid, U may be a velocity field.
F is an unknown function on the right side of the equation.
It may be related to your physical phenomenon.
For example, in fluid mechanics, F may be a gravity field.
In the Full-Weight Fragmentation, F may be a heat source.
It is a thing that generates heat without realizing it.
If today's Full-Weight Fragmentation is the exact solution,
The real solution of the real world is called U-exact.
Although we want to know what U-exact is,
Because it is the real solution.
In fact, in real life, we can't get it at all.
Because in the Full-Weight Fragmentation, I'm not sure what it is.
But in theory, it should not be guaranteed that there is a real solution.
So we can't get the real solution today.
Then we think of another way.
Let's assume a solution.
For example, if today's U represents temperature,
Let's assume that the temperature in this space may look like what it looks like.
After we assume what it looks like,
There will be some unknowns in it.
Let's solve it again.
For example, today we assume that the temperature field will be a function series.
Like Fourier series or Laplace series.
Then you can write it as a sigma c i phi i.
c i is an unknown constant.
Then phi i is what we assume it looks like.
For example, I have a very simple example here.
If phi i is defined as x i,
If phi 0 is a constant,
Then phi 1 is x, phi 2 is x², phi 3 is x³.
Let's assume that the temperature field today is C0 plus C1 times x, plus C2 times x², plus C3 times x³.
Today we have assumed that the temperature field looks like this.
The rest we need to decide is how much C0, C1, and C2 are.
So the whole numerical method, numerical simulation, numerical partial differential,
All these things are actually discussing two questions.
What is it? What should we assume this U looks like?
What is this phi i?
It can be sine or cosine.
It can also be like the example I just mentioned, x, x², x³.
So what kind of assumption is the best?
This is a question.
The second question is, how do we find out how much C0, C1, and C2 are?
So the whole numerical method, numerical analysis,
In fact, when you take these classes,
It's all about these two questions.
When we talk about how to determine C, C0, C1, and C2,
We're going to talk about how to determine C.
We hope that we can find a set of C0, C1, and C2.
The definition of C0, C1, and C2 is that
When you take the assumption back to PDE,
It's a perfect zero error.
No matter where you are,
Assume that the function is always perfect.
There will be no imperfection in it.
But the problem is, it's impossible.
Because if you bring in the assumption function today,
It's a perfect zero error.
It's like you're guessing the function today.
It's just the exact solution.
Then it's not called the assumption function.
We don't need to guess.
So it's almost impossible.
Only some toy problems in textbooks.
You're just guessing a function.
Guess it's C0 plus C1x.
It's just the exact solution.
But in real life, it's unrealistic.
So we, for example,
And then the second question is,
If you use this method today to find C1, C2,
How many of these are there?
You'll find that you have several unknowns,
But you only have one square.
For example, if I guess today,
This function is C0 plus C1x plus C2x squared plus C3x squared.
And then I'm going to solve a Poisson equation today.
Then you put this assumption function
After bringing in the original Poisson equation,
It's a two-step equation.
The remaining two-step equation of U is 2C2 plus 6C3x.
And then you bring it in.
Your product will look like this.
What you see on the screen is 2C2 plus 6C3x minus 3pi x.
You only have one square.
But you have four unknowns from C0 to C3 today.
You can't solve it.
So these questions mean that
We can't use this method to find the unknown.
So today we're going to use the numerical method to
To broaden our understanding of the function.
We don't want it to be perfect today.
We want it to have some flaws.
But as long as some conditions are met, it's good.
This is called the weight multiplication.
You see the first point on this list.
This point means that
R is still the same as the multiplication of any point in space.
But today I'm going to multiply it by a weight.
This weight means that
In space, the value of some places is more important.
The value of some places is more important.
For example, x is equal to 2.
This place is very important.
I want its value to be multiplied by 10.
Then in x is equal to 3,
I don't care so much about its value.
I don't care if my assumption is correct.
So its weight may only be 0.1.
Then the requirement that I broadened today is that
Multiplying by the weight of the entire space will be zero.
multiply by the weight of the entire space will be zero.
This is good.
I no longer require that there are all points have negative parts.
So this is a broadened condition.
Then we're looking at this weight...
Hey
This is a little problem.
Your weight is
a function of x.
Then in your entire
range of interest in x
Is this w going to be positive?
Because negative will have
a strange meaning.
No, it's negative.
Negative can also
Even later
may be mentioned a little bit.
Even it will have infinite
Like the delta function at a certain point
It will have an infinite weight.
Then all the other places are zero.
Ok
Then you need to put this whole
You are now the first
The points above the points
Remove
w itself
dx and then the entire range of points
It's a bit like renormalize.
Is it total probability?
Is it total weight?
Or do you not need it?
You said
You are now the point
This equation
Its denominator
Is the same equation
But there is no r.
w itself dx
No need
We didn't do this.
Because theoretically
It is
Theoretically it is zero.
In fact, if you subtract something else
If your method
If it's perfect, you subtract something else
It's still zero.
We just divide it directly.
Ok, I understand.
Then we today
Then we continue to talk about this weight.
You see I have a j here.
In fact, it means that I am not only a set of weight today.
I just gave an example
For example, x1, the weight of this place is 10.
x3, the weight of the place is negative 0.1.
0.1
This is a set of weight.
But when I design the method today
I will not only design a set of weight.
I usually design
Enough weight to let me
Solve my unknown number
For example, the example I just gave
There are four unknowns from c0 to c3.
Then I have to design four groups of different weight today.
Then I will have four groups.
That linear equation
I will get that linear equation.
So I can solve four
That c0 to c3
These four unknowns
That constant
So we are equal to simplify
I just said that the numerical method is around two problems.
One is how we should assume
What does it look like?
The second is how to calculate
The constant c0 to c
The second question is how to calculate c
This constant
We can change it
In other words, it becomes another question.
How do we define our weight?
Then
This is our question now.
The question we just asked
We will remember to go back to this question later.
Then we just talked about it before.
Is the standard that has been relaxed
As long as the weight of the weight
After the weight is multiplied by the weight
The residual value of the weight is zero.
Then in the numerical method
We will be further relaxed
Is that we often hear
You may hear some elements
Then grid
Or some more
May be more formal
Will be called piecewise solution
That is to say
Today this space is interesting
I wrote it in the first video called space
I cut it into a smaller area in space.
For example
Subdomain 1, Subdomain 2
This kind of subdomain is called element.
Is what you often hear
The so-called element in the finite element
Or you hear that grid
A grid inside
Then I use a 1 today.
To represent this kind of subdomain
Then k under the label means different
Subdomain
Then let it go today.
I
Inside each element
Have their own guesses
For example, U0 means the 0th subdomain.
It has its own assumption function
That U1 inside
Is the 1st element
It also has its own guess function
Then
So the whole global
The guess function is actually a lot of different
Small elements are combined
If X is in the 0th element today
Then we use the 0th guess function
If X is in the 1st element today
We use the 1st guess function
Why do you say
This is a kind of relaxation
Why is it a kind of relaxation
Because it means
Today if the real world
Exact solution
Is a very high-level function
For example, a high-level polynomial
Or a sine, sine wave or cosine wave
Its fluctuation is very large
You see, like this example
The black line in this example is the exact solution
It has three fluctuations
It is equal to at least three or more
Its solution is three or more polynomials
Even sine or cosine
But if I take the whole domain today
Divided into many small elements
Like this example, I split it into six small elements
I mean I have each element
Just use a straight line
Then add six elements
I can see my real world
So this is a kind of relaxation
It means I'm guessing
What does this function look like
I use the simplest straight line
I can be my assumption
You can guess what this function looks like
So we will say this
Divide it into subdomain
Elements or cells
Is a kind of relaxation
A more relaxed condition
That's what this video is about
This kind of relaxation
As I just said, its advantage is
Even if your real function
Is a very high-level function
Or a very vibrant, very fluctuating
If it's a big thing
I can also use a very low-level guess
To look at this exact solution
This is its advantage
The disadvantage is
We split this domain today
Into many small subdomains
What is the relationship between the subdomain and the subdomain
This is a new problem
A new problem
For example, what is the relationship between element 1 and element 0
It's impossible to have nothing to do with it
Because they are all describing
Different sections of the same real node
So they still have a relationship
So you have to make some assumptions
What we use the most in our numerical method today
The so-called continuous function we call C0
That is to say
Today, if there are two elements connected together
Like on the picture, if you see this blue element
And yellow element
C0 is that they just have to
The point where the interface is connected
It's just continuous
That's the easiest
So today you can see this blue line
And the orange line are connected
And the orange line and the orange line are connected
As for the number of points, is it connected
In this C0 condition
We don't care
So if we talk again
To refresh
Today's modern numerical method
We just talked about the surrounding two issues
So now you can add one more question
Is to first
So first
is the assumption function
What does it look like
Then the second is what this whole function should look like
Then the third is when we split the domain into many small elements
When we split the domain into many small elements
What are the relationships between elements and elements
The combination of different answers to these three questions
Will give you different
The so-called numerical method
I have a question
My question may be very basic
People who understand
My question is like this
For example, the thing you just described
Is a coordinate field
But if you care about the nature
If it's speed or acceleration
But if it's speed or acceleration
Are you
Right
So you will know
Because if your conditions today are very simple
But if you are
You can find a number on the right
And limit them to be equal
You are equal to saying that the conditions
It will be tougher and harder to meet
But this is every
How strong is the boundary condition of the small element
So the actual operation will be with
What kind of problem do you want to solve?
It's about your actual problem
I see
This is why different areas
Will use different numerical methods
So maybe the most common thing we hear is
Limit difference, limit element, limit volume
These are the three most common
Then you will find out why
People who calculate mechanics use limited elements
Then why
Fluid mechanics uses limited volume
Then other people use limited difference
It's because they are likely to be
C0 or C1
This kind of requirement is different
Then
So back to the three questions here
Then there are some examples here
Different answers to these three questions
What kind of different
Numerical methods
The first
Its formal name is pseudospectral
Or that positive
I don't know the Chinese name
Orthogonal collocation
Then why mention this
Because we hear the most
Limited difference, finite difference
Is a special case
Then this numerical method
That is to say, its weight is a delta function
That's what I just said
It will be infinite at this point
That
Delta function
This thing is very interesting
It will become
I don't know
After it is accumulated
I should be able to go back to that video
Delta function
After the accumulation becomes
Only this point has value
A little slow
It's like this
Like this point
If wj is a delta function
That delta function
If the point is in xj
Then this point will become
The right-hand side is equal to
R of xj
That's it
So this is why you are in a finite difference
I can't see any weight at all
I can't see it
It is
The finite difference is defined at the point
If you are
Then
The finite difference is this
So-called pseudo-spectral
A special case
Except that the weight is a delta function
Its
The diameter is also very low
It is a straight line
Its so-called phi is a straight line
Just guess
You can see
The solution of the assumption
It only has phi0 and phi1
Two things
So today you are doing
When there is a finite difference
In fact, you are solving
It's just C0 and C1
Then the finite difference
The continuous condition of C0
The finite volume
It's like fluid mechanics
Its weight is
As long as it is
This one
I define it in ej today
Inside this element
Its weight is all 1
Outside this element
Its weight is all 0
This is the definition of its weight
Then
The solution of the assumption
This is what we guess
It's simpler than the finite difference
It's just a parameter
Today in an element
In a subdomain
For example, the temperature field
The temperature field in this subdomain
It's just a parameter
It won't change anything
It will be very complicated
It will use the so-called
Riemann jump condition
It's complicated
I just want to say
It's not a C0 condition
What is it
It's beyond today's scope
So I didn't say
It's just an example
How do we answer those three questions
Will define a different value
The third is
The so-called continuous Galerkin method
We often hear that finite elements
This is a special case
In this case
Its weight
Will be equal to
The function we guess
Is phi j
Phi j is what we just guessed
Assuming that function
Its weight is this
As long as you use this weight
It's all called Galerkin method
The finite element
It's more advanced
It also uses C0
Continuous condition
But as for this phi i
What is it
Is it sine, cosine, polynomial
Or exponential
In fact, in the traditional Galerkin method
It didn't say
It's just in the finite element
The traditional phi i
Use a straight line to define
It's a straight line polynomial
This video
Just to introduce to you
Our numerical method
What is it all about
That's the three questions
I'm going to introduce this today
The weighting method
Because the flux reconstruction
Will use the weighting method to push down
I didn't mention it in the video
The so-called low-order method
Or high-order numerical method
So I want to be here today
Also want to introduce
Not everyone has a numerical method
Background
So I want to introduce this order first
What is it
We just had a projection
There is an example
If there is one today
The physical field of the real world
For example, this black line is its real field
We don't know
The field we can't guess
Then we use six elements to define it
Then in each element
We guess it's a straight line distribution
That's what it looks like
If we want today
You can clearly see that
Although at some points
The function we guess is very
Basically close to the physical field of the real world
But other parts
You see, like this blue straight line
With that black curve
There is a big, obvious error in the middle
So if we want to improve this error today
What can we do
The first thing we can do
Is to use more elements
Just make it finer
So in each element
Still use a straight line
But the straight line may be because it is smaller
It will be closer to the black line
Is the real physical field
The next projection
The next projection is an example
Like this projection
I added six elements today
Let the total number of elements become 12
But in each element
Still use a straight line
That guess
Then we will find that I just added six elements
Now the whole guess
The solution will become very close to the real solution
This method
This is a kind of increase
Reduce error
Then increase the accuracy
A way
Why did you mention this?
Because when we define the so-called order
It's related to this
Order means when I add today
When the number of my elements
How to reduce
When we define the speed
Is defined by the index
For example, I
The number of my elements has increased by m times
Then my error
The speed of the decree
Is the square of m
That square is the so-called order
Is when we define the numerical method
A definition of order
Then this order
Or this so-called rate
It is also called the convergence rate
Is the speed of convergence
Then like some examples
For example, today if my
The number of elements from n1
Changes to twice n1
Then my error from epsilon
Reduce to one-second epsilon
Then this method is called first order method
Because
I mentioned this m today
Is 2
Then my error today becomes one-second
Then it is the square of 2
So it is the first order method
Then my error from n1
Increases to twice n1
But my error from the original epsilon
Reduce to one-eighth epsilon
Then this is the third order method
Because 8 is the square of 2
3 times
Then this is our so-called order
So the so-called low order
We are talking about low order method
Usually refers to first order or second order method
In other words, you double your number of elements
As a result, your error value
Only reduced by half
Error value becomes one-fourth
Then high order is usually three steps
We usually call high order
Then here is a
Is
High degree expansion
Is to be distinguished from high order
We just assumed
The function is the u, there is a hat above
We use a sigma
Then ci times phi i
The more i i use today
For example, I use from c0 to c10
The more we use
We will say this is a higher degree
Expansion
For example, c0
If your guess today is c0 plus c1 phi 1
That's it
Maybe you can say it is degree of two
Degree of one
Then if you use c0 today
c1 c2 c3
Then it is degree of three
What a coincidence today
If I am building my assumption
When that function
Is also high degree expansion
Is my
There are more in the series
If there are more phi
It will usually be a high order method
That is to say, the speed of error collection
Will be faster
For example, if you use
There are a total of ten phi
You may only multiply the number of elements by two
Its error may be
Collection is
It's just one percent
The speed of error reduction is very fast
At the same time
In addition to the speed of error collection
The so-called high degree expansion
It can usually give us a more accurate solution
Like the following picture
Is an example
I still use six elements
But in each element today
I no longer assume it is just a straight line
I assume it is a quadratic equation
I just added one more
x square
I still use six elements
But you can clearly see
It's very, very close to the real world
I just made such an assumption
So you can see
If you are in the element today
The higher the degree
The accuracy it gives you
Will be better
This is actually
I want to emphasize a little
Can't mess up
The so-called convergence rate
Is the so-called order
Can't mix it up with accuracy
Because order is just a definition
It's just how fast it gets smaller
But it doesn't mean that the error it gives you is very small
Accuracy is
The error I gave you today is very, very small
But it doesn't mean that after I double the number of elements
Its error
It really gets smaller
Even if you have ten elements
Give you such an error
After you double it into twenty elements
Your error makes it bigger
So accuracy and the so-called order
Can't mix
I have a question
My question is
I'm not sure
But I assume your black line
When you were writing code
You are using a
Three-time polynomial
Just c0 plus c1x plus c2
Plus c3x three times
If you want to use
This uj
You also get its degree
Is up to 3
In fact, you use
3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9
There will be no more
Improvement because of its critical
It has perfectly described
Is this a problem?
Because all the coefficients after you
Will be zero
But isn't this the case?
Isn't it just case by case?
Yes so
It's not wrong to say that
But
We can't know the truth
Because
This is an example
So I use a three-time polynomial
To draw it
But in the real world, you don't know
It's a three-time polynomial
So you can only use
More and more order
To see what it looks like
You mean
The real signal in the natural world
Maybe you get five squares
Can describe some
Then maybe you get
After ten squares, it can start to describe
For example, another kind of perturbation
Then fifteen squares can describe
Some kind of noise
It will keep describing
Smaller signal
Not what I'm talking about
What I want to say is
I'm building this uj today
What should it be used for
When
It is indeed case by case because
I don't know the real solution
What does it look like
So I can't tell
What should I use
What I can do is
For example, the same six elements I just did
I assume it is c0 plus c1x
It's just like this
Then see how much it is
When I do the second calculation today
I add one more
Plus c2x square
Then see how much it is
Then see if it is
Is the difference getting smaller and smaller
For example, if I use three elements today
Like now
If there are three elements in my projection
If the error is 10 times 10
1 times 10 times 10
Then today if I add another
c3x3 square and calculate it again
The result is c3x
The assumption of four elements and three assumptions
The error is only
For example, only 1 times 12
That is to say that you are adding another
When c3x
It doesn't help
So that is to say
That is to say
In fact, we don't know what to do
We can only use this method to guess
A bit confusing
A bit difficult to describe
I can understand what you want to say
But what you are talking about now is basically
Assuming a perfect
Mathematical discussion
But in fact, when you are writing code
If you keep increasing your degree
You may keep reducing
Your
Uncertainty or inaccuracy
But to a certain extent
You no longer have so many advantages
To reduce the difference between the model and the actual
But you start to magnify
Your own computation
Will it?
Will
So that's probably what you don't want to do
More
At that time
You may not need to
Put more
Elements into your uj
I see
Thank you
Then
The next page
So like I just said
The previous video
In addition to using more
Elements in your
Assuming function
In addition to giving you
A very precise answer
At the same time
Its convergence rate is also very high
So it is equivalent to the speed of its chain
Its error reduction speed is also fast
At the same time, the error it gives you is also very small
Then it is a very
It's a very attractive way
In fact
Starting with a computer
Starting with a numerical method
The so-called high degree
Everyone wants to use
But why is everyone still using
Limit element and limit volume
The bottom line is that it has a lot of
The disadvantage is that if I
Today's physical field is a
Time dependent
Unsteady problem
There is a countdown for time in the unified square
That usually
This kind of thing is very unstable
Because there will be errors in the computer
The computer can't use it
To show all the numbers
So it has some numbers
Can't express
Errors in the calculation process
If today
T is equal to 0
0.1 seconds
A very small error
The so-called unstable is that it is very possible
At 0.2 seconds
The error in the first second
In this second
Let your calculation explode
For example, it becomes infinitely large
Or infinitely small
This will happen
This situation is called unstable
That high degree element
It is particularly easy to be unstable
The reason is obvious
Like you just saw
If we use 10 today
There is a c10x10 square
If I have a small error today
There is a small error in this step
Is 1
1 square
You bring this error to x10
The whole error becomes
1 square
This will make your computer
Let your calculation explode
So this kind of thing
It becomes so-called very unstable
The second is that it is more involved
The concept of linear代数
It is Eocondition
If I am today
We just said that we must have a linear equation
To solve those c, those functions
For example, four
Four linear equations to solve
The so-called condition number
There is a thing called condition number
The higher the condition number
It means that this linear equation is more difficult to solve
The lower the condition number
It means that this linear equation is easier to solve
Usually you use the higher
The assumption function
For example, when using x4 to 8, x5 to 8, x6 to 8
We will
It will become the so-called Eocondition
It's a sick
Its linear equation will be very difficult to solve
You may need
Very, very long time
Those c0, c1, c2, c3
That is
The so-called high degree and high order method
The second
Then the third
The more you use it, the more complicated it is
When you write a computer program
The more difficult it is
Even if it's not easy to write
There may be more bugs in it
It will be more difficult to debug
Then the fourth is like now
Everyone's program is parallel
Run on multiple boxes
Even our computers are at least four cores
Then when this high-level method
You want to design it
Can be at the same time on eight cores
When you go to solve together
It will also become very difficult
So this is the most obvious high-level method
Four disadvantages
That's why
So far everyone is familiar with the numerical method
It's still the kind of first order
Or second order
Limit difference or limit element
But everyone is still working hard
Is the so-called high-level method
Because he is very appealing
He just gives you a very small error
Then his error is very slow
So everyone is still studying
So everyone will find a way to say
From the three questions we just said
The three questions around the numerical method
If we can find a combination
A combination of three answers
Can give us a better high-level method
Everyone has been trying in this area
That is indeed possible
Maybe everyone has heard of
The so-called discontinuous Galerkin
Is a continuous Galerkin method
He is probably
A major breakthrough after 2000
Then he can be very high-level
Then his
Also relatively stable
Then his conditions are relatively low
So after 2000
You will hear very often
The so-called discontinuous Galerkin
Because it becomes very popular
Then I
Here is an example
I just said
Different answers can give you
Maybe the same high-level
But relatively stable
Or conditions are relatively low
The numerical method
Like the three lines above me
Represents three different
Phi i assumptions
The steepest straight line
Is the so-called
He should be the moment expansion
Is the example I just used
Is c0 plus c1x
Plus c2x2 plus c3x3
That is to say
Phi i is equal to x i
This is very obvious
You can see how many x axes
I used
Phi i
Then y axis is the condition
You can see him
The more you use, the more conditions
Increasing faster
So it means that you use too much today
If you use too much
It will be very difficult to solve
Then the second
This is the connection between the two
He uses the so-called
The so-called
And even the third triangle
This line is a popular one these years
Which is
The so-called
Phi 0 is a
Phi 1 is
Let's use this method to
Assume a function
You will find that the more you use phi
Its conditional value does not change
That is to say
The more phi you use today
The so-called EO condition
It can be counted as eliminated
It doesn't exist anymore
Now show this diagram
For everyone to see
Why different answers
Can possibly solve
Those drawbacks of high-level methods
I have a small question
So
In fact
Usually condition number
Is it about equal to
Calculation time
Because you just count a condition number
Is it a linear equation?
Yes, but I don't really know
I haven't thought about this question
It's hard to say
Because you have to see
What is the method to solve the equation
For example, you can use
You solve a linear equation
You can use
Is the most basic Gauss elimination
Then you can also use some
Is more
Faster method
Is like
Or like you can use some
More fancy method
Is to first solve its eigenvalue
Then use the eigenvalue
To find its characteristic equation
Then use the characteristic equation to combine
Its linear equation
So
I don't think
Different ways to solve
The same linear equation
Condition number
Is equal to calculation time
And it may not be equal
Because you basically have to put all conditions
All together
To solve the eigenvalue
Oh, I see
But I'm sure
The more conditions, the worse
The more it solves, the slower
As for the slow ratio
Is it linear or what?
I haven't studied this
So I'm not sure
So now
Enter the main topic
Weighted residual method
Is used later
Flux reconstruction method
Then just explained
That order is just
Give you a concept
What is low order, what is high order
Why do we use high order
What is good to study
Here is a hint for everyone
Just give you a concept
We just mentioned that there are three ways
The answer to three questions
Can define a new
That's why I'm talking now
Give you a hint
Flux reconstruction
What is the answer to these three questions
For the FR method
Its assumed function
This phi i is used
You can say it is
Lagrangian function
But you can also say it is Lagrangian
That polynomial is
Lagrangian
Interval function
That's just this interval function
Interval function needs
You need some points
To define the interval function
In the FR
The interval function of phi
Is defined in
The so-called quadrature point
Everyone knows
It is a special point
It is not randomly distributed
It is not evenly distributed
The distribution of points must meet certain rules
This rule is Lagrangian polynomial
It must meet the Lagrangian rule
This is its expansion
Its expansion is phi i
What is it?
What is its weight?
Its weight is Galerkin method
So its weight is used
It's the same as phi i
wj is equal to phi j
That's the same as Galerkin method
But we'll show you later
Where is it different from Galerkin method
It still has some different places
Then the third question is
What is the relationship between different elements
What I wrote here today is
Orthogonal polynomial based blocks reconstruction
In fact, it is the same as
The same as the finite element
The same as the finite volume
The so-called Riemann
Riemann jump blocks
If you have
If you have learned
The finite volume, you will probably have an impression
It doesn't matter
I will still talk about this
What is this
This is just a heads up
Now let's start the formal introduction
When this method was proposed in 2007
It is mainly to solve the so-called
Hyperbolic conservation law
This kind of PDE will look like this
When there are three or five corners
There will be an end mark for y and z
Today we assume
The effective range
From xA to xB
If we cut it into
N1 elements
And then we use 1
To represent each element
And then each element
Your own effective range
Let's write it as xk to xk plus 1
Todaywe have two guessed functions
The first is the guessing function on u
The guessing constructions inside dkget
And then we write
It like this
Sigma u,k,i,psique
u,k,i
U,k,i means the value of dk
In fact, only u,k,i is unknown
Because f,k,i is defined from u,k,i
f,k,i means you bring u,k,i to the f function in your original pd
You can get u,k,i
So although we have two guessed functions
But only u,k,i is unknown and needs to be solved
Then we go back to the weighting function
The weighting function is applied to dk element
Only in dk element, we don't care about other elements
So its base range is xk to xk plus 1
Then weight wj
Then the right side is our original pd value
That is r
Then the second line below, I just split it into two
Then we are now for the second item
The second item is weight wj
F is the derivative of this function to x
Then we use the distribution points today
Distribution points in the distribution points
We can get the equation on the right
This is the value
It will become xk plus 1 value
Then subtract another base function
This function is the so-called weak form
Weak form of dsk
I only mention it here
Because we don't want to do dsk
Then if you want to do dsk today
After you get this value
Your next step will jump directly to
How do I define f at xk plus 1
Or how to define f at xk
Then we are not going to do this today
So skip this step first
Let's move on to the next step
The next step is the one I just
Wait for the point on the right
I will go one step further and do it again
Distribution points
After I do the distribution points again
I will get the original point function again
Is the derivative of weight wj
But on my left
I will have two more
I will have one more fk at xk plus 1 value
This is what I just said to f
Assuming that the function
The derivative function at xk plus 1 value
Then this fk
Then xk is the value
It means that f is the assumption function
The derivative value at xk
So the third line is just a reorganization
You will get an original distribution function
Then subtract the following two
Weight wj
What does wj mean?
It means
A jump
I hope xk this place
The first f
If you can see my mouse
The first f means
I hope xk this place
What is its value
Then the second f
Is the f obtained by the inner product function
It means that I actually calculate the inner product function today
At this point
How much is this point at xk?
So it's called jump
Is the value I hope
The difference between the actual inner product value
This is called jump
This kind of thing is in that document
They will be called strong form of discontinuous skeleton
That's just
No one is trying to solve this equation
Then
The last point is to remind everyone
Pay attention to the definition of two different f
One is how much I hope it is
Then one is the inner product function
The actual value of the inner product
Then the next page
A little slow
Then I am today
This page is just about
The so-called strong form
Of discontinuous skeleton
Back to the original
The points of the entire product function
Then it will look like this
You will find that the first one is still the original
The points of the entire product function
Then there are two more things related to jump
Then today
In Flux Reconstruction
The so-called strong form
Of discontinuous skeleton is different
He used a trick at this time
He assumed
I have a place in front
There is xwjxk
This one
If I can write it in the same way
A formula
Then find a so-called gl function
Let him say wj
The value of the entire product function at xk
Will be equal to
This point
Then wj at xk
The value of this point
Will be equal to the point defined by gr
Then I put these two definitions
Take it back to the original
The points of the entire product function
I can write it as a whole
Everything
Stuffed into my points
It will be like this
Everything will become a point
Then the entire weight multiplied by everything else
Why do this
Because if you do this, you can put
If you delete the whole weight, you can delete the points
Becomes a pure polynomial
So this is
Flux Reconstruction
Is me
Assuming that wj can become a point
Then take it back
I can delete the points and the weight
Back to restore
A primitive polynomial
This page is just
Just rewrite it
I have a small question
So you
You this method
Basically rely on
Is grgl
Exist
That's right
Will this be a problem
It is the focus
It is a focus of fr
Is
Its focus is
What is grl and gr
Because we assumed first
The same grl and gr
But we didn't mention
Did you really find it
So wait
I may not talk about that today
Because that will become more
But I will directly
One or two
Already found function
Then
This page is rewritten
Flux Reconstruction
Is what we are looking for
This method is looking for
So you can see
The biggest difference between fr and grl
Is
Its weight
wj this function will disappear in the end
But
What to pay attention to is that it is not
No weight, it's just weight
Will disappear
Then
In the end
How to use that primitive polynomial
To find the real u
Then we have to go back
Involve in the so-called
Time point
Time point is the simplest
Euler
Is a finite polynomial
Euler's temporal time margin
Is
Is the simplest point
Is equal to
t plus delta t
minus t
The value of this time point
Is your delta t
We put it as partial u partial t
Is an Euler method
Then we put it
Just that
The primitive polynomial of fr
Bring back
We can get this
A finite polynomial
Then
We use t plus delta t
And t to represent
The solution of different time points
Is
Is it missing a page or two?
Let me see what the next page is
it is good
Then
In this function
We have seen a lot now
That variable u
Then t plus delta t
Then we have to know
Which is unknown
To know how to solve
So we have to review
Is that we just didn't
Although I didn't mention how to calculate
I want to be in xk
How much is xk plus 1
But we are here first
Assuming we already have a way to
Calculate how much we want
Then the second is that we also assume
We have found the right
gl and gr
That
And what we use is
Our phi is the so-called Lagrange
Input function
If my uki is defined in xk
Then my uk this
Assuming the function
When I put xk in
I can get uki again
Then the second point is the so-called
F to f this assumption function
It's actually still a
That one
Polynomial series
It's just that
Its division will be transferred to
The division of phi
Because fki is a constant
So you can't divide it
So this is f
Then fki will remind you again
It's just f this function
Then bring uki in
So it's not an independent variable
Then phi
Or how much gr
These are actually you can assume
It is unknown because these are
Polynomials defined by yourself
So of course you define it yourself
Of course you can get its derivative
So back to this
Square
We put it all in
You will find that everything is unknown
You are at t this time
U and then f
And then phi
These are all unknown
The only unknown thing is t plus delta t
So today in this method
It's actually like this
You use this method to calculate
How much is t plus delta t
So today you divide the square
There will be a initial value
It's the value of t equals 0
That means you have the value of t equals 0 today
Then your uki is 0
So f at 0
t equals 0
Then you can use this formula to calculate
How much is 0 plus delta t
Then you have you know
Then you bring 0 plus delta t to the right
Then you can get
How much is 2 delta t
Then you step by step like this
In the end you can get
This u function
What is the change in time
That's a simple summary
t equals 0 we have
So we know uki 0 and f 0
How much
Then we use that method
Use some of the methods we haven't mentioned
Calculate f at
The interface of each element is xk
How much is it
Then the third step is
You can use the formula from the last page
Calculate the value of u at t plus delta t
So you can go back
Step 1 and Step 2
Then keep repeating
This is what I just mentioned
The algorithm
It's very simple
So now it's time to say
We just kept saying
We assume that we already have a way
To calculate
We want f at xk
How much
That's why I mentioned
What the hell is this thing
That's what we want
We call it numerical flux
Then we just follow
This kind of thing is in the limited
The limited volume and the Galerkin method
Is a very common concept
Calculate fluid mechanics
The most simple way we use
Calculate numerical flux
Is the so-called rose flux
ROE rose flux
It involves a lot of
It's just some physics
Physics of flow
It's going to get complicated
So I just gave it a formula
Prove that we really have a way
How much is this f
If you are interested in this
You can actually go back and look at some
Some volume has been developed for 30 or 40 years
So how to calculate this
Numerical flux will become
It's actually very, very easy to find
Then we solve f
Then there is f
The most important thing in the method is
How to find gl and gr
Then we mentioned that gl and gr
These two functions must match
These two points
Then the second one is
In fact, gl and gr
Its meaning is
Point to the boundary
We just said that there is a boundary in the formula
Jump
It's equal to
The value we want on the boundary
The difference in value
So this function is theoretically
Only for the boundary
Then it's inside the element
It must be almost non-correct
So we hope this function
It's on the boundary
For example, glx
Its value will be very large
For example, 1
Inside the element
Then
It must be higher than
Its degree must be higher than
The function we assume
Because after you do this
Its degree will be the same
So the first thing I found today
Is the so-called rado polynomial
It looks like this
You put it into this formula
This is the most primitive
gl and gr
There are a lot of gl and gr
You can find it in paper
But I didn't mention it
Because it becomes very mathematical
I just want to tell you
I really found this gl and gr
This is an example
When using different gl and gr
You can see it
The change of the numerical method
Like I said just now
Same
The same linear equation
You use different gl and gr
Will get a completely different accuracy
If you are interested, you can go to paper
Just play
Because this is very mathematical
Just show it to everyone
Let everyone know that this thing exists
I just talked about
There is only one dimension in space
If there are two dimensions in space
If you want to use fr
The current method can only
Divide the two dimensions into two dimensions
The function
Then apply fr
Like I said just now
But this thing is still under study
So you probably only have one or two papers
Have seen
Let me mention it to everyone
This is a difference
Maybe the time is a bit limited
I have talked about it before
The difference is that it is one
One is the default form
One is the strong form
One is the weak form
The time is limited
So let's skip it first
Now let's talk about how to use it
In computational fluid mechanics
If I do it today
If it is compressible flow
In fact, the same method of compressible flow
It is a conservation law
If you apply fr today
There is no problem at all
There will be no contradiction
But if I am incompressible today
Incompressible flow
You will find that the same equation is inside
One of the equations
It lacks the division of time
So it is no longer a conservation law
If you want to use fr today
It will be very difficult
You don't know how to apply
The fr method we just mentioned
Then
Of course, some people today
There will be a way to use
Assuming this incompressible flow
There is a false compressibility
Then we assume that there is a false compressibility
We can use it as a compressible flow
But the question is
What is this false compressibility
It's hard to define
It's very unreasonable
So I don't want to use this method
And
Now the mainstream incompressible flow
All use the so-called
ProjectionStype method
Use this very complicated
To solve
So how should I do today
Bring fr to this
The most popular projectionStype
To solve
It will become a very challenging problem
That's why
I want to do
Is to do
Because
There is no one doing this
Then I want to use fr today
In incompressible flow
The two basic elements I need
I have to solve this
Poisson equation
So it becomes
You have to use implicit method
You have to solve a very big equation
You can't be like just now
t plus delta t
Then step by step
You can't
You can only solve it once
And now a lot of people
They will assume the same
This thing is a state
This Poisson equation is a state
Then step by step
After the value of t goes to infinity
Assume it as
Stable solution
This thing is very inefficient
Because you have a stable solution
You have to go from t equals 0 to t equals infinity
I want you to know that it is very inefficient
So my
For my own plan
I hope I can find a way
To be able to solve
Poisson equation without time
This thing is very simple
You just have to do it
But the problem is
Different gl and different gr
There will be different values
No one studies
How should I choose gl and gr
If you want to solve today
Poisson equation without time
Then there is the second
I hope to be able to
Develop a projection style
That can't be compressed
Solver
The third is that I hope
I can put the solver with
The so-called Immersed Boundary Method
Coupled together
This is my current plan
My research goal
Talk a little bit
Just time
Thank you all
Good
I think it's very good
At least for me
It's a field
I think it's very clear
I think it's too much
And I think the time is very good
It's 17 minutes now
Then
So the other one is your friend
Right
So we're the only ones here
Then I just asked a lot of questions
So
That's it for today's speech
If you have any questions
You can find it on our website
Announcement of today's speech
Then we will be late
Upload the recording of today's speech
If you have any questions
Just click on the speaker's name
Will connect to his
Self-introduction page on our website
Then there will be his contact information
Email or I don't know what you left
Then you can discuss it directly with the speaker
Then we will thank our speaker again
Thank you all
If you have a look on the Internet
That's it for today
I'm going to stop recording