Welcome to this week's Tera Talk. I'm your host, Yu-Wei Lin.
I'm pleased to welcome our speaker today, Louis.
He is currently a Ph.D. student at St. Louis University of Washington.
His main research projects include intellectual property rights, law, anti-Thorax law, and economic analysis.
Before he was a Ph.D. student, he was an intern at Winston & Stone, a law firm in Taiwan and abroad.
He also analyzed the legal behavior of Taiwanese clients and non-independent individuals in the U.S. and East Germany.
Louis is also very interested in entrepreneurship.
He is a member of the China Entrepreneurship and International Exchange Association,
and regularly holds meetings and talks in Taiwan to promote entrepreneurship.
Today's topic is about his background in law and entrepreneurship.
Louis, please turn on your microphone.
Thank you, Yu-Wei, and thank you, Tera, for inviting me.
Last year, I also talked about the topic of streaming, which is the issue of copyright for online streaming videos.
If you are interested, please go to Tera's website and click on the link.
Today's topic is completely different. It has nothing to do with copyright, but is related to patents.
This topic has a little to do with my graduate thesis, but it is not all of my graduate thesis.
Instead, I use different angles to analyze the case study of my graduate thesis.
As you can see on the screen, my graduate thesis was co-written with a friend from Shanghai Fudan University's Administration College.
The main part of my thesis is to study whether the use of bundling in the market,
or the use of bundling in the market, or the use of bundling in the market,
or the use of bundling in the market, and some economic analysis.
The main details of the content will allow me to talk about it for about 30-40 minutes.
It should not be too long, because this is a bit of a background, so I have to talk about it in detail.
I'm just curious about which background friends are coming to listen to my speech today.
I don't know who will respond, so I'll turn off the full screen to see.
There are those with a deep background, welcome.
Then there are those with physics, mechanical.
So none of them are from the Academy of Social Sciences.
Okay, very good. Then I will talk about it in detail.
In fact, the things in the Academy of Social Sciences or the law are not so complicated.
Today we will use some mathematical things, but I will not show you the whole process of deduction.
I think there is no need to show off, just to show you what our results are.
I don't have much to say.
The things I study have some background knowledge that needs to be understood by everyone.
If some of you are interested in this industry or already know it very well, please add it if I say something wrong.
What I want to talk about today is actually related to modern chip.
Modern chip is the so-called communication chip industry.
In fact, I found this Samsung Galaxy S4 on the Internet.
Its structure looks like this.
One of them is modern chip.
What are the benefits of modern chip?
The advantage is that after the modern chip is installed in the mobile phone today,
For example, we all know that the communication standards of 2G, 3G, and 4G will not have so-called problems that cannot be used in different countries.
Just imagine that if you buy an iPhone today, whether it is iPhone 4, iPhone 5, or iPhone 6,
The result may be that your communication standards are different today, or your communication bandwidth is different.
In fact, this is very blind.
How to solve this difference in bandwidth or communication standards?
Modern chip plays a very important role.
Another example is that everyone is in the United States.
I assume that everyone is in the United States.
If you take your mobile phone and go to some remote places, it is not 4G that covers the range, but 3G or even 2G.
But you can still make calls and you can still go online.
It's just that it's very slow.
How is this function done?
In fact, this is the function of modern chip.
It can still operate under different standards and under different levels.
However, its operating function is limited.
This is the function of modern chip.
It can be seen that a mobile phone has a lot of functionality.
But the value of a smart phone is to be online.
Modern chip plays a very important role.
What I want to discuss today is a small communication chip problem.
Let's take a look at the situation of this industry.
This is a total of 1.2 years.
From 2007 to 2012, there were several leading companies in the modern chip industry.
We can probably see that Qualcomm has been playing a leading role in this field.
Qualcomm has been playing a leading role since the 3G in 2007 to the 4G in 2012.
Later, I will show the state of the 5G patent layout.
In fact, Qualcomm has been playing a leading role.
Qualcomm has been playing a leading role since Samsung, Intel, and Huawei.
Huawei has not written here yet.
Huawei started to layout from 4G to 5G.
This is the current state of the industry.
From 2012 to now,
we can see that the green part of the patent layout is high-speed communication.
In fact, in various fields, including radio front, modulation, and core networking,
the patent layout of the modern chip has a very high status.
From these pictures, we can see the current state of the industry.
The inter-digital and blackberry are all gone.
These are all in the past.
The former dragon head is no longer in use.
You can see that there is a lot of high-speed communication in green.
The gray part is Intel, which we will discuss today.
In fact, the patent layout, especially 5G, is not as good as Qualcomm.
So we can simply summarize one thing.
Qualcomm is almost in monopoly in the modern chip industry.
Because most of the chips are sold due to the patent layout and the maintenance of product quality.
So the state of maintenance is very good.
So most of the big manufacturers, including Apple users,
mostly use Qualcomm's modern chip for their important suppliers from iPhone 4, 5, 6, and 7.
But the problem is that these so-called communication standards,
as mentioned above, 2G, 3G, and 4G standards.
Although there are a lot of patent layout behind these standards,
and the negotiation process of each party,
because we always have to decide which standard to use.
It must be of good quality and easy to promote.
I think everyone can understand this.
In fact, there are international standard organizations behind the standard promotion.
So let's go back to the picture just now.
I think this picture is very important in the context of my law school.
Why is it important?
Because it explains the relationship between people of different levels.
Because on my left is IEEE, ITU, and ETSI.
These three are very important to develop 4G and even 5G technical standard organizations.
These technical standard organizations play a role in promoting technical standards.
The core concept is that I want my 4G standard or 5G standard in the future
to be able to be used by many people.
It's not that I only let a group of people use it.
A small group of people using it is not a standard.
So everyone must be able to recognize that this thing is good for them.
It's easy to use and has a high rate of measurement.
The standard of 5G and 4G can be slowly promoted because the industry recognizes it.
But behind it, it involves a lot of different patent layouts.
Because it's impossible for a company to have all the patents of technical standards.
This is impossible.
It must be a segment.
It must be cut into many segments.
Some companies focus on that.
For example, you can see Radio Front End.
Although the patents of Ericsson and Qualcomm are similar,
it also means that there are a lot of things that Qualcomm can't do.
So today I'm going to talk to you about this.
This industry is very dense.
This patent is called SEP.
SEP stands for Standard Essential Patents.
The holders of SEP, such as Ericsson, Qualcomm and Intel,
are considered to be these players.
If people all over the world use this standard,
can they boost the price?
In order to prevent this from happening,
this is one point.
Another point is that it can take advantage of the patent status of the market.
Because patents are legal monopolies.
You can understand it this way.
Most people don't study law.
If you want to ask me how to understand patents,
the way to understand it is very simple.
It is a law that gives you the right to monopolize.
It allows you to have the right to monopolize within a period of time.
For your technology, for your patent.
So it is a limited monopoly.
After these people have patents,
if these patents or technologies are used as standards,
it can increase their price infinitely.
Isn't that against the purpose of these technical standards organizations I just mentioned?
Because the price is too high, no one can use it.
If I want to pay so much, who will think about my rights?
So in this atmosphere, in this concept,
all technical standards organizations in the process of setting standards,
remember that this structural organization in the process of setting standards,
it will require all technical standards organizations,
all SEPs,
you have to provide an LOA.
You have to accept the conditions provided by the technical standards organization.
That is to say, you want to become a 3G standard,
for example, or 3G or 4G or 5G standards in the future.
But your patent price must be within a certain range.
But the condition of this range, we call it FRAMED.
Let me stop for a moment.
Because I really can't see everyone's conversation.
Does anyone have any questions now?
Let's take a look.
It seems that no one has asked me a question.
If you have any questions, you can ask me at any time, it doesn't matter.
If there is no problem, I will continue to speak.
Because I found that there is no social science background,
I have to speak particularly slowly.
The full name of FRAMED is Fair, Reasonable and Non-Discriminatory Licensing.
FRAMED is included in the conditions provided by all technical standards organizations.
This condition actually includes a lot.
If you are interested, you can check it.
One of the most important conditions is that your patent must be used as a standard.
You can use your technology to become my 5G standard.
You can provide your patent and submit your patent application.
But you have to accept FRAMED's restrictions.
Why?
Because, as I said, you can't raise the price too high.
If the price is too high, everyone will not use it.
The other point is the box below.
The box below is the implementer.
What I mean by implementer is, for example, our great HTC.
HTC may have some patents, but it is not a player.
HTC is not the patent holders we just saw in the picture.
HTC is simply a person who is authorized to use the technical standards they have.
Then I use it and I adopt the technology.
We call it implementers.
It is not a person who develops modern chips.
Simply put, HTC is the same as Apple.
Of course, if you pay attention to this industry,
Apple has already released a message that it wants to step in.
It also wants to make its own chips.
If you are interested in the future, you can talk to me.
It's a matter of whether you can do it or not.
In fact, there are still some entry barriers.
First, you have to accept it.
You have to accept it in the SEP holders.
You have to become a technical standard.
You have to accept Friend.
Second, the condition of Friend will not be limited to the relationship between you and the technical standard organization.
It will have a third-party interest.
We call it a third-party interest contract.
The efficiency of these terms will affect the third person.
The meaning of the third person is to include HTC.
HTC is not an SEP holder.
HTC is not an SEP holder, but its efficiency will affect the third person.
So everyone can enjoy the benefits of Friend.
For example, HTC also uses the 3G, 4G, or 5G patents of these technical standard organizations.
You can't say that I'm not in this technical standard organization.
Or I didn't participate in the process of designing this technical standard organization.
So these SEP holders raised my price very high.
No way.
Basically, these SEP holders join the technical standard organization and submit their patents to the technical standard organization as a prerequisite for the 5G standard.
You have to accept these two conditions.
First, the price of your patent must be within a reasonable range.
Second, it will affect the third party.
As long as everyone wants to use this technical standard, everyone can enjoy the benefits of Friend.
I won't give you a discount because you are in a technical standard organization.
No one else will.
But I made a signal here.
My research is in this area.
The source of all problems is here.
It's because of the so-called market monopoly.
Why?
Think about it.
Who are the members of all the technical standard organizations?
Isn't it the so-called industry leaders?
Because who sets the technical standards?
It must be the industry leaders.
If everyone gathers together in these industry leaders to have a meeting,
Taiwanese people may not know much about this law.
It seems that many manufacturers sit in a row together to eat and discuss things.
It seems to be very simple and there is no legal problem.
Let me tell you.
The problem is here.
The problem is that the U.S. Anti-Trust Law and the so-called EU Competition Law strictly prohibit this from occurring.
This prohibition is actually a so-called joint pricing behavior.
The U.S. Anti-Trust Law has many different review standards.
The most taboo thing is the so-called joint pricing.
A bunch of competitors in the same industry.
For example, Ericsson also has a patent.
It is also in the ETSI, ITU, and IEE.
Qualcomm is also a member.
Because they all submit their patents and join their members.
So this group of people are all competitors in the same industry.
All set standards here.
Of course, as a government role, the government will be very worried about this matter.
Are you guys doing something?
Why?
Think from another perspective.
Friend is what we just talked about.
The problem with Friend is that I promised you today.
SEP or not.
I promised you to set the price of Friend.
But this is for everyone.
All SEP holders must require this condition.
What about this technical standard organization?
For example, if I ask for 5%, the price of Friend is 5% for each product.
5% may be too high.
1% is called Friend.
Think about it.
If such a condition appears.
What is the price of Friend?
What is the reasonable and non-discriminatory price?
Everyone can only charge 1%.
In fact, from the perspective of the government, it will feel strange.
Why did you all create this RATE together?
Is there a joint pricing behavior?
So this problem is stuck.
This technical standard organization, I call it SSO.
It's easy for me to say.
SSO will worry.
If everyone is investigating me, everyone is doubting me.
Am I doing joint pricing over there?
Because I said a sentence.
The price of Friend is 1%.
Am I not being investigated all day?
So the problem is here.
Although it is a very important organization.
It made Friend.
It requires everyone to accept Friend.
But it is not responsible for the so-called pricing behavior.
Because of this, what is Friend?
I can report to everyone.
What is Friend?
In the legal circle.
There are many discussions in the paper of the Chamber of Commerce.
Too much.
Because no one really dares to go to court.
It should be said that the court itself or the government unit.
He never dared to respond positively to this matter.
Includes his definition.
He has his calculation method.
But every court in the United States.
Are using different methods of calculation.
Today.
So this thing is actually complicated.
OK.
In fact, I will introduce this kind of background to everyone today.
Because I think this thing needs to be explained to everyone.
Then his background state.
Then I can get into what we are studying.
Because of this, everyone will have the so-called level playing field.
That is, everyone has a rough idea of ​​this matter.
I know what I am studying.
I'm getting into my stuff.
This is easier for everyone to understand.
Before we officially start talking.
Before this fun case.
Let me ask you first.
The simple industry I just introduced.
Or some knowledge background.
Is there any problem with the introduction?
Talk.
5 seconds.
3, 5, 4.
No problem so far.
OK.
No problem, very good.
But if you have any questions, you are welcome.
I also want to train.
Talk to people in the legal field.
See what you think.
OK.
After having such background knowledge.
Then we know that the technical standards have a lot of patents.
OK.
He has to authorize him to be restricted by this regulation.
Then he has a third-party regulation.
So everyone can enjoy the friend.
OK.
Good.
Then there is that we all know that the modern chip is selling.
Usually there are a lot of patents behind.
OK.
So just about summary.
Summary is like this.
The problem is that we all know.
I just mentioned that Qualcomm is an industry leader.
OK.
The quality of the modern chip is very good.
Then he is also Apple's long-term supplier.
OK.
But last year, at the beginning of 2017.
The US Federal Trade Commission FTC.
And Apple itself.
Apple is his downstream manufacturer.
OK.
Then he specifically has a lot of this kind of claim.
That is, he has advocated many things.
What I want to focus on today is that Qualcomm is on the so-called contract.
Playing with everyone in a so-called.
Uh, he uses his position in the market.
And then to achieve his goal of making profits.
So how does he do this?
First of all.
This picture is actually public.
It's not me.
It's not that beautiful.
This picture is when Apple is suing Qualcomm.
He added his.
This content of the prosecution and his analysis of the picture.
That is, how Qualcomm.
How does Qualcomm do it and how does he do it?
Basically, Qualcomm's approach is divided into two stages.
Qualcomm's two-stage behavior is that before Qualcomm officially became Apple's supplier in 2007,
Qualcomm already had a contract with Apple's assembly plant.
If you want to assemble, you will also use Qualcomm's patent.
Because Qualcomm's patent layout is very wide.
In fact, I just gave a simple example.
If you look at it, Qualcomm's patent layout has exceeded the scope of Modern Chip itself.
It contains the entire technical standard.
This is what he said.
I also believe that this is the case.
If you look at Qualcomm, it was established in 1985.
Then continue to develop in the communication chip industry.
Then continue to expand the patent layout of his business.
So in fact, the influence of his business is not just in the Modern Chip itself.
It also contains the entire technical standard.
So Qualcomm has been cooperating with Apple's suppliers.
Because Apple's supplier, for example, I just said Fushkang.
Fushkang is not just an Apple product.
He also does other things, such as HP.
You do other products.
HP's, for example, subscriber.
Qualcomm's patent or technology will also be used.
Also need to do patent authorization.
So it turns out that Qualcomm has been cooperating with Apple's other suppliers.
So why did I mention Apple's supplier?
The complexity is here.
Because Qualcomm did a very interesting thing.
Before he became Apple's supplier.
He told Apple's supplier that I signed a contract with you.
You want to assemble this Apple product.
Then I will collect this patent with you.
But the content of this patent, the scope, the content, the specific details.
How is it NDA?
Non-Disclosure Agreement is not open to the public.
What about other things?
Because this is a bit complicated.
But simply put, Qualcomm and Apple's assembly plant today.
Then do the patent authorization.
These assembly plants can actually come back and ask Apple for reimbursement.
Because the assembly plant feels that there is no need to bear this responsibility anymore.
Because this contract is actually negotiable.
But in the real world, I can report to everyone.
In fact, most of the money in Taiwan's assembly plant.
A lot of money has become Apple to squeeze.
Of course, Apple will say that I did not squeeze them.
Of course, in this case, Qualcomm is.
Qualcomm claims that I have been working with these assembly plants today.
Then I asked them to pay me the rights to these patents.
If you don't want to pay this right, you can go back to Apple.
You don't have to pay this money.
Does Apple pay for you?
But the fun thing is here.
Qualcomm, I just said that Qualcomm is SEP.
In fact, its SEP is a range.
Its range is the so-called Friend.
OK, it is fair and reasonable.
It must be reasonable and non-discriminatory.
But it signed the NDA with these assembly plants.
Then think about it, if you are Apple.
Then there is a chip that I want to use Qualcomm.
As a result, I use Qualcomm chips.
The assembly plant below me has been asking me for money.
Qualcomm and I have received more money.
Then you have to compensate me.
Then how much compensation?
Then how much according to the contract?
Then Qualcomm asked him why it was this price.
Apple asked those assembly plants why it was this price.
As a result, the assembly plant said I can't tell you.
Why? Because Qualcomm said this is NDA.
I can't tell you.
OK, so this is amazing.
The first stage is that Qualcomm went to Apple's assembly plant for a sum of money.
Then the source of this sum of money is NDA.
It is not public.
Then it becomes that Apple can only accept it unilaterally.
Because the account is there.
Qualcomm asked me for so much money.
Then Apple transferred the money to Apple.
Then Apple can only accept it unilaterally.
Apple thinks it's strange.
Is this price reasonable?
But I asked my assembly plant below me.
He can't say.
OK, that's weird.
OK, so Apple actually wants to get rid of this state.
How much did I pay Qualcomm?
I don't know.
I should say that I don't even know my source and my calculation method.
I just kept paying for it.
He thinks it's unreasonable.
It feels like the price is inside.
Managers or lawyers or lawyers feel that this price may be unreasonable.
Qualcomm wants too much money.
He decided to talk to Qualcomm directly.
OK, so this picture is later.
Apple went to talk to Qualcomm.
After he went to talk, Apple said, OK, I can sign a contract with you.
This contract is the gray part below.
It includes BCPA, TA, FTA, SDA, ASDA.
These are all the abbreviations of this contract.
BCPA, for example, is full name is Business Cooperation and Patent Agreement.
TA is Transition Agreement, etc.
Anyway, it's an abbreviation.
In these contracts, Qualcomm and Apple went to talk.
Then Apple felt very uncomfortable.
You're going through my assembly plant in the middle.
I want to talk to you directly.
OK, I'll talk to you directly.
Qualcomm agreed.
After he agreed, he signed these contracts.
But he added some conditions to these contracts.
These conditions are fun.
This is what you see now.
Rebate Agreement and Chipset Supply Agreement.
These two.
It sounds very simple.
In fact, the specific content looks like this.
This is the lawsuit.
This is mentioned in the Apple lawsuit.
Of course, it contains a lot of confidential documents.
I don't know what the confidential thing is.
The main thing is these two.
One is that you have to promise me.
You want me to provide Qualcomm to provide you chips.
The US Federal Trade Commission uses a word called No License, No Chip, No License.
It's the other way around.
Sorry.
It's No License, No Chip.
He said, OK, you want me to supply my high-quality modern chip.
Yes, but you have to accept this price.
Accept this.
You have to accept a certain price for my SEP.
Then he found out inside Apple that the price was a bit higher than the market.
But Qualcomm said, what can you do?
If you don't accept this price.
Then I can't provide you with this modern chip.
So these two are bundled together.
The so-called bundle is to say that I'm going to sell you a modern chip today.
Yes, but you have to accept an Apple.
In fact, this case is still running.
The so-called price is not a friend.
It is possible that everyone in the market public thinks that these SEPs are 1%.
But sorry, I want 5% from you.
The 5% sales price.
But because Qualcomm's quality is good.
Then he is a market leader again.
Then there are a lot of patents.
So Apple has to accept this thing.
Okay, this is the first point.
His so-called no license, no chip.
The policy is that I must accept you.
You have to, you have to, you have to, Apple has to accept his contract terms.
In return, it means that you want me to use his, I use Qualcomm's modern chip.
But I have to accept a higher friend price.
The second point is.
Okay, you want me to supply this, right?
But Qualcomm, in order to make Apple feel that I did not treat you badly.
He provides a rebate from the top.
This rebate is a fixed total price.
That is to say, because you are my customer for a long time.
Use my communication chip.
Then I will give you a return.
Let you continue to use.
But the fun thing is coming again.
Always hurt everyone.
If I, because everyone is not learning law or business, it is in the mall.
All the conditions, all the benefits, or the so-called rebate, this kind of return.
I'll give you a sum of money.
Ah, it's all conditional.
Qualcomm said yes.
Uh, Apple said yes.
Then you give me back.
You give me a return.
But Qualcomm said yes.
I'll give you a return.
But you have to accept the following conditions.
The following conditions are two.
Ah, this condition includes the following.
Chipset Supply Agreement.
What does this condition include?
First, you have to continue to use my communication chip.
You can't jump.
You can't run to use Intel.
You can't run to use.
Ah, Samsung or whatever.
You can't run to use my competitor's chip.
Does this sound reasonable?
OK, it seems like nothing.
OK, what about the second point?
It's just fun.
You can't go to any government unit to investigate me.
Ah, you can't sue me.
You can't issue a patent lawsuit.
You can't use any other government.
You can't start a lawsuit to investigate me.
OK, that's actually controversial.
OK, one is that I provide a return.
Ah, but you have to continue to use my chip.
Ah, this is called the so-called Boundary Bait.
OK, the second is that you want to use.
You want me to provide a return.
You can, no problem.
But you can't sue me.
OK, so there are two points.
One is that I let you not investigate me.
It completely locks you up.
OK, the other point is that you can't jump.
You can't jump to another place.
And then you can't.
You can't sue me.
So this makes Apple very upset.
Because he thinks I can't use other people's.
Ah, I can't use other people's chips.
And then you use the so-called No License No Chip in front of me.
And then the price is so high.
OK, the price is so high.
And then you don't let me start a lawsuit.
And then I don't know what the hell you're doing.
And then you're the market monopoly.
And then the whole thing comes together.
Ah, that's just the whole case.
The whole thing comes together.
Just let Apple jump.
And, uh, it triggered a lot of, uh, the EU.
And that China, Taiwan, Taiwan.
Maybe you've heard of it.
He's also investigating this.
And then the United States.
And then the U.S. Federal Trade Commission is investigating this whole thing.
What is his legitimacy?
OK, so what we're talking about in this paper is.
Say, uh, one thing we want to study is.
What is the reason behind what Qualcomm is doing?
Why does Qualcomm want to provide?
Uh, this is the return to Apple.
Because you can think about it.
If Qualcomm's quality is so good.
Right?
Good quality.
Ah, it's the market monopoly again.
Why does he provide a return to Apple?
Right?
Because I'm lying down.
I'm lying down and Apple's coming.
You can think about it.
That's the question.
I think it's interesting.
If you're a market monopoly.
And then basically everyone's products.
Almost all of them will use my modern chip.
And then.
And then my quality.
People can't catch up with me.
For example, he mentioned Intel in it.
Intel doesn't matter to him at all.
He can't catch up with me at all.
Ah, there's a very high entry barrier.
You might.
I don't know if you've learned this.
I personally think he's on the entry barrier.
It's pretty high.
The cost of this investment is very high.
Ah, so.
This question has always been this question.
It becomes the core of our paper.
That is, if Qualcomm.
He's in a position that's close to a market monopoly.
Or he's in a market leadership position.
And then?
The layout of the patent is so wide.
OK, and then the quality of the product is also very good.
So why did he provide this rebate to Apple?
Ah, that's what he did in the real world.
And provide this rebate.
This one.
I'm going to tell you about this contract.
This deadline.
It's not even a year or two.
It's three to five years.
During the period.
So, in fact, he continues to provide this rebate.
And then.
Provide such a return to this Apple.
And then the two requirements are that you have to continue to use it.
And then you can't investigate me.
And then.
Uh, you have to.
And then you have to accept my friend.
You have to accept me.
This seems to be similar.
This is not the price of the friend.
In fact, even the price of the friend is controversial.
I'm not going to.
Uh, not in today's.
Within the scope of the report.
Because.
Because you say everything.
Apple says you're not a friend.
Qualcomm says I'm a friend.
Because I include the whole.
This is the patent I authorize you to give.
It's all about this.
This know-how.
And this.
The so-called technical standards.
Of course.
The price is so high.
It's reasonable.
So, of course, it's not reasonable.
This is.
Uh, the industry's problem.
So, today.
The problem is on this rebate.
So, today, I'm going to tell you a little bit about it.
That is to say.
The point I focused on today.
It's also this paper.
Me and that.
The focus of the study with the classmate is.
Why Qualcomm, he will.
So insistent on providing rebate.
This thing.
OK.
Okay.
Uh.
I'll pause it again.
See if you have any understanding of this case.
Hey.
Do you understand the story I just told you?
Because I don't know if you understand this story.
Content.
Hello.
Do you understand?
This story.
OK.
All right.
I think if I didn't listen.
Uh, listen.
Does anyone not understand?
That's what I should say.
I don't understand which link.
OK.
If you don't understand.
Can you tell me which link you don't understand?
Because he's a little bit complicated about this thing.
Because I.
Uh.
This thing involves my graduation thesis.
So, he.
Some small and complex.
Some of the details of the industry's content.
Let's see if you have any.
Which side I just said a little bit.
I don't understand.
Is there?
Good.
54321.
Just pretend.
Just pretend you understand.
Good.
OK.
No one.
There is a response.
OK.
Just pretend to understand.
Good.
On the basis of this posture.
We know.
The love-hate relationship between Apple and Qualcomm.
It's just like this.
It was sued like this last year.
That.
This.
For me.
At the beginning of this paper.
First.
Uh.
He is a.
The cross-section is a cross-domain.
But the cooperation paper is like this.
What I'm in charge of is the legal analysis.
Then my partner is.
Responsible for the study.
Game theory model.
The introduction.
And then.
And from a commercial perspective.
And.
Uh.
Economic perspective.
To analyze this whole thing.
The first is.
Everyone is already curious.
But from my point of view.
Is there a similar case in the past?
Or in this kind of debate.
The case.
How did they judge?
Or what is the result of their judgment?
Then I will report to you.
Just.
Simply put.
It's this thing.
This problem.
Even the court itself.
It's hard to get it done.
OK.
That.
Uh.
The picture.
What you see on the screen.
The red part.
Uh.
Represents.
The court is.
Uh.
The red part right.
The page.
These.
This red case is the court.
Sentence.
The defendant is like.
Uh.
This kind of company like Gaotong is illegal.
OK.
The black part is that I don't have a label.
I don't.
These cases in the black part.
Is.
The court believes.
Legally.
It's like this.
It's called.
You have to accept this.
If you want to use.
As if Gaotong.
The state of Gaotong I just talked about.
Is that if you want to use.
Use my.
Things you want.
Uh.
Become my supplier.
Can.
Uh.
Or I'm going to supply you with good stuff.
But you have to accept my conditions.
Or I.
Uh.
You can buy it.
But I.
You have to buy a certain amount.
Okay.
After buying a certain amount.
I'll give you a rebate.
It's a concept like this.
It's like this.
A transaction mode like this.
That's it.
These six cases.
I sorted it out.
That's because everyone is not legal.
OK.
That.
I won't say it one by one.
Ah.
That's actually the result.
His.
The result is analyzed.
The reason is also analyzed.
That.
Three red dots are.
These are the different courts.
For.
These cases.
The reason for the use.
So, as you can see.
A very special phenomenon is.
Hey.
On the subject of this rebate.
Or say this kind of bundle rebate.
Different courts have different reasons.
OK.
Also different results.
That.
I'll talk about it later.
That is, Qualcomm actually used this point.
Ah.
It's not a use.
That is to say, he should.
Maybe he saw this point.
We infer.
He saw this point.
It may also become his.
This.
To continue to use.
His bundle rebate.
To Apple.
OK.
This is a.
Our inference.
I'll mention it later.
This is my preliminary investigation.
Found that.
Ah.
If the defendant.
The black one.
The red case is illegal.
The black case is legal.
Then I'll see.
That red case.
What is illegal?
Common features.
The first.
Those illegal cases.
The red part.
I just showed you.
These defendants.
In fact, all.
Ah.
Have some.
Market monopoly.
So.
If you are a.
Market monopoly.
Easy.
If you are a monopolist.
It may be easy to violate.
Antitrust law.
Ah.
This is in our.
If you learn this in our law school.
Antitrust law.
Basically, this.
This.
This is a high probability.
If you have this market.
If the monopoly is basically easy.
This antitrust law.
This is.
Ah.
This is normal.
OK.
Then in this bundle.
In the context of the rebate.
It is also.
It's not an exception.
But we have seen.
The second point is very interesting.
We see the legal.
We compare these legal cases.
Ah.
It's the black one.
In those cases.
We found that.
The defendant is actually still possible.
Is legal.
Why?
Because imagine.
Today.
He's in front of him.
Uh.
That's what I just said.
In these black cases.
He has some.
Ah.
These judges.
Why?
In the same situation.
I think they are legal.
Because they don't have it at all.
Eliminate the effect.
OK.
In general.
Let's make it simple.
Is.
Anti-tax law is actually in the regulation.
Is a law of corporate behavior.
OK.
It is the law of market economy and corporate behavior.
So.
That.
The market economy must maintain a competitive attitude.
Instead of letting a person.
Independent or say.
Present a state of monopoly.
But imagine.
If he was originally today.
Although he is a.
Through.
Uh.
His sales behavior.
And then his innovative business model.
Achieve his.
The leadership position of the market.
But it's not monopoly.
Leadership position.
Then he wants to continue.
The.
When increasing his market share.
He might let.
Some other competitors.
Uh.
Some may have progress barriers.
Or what is the situation.
His elimination effect.
He might make some.
For example, killing competition or something.
His.
He might let some other competitors.
He can't come in.
Or potential competitors.
For example, like I just mentioned.
Intel.
Intel in the so-called.
This.
Computer CPU.
Everyone should know.
It's all done very well.
Ah.
This kind of patent.
The patent series are all very strong.
And then with this Microsoft.
In the late 90s.
It's almost.
This is.
It's almost all computers.
But.
He's in that communication chip.
He just can't stand still.
He just doesn't have the so-called.
This status.
That today.
Uh.
He's coming in today.
But in fact.
He's coming in.
He just needs to invest enough money.
In fact.
In fact, he is also doing it.
Just keep doing bad.
OK.
But it's not that he can't do it.
Ah.
There's a difference.
That is to say.
Let me talk about it again.
There's a difference.
It's the so-called can't do it.
That is to say, I.
I took advantage of some commercial behavior.
For example, I.
I join all the people.
I don't provide you with the material.
You can't do it.
But this doesn't work.
Ah.
This must be against.
This antitrust law.
Because this is against this.
This market competition.
The situation.
So now the situation is.
Hey.
We.
Observe the previous few black cases.
We found that.
Why are those cases legal?
Because of those potential intruders.
He wasn't excluded.
Enter this market.
He can still enter this market.
Competition.
It means that his entry barrier is low.
If the entry barrier is low.
The court sees that the entry barrier is low.
That's just to say.
You might come in today.
It's just that you chose not to come in.
Or you.
Maybe you have other commercial considerations.
Instead of coming in.
So.
Before this.
Before.
Let me go back again.
Why are these black cases from before legal?
Why are these Bando Rebellion legal?
Because.
Other competitors.
He.
It is not excluded.
It still came in.
It still joined this industry.
Continuing with.
These defendants are in competition.
Let's say the defendant is Gaoton.
It is still.
Still come in this industry to compete.
That's like what we're talking about today.
The case of Gaotong is not the only one.
Provide a modern chip.
Samsung also has.
Huawei also has.
OK, so it becomes.
It's me.
To provide a chip.
So.
Look at my phone.
You see.
I have a mobile phone.
I'm on his mobile phone.
So.
It becomes.
In this case.
In fact, there is a bit of a swing.
If you listen to me.
You know what I mean.
Although Gaotong.
He is in this market.
Based on monopoly status.
Based on this leadership status.
Then maybe.
There are some monopolies in sales.
Power.
Because his product quality is good.
But.
Other people are still in it.
Right.
Other players are also in it.
Other manufacturers are also in it.
So.
If you follow this.
The logic of the black case.
Then he might be illegal.
But according to the logic of the black case.
OK.
So on this matter.
In fact.
why.
Let me tell you.
Why Taiwan.
I personally think.
Can't judge Gaotong so soon.
Illegal.
The reason is actually here.
I'll share it with you.
I don't know if it's good to say that.
But I personally think.
It is worth thinking about.
OK.
Every country has probably different.
But I personally think.
Whether Gaotong is really illegal.
Then you are like this.
A.
A law is going on.
Will you be influenced.
Other manufacturers are against this matter.
I think there are casualties.
OK.
Since there are so many people in this business.
Since there are so many people in this industry.
Why is he being punished?
You have to give a fair reason.
The United States is a public debate country.
So this thing no longer judged.
So that's it for now.
So.
The conclusion of this paper.
Is here, in this study.
And then there's a question in the paper.
That is the question in the paper.
The question is about why bottled readers continue to act on it.
Regardless of this green act.
Regardless of this red act which has already fallen.
Regardless of this green act which has already fallen.
After the model reads off,
we see some things in the model that we are spurred on.
We see some things in the model that we are spurred on.
Then we bring some possibilities of what the model might have in behind.
This is the case this model is one of the things.
And then from the business perspective.
and a law perspective
This is the case this model is one of the things.
Watching these things.
Then this is what we're doing.
One of the steps for how this paper answers the question.
One of the steps for how this paper answer the question.
Do you have any thoughts or questions?
Yes.
MRI is not in the scope of modem.
No blueprint is in the appraiser system
and has the blueprint design in a presupedit
and has the blueprint design in a prespedit
This is a bit complicated,
I believe if you're in engineering school,
the math will be better than mine.
I just briefly talk about math
The story that we just heard
After hearing our story,
let's talk about assuming these mathematical models.
Let's talk about assuming these mathematical models.
First, for the game in the promotion theory,
we have three different games we play,
One is One Stage Game
is divided into the Exhaustive and Non-exhaustive.
OK
About Exhaustive, let me explain to you.
Just like the FRIEND I mentioned just now,
there is a so-called price issue.
Then why is there a FRIEND
What do you think is reasonable?
What do I think is unreasonable?
In fact, one of them is the amount
and the scope of authorization.
Apple thinks that
you sell me ModernChip today.
OK, you provide me with ModernChip.
The price of the sales
should include the price of the patent.
OK, this is a bit tricky.
Let me say it again.
Apple will think that
you provide me with ModernChip today.
OK, this is a price.
Let's say it's $100.
But it's not that cheap, $100.
OK, maybe this $100
already includes the price of the patent.
OK, so when you sell it to me,
there is a basic concept in the patent law.
I simply emphasize this.
You don't have to go into detail.
There is a concept in the patent law.
Once my patent is included in my product,
it will be sold together.
If this thing is bought by someone else,
for example, I have already paid once for Apple.
Do I have to pay again?
No.
Because Apple has already paid once.
It has already sold me the patent.
It has already sold me the price of ModernChip.
So why do I have to pay again?
Right?
Of course not.
So of course the core concept is
The core concept of Exaustive is that
there will be such a dispute because
Apple thinks that when Qualcomm provides ModernChip to me,
it already includes the price of all patents.
You shouldn't add another patent price
and raise it so high.
OK.
Qualcomm, of course, thinks no.
I authorize you
or I sell you ModernChip.
The patent I include is only a small part of my patent combination.
There are many patents.
You didn't use it.
So you have to pay extra.
Everyone should understand this.
Why do we design Exaustive and Non-Exaustive?
The reason is here.
Because this involves the business itself.
Now in this industry,
some of its game rules are played like this.
Right?
Because I originally supplied ModernChip to you.
It should include all prices,
including patent prices.
This is Apple's idea.
But Qualcomm doesn't think so.
Qualcomm thinks that I only give you a part.
There are many things you don't know.
So you have to pay more.
This is why I just said
Qualcomm's so-called No License, No Chip is reasonable.
Why does it dare to talk about this condition?
Because it dares to say
even if I supply ModernChip to you today,
I still have other patents that you haven't used.
So you have to pay more.
Otherwise, it's gone.
OK.
This is the so-called One Stage Non-Exhaustive.
Non-exhaustive is like a game.
Exhaustive contract game
is based on Apple's point of view.
Non-exhaustive is based on Qualcomm's point of view.
And then we go to the two-stage game.
This is interesting.
We go to the two-stage step
to run this model,
this Game Theory model.
In Exhaustive Game,
as we just mentioned,
that is to say,
because Apple thinks
you give me ModernChip,
it includes all patents.
OK.
Because it includes all patents.
So
the way it calculates
is the percentage of each chip.
That's it.
Non-exhaustive,
that may be because Qualcomm thinks
the patents in ModernChip are just a part of me.
OK.
So I have many other patents
that haven't been given to you yet.
So the money I added
is for the whole technology.
This is what Qualcomm said.
Qualcomm is very ambitious.
He said that my patent
laid out all the technical standards.
So what does he think?
What does he think Apple has to pay for?
The basis for Apple to pay for money
is the entire market value,
the value of the entire market,
not just the chip.
OK.
So this model
is based on the price.
The basic foundation of the price calculation method
is different.
OK.
In this exhaustive,
Apple's point of view
is that the price of patents
is calculated according to the percentage of each chip I sell.
But Qualcomm thinks it's wrong.
It should be calculated at the price of the entire market.
OK.
This is the calculation price of our two different games.
The price of the patent is different.
What about the two-stage game?
Intel,
we assume that
because Intel is a...
Although we just mentioned that
Intel is not a very good player
in the modern chip industry.
But it was mentioned in Qualcomm's petition.
It's a funny point.
Qualcomm's petition said
I don't know if you remember
that in 2016 or 2017,
in 2015, 2016, and 2017,
I forgot which year the iPhone 7 was launched.
OK.
In the past few years,
Apple has done so-called recycling in the iPhone 7.
They took the machine back.
One of the reasons is that there are some
problems with the quality of communication.
Then it is said that
this is what Qualcomm wrote in his petition.
It is said that
it is because Apple violated the contract.
It violated the contract.
It went to Intel
to use Intel's modern chip.
As a result, Intel's quality was not as good as Qualcomm's.
So it led to some of these mobile phones,
not all of them,
some of the mobile phones with Intel's
modern chip
had poor quality of communication.
It was bad.
Then it caused some customers to be unhappy.
So it was required to withdraw.
It was really withdrawn.
OK.
So under such a fact,
let's assume that
in the future, is it possible for Intel to
change its modern chip quality?
Assuming that Intel,
we assume that
this is an assumption.
Assuming that Intel
at a certain point in the future,
its product quality
becomes very close to Qualcomm.
OK.
Then how will this game play?
What will happen in the market?
Will Apple accept
this bundle rebate we just talked about?
And Qualcomm,
our most important role,
does it have a reason to provide this rebate?
OK.
This is our basic game.
Then,
this
mathematical model,
in fact, we have a few assumptions.
In fact, they are all based on the story we just heard.
So in fact,
they are all quite intuitive.
OK.
First, we assume that Qualcomm is a
very
high-quality in the market.
Provided to
and higher than Intel
in the first stage.
Everyone should be able to understand this.
OK.
And it has been like this in recent years.
And these manufacturers,
that is, Apple,
Apple and Qualcomm,
are actually a
measurement standard for their companies.
That is to say,
I want to get the maximum profit.
I think everyone should be able to understand this.
OK.
Third,
that is to say,
the game we play is a bit like
Apple is a follower.
Because Apple does not produce the so-called modern chip,
it does not make the modern chip.
OK.
So it's a bit like
this game is
the first Qualcomm,
it provides a contract
clause,
which includes the bundle rebate.
OK.
Then Apple only has two options,
accept or not.
That's it.
OK.
So the game we play is like this.
Apple accepts or not.
OK.
If you accept it,
for Qualcomm,
what is its profit?
Then what is Apple's profit?
If you don't accept it,
how does Qualcomm's profit change?
How does Apple's profit change?
OK.
So we use this pie
to denote the entire profit.
Then A, Q, and I are these players.
OK.
A is Apple,
Q is Qualcomm,
and I is Intel.
OK.
Then a few numbers.
In fact,
I will simply report to you.
It's a bit boring here.
OK.
That's just an assumption for everyone.
Then this is Q.
Q is this.
Qualcomm's quality.
Uh, yes.
Qualcomm's
Qualcomm chip quality.
Then CQ like this.
You can just look at it like this.
In fact,
the main thing is to explain to you that
we set these functions.
Then it also includes its demand function.
Demand function,
then its value,
that is to say,
we don't want it to be low.
You can know that
the demand function we set here
is D equals A minus BP plus Gamma Q.
OK.
Then we have to let this
A must be greater than or equal to zero.
OK.
So it's actually its demand function.
Then its price and quality.
OK.
Then I set it to avoid this model.
It's complicated.
We must be greater than or equal to D.
So A must be greater than or equal to the thing behind it.
It must be A.
Because A minus the back.
OK.
A, we set a market size here.
Then you can think about it.
Just be intuitive.
That is to say,
if A is the market size.
Because you have three players today.
So your market size must be greater than the two behind it.
Apple and Qualcomm.
Apple and Intel.
And Qualcomm and Intel.
The whole market share.
The market share.
And then what.
OK.
So simply put,
that is to say,
we set D to be greater than or equal to zero.
Simply put, that's it.
OK.
So you see,
so that's Maxima.
And then BCQ.
And then minus Gamma.
And then this BC1 minus Q1.
So the front is Qualcomm.
The back is Intel.
OK.
So it must be greater than this.
And then we set this contract.
OK.
Then WQ, we set it to be a cheap price.
Then Alpha, we set it to be a royalty percentage.
What's fun about us is that Alpha,
it's set to this.
Uh, we just said it was the condition of the front.
So it has an interval,
which means it's between 0 and 1.
OK.
So W is his cheap side.
I think this is basically what it is.
So we just denote.
OK.
So we just,
you might also mention,
that is to say,
what is that rebate?
We will provide a rebate.
That rebate is to provide a Gamma.
Because it's a rebate.
Why is it so fast to choose this Gamma?
Because it's from,
it's a fixed amount.
That is to say,
it's from the whole sale,
from this WQ or WI.
WQ is this Qualcomm chip.
WI is Intel's chip.
Because it's from this whole chip,
the total sales,
to be deducted.
So,
this is also in line with the reality.
Because the reality of this rebate,
uh,
the situation is also from this overall sales number,
and then the total,
and then to,
to provide you,
and then deduct a number.
Then this number is deducted from the total.
So we just set it to Gamma.
OK.
Uh,
it should be R.
R.
OK.
Set it to R,
like this.
OK.
So,
uh,
this is my good friend,
my other partner's conclusion.
Then I'll just show you,
appreciate the beauty of this math.
Because I really can't do this.
OK.
So,
actually, I'll tell you about it.
The result of our run.
OK.
Let's stop for a moment.
I think there should be no problem here.
I think everyone should,
I hope everyone is still awake.
OK.
It's just a mathematical model.
That's it.
The main thing is to know how to play our game.
I think everyone knows,
that is,
how our Game Theory model is set.
OK.
I think there should be no problem.
No problem.
Ah,
I don't understand Game Theory at all.
Crying.
Actually,
no,
Game Theory is,
you know,
everyone actually understands Game Theory.
Don't be too complicated.
Game Theory is actually a math.
So you can actually see it.
In fact,
it's actually a,
uh,
application of math.
OK.
So,
in fact,
it's not that much.
I think it's quite intuitive.
But I just,
that is to say,
I think,
I hope I can make it clear to everyone.
Because,
to be honest,
because of this PowerPoint,
I have to tell other people in the legal department.
The other people in the legal department,
they are completely less sensitive to math.
So I have to make it extremely simple.
OK.
If everyone,
if it's a little difficult to listen to,
maybe I have to review it.
OK.
Simply put,
how to play this game?
In fact,
anyway,
it's Qualcomm.
I provide a contract.
OK.
Provide this contract.
Then it has a rebate based on a certain price.
And then this rebate,
sorry,
this rebate is a fixed amount.
Like this,
and then this amount,
and then see if Apple wants to accept it.
Like this,
and then we look at the response of Intel.
Let's look at the response of Apple.
And then their profit maximization.
And then what is the two-stage?
Two-stage is good.
Assuming that Intel is at a certain time point in the future.
Its quality has risen to the same as Qualcomm.
Okay,
so let's look at that.
Today,
Apple provides this rebate.
What is the change in its profit?
What is the change in profit?
What is the change in Apple's profit?
What is the impact of Intel on this whole thing?
OK,
so the simple game is like this.
OK.
Okay,
so what?
In fact,
the result we came up with at the end was that we found that it was fun.
It's one-stage game.
It's the so-called one-stage game.
I just said that Qualcomm provides this bundle rebate.
Okay,
Apple accepts it or not.
That's it.
And then he set his quality to be much higher than Intel.
Simply put,
that's it.
Okay,
so you'll find that Qualcomm is actually intuitive.
It's actually very easy to look at.
Why?
Just like I just said,
Qualcomm is a market monopoly.
No one has a better quality than him.
Why does he provide rebate?
It doesn't make sense.
Why?
Because he doesn't allow it at all.
Because what does it mean to provide rebate?
It means that he can't maximize the profit.
Right?
He provides an amount to Apple.
What is he doing?
Right?
Because I don't provide it anyway.
Apple has to pay for it.
Yeah,
so Apple has to pay for it.
So why do I provide rebate to Apple?
I just maximize the profit.
So at the first stage,
the results of the model we made showed that
this is not necessary.
Boundary rebate is not necessary.
Okay,
so non-exhaustive actually didn't change much.
That's just because of this.
Because Alpha is still in this range.
So Alpha,
I just said,
it's the range of this Royalty.
It hasn't changed.
Okay,
so no matter what you do today,
this Alpha,
you calculate the entire market value.
It's the entire market value.
It's still just modern chip.
It doesn't actually affect high-speed communication.
Why?
High-speed communication still feels like I'm a market monopoly.
Why do I provide a rebate?
And then it affects my profit maximization.
So one stage,
and then non-exhaustive game is the same.
It's from a high-speed point of view.
He doesn't need to provide rebate to Apple at all.
But it's fun.
That's the third one.
We found that from two-stage game,
we found that Intel's quality has risen.
Okay,
but he's starting to have conditions.
That is to say,
it was not necessary before.
Then we went to two-stage game.
We found that this quality.
This quality,
when Intel's quality is close to high-speed communication,
we found that,
hey,
high-speed communication to some extent,
he has to provide rebate to Apple.
Oh,
okay,
that's it.
This is the red line.
This is the condition that we came up with mathematically.
That's the MQ.
That's bigger than this.
Okay,
so we found that the appearance of mathematics.
That is to say,
he has a condition that he has to provide rebate to Apple.
Otherwise,
he can't maximize the profit.
Okay,
that's the problem.
Why is there a condition?
Okay,
what about the business behind this condition?
What is the commercial consideration?
Okay,
so we thought about it.
We thought about it a lot.
Okay,
then we will find that,
the first.
In the two-stage game,
we found that,
if we assume that this cost of Intel,
uh,
not the cost,
wrong,
this quality,
the quality of modern chip is very close to high-speed communication.
If he is very close,
it means that Apple's,
this one plus one is high.
Apple's one plus one is high for high-speed communication.
This should be easy for everyone to think about.
Because why?
Because Apple has a choice.
I said I would choose Intel.
If you still provide that price,
I don't need your modern chip.
So in this case,
if everyone's quality is very close,
there will be a so-called price war.
I think this should be easier for everyone to understand.
When the price war occurs,
it will cause profit loss.
So in this inference,
we,
we boldly infer that,
why is there this red condition in front of it?
Why is this rebate produced?
This R is produced.
Why is there such a change in the two-stage game?
Because the one-stage does not need it in the front.
Why do you want two-stage?
The reason is because we infer that,
high-speed communication,
because of the game,
he has an assumption in this game.
Because of this,
we haven't learned the game theory.
So I'll put it simply.
This game theory,
he has a lot of,
he has an assumption.
The premise is that both sides are actually in the case of knowledge or full knowledge.
For market information,
and for this information of both sides,
it is a full-knowledge situation.
OK.
The so-called information includes the so-called patent information,
including price information,
including the case.
These are all full-knowledge.
Apple, Qualcomm, Intel all know.
OK.
In such a full-knowledge situation,
Apple, he may be,
not Apple,
Qualcomm, he may be able to predict that,
in the future, if,
and in real society,
I just mentioned that,
that Apple is really careless,
or whether it is careless,
or deliberately,
jump the bridge,
secretly use Intel's modern chip,
but the effect is not good.
Well, just based on this fact,
will there be a doubt?
That is to say,
Hey, Qualcomm will worry that,
if Intel's modern chip quality rises,
will it threaten my market,
market leadership?
It is possible.
If it really threatens,
then it will produce our previous,
this mathematical model,
will it produce such a result?
Right?
If it produces such a result,
isn't it just to say,
you can think about it.
Then,
why did he,
at the beginning,
regardless of his state,
regardless of other people's state,
regardless of Intel's state,
I will propose a rebate first.
What is the reason?
Because he is worried that,
in the future,
if anyone comes in,
Intel is just one of them,
we think of the object,
it may be Samsung,
it may be Huawei,
or others,
or Ericsson,
no matter.
These potential investors,
if his,
the quality of this modern chip has risen,
then it is possible to produce a price war.
If in our model,
the situation is like this.
Then, in order to avoid this,
the loss of the price war,
then I might as well,
at one stage,
at the beginning,
I will receive this rebate from Apple.
In case,
I am a bit like receiving a security fee,
I am in case,
in the future,
if there is a price war,
at least,
this,
the loss of this profit,
I can make up for it from the previous rebate.
OK, I provide such a rebate,
I provide such a rebate to Apple,
in the future,
Apple will continue to use it,
right?
Because I provide such a rebate,
everyone,
although Apple is very happy,
is to get one more money,
but Qualcomm has a little loss,
but there is no difference,
why?
My loss today,
I am better than the future big loss.
If I have a little loss today,
but in the future,
if you today,
suppose we don't say that we can't breach the contract,
this is because Apple's private breach,
this is not good.
Tell everyone that private breach is not good.
If Qualcomm,
if Apple does not violate the contract,
it will continue to use Qualcomm chips in the future,
otherwise it will violate the contract,
right?
In order to allow this thing to continue to occur,
I will continue to provide rebate to you,
I provide a little loss to Qualcomm,
but I can always guard your Apple,
I don't want Apple to jump to Intel.
At least in the future,
this price war will not occur,
right?
So its logic,
the overall logic is like this,
because price war will occur in the future.
In order to avoid
such a high price war for Apple,
I might as well be in the first stage,
when I was in the first stage of the game,
I would lock you to death,
I would use Bundle Rebate,
I provide this Bundle Rebate Contract to force you to accept,
what are the conditions to accept?
I just mentioned that you can't jump to Intel,
then you can't sue me,
you can't jump to Intel,
these two conditions,
then you have to pay me such a high power,
Apple also has a loss,
in fact, the mathematical model just said,
that is, it actually has to deduct one,
that is, you have to deduct that Alpha,
the profit of Apple has to deduct that Alpha,
OK, then the profit of Qualcomm has to be added to Alpha,
because that is the Friend Royalty,
then my Friend Royalty,
if I charge a higher price,
conversely,
first, I charge a higher price,
I can make up for the future loss,
second, Qualcomm can also lock your Apple customers,
so the whole model's implication,
the core essence is here,
so to put it simply,
the essence of this model is here,
but it's not enough to say that,
this is just a business perspective,
what other reasons do we think that
Qualcomm can dare to keep doing this Boundary Bait?
Back to the legal point of view,
we just talked about this business point of view,
it is to avoid future losses,
so I have Boundary Bait here,
I lock Apple,
then collect a very high Friend rate,
OK, a little higher,
I don't know how high it is,
a little higher rate,
then lock you,
then for the future loss,
what about the law?
In fact, it will be found that the fact,
the fact of this case,
that is, the fact of Qualcomm,
in fact, with the previous six cases,
I will report the conclusion to everyone,
because I will not talk about the process,
the conclusion is that
Qualcomm's case
is different from the previous six cases,
OK, they are all different,
if everyone has some basic common sense
about American law,
different facts can not be used,
different facts will be compared,
compared later found that it is not to be used,
so that six cases,
regardless of whether you are legal or illegal,
can not be used in this case,
OK, this is a point,
the second split reasoning create possibility,
I just said that
there are red and black,
there are legal and illegal,
OK, Qualcomm sees this situation,
the court itself has been arguing for a long time,
you do not know at all,
you do not know whether it is legal or illegal,
the legal probability is 50%,
the illegal probability is also 50%,
but for business people,
everyone thinks that
whether I rush or not,
of course, rush,
right,
of course, I care about him,
anyway, there is a 50% chance that I will win,
right,
so then plus the previous few cases,
the facts are different from me,
then I have to rush,
because those cases
may not have anything to do with me,
OK, so these facts are different,
including the disagreement between the courts,
resulting in my personal opinion,
from the point of view of the law,
Qualcomm,
these situations also increased
Qualcomm will continue to execute
the right-hand man of Fund Rebate,
from the business,
he said that in order to make up
or to prevent future losses,
to the law,
he is not in line with the past cases,
OK,
then the reason is not sufficient,
nor is it consistent,
so that he has such a
legal right-hand man,
although there is a legal risk,
but this risk to him,
he thinks he can control,
so we found that
this problem
is that there is a business reason,
there is a legal reason,
OK,
business is that I have to prepare for the future,
for the future,
the legal reason is that
those six cases,
whether legal or illegal,
have nothing to do with him,
because this is my brand new Fund Rebate,
OK,
then the different point is that
the first six cases are all
the combination of products and products,
what is my product,
what is the combination of patents,
the first one has nothing to do with me,
so based on the business and legal reasons,
they all give me a very strong right-hand man,
let me continue to execute Fund Rebate,
even if he may also have a very high
risk of anti-Thoracic,
OK,
so this paper is actually basically here,
of course, when I concluded,
my paper,
when we concluded this paper,
I also mentioned one point,
that is,
in the end,
this case,
because this case,
if you are interested,
you can check it,
it is still in progress in the United States,
there is no conclusion,
that is,
this question is actually my graduation,
the real question of the graduation paper,
OK,
if you are interested,
you can talk to me in private,
because my graduation paper is from a different point of view,
then my graduation paper point of view is this question,
that is,
the court as such a role,
if he is judged to be legal,
his influence on Apple,
what is his influence on the public,
and if it is illegal,
right?
Then I just mentioned that
he is a
law of the jungle,
he may accidentally go the wrong way,
it may affect a lot of people,
yes,
if he is
very bold in the court,
what is his influence on the public
when he is judged to be illegal?
This is the future study,
that is,
including my paper,
I am also doing this thing,
then this paper is the last stop here,
that is,
if you are interested,
you are welcome to join in
and do this kind of research.
OK,
so
today my
sharing
is about to end here,
then
ah,
OK,
someone asked in the middle of the round,
so
my sharing is about to end here,
then
do I have to answer the question first?
Or
let us
applaud and thank Louis for today's
in-depth sharing,
thank you,
do you understand?
Everyone should understand, right?
I don't know what everyone's question is,
I'm very worried,
I think I want to talk about it,
you are very lucky,
because this is my first time talking,
it should not be the first time,
it seems a bit too much to say like this,
my first time sharing something related to my graduate thesis,
yes,
the question,
do I have to answer the question first?
Or how?
Louis,
let me stop recording first,
then we can start to answer the question,
OK,
no problem,