Yes, Project Terra is an international platform for sharing information.
We hope that scholars from all over the world can share with us
the results of our current research and development,
and more importantly, what is the trend of development.
This is not something you can easily find in Taiwan.
Project Terra can also provide people who are doing research
with opportunities to exchange and collaborate.
So we hold a seminar like this every week.
The speakers are basically all members,
and they will share their new ideas and research trends.
Project Terra is a self-releasing organization
that is dedicated to public service.
We have no intention of making any profit.
All of our members are very enthusiastic doctoral students and post-doctoral students.
You can see our website.
If you are interested in Project Terra,
you can take a look at our website.
and would like to keep in touch with us,
you can join our membership.
If you can find other people to work with,
we will be happy to help you.
If you have any questions,
you can ask us directly.
We are usually very free to talk.
Sure, no problem.
I would like to remind you that
when we have more and more listeners,
we will set the volume to silent.
So if you remember to click on the microphone icon
before speaking,
you can ask questions or
if you have any questions,
you can directly talk to the speaker, Beta.
Okay, Beta, let's get started.
For some reason, I can't share the screen.
Let me re-join.
Okay, thank you, Ted.
My name is Chengxinda.
My Chinese name is Ergongcheng.
My surname is Daoda.
Today, I would like to thank Ted and Terra
for giving me the opportunity to introduce
a method we are developing.
This is a new method.
The main purpose of this method is to deal with
the interaction between light and matter.
We hope to provide a new way
to do this.
The method we propose is called
Mixed Quantum Classical Electrodynamics.
In English, it should be called
Quantum-Fixed Mixed Electrodynamics.
I will introduce to you in detail
what kind of method it is.
Okay, let me introduce myself.
My name is Chengxinda.
My background is that when I was in Taiwan,
I was studying math and physics in college.
I majored in math and physics.
Later, for some reason,
when I applied to go to college,
I saw that there was a program called
Chemical Physics in Columbia.
I thought it was very similar to what I was doing.
It was also something I was interested in.
So I applied to this program.
I was very lucky to apply to this program.
I found out that when I came to the United States,
I became a chemical physicist.
I have been used as a chemical physicist from beginning to end.
Because of this reason,
I am now working as a chemical physicist
at Penn University.
To sum up,
I use the theory of physics
and the computational method developed in physics
to study the problem of chemistry.
My professional field is
studying dynamics,
which is the theory of dynamics
and the computational method of dynamics.
Specifically,
my Ph.D. is in Columbia.
I am doing chemical dynamics,
that is,
electromagnetic dynamics in a chemical environment.
My postdoc,
what I am doing now
is a little different from my Ph.D.
I am doing the interaction of light and matter.
Today,
my talk will focus on
my postdoc work.
OK.
First of all, what is light?
We often say that light is an object.
Basically,
light is a very important thing in everyday life.
Light is basically an electromagnetic wave.
Electromagnetic waves
are basically the source of all our information.
We see things in this world.
From the greatest extent,
how do we know
what happens on other planets
or on Mars, for example?
We can
reflect the light of the sun from Mars
and see from the spectrum of sunlight
what kind of matter there is on Mars.
How much of this matter is there?
Then,
there are more possibilities
in the development of modern science.
These are no longer visible light.
We have different kinds of light
from low energy to high energy.
Then, from the low energy range,
we have NMR
to Raman
or IR spectrum.
These things are
lower than visible light.
Within the range of higher than visible light,
there is UV,
which is ultraviolet,
and
X-ray spectroscopy, which is more powerful.
Basically, our feature is that
basically,
this
spectroscopy
shows that
the stronger the energy,
the deeper we can see.
Just like in the form of X-ray,
we can see that it can
reflect the electrons in the inner layer.
So you can know what the behavior of the electrons in the inner layer is.
This is one of the functions
of light and matter interaction.
In recent years,
because of the development of nanotechnology,
we can make our devices
in a smaller scale.
So we can even use light,
the quality of light,
to manipulate matter,
to change the nature of matter.
For example,
we can put
a chemical reaction
in a cavity,
and the nature of the chemical reaction
may be changed.
Or we can put this chemical reaction
on a crystal.
This chemical reaction may have
different behavior.
There are other
different nanostructures,
nanostructures,
which can have different
effects on light-matter interaction
and change the nature of matter.
Another very important example
is that in recent years,
there is a very popular
study
on how we use
light-matter interaction
to change,
for example,
this paper
is a paper
about
the conductivity
of organic semiconductors.
They put a very thin
membrane structure,
and there is a circle
above it,
and attach it
to the organic semiconductor.
It can change
the conductivity of the semiconductor.
It can change it
from a bad conductor
to a better conductor.
But these
modern developments
all use the nature of light-matter.
When we need
to understand the nature of light-matter,
we need to discuss
what is light
and what is the difference
between classical light and light-matter.
The classical light
is in the left panel.
We regard classical light as an electromagnetic wave,
and the development
of the electromagnetic wave
is based on
the Maxwell's equation,
which is
the Maxwell's equation.
This is a Maxwell's equation
without a source.
This is a
propagate,
a electromagnetic wave moving forward
without any source.
This is the classical view
of light.
In quantum mechanics,
we regard light as a group
of energy.
Its energy
is discretized.
You may have heard of
the Uncertainty Principle,
which is
the Uncertainty Principle.
The Uncertainty Principle
in light
corresponds to
the distribution of energy.
The energy may not be
only one energy,
but a distribution of probability.
How does quantum mechanics
evolve light?
It is based on
the Heisenberg equation.
The H is an operator
in quantum mechanics.
This is a description
of how light
evolves
in a space.
What is the difference
between classical
and quantum mechanics?
Let's take a look
at the matter part.
We can also see
what classical matter
and quantum matter are.
Classical matter
is a particle
or many particles.
Many particles
follow
Newton's law
in quantum mechanics.
We all know
classical mechanics.
A particle has a certain speed
and this speed changes over time.
In classical
quantum mechanics,
we take
the energy
as a series.
In quantum mechanics,
we describe
the energy
as a wave function.
In quantum mechanics,
we describe
the energy
as a wave function.
The wave function
is a
distribution
in the direction
of space and momentum.
It is not a solid
particle.
It is a
distribution
in the direction
of space
and momentum.
It is a
distribution in the direction
of space and momentum.
It is a distribution
in the direction
of space
and momentum.
It follows
Schrödinger's equation.
classical and quantum mechanics.
It follows quantum mechanics
and quantum light mechanics.
When we describe
the interaction
of modern light
and quantum mechanics,
we can use
quantum light
and quantum mechanics.
When we have quantum light
and quantum mechanics together,
we can get
quantum electromagnetic energy
In QED,
we can
integrate the matter
and light
into the same wave function.
Then they will have a combined Hamiltonian.
Then they use this huge thing
to evolve together.
This can include
all the interaction
in high-level quantum mechanics.
But this is
a very, very large
calculation.
It is very difficult
to do a real calculation
except for some basic models.
One of the reasons
is that the total wave function
contains a lot of
degrees of freedom.
There are a lot of variables
in it.
In a real situation,
for example,
I take a real nanoparticle
or a real
nanostructure
to calculate this thing.
Basically,
the current theory can't do it.
So we have
a more
compromise approach.
We develop a set
called Mixed Quantum Classical,
which is a combination of classical quantum
electromagnetic theory.
In this, we treat
light as classical,
as classical,
and material as matter.
Therefore,
we don't need to evolve
the light.
We only need to care about
the behavior of matter.
Then we treat
the behavior of light
as a time-dependent perturbation.
We treat it as
a driving force.
It's like
something is pushing
matter
into evolution.
This is a more
practical approach,
but it has some problems.
Of course,
it's OK for some problems.
This is not
the method we first proposed.
This method has been done by many people.
But it still has some problems.
The first problem
is that it has no feedback.
The so-called feedback is that
we treat the light here
as bending,
and we don't
transfer any energy
to the light.
We don't
transfer any feedback
to the light.
Basically,
if you take the whole system,
the light and matter
together,
you will find that
this theory does not meet the energy conservation.
The second problem is that
we don't have fluctuation.
There is an uncertainty principle.
In other words,
I should have a
standard difference
between light and matter.
Because
my thing is a
distribution,
I should have a
distribution width.
But here,
because we use classical light,
there is no
fluctuation.
Another problem
is that
because we treat it as
time-dependent perturbation,
it is a linear response.
Basically,
the material
responds to
what the light pushes.
The light pushes
very hard, and it responds very hard.
However,
in strong coupling,
if the light pushes very hard,
it can change
the quality of light.
This theory
cannot be explained.
The most serious problem
is that
it cannot capture
a very important
physical quality called spontaneous emission.
In Chinese, it is called spontaneous emission.
I will explain what it is later.
These problems
cause
classical methods
to be stuck there.
It can't explain
the quantum mechanics
we want to explain.
So,
my job
is to
develop a new
method
based on
mixed quantum classical dynamics.
We hope
to develop
a new method
that
can
reconstruct
spontaneous emission.
We can
enforce
energy conservation.
We can also
add
the fluctuation
of classical light.
How do we
do this?
Sorry, I have a question.
Please go ahead.
I want to ask
because
using all quantum mechanics
is a bit difficult.
We cannot calculate it
by analytical solution.
For example, can't we calculate
molecular?
Can't we calculate single element?
Can't we calculate many-body?
Yes,
usually many-body
is
exponential n.
Think about
how many particles
exponential n
can't run fast.
What we can do
is
to treat some degree of freedom
as classical.
There are many good classical methods
to propagate Maxwell's equation.
For example,
single molecule
can be calculated?
Yes.
As a
chemist,
I want to do
something practical.
I see.
I am doing high-performance.
I don't know.
I only calculate one by one.
Two or three more
are difficult.
What we want to do
is to put
a molecule
into a cavity.
I see.
Is LR
the same
as Lindblad
equation operator?
Thank you.
Is it?
I just want to make sure.
It is very similar.
I will not
write it down.
It is very similar to
Lindblad,
but it can't be written as
Lindblad form.
It is a non-linear term.
It is not like Lindblad.
It is a linear term.
It is a time-dependent
and skewed Lindblad.
I see.
Keep going.
I am looking forward to it.
I will talk about it
later.
Basically,
what we want to do
is to
make a low-energy
chemical system.
We don't
consider
relative efficiency.
We don't consider it.
Next,
we will talk about
spontaneous emission.
What is
spontaneous emission?
The quantum theory of spontaneous emission
was proposed by Dirac
in 1927.
Before Dirac,
Einstein introduced
spontaneous emission.
In 1927,
he introduced
spontaneous emission
from the first principle.
So,
I consider it
as a major contribution.
What is spontaneous emission?
It is basically
a transition.
It is a transition from
a stimulated state to an excited state.
In short,
I have an electron.
It is in a stimulated state.
It is in an excited state.
It emits the same light
as the transition energy.
This is called spontaneous emission.
The most important thing is
a quantum system,
a two-level system,
a stimulated state and an excited state.
It still emits
in vacuum.
This is because
in quantum theory,
we use
a thing called
zero-point energy.
It represents the
minimum energy of light in vacuum.
Some theories
correspond to
vacuum fluctuation.
Although it is in vacuum,
it still
interacts with
the quantum system
to emit spontaneous emission.
Why is
spontaneous emission
so important?
Fundamentally,
it is a quantum process.
In classical theory,
it is impossible
to get spontaneous emission.
Second,
spontaneous emission
is responsible
for almost
all light.
The light we can see
is because of spontaneous emission.
Zero light,
visible light,
the mechanism at the bottom
is because of spontaneous emission.
It is a
leading theory
of quantum electrodynamics.
After Dirac
in 1927,
a group of people
started to invest in this field.
Pauli, Wigner,
Eisenberg, Fermi,
Freeman Dyson,
and Feynman.
They started to do
QED research.
If we
use
mixed quantum classical equations
to deal with
spontaneous emission,
what will happen?
I am going to
explain
what is
mixed quantum classical.
First,
we can see
my mouse.
Great!
Can you see my mouse?
Yes.
There is a little
lag.
If you want to stop,
please slow down.
No problem.
First,
let's assume
a two-level system
is placed in the vacuum.
The system is
completely in spontaneous emission state.
There is no
distribution
in the state.
In
mixed quantum classical,
there is no spontaneous emission.
This is the line
I am drawing.
The line I am drawing
is the time axis.
The axis is the
population of
the stimulated state.
The red line
represents the
time axis.
The system
does not emit any light.
First of all,
this is wrong
in terms of quality.
However,
we found
that
if I am not
completely in the
stimulated state,
for example,
I have half
of the stimulated state and half of the
stimulated state,
I will find that
there seems to be a little
spontaneous emission.
However,
there is still a gap
compared to the
real spontaneous emission,
the black curve.
This is
a method we have tried.
We have tried other methods.
We have tried other three methods.
For example,
we have tried MCCC.
It is called SQC,
or CPA.
These other methods
have problems.
The right side of the graph
represents the curve in the middle
of the graph.
The curve in the middle
represents the spontaneous emission rate.
The red line
is the red line
in the left side of the graph.
From there,
I get the emission rate
and compare it
with the real
spontaneous emission rate.
Sometimes,
for example,
when it is almost at ground state,
it will be very close
to the real
spontaneous emission rate.
However,
it will get worse and worse.
When more and more population
are at ground state,
the distance
will get bigger and bigger.
The other methods
have the opposite
effect.
This is the second problem.
The last problem
is
a very old problem.
Our factory
is a classical factory,
so there is no
any fluctuation.
If I want to calculate
anything about fluctuation,
I must be wrong.
The method we propose
is called
PLOS R.
We call it
the average length method.
We use PLOS R
because it is the simplest
average length method.
In the average length method,
we add
LR,
which is a little bit like
the Limplot form.
What is PLOS R?
It has three functions.
The first one is
an additional relaxation.
We take some population
from the ground state
to the ground state.
The additional population
is based on
the Ehrenfest equation
to deduce
how much is missing
and how much
relaxation we need to add
to make it
exactly the same
as spontaneous emission rate.
This is the first thing.
The second thing is
that we took some population
from the ground state
to the ground state
in the previous step.
Where does
this energy go?
This energy should be
put into
the power plant.
It should
become
a part of
the power plant
or the magnetic field
to ensure
that
the whole system
is energy-stable.
So we designed a method
to make
this energy
to be put
into the power plant.
We also designed
a thing called
stochastic,
which is a random
defacing.
In a random process,
the system
will decide
whether to
turn the system's phase
a little bit.
It can decide
whether to
turn the system's phase
a little bit.
This small
stochastic defacing
introduces
the fluctuation
of the classical
power plant.
I'm not running
one trajectory,
but many trajectories
to balance
its trajectory behavior.
We can
tell
what is
the coherent
of the power plant
we are
generating.
Is there
a part of
coherent,
which means
it has
a certain frequency,
and the other part
is incoherent.
The incoherent part
means the frequency
shifts a little bit,
and the value
is zero.
With these three
additional
plus-or strategies,
we can
recover
the green line.
We can
recover
the spontaneous
emission rate.
It's a little bit
of a pain in the ass.
We know
the difference,
and we can
recover the spontaneous
emission rate.
However,
this is not
the selling point.
The selling point is
that we can
recover
the correct emission rate.
Although our emission
will be a pile of
thousands of
classical
power plants,
on average,
it will be
consistent with the
quantum intensity.
Let me
explain this to you.
The blue line
is the intensity.
It's like the
square of the power plant.
The blue line
is the
square of the
power plant.
We all know
that the
difference between
the average square
and the average square
is the standard difference.
From 50-50,
when the
system is
50-50,
the standard difference
is smaller.
If we
start from
100%,
from
78,
the two-level
system
will have a
very big standard difference.
What does this mean?
It means that
from this 100%
two-level system,
there is no coherence emission.
The blue line below
is the coherence emission.
Anyway,
we are
very satisfied
with this result.
We can see that
although we use
classical power plants,
we are still satisfied
with this result.
Now, let's recap
what we have done.
We have proposed
ERMFES PLUS R
Mixed Chromium Classical Dynamics.
It can recover
spontaneous emission.
It also satisfies
energy conservation.
We even
modified
ERMFES PLUS R
Mixed Chromium Classical Dynamics
to simulate
quantum fluctuation.
I have a question.
Sorry.
Can you go back
to the previous slide?
Why is the
electric field
average
not zero?
Generally speaking,
for spontaneous emission,
the average square of
the electric field
should be zero.
The average square of
the electric field
is only
zero in one situation.
If the system
is fully
activated, it is zero.
However, when the system
is fully activated,
the average square of
the electric field
is not zero.
Sorry.
My question is
for any electromagnetic wave,
the average square of
the electric field
should be zero.
The average square of
the electric field
is zero in one situation.
The average square of
the electric field
is 0.
Is it right?
Sorry.
The average square of
the electric field
is 0.
Sorry.
I have absolute value here.
I want to compare
the difference between
coherence emission and
all emission.
You can think of it as
the amplitude of the electric field.
It's like a sine.
It's the value in front of the sine.
Sorry.
It's the amplitude of the electric field.
It's the square of
the amplitude of the electric field
and the intensity.
I see.
Thank you.
Let's continue.
Now we have this.
Very good.
I want to do more
with this good tool.
I don't want to just do two-level system.
I want to do a more complicated system.
Of course, it can't be too complicated right away.
So we looked at two different cases.
One is Raman.
The first case is Raman scattering.
It's to test
our
Ernefest plus R method.
Is there a way to
deal with multiple quantum states?
The second question
is called Moller triplet.
Basically, it's a very strong
phenomenon.
We want to test
if Ernefest can handle
the electric field in the wall.
First,
Raman scattering.
Raman
is basically
a
Indian scientist.
Very cool.
The most basic model
of Raman scattering
is three-level system.
You can see on the right
0, 1, 2.
Energy from 0 to
1 to 2.
In the beginning,
the system
is on 0.
There is a
beam of light coming in.
This beam of light will
pump the electricity from 0 to 2.
0 and 1
are not coupled
in the system.
So,
they pump the electricity
from 0 to 2.
There are two possible
pathways from 0 to 2.
One is from 2 to 0
or from 2 to 1.
So,
the beam of light
comes from every transition.
The beam of light
is elastic.
It is the same frequency
from 0 to 2
and back to 0.
So, it is called elastic process.
The other frequency
from 2 to 1
is called
inelastic process.
In quantum mechanics,
the whole process
can be explained
by a formula.
This is a
KHD,
Kramer, Heisenberg and Dirac.
This is a
quantum formula
to explain
the spectrum.
Why
Raman Scattering
is so important?
It contains a lot of important information.
For example, it can tell us
the excited state,
which is the state above.
What is the movement
of Raman?
It also contains a lot of
molecular structure information.
For example,
Raman's
spectroscopy is used on the surface.
So, it can know
the structure of
the molecule attached on the surface.
Is it straight or curved?
There are different
Raman's movements.
I forgot to mention that
Raman has
three different transitions
with different labels.
R stands for Reidy.
Reidy means
from 2 to 1, which is the elastic part.
Stock Raman
is from 0 to 2
and back to 1.
This is from 0 to 2 to 1.
This is called
Stock's Reidy.
Anti-Stock's Reidy is a
weaker signal.
It still has a chance
to go from 1 to 2 and back to 0.
This is a weaker
signal.
OK.
Next,
basically,
we want to know
whether Mixed Kronenklassik
can
capture Raman's scattering.
There are some
problems here.
Basically, Mixed Kronenklassik
does not have a plus R.
There is only one
elastic scattering.
There is only one R.
You can see it in the
picture.
I have different
scattering frequencies
from
3 quarters
to
3 quarters of 0 to 2
to more than 0 to 2.
There are different frequencies.
It is not necessarily resonance.
This is Resonance Raman.
OK.
Although I can get
this one,
but
in Mixed Kronenklassik,
I don't have
any other mechanism
to make it go from 2 to 1.
Basically, it is impossible
to have any
Raman's scattering.
In addition, the old problem of MQC
is that there is no fluctuation.
After adding
RMFS plus R solution,
we will find that
the picture on the right
can completely recover
Dock's Raman.
In fact,
we can also get Anti-Stock Raman,
but the signal
of Anti-Stock Raman is very small.
If we draw a
log plot,
there is a signal,
but it is relatively weak,
so the signal is very small.
We can see
the Anti-Stock Raman.
But how accurate
is this Anti-Stock Raman?
So we can
compare it
with KHD.
The picture on the top
shows
RMFS plus R
blue line.
It is almost
qualitatively agree with
quantum mechanics.
The red line
does not add RMFS plus R.
We find that there are
several order of magnitude
difference.
This picture
proves that
RMFS plus R
is not only a quantitative improvement,
but also
different physics.
There is a
qualitative difference.
Next,
we see that
Riley and
Raman,
RMFS plus R
is very similar to
KHD.
Let me
recap again.
What did we learn
from Raman Scattering?
RMFS plus R
is very similar to
KHD.
RMFS plus R
is very similar to
KHD.
RMFS plus R
allows us to
do the multistate transition.
allows us to do the multistate transition.
We can get a multistate transition
with a good
quantization.
We don't need
to use our hands
to create a frequency
to make it vibrate.
We can get a
inelastic scattering
with RMFS.
Lastly,
I'm sorry,
I interrupted you.
You can continue.
I have a question.
RMFS plus R
So if I understand correctly, you add a Resonance Intermediate State in the middle
Add a Resonance Intermediate State in the middle
Because if it's Fermi's Golden Rule, you choose an energy and all your In and Out will be Resonant with that energy
No, what I mean is
What I mean is
I know
For example, I know every transition 2-1
2-1 and 2-0
They all meet different Fermi's Golden Rule
Fermi's Golden Rule is a rate
There is a transition rate
In my theory
I can deduce
How much is the difference between RMFS and Fermi's Golden Rule
Then I will use those three methods to add the difference
That's OK
Let me ask
Sorry, can you go to the next page?
Yes
Next, I want to see the picture on the right
Sorry, I want to see the picture on the right
So the input frequency
In these ranges, do you have to re-calculate how to add other parameters?
Or these are already
Omega i
There are ten
Do you have to add other parameters ten times?
That may be easy
I don't understand
I just ask
It doesn't matter
Actually, it doesn't matter
Every trajectory is exactly the same
Just change a parameter
Omega i
Yes, I just need to change Omega i
I didn't change anything
I didn't change anything else in the calculation
So I don't need to re-calculate
Can I ask a question?
Whether it's Rayleigh or Raman
You said you want to use Fermi's Golden Rule
But in general
State 2 is a virtual state
So in reality
You can't get the real coupling constant
How do you solve this problem?
Can't get the real coupling constant
In practice, you can measure Rayleigh scattering cross-section
Or Raman scattering cross-section
But you can't get a
Real state and virtual state coupling
How much is it?
Yes
It's like this
I don't have virtual state and real state coupling here
The coupling I use is
Resonant coupling
I shouldn't say resonant, sorry
The coupling I use is actually 1 and 2 coupling
Then
If you look back from the lab
Because my idea is more from
First principle
If I want to calculate this
In fact, the actual molecule to calculate this
I will use electronic structure
Use electronic structure to calculate the real coupling
This coupling
Not the real coupling
In the electronic structure
How big is the coupling
This coupling is good
This coupling can be calculated in the electronic structure
It's a transition dipole moment
1 and 2 state transition dipole moment
The light I hit
Whether there is resonance
I use the transition state dipole moment
So what you mean is
You have real state in the molecule
Then you use real state transition dipole moment
Then you sum up all these real states
Yes
Because in this mixed quantum classical
I don't have any virtual state
It's not like the sum over state theory
I have a lot of virtual state
No, this is real state
Then different frequency
Thank you
Because it is a bit like a driving system
It is a dynamical system
I hope this will answer your question
Any other questions?
No, I will continue
Where did I just talk about
In the end, we want to say
In the end, the problem we want to deal with
Is a strong problem
What about this strong problem
It's called model triplet
It is a two-level system
Back to a very simple two-level system
But there is a very strong classical field
What is the biggest feature of model triplet
I think the coolest point is that it is classical
Classical in quantum now
It's a bit like laser
It's a coherent state
It's very close to classical mechanics
Classical mechanics
But the spectrum it emits
It's a very, very non-classical
It's a very quantum spectrum
Why is that?
Because this field
This field is because it is very strong
So it's basically
It has exceeded all the encirclement theory
So we can't use the encirclement theory anymore
So in quantum theory
It's a bit like a mixing state
It's a bit like a hybridization
What about the picture in the lower right corner
Actually on the left
On the left side of this diagonal
It's bare state
I made
Two-level system
Generate
Sorry
Two-level system and light frequency
The state generated
Draw it out
After the hybridization is drawn
You will find that the one on the right is the state after the hybridization
It's a bit like a mix
It's a bit like a dress state
But it's light
Hybridization is the hybridization of light and two-level system
So its energy level
Will be changed
Then
Inside the dress state model on the right
It has three different
Launch frequency
The first one
We call it T
Why is it called T? It's actually very simple
It's called three
Three photons
You can see it from the highest
After one, two, three
Three times to the lowest
So it's called triple
Three photons
Then what about F? F is called fluorescence
Fluorescence is basically
It's the lowest level
It's the two closest
Between
Launch
Then the other two
It's called Rayleigh
Two Rayleigh
It goes through two photons
It's called Rayleigh
That
This
The whole quantum theory
Gave us three different
Frequency, which means it's three different
Peak
Then inside these peaks
Will be produced
It contains the Rabi frequency
Rabi is
The gentleman on the left is Rabi
He was actually in Columbia before
Very cool
Then
The same we can use this
Mixed quantum classical method
Let's try
We found that if we don't put any
Change we don't put any
We found that this system is basically
Classical in, classical out
It's classical in, it's classical out
There won't be much change
If you were a kid
Or high school
There is a physical phenomenon
That is, you put
A pile of protein
Put in a
Tie a pile of protein
Tie a pile of protein on the same pole
The pole has a fixed frequency vibration
After a long time, they will be synchronized
Together
This phenomenon is basically the same as what we see here
It's like
I
Although there are many different frequencies in it
Run in there
In fact, we are looking at
This mixed quantum classical
In a short time, you will see three peaks
We can see three peaks
But for a long time, you will find that the two peaks next to it
Gradually disappeared
Only the middle peak is left
Basically it is a
Classical driving system
Classical in, classical out
Nothing else
The other is
There are other old problems
We don't have any fluctuations here
That
With this plus r
We will find that this blue line
Is the line after the plus r
We can see that they can
Have a stable
Side peak
It won't be because of time
It won't disappear because of a long time
Why is there a stable side peak?
In fact, it is
In fact, it is a
Return to
Random perturbation
Stochastic defacing
It's a bit like
In this classical system
Push it from time to time
Don't let it fall back
The huge frequency
Don't let it be forever
Classical in, classical out
There is a small stochastic
Defacing is actually very important here
It can make
The two side peaks are stable for a long time
We want to know
Here we can see that
These three ratios are r
With f and t
With
All classical theory
The prediction is consistent
We want to know
Is there any other
More interesting properties
We can compare with classical theory
What about here
We show
This picture above
Is the result of an experiment
The result of the experiment
What did it change?
It is also a model triplet
Then the different lines
From the bottom to the top
Also different
Infrared light frequency
Then you will find that
There are several features
The wind in the middle
Almost unchanged
But the wind next to it
Different
Different evolution
The first one is
Peak position
You can see the picture on the right
The middle line
The middle line is
Central peak
It doesn't change much
But this
Side peak
It is with
This width is called
Many people call
Generalized
Rabi frequency
It is off resonance
Not necessarily resonance
Rabi frequency
This experiment
Very well with theory
This
This peak
Basically
This
The position of the peak is not a rare thing
So in practice and theory
Not too much
Then we
In
In urbanfest plus r
You can also see the same behavior
That is to say
Central peak
Fixed
Side peak
There is a
Generalized Rabi frequency
These two pictures
A little flip
Because I want to be the same as the left
X and y are above
The experiment is the opposite
But if you turn it over
The color is correct
Blue against blue
This is what we observe
Very good point
This is basically
Is not a difficult thing
But
Excuse me
In addition to these three peaks
There is another peak outside
Correct
There are more on the left and right
So that is also
Resonance
It may be higher
Higher
Correct
Let me make sure
I have an impression
Please tell me
I remember the so-called
Because the light is very strong
So
Equal to this original
There is an ac
This way
Create two more
My previous understanding is like this
Correct
So this calculation method
Above
The method they came up with in 2012
Is it a simulation method?
In fact
Use you today
The method of analysis
The method they use is
Is
Dark shift
There is
Electrophonic hybridization
You can put those
The relationship between
Calculate
OK
Then continue
The earliest MOLO paper is
The earliest prediction
MOLO triplet was in 1967
Then later
Of course a lot of people
Just go in and explain this thing
There is a very good resource
Do a lot
Work in this area
Then
Okay, let's take a look at one
More interesting thing
That is, I am comparing
This picture is what I compared
Except that I want to compare
The position of the peak, I also want to compare
Can I get
Can I get the correct
Coherence emission
What about this one on the left?
What about this curve?
Quantum mechanics
Is the whole quantum theory
That
Coherence emission
The ratio
That
This green dot
There is a dot
We use
Ernest plus r to calculate
Then we found here
Especially near the place
Delta omega is zero
Near the place
Very good
Is there a way
We also have a small caveat
In fact, this quantum mechanics
The theory is based on
Rotating wave approximation
It is based on
Very close to this
Very close to the resonance
So we don't know
Far away
Where is the resonance
The theory of quantum mechanics
Is our calculation method
Is it accurate?
So this place
We are not very clear
Is this place accurate?
Anyway, what we get is
Quite different
At least near the resonance
Their results are very close
What about this thing on the right?
Is a
Can play
It can almost surpass
Rotating wave approximation
That is to say
If we look at the peak on the left
For
Different frequency changes
That
The red line
Is the right side peak
The blue line is the left side peak
That
Is the quantum theory
Under this
It is a line
It will not predict at all
Irregular situation
Because it is only
Focused on
One level
One level quantum behavior
Because of this
Rotating wave approximation
It only focuses on one level quantum behavior
So it can get the middle one
It's right, but it can't get it
At this point
But our
Mixed quantum classical method
Because I didn't do anything
Rotating
Rotating wave
So the result I got
I can get this
Linear crossing result
This result is actually
The result of the experiment is the same
That is, in practice, we can also see
This is not a fixed point
It is a
Linear crossing
This result is very
Exciting result
So
Finally
This is a final recap
We found this
RFS class R dynamics
It can almost simulate
Quantum mixing
There is no mixing mechanism
But just use
Driving field
With a small stochastic
Diffusing, I can simulate
Quantum mixing
We can also
Very clearly distinguish
Coherence emission and incoherence emission
I hope
These
Advantages can tell
Everyone that we are developing now
The theory is a very reliable
Method
To deal with
Light-material interaction
But this method still has a lot of problems
This method
We are still
I haven't thought about any
Quantum mixing
That is, our current
Matter is a very simple matter
Two-level system, three-level system
Is a very simple matter
From the perspective of a chemist
We are
We hope that we can
At least put some
Chemistry
Put potential energy
Put nuclear
Put in
Non-adiabatic dynamics
Put these different behaviors
This is a
A good direction
Another question mark
Can we get
Photon counting statistics
Because there are
The second point and the third point
Very similar
Anti-function
Because
There is another big feature of monostripe
I haven't covered here
Three-wind
Quantum counting statistics
Because
The sequence of light
So every light
For example
F light
The first one
The next one may be very close to it
T light
The first one
Must be far away from it
Can't release a light right away
When you measure the light
When the statistics are
You will find
F light may be
In line with
Poisson distribution
T light
Subpoisson distribution
The quality of light
Will be different
Here
We haven't tried it yet
Of course
There is no light here
We can get similar
Last
Thermal light
If the light is not
Not
Not at 0 degree
There is a thermal distribution
Then
Can we
In mixed quantum classical
Get detail balance
Or we may
Violate detail balance
The last question
Is a very important question
In many systems
Two-level system
Spontaneous emission rate
May be changed
Not in line with Fermi's golden rule
Spontaneous emission rate
Because of cavity
Cavity causes strong interaction
Strong interaction
Causes
This
The frequency of emission will change
This method
Based on Fermi's golden rule
May be
So this is also a possibility
Need to consider
Then
We do this
Method
Method development
For people
The most common thing we do
Is that we have created a new toy
Is
We want to use it in many places
Hope many people
Use it in many places
For us
A very important question
When will it break down
This is the most important
The most important thing we want to know
When does it not work
That
Of course there are many
Application
These things are
We hope to push it to
Other
Spectroscopy
Spectroscopy group
Let's try
Can we use this
Same method
To see
Chemistry
Put it in a cavity
It may be because of the interaction with light
To change
Its
Vibrational energy level
Because of the change of the vibrational energy level
It may have different
Reaction pathway
So it will have different
This is
This is a thing we can do
A direction
Another application
Is a new theory
Called
Model
Then
In this model
I use
Classical source
Generate quantum light
Then use this quantum light
Different light
Go to
The target
Then
I can see
This target
Different
Photon statistics
The
Behavior
This is a new thing
But this thing
There is no experimental implementation yet
But in theory
Many people are
Pursue this direction
Finally
A very
In device and material science
A very useful application
Conductance enhancement
Application
Can be used
Cavity
To simulate
We hope
Can use this method
To understand
Why
Conductance enhancement
Finally
Thank you
Professor
Dave Reichman
The middle one
Old man
Not old
With me
Joseph
Then
Half a year
Visiting scholar
The
Maxine
Arizona State University
Professor
This method
Generate
Three-dimensional
This method
I have a
Electron system
The evolution
The evolution of the classical electron system
Maxine is a classical electron system expert
So he can use
I don't know the theory
Put it
With some
Very mature classical electron system
Combine
Then Taoli is us
A researcher in my group
Then he is
We did a lot of work together
Finally, I want to thank
Ted
Organize the whole
Let me have a chance to share with you
Thank you
Hello
Everyone
Does anyone have any special questions?
The
Okay, let me ask
I am
Good
When we look at it recently
I
What I've been doing lately is
Light polarization
Interaction
Use
In the semiconductor
What's in there
We are looking at it recently
In addition to
Because we are more concerned
Like what you are talking about now
Light in classical way
The electromagnetic wave
To present
If like us
So we do it
We do more polarizations
Or
So it's
It depends on the light itself
His own characteristics
Then we recently
Looking at one is
You should probably listen to it
Just
There is
This kind of thing
I'm thinking
If there is
Although it was quite new at first
but
There is
The light is recently
I think it's a hot topic
One
Have you ever thought about it?
His whole disease
He is also a
That one
This boundary
One of the conditions
Square
Its light is a bit like it
A wave of rotation
It's different from the circle
Still not the same
So it is
There is also a moment
Then you
This may be
Maybe you are now
It may not be the same
But I want to say
You have a way to analyze this
The light will be
With
Maybe not yet
The interaction of molecules
Or with any two-level system
Interaction
How does it react
I think
This
I was not born with light
These things are a bit difficult
I
I am now
What they are doing
Very confident
I have
FDTD
These good
Classic electric mechanics
That basically
He
What he does now
Different
Can do
I think
If he does this
I think it should be
The problem you are thinking about is helpful
Great
Let's pay attention to this
Professor
I have a question
Ok
This is
This is a long-standing question
I want to know
When will it happen
Outer tongue splitting
Then
What is your second
Outer tongue splitting
Oh
Then
I know it's probably
Only in molecules
Or the atomic system
This mole triplet will occur
But in the acetone system
It will only happen
But what is the specific reason
Do you know
I don't know the specific reason
Because my understanding of him
Same as you
He is in
In the molecule
In the molecular system
He will be
In the acetone system
I still have to learn
I haven't
I have been doing this
This set of theory
About a year and a half
Ok
There are still a lot to learn
There is another thing
Outer tongue
What is the other one
Called
EIT
Electronic
Transparency
What's the difference between the two
I really don't know
Ok
Out of my
You may ask
Ted may not understand
I remember EIT
With male triplet
There seems to be a difference
EIT seems to be more in the atom
But I actually don't remember
EIT
EIT and
The effect of outer tongues looks the same
But it's completely different from male triplet
Male triplet you will see three states
EIT and
Outer tongues you see two states
I forgot
Sorry
It doesn't matter
But I think this is a pretty interesting question
I think I should
I should use
Because male triplet is basically
The first thing we try
Let's try to break down
This method
See if this method will break down here
Actually quite good
So I was thinking
Maybe our next project will use EIT
Ok
Then another thing
You said you add
You add fluctuation in the electric field
Then in the classical field
Add fluctuation
Then let it
Looks like there is spontaneous emission
Then
Which electric field are you
Is it driving force electric field
Add fluctuation
No, I'm in the radiation field
Driving field here
We still treat it as
It's a
Electric field running past
Maxwell equation is linear
You can break it down
But this
If you are in emission
That
Add fluctuation in radiation
Then
You said your addition is
You just assume
It's running above the time
Then
At a certain random time
Let it change the phase
Like this
Then
This thing seems to be with that
Is two-dimensional
Spectroscopy inside
The method they use
Very similar
Do you say pump probe method
Is in two-dimensional
Spectroscopy inside
They have
One is called homogeneous line width
Another one is called
No, this is homogeneous line width
There are two components
The first one is
Free induction decay
The second one is
Scattering of phonon
Scattering of other things
Then the second
Their assumption
They bring in
Model method
In the radiation field
Add a random
Phase drop
So these two things
Is it the same
Actually different
A little different
That is to say
OK
I want
That is
I want to say one thing
Because i'm not
I'm not really
Add a random phase
I am adding a random phase
In
Two-level system
Then this two-level system
Random phase will reflect on the electric field
So i'm really adding
Electric field
There are two benefits to this method
Because
My
It is natural
There are two benefits to this method
Because my
Two-level system
Also need this defacing
He also needs
This little defacing
Correct his
His fluctuation
He also needs this thing
From
Then another benefit is
Because i'm
Put
There is actually a
Difficulty point is because i put
I want to put this
Add a little fluctuation
I can't just add it
Add to a certain place
It just caused his self-interaction
Will destroy the whole system
That
So he will have one
Specific method
Add it to a correct place
That
This thing
Because he
Because of this field
He is not like he is not only a point
He is a whole space
And he has to meet some basic
For example, he can't go beyond the speed
I can't put a field suddenly
Add to a place beyond the speed
Right
So
Try not to add directly
On field
So when we design this method
This fluctuation
Add to two-level system
Naturally generate this fluctuation
OK
Then there is a more detailed question
I want to know this
Why this classical
It's just
Quantum matter and classical
Field
That
Only when
When that
That
Low
Low 0
Low 1 is
There will be no emission
Then there will be other emissions
I always thought it was all
No emission
Thank you for asking this question
Because
Because of my time
I missed a part
That's it
Here
Mixed quantum classical
It's not pure
Is the most
The most basic
Mixed quantum classical
It is a mixed quantum classical
That is to say
I am in this
This
In uranfest
Two-level system
Classical
Field
Will also
Interact to two-level system
Let it decay
So this is already a non-linear system
So you see these
These red lines are not
A simple
Simple exponential decay
So it's a
It will continue to
Self-interact
So
There will be some decay
Basically
This is
One of our recent papers
His point is uranfest
This is the most basic
Mixed quantum classical
Can get some
Partially correct
But
He won't get all
Sorry
You can go to the front page
Let me see what is called uranfest
You said
His equation
I didn't write it out
OK
I can give you
Our paper
There is
I can check it myself
Because I didn't
Write it all out
A bit complicated
Thank you
Other listeners have no questions
Discuss
If there is no problem
That's the end of our speech today
Thank you all
Thank you
OK
You think
Tell us when you are ready
We will put the video up
OK
That's all for today
Good night
It's okay
4.30
OK
Thank you all
Bye