Hello, everyone. Welcome to today's TAR Talk. I am today's host, Zhang Yanyong.
I am very grateful to my good friend, He Shuyu, for being willing to give us this speech on the upcoming New Year's holiday.
First of all, let me introduce He Shuyu. He is currently a 2nd-year Ph.D. student in the Department of Physics at Tohoku University in Japan.
His field of study is mainly in the field of particle cosmology, and he is exploring how to understand the evolution of early universes from the perspective of particle interaction.
Most of his work is related to dark matter, and he did not mention it in the introduction he gave me.
But before he came, he was doing physics with Mr. He Xiaogang at NTU, so it is actually very related to his current research.
I have also had a few years of overlap with him in Caltech, where I am now, so we are very good friends.
His main research recently is Exxon. They think this is one of the most popular candidates for dark matter.
The topic he is going to talk to us about today is also related to Exxon.
His topic is Enhanced Photon Coupling of APL. APL is Exxon-like Particle, Dark Matter Adiabatically Converted from QCD Exxon.
A little reminder, if you want to applaud, remember to turn on the microphone so that our speakers can hear.
Let's applaud and welcome He Shuyu to give us today's speech.
OK, you can start now.
Is there a full screen now?
What do you mean by full screen?
I am recording a video here, so I have to press the full screen, right?
Is this OK?
Yes, I think this is OK.
OK, then I will start right away.
Zhang Yiyang has already introduced it to me, so I will talk about it directly.
The topic I want to talk about today is Exxon.
Exxon itself interacts with light.
The interaction between light and Exxon is very small.
In other words, we can't really detect it in the current experiment.
The main purpose of this work is to enhance the coupling with photons from a phenomenal point of view.
Our main method is to match the effect with the so-called MaxMixing of ALP.
I will talk about the rest of the details in the following slides.
Before that, I have to give you some preparation knowledge.
Maybe not everyone is familiar with Exxon.
Some people may not even know what DocuMator is.
So I will do some basic introduction in the front.
Then we will start directly.
The first thing you see now is the so-called example physical standard model.
Then we generally call it Standard Model.
Or SM, take the first English letter.
Basically, the standard model is very simple.
It is divided into two categories.
One is the so-called material.
The left side is the so-called material.
The right side is the so-called basic interaction.
The material is actually divided into two categories.
One is called quark.
The other is called hydrogen.
For example, everyone is more familiar with Electron.
It belongs to the category of hydrogen.
The other one may not be familiar to everyone.
But in fact, everyone is more familiar with it.
It is the so-called magnet.
Like a magnet, there is a so-called
You can see this U quark on the picture.
This up quark is composed of this down quark.
The same is true for neutrons.
So these are the more familiar particles.
Of course, there are other quarks.
This is a new example found later.
In addition to the material,
Of course, there is also the so-called interaction.
The interaction is basically divided into these categories.
The first one, everyone sees this G.
We call it Grouon.
It is a so-called strong interaction particle.
What about strong interaction?
We generally call it QCD.
That is, quantum quark dynamic.
We will see this word later.
Because this is related to the so-called CP problem we will discuss later.
The second one is the so-called electromagnetic effect.
This should be the most familiar to everyone.
Maybe from high school,
Even in everyday life, you can know
This interaction.
What about the electromagnetic effect of this magnet?
We use light to transmit.
The electromagnetic effect in our field
We like to call it QED.
That is, quantum electrodynamic.
In addition to these two effects, there is also the so-called weak effect.
The weak effect is generally used to describe
The so-called beta decay phenomenon.
Have you noticed that in addition to these interactions,
There is also an interaction
Not written on this table
The so-called gravitational effect
But because of the current standard model
I didn't include this gravity.
Because I didn't find the so-called gravity.
The so-called graviton is the gravity value.
It is not included in the standard model.
That may be something else that everyone may be familiar with.
but
This is the so-called Higgs particle.
What about this Higgs particle?
It should be 2012.
I remember when I was a substitute
Found this Higgs particle
Higgs particle is generally
The origin of this mass
Is the source of the value
What about my research today?
It has something to do with Higgs, but it doesn't have much to do with it.
I mainly focus on the so-called
This part of the skeleton
Because this skeleton will lead to
The so-called action problem
it is good
Of course, although
Although the quantum mechanics model is currently
It is very tested by the experiment.
I can't say it's perfect.
But at least most of the current
Some of the phenomena we see can be used
Use the particle physics standard model to explain
Of course, there are some shortcomings.
Because there are some problems
The standard model is incomprehensible
For example, the first so-called dark matter
I will introduce it later.
There is also the so-called strong CP problem.
This is what I translated directly.
Generally, we call it a strong CP problem.
There is also the so-called
There is also the so-called medium quality
For example, just inside this table
Did you see this green one?
The bottom three particles
This is the so-called neutrino
Because in neutrino
Because neutrino is in the standard model
It has no quality
But because through
We see this neutrino oscillation
This implies that neutrino must have quality
But the standard model
Our neutrino can't have quality
So this is also a standard model
There is also the so-called dark energy
Generally, this may be possible
Use the so-called cosmology constant to explain
There is also the so-called current gravity
Today my
The study is more related to the first
The so-called dark matter and this
This strong CP problem
Let's introduce the so-called dark matter first.
How do you know that there is a dark matter?
We can start with this
This so-called star rotation curve
Look at
This star rotation curve, I remember
It should be Rubin
Rubin said
He is a female scientist
But it seems to have passed away a few years ago
If I remember correctly
This star rotation is very simple
That is to say
We may have learned this Newton's law
So we can predict that a object
Just a planet
Do this to the solar system
If the shape
What about the speed of this shape?
It should be with the sun
Or the center of the star
What about this distance?
Yes, when it's far away
You should see this star
The speed changes with the distance
It should be this red picture on the picture
That is to say
If it's far away, it's the distance
If the center is far away, the speed should be going down
But what we see is not like this
What we see is this
The white part is
He is at speed
When it's far away, it's a constant
This is a mystery
This is the Newton's law
The gravity law to explain
Of course there are many
Ideas to deal with this problem
That
It's easier to say
Maybe there are some objects
We can't see it, but it will provide gravity
If you have additional gravity
You can explain this speed
Why is it still a constant far away?
Of course there are other theories
Like the so-called modified gravity
That is to say, Newton's law
It's not what we usually see
For example, FMA may have some corrections
That can also explain this
Star curve
So why is it that the object value
It's a little bit bigger
Because we have a lot of this
Astronomical evidence
I just looked at this picture and said that the upper left corner
This is the star curve you just talked about
In addition, there is also the so-called gravity
And this mirror seems to be wrong
That is to say
If there is a
Invisible object
Then it will provide gravity
If there is a
For example, the star is behind this
Invisible object
Because you know
According to the relativity theory
The light passes through a place where gravity is very strong
So this light
From behind this star
It will bend
Then let us see
It will be a circle
Instead of a point
This is the so-called gravitational effect
In addition, there is the so-called CMB spectrum
CMB is the so-called cosmic microwave background
radiation
It is a microcosmic microwave background
That is to say
If we assume that dark matter exists
At the same time, there is dark energy
We can
Use the cosmological model
To fit this so-called Park spectrum
You can see this picture
This black dot is a good fit
Of course, there are some parameters to adjust
But it is roughly
The cosmological model
Can also explain this Park spectrum
Then this
Must assume the existence of dark matter
The last more famous is the so-called
Bury cluster
The so-called Bury cluster is
When we find that the two clusters are contrasting
We can see this x-ray
This
That signal
Simply put, I found that in fact
In addition to
This visible part is what you just saw on the picture
This
The red and purple part we see
Part of it is that it goes straight through each other
And then there is no interaction
In fact, that can explain
It may be an evidence of dark matter
This phenomenon seems to be general
This correctional gravity seems to be
It's better to explain
So the last thing is dark matter
So we have a lot of evidence
Show the existence of dark matter
But I still believe that many people
To challenge the idea of ​​dark matter
At present, the mainstream still thinks
Dark matter is a more feasible
A way
it is good
This is the so-called Cosmic Pi
It is based on the so-called
The standard model of cosmology
We can measure this
Dark energy, dark matter
And the so-called Baryon, which is the so-called
Like the standard model just now
The table of particles
In this
The purple part is probably
If its effect can form a bond state
Then we can call this bond state
This Baryon
That is to say, we are currently
Except
For example, I currently see these stars in the universe
Most of them are
This Baryon and some
Electrons, some leptons
This one takes up only 5% of the universe's energy
Just very little
On the contrary, dark energy and dark matter
It takes up a very high proportion
Like this dark matter
It takes up about a quarter of the universe
Energy
Of course, today I will focus on
On this dark matter
What about dark energy
Generally, of course
Some people often use this
Cosmic parameter or some
The so-called quintessence
It seems to be called the fifth element
To explain
Why does dark energy exist?
That is to say, we have observed
This universe is accelerating expansion
If we assume this dark energy
Can explain this phenomenon very well
It seems to have won the Nobel Prize
A few years ago because someone observed
The accelerating expansion of the universe
And won the Nobel Prize
Of course we are familiar with this Baryon
There are some problems
Maybe you have heard of the so-called antimatter
The universe has so-called positive matter and antimatter
Why is there more positive matter in the universe?
Antimatter is less, this is also a problem
For example, why did I just leave this 5% positive matter?
This theoretical chemist
Still studying it
Anyway, today I will focus on
On this dark matter
Since we are studying dark matter
Of course we have to understand its nature
It has a few simple
Simple nature
The first one is because it is
It is invisible
That is, we just talked about
Neurotransmitter
Before we do this prediction
We did not realize that this dark matter exists
So it means that it is with our general battery
Batteries do not interact
It means that the dark matter
It is electromagnetic
In addition
Since it exists
It has existed until now
It means it is
Its lifespan is longer than that of the universe
So it has to be very stable
It is very easy to change
But it's not that it won't change
It changes very slowly
Because in fact, some astronomical phenomena
Can also be explained by dark matter
For example, dark matter can
Change into light
To explain
Unidentified signals
According to what I just said
This CMB and the so-called universe
Early nuclear fusion
Observation prediction
That is, it will not be like what we just said
Some
The substance composed of nucleus or neutrinos
It is a baryon
Matter
What about the last
If it is formed from a star structure
Its movement speed is probably moving
But its movement speed is not very fast
This is mainly because we observe this star structure
Formation to judge
That is, if
Because dark matter itself has quality
Its quality is very large
Of course it will be in the universe
Will have its own distribution
In other words, if it is dark matter
If it is in a place
If it moves very fast today
Then it is more dispersed
On the contrary, if it moves very slowly today
It is easier to gather in a certain place
If
If there is a lot of dark matter in a certain place
It means it will provide more gravity
That's the general so-called
These heavy materials are easier
Slightly attracted
Gathered in dark matter
This density is relatively high
Then gradually form stars
Then we currently see the universe
Are relatively close to the star structure
This implies that this
Dark matter
Its speed is much less than the speed of light
Of course there is also the so-called
Borrowing light
Just
Very close to the speed of light
Of course there is a borrowing in the middle
Borrowing dark matter
I don't know how to say it in Chinese
Maybe it's called cold dark matter
In general, we study dark matter that is less than the speed of light
We call it cold dark matter
Is cold dark matter
What's next
Let's talk about a few possible dark matter candidates
We just talked about
Just introduce the nature of dark matter
Of course, if you think about it
What kind of particle is it
Of course there are a lot of models
I can only use English here
The first one is more popular
Is this so-called
Massive particle
The first one I just talked about is dark matter
Because it has to be with this
General matter interaction is very weak
Otherwise we should be able to measure it easily
The other one is that it must provide
Very strong gravity
So it probably has to be a very heavy particle
So this so-called
Massive particle
Is more popular
Generally we call it WIMP
WIMP
WIMP also has a lot of options
It may be
A kind of Sushi particle
Sushi is translated into Chinese as super symmetry
It may be
The latest super symmetry
Super symmetry example
Like the so-called neutrino
It may also be the so-called
The latest one is called KK particles
KK this thing
Is related to this
Extra-dimensional model
But my topic today is not to discuss
The so-called WIMP
What I'm going to discuss today is the other candidates below
The first one, the so-called action
That Chinese
Maybe just turn it into the axis
It seems that there is no
May not be
Someone said that in the file
But I just turned it into an axis
Of course there are other candidates
Like the so-called standard neutrinos
Or the so-called SIMP
SIMP is the topic I studied a few years ago
This S is actually strongly
It is
It is different from this weakly
It is a strong massive particle
The work I did a few years ago
Is to combine this SIMP with neutrinos
I gave this speech at TERA last year
Today I will give another
Different theme is related to action
How about this WIMP
How to detect it? I think this
Maybe Zhang Yong is more familiar
He may have a few speeches before
Related to this WIMP
Experiment
Today I will focus on this WIMP experiment
I will mention a little later
How do we use experiments to detect this action
it is good
Then
Enter the topic behind me
Because I was probably in the first 20 pages
Is to do some basic introduction
What about the back?
It's basically what I said before
So basically it's more difficult
More mathematical
It's hard to understand
This is my last slide
To explain the so-called strong CP problem
Before
Some
Terminology
So
What I'm talking about here is the so-called symmetry
The first P
We call it parity
So-called mirror symmetry
Everyone may be familiar with this
If you look at it from a mathematical point of view
For example, put x into negative x
Put a negative sign
Then we call it mirror symmetry
In fact, for a long time, physicists believe
All physical laws should be mirror symmetry
Of course, this law
Of course, it should be known
Yang and Li
Found that our universe is
Irregular
Mirror symmetry is not a good symmetry
Should not
Not a good symmetry
It's not a symmetry in our nature
For example, I just talked about this
In our standard model, this has a negative effect
The negative effect itself
This interaction is valid
This parity symmetry
Okay, the second one is the so-called
Charge conjugation
We use C to represent that it is
The Chinese text should be translated directly
The reason is quite simple
It is so-called the opposite of this electric
But the quality does not change
So just inside the table, for example, electron
We know that electron itself also has an antimatter
It's called positron
The charge itself
The same direction but the opposite
So we can simply say we can do
Charge conjugation
Did you hear it?
My head didn't jump out, sorry
Then we can do a power equation
Change its electric
In fact, we found that
C is not a good symmetry
Then there is the so-called time reversal
It's actually very similar to this
Basically, you change the direction of time
Theoretically, it is to change T to T
Then I just talked about
P is not symmetrical, C is not symmetrical
Then you will think about some strange symmetries
So someone considers whether C and P are symmetrical
Even a theory
Don't just do P conversion
You also do C conversion, then we call C and P symmetrical
That's the same for a while
After Yang Zhengning found that P is not symmetrical
We think that C and P are very good symmetries
Yes, then later
In this so-called
The decay
We found that C and P are not symmetrical
This is also a Nobel Prize
So our conclusion is that
C and P and T and C and P
C and P are not symmetrical
Then we can go further
For example, C and P and T are not symmetrical
So far
The answer is
Because I have not found that C and P are symmetrical
Destroy this phenomenon
Unless we measure this
The quality of antimatter and real matter is different
Otherwise our current
The conclusion is that C and P are very good
This symmetry
Anyway
My conclusion here is that
C and P are not symmetrical
OK, so far there is no problem
Can ask first
Have it
Or do you understand
If you have a question
Remember to turn on the microphone
Otherwise you may talk for a long time
I found that I did not turn on the microphone
It seems that everyone understands
OK
I want to ask
So here
Can mention a little bit
Verify it separately
Symmetry and asymmetry
What is it
That's it
I am not
For example, you can go to this
Wu Dayou is doing this
He should be doing
Wu Jianxiong
He is a female scientist
Measure this
This is the beta decay phenomenon
Yes
Found that this is not asymmetric
If you look up this in Wikipedia
Asymmetry should mention this experiment
What about C and P
C and P
You can take the so-called C and P
You can also find it online
Their experiment
He found this
Kaon
Charge Kaon
There are several types of Kaon
Long Life
Joe Life
Because there are some asymmetry
Long Life and Joe Life
Maybe two lights or three lights
I am two lights and three lights
This
Final state
Wu Jianxiong should be
C and P
Final state C and P
C and P are different
If your final state is two lights or three lights
I found that this KL
I forgot if it was KL
It should be KL
Long Life
If you wait long enough
It will actually decay
One final state
I forgot if it was two lights or three lights
Check this detail
Zhang Yong, do you remember
I don't remember
When I was doing
We are doing B behind me
I know you are doing B
Anyway, this has nothing to do with Kaon
I've seen the story before
But I didn't prepare this story today
Sorry
Is there any other questions?
If not, let's go straight to my research topic
Of course, the next step is more
English
More mathematical
it is good
Then I will directly cut the topic and talk about this so-called action
Especially
QCD action
So why
This idea
In other words, it comes from this
In QCD, we have this so-called strong CP problem
In other words, in QCD, we have this so-called strong CP problem
In other words, I just said
In the natural world, CP is not very symmetrical
So mathematicians can write some
Destroy CP symmetry
The theory of interaction
There is a very complicated mathematical formula on the screen
It's called Lagrangian
In other words
Because CP is not symmetrical
So we can write this
In this strong effect
In our theory
It represents
This strong effect
Of course you can write this
There is no problem
But we found
If you go from here
This so-called Neutron EDM
EDM is called Electrodipole Moment
It's a kind of
We found from the experiment
This interaction
There is a factor called strong CP phase
This theta must be less than 10
Of course this number
To some physics
It's very uncomfortable
We naturally have this
It's called
It's called Neutron
It may be 0.1 or
10 to the negative 10 is a little bit small
10 to the negative 10 or negative 10
Is a little bit
Of course you can't say
The natural world
You can choose such a small number
Who knows
You don't know how the natural world works
But from the view of the theoretical student
This theta term has two
Of course I won't
I won't introduce this contribution
Basically it has two
Physics
It's made up of completely different physics
Then this is a problem
That is to say, if you look at this theta
Equals theta 0 plus this
What is this determining thing
Because the two of them are different physics
Then ask why these two
Different physics
They will be so good
Cancel to each other
That's a very
It's a problem
Basically it's a reaction
That is to say, why is this theta so small
Then give everyone a little feeling
For example, you can imagine that this
This theta is
The simple mathematician on the right side of the screen
It may be this 10 to the negative 11
Then it will be equal to
For example, if this theta is set to 1
Then the second one behind this
It may be 0.999999
Then you become
This
Just this two different physics
It's just a little bit
It's a fine-tuning
Then this is in our physics
I don't like it
So we don't need to solve this problem
Then this is the so-called strong CP problem
That
Of course, there are many theories to explain this strong CP problem
Then the most popular at the moment
The so-called introduction
The so-called action
Then this general mechanism is called
Perseverance mechanism
Or abbreviated as PQ mechanism
Then in this mechanism
The so-called strong CP phase
It's not a simple
Parameter
It is a dynamic parameter
Then I don't do too much here
This
This action theory introduction
I just introduced it directly
For example, in the mathematical world just now
We only have a theta term
But I added another one
There is a second one in this box
Then there is a big A divided by a FA
Then this A is the so-called action
A constant
It has something to do with this
A symmetry destruction
Maybe you don't need to know this
This detail you know this is a
A constant that is very important
Because it will be with us later
This photon has something to do with this action
Good
What about the introduction of this action?
When we do the calculation, we will find that it is at a very high temperature
Just look at this picture
The picture below
When you are at a very high temperature
This T represents this temperature
The temperature is far greater than this
QCD
When this QCD action
This QCD action
Its potential
Its potential is very flat
When its temperature is very low
Through this QCD
What is called non-circulation
Non-circulation effect
Its potential will be raised
So it means that at the beginning
It may be sitting well
This red part
After it is raised, it starts to fall
Falling in this blue part
This potential
The smallest part
Potential minima
Just in this position
Just put this theta
Cancel it
Theta plus A
Define it as theta effective
Just in this minima
Theta effective will be equal to zero
This theta will be
This action
Generally called vacuum expectation value
Will cancel it
So this theta effective
Is a very small number
That can explain why
We observe that this theta
Is the negative ten of the original value
That is, it is almost equal to zero
Yes, so action
It actually
The appearance is to explain this
Strong C problem
This is the so-called
This part
Is there any problem with this?
Still OK
Understand
Anyway, it is to introduce some things
Then cancel some things
That's it
The first one is canceled, so we don't see it in practice
Then I will talk about
Some action properties
We just said why
That
The same as I just said
It will pass through this QCD
Non-circulation
Non-circulation is called non-perturbative
The effect can be calculated
Just look at the formula
This T is the temperature
If the temperature is very high
This ma represents
The mass of the action
It will go to zero when the temperature is very high
When the temperature is very low
It will approach a constant
This constant is called zero temperature mass of QCD action
It can also be calculated
As long as you know
As long as you know that QCD is at a very high temperature
It is non-circulation
And when it is at a very low temperature
It is a mass
Its mass relationship is at a very low temperature
It has this relation
It can be connected to the constant I just mentioned
No connection
There is a unit on the picture here
I don't know if you are familiar with this
There should be
This is the so-called electron volt
We are talking about 1.6 times 10
Minus 19
Yes
Why this is the mass
Then you can use energy to represent
That's because we're in high energy
We are used to making this light speed into 1
In other words, you can say that energy is actually the mass
OK
So we use this unit to represent the mass
It's called EV
This GV is convenient
It's 10 to the power of 9
But there are other abbreviations
Such as NEV or KEV
If you do experiments
You should be familiar with this
This abbreviation
G or
KEV or GV
Anyway, QCD action
Its mass
It has something to do with the constant
Let me tell you in advance
We will mention a kind of action light particle
It's a kind of light particle
It is not satisfied with the above relationship
So that means
Its quality and its
Its decay constant
It has nothing to do with
They are two free parameters
Yes
Then there will be some
There are some operations
Because it is after all two free parameters
Anyway
What's more special
We found that this QCD action
It can not only solve
Strong C problem
It is also a good dark matter candidate
That is to say, I just said
QCD action
When it is very low temperature, it will form a potential
It just happens to be echoing the potential
And just this phenomenon
What about this model
We can
See it as a dark matter
A model
Yes
Then we can
Can I ask a question
Please ask
You just said the temperature in the front page
Is it the temperature of the universe
After the particle
It's Proxima
It's the radiation temperature
Then when is it in the universe
Will
Will reach the TQCD
Hello
How much will the universe temperature reach
That's the TQCD
You mean Lambda QCD
Lambda QCD
TQCD is the same as Lambda QCD
It's almost the same
Maybe a few times
TQCD
Let me see if I remember correctly
More than 100 MeV
Because QCD
The scale of QCD is probably
Hundreds of MeV
It's probably a value
Yes
So TQCD
Is it before inflation
After
When it's low temperature
Is inflation high
Is it before CMB
CMB
Should be earlier
You have to have CMB
Let me see
What is the temperature of CMB
It should be
Are you doing astronomy
Do you remember
I want to think about it
What is the temperature
CMB temperature
I don't remember
It should be a little later
Should
If you want to type EGV
Corresponds to how much temperature
I should check this
OK
Thank you
Ok
The formula above
Of course you don't have to remember it
This is us
Since we theorize that this action
It can form this atocometer when it vibrates
Then we can estimate this
Its energy density
What is the energy density
Then you can use this formula to represent
As long as you know
Omega A in this equation
It's this Omega A again
It represents the energy density of action
So far we have observed that the energy density
It's about 0.1
Or 0.12
So that means this FA
This formula is FA
Roughly it's about
10 to the 12th square
GEV
Basically it can't change
OK
This formula
Is the position of this action
So of course you can
You can adjust this formula
And then you change this FA
But that's more fine-tuning
For example, you can assume that if
The universe
This action
At the beginning of the vibration
It's very close to this
Top of this
Does that mean it will slide slower
If number 5 slides slower
Its energy density will be higher
So this theory
If theta is close to pi
This will contribute a lot
Very big
In this case, this FA
You can make it smaller
Yes, that's a little bit more fine-tuning
But we don't like it
So generally this theta initial
We won't assume it's that big
Generally speaking, this FA
It's close to 10 to the 12th square
GEV
Then it can explain this wind speed
About 0.1
OK
Then let's talk about this action
Why can't we see photons
Generally the same is through this interaction
To describe
Just put this on
It should be the left index of the first line
It's LA Gamma Gamma
Yes, this F is represented by light
Yes, you don't have to remember this
If it's not a theory
You just need to know that this represents
Action and two
The interaction of light
What about the intensity of this interaction
We can use this
GA Gamma Gamma
We call this GA Gamma Gamma
Action Photon Coupling
Then we can find out
This coupling will be with Gamma
This decay constant
It's a contrast
That is to say, if the decay constant is bigger
This coupling is smaller
OK
The one on the bottom right is the so-called
It's used to describe this action
How to interact with the light
That's usually through this
Loop of loop
Induce out
Of course you don't need to know this detail
Sorry
If you want to
That is to say, I just said
QCD action
Can be done
So if you want to meet this
We observe this
What about the energy density
This FA
12 square GV
Then you bring it into this formula
You will find this A Gamma Gamma
It should be about
10 to the negative 10th square
GV inverse
That's great
Because this coupling is small
QCD action
It won't be easy to change into light
So it's not stable
So it's in line with what we just said
One of the properties of dark matter
That's because
This A Gamma Gamma is very small
So in practice
It's not easy to measure it
Of course we can do it again
We can introduce this experiment in the future
Of course there is a chance
it is good
So let me show you this experiment
That's a few
Measurement action
This experiment
This picture was made by my boss
Because it's too beautiful
There are several types
There are indirect and non-indirect
My research
What about my theory
I will focus on this
Direct part
You can see it on the picture
Related words
Like the middle
The one on the second row in the middle
This solar action
Because action will work with light
So we can predict
It may be from this solar system
Then we can use
Maybe it's a telescope
There is a so-called
Or the second one
Or these experiments
Then there is the so-called
Cosmic
Cosmological action
Cosmic action is what we just said
It may be from the early universe
These actions
Then we can use
To measure WIMP
Let's say
It can work with these nuclear principles
Then we will measure these
For example
Because
If the nuclear principle works with this action
It may rebound
There will be some signals
Then we can measure
Related to these experiments
Like the so-called
Or the Casper
On the table
Directly listed
This is the experimental picture
Of course it's a bit complicated
You can see this
This gray band
It is the so-called QCD action
If you want to satisfy it as a document
Then it has to be painted
This red point
So you can see it
Quite close to the so-called
ADMS sensitivity
So there is a chance in the future
ADMS
Perspective
If they can
Improve this sensitivity
Maybe you can measure this
Document
Of course there are other experiments
Like the one I just mentioned
Measure solar action
Its current upper bound is a bit higher
So in the future
They can lower the upper bound
Also have the opportunity
To measure this QCD action
You may see
Another one
This brown
This brown band
This corresponds to the so-called ELF document
Let me go back here
What is ELF document
The same thing
You can go back to the previous one
There is a bunch of
Constraint
I gave a talk a while ago
I can't answer the question
Is it a problem of experiment?
No, it's like this
Because I am
Thermorelic
Then your axiom is not thermorelic
Then there is a person who does astronomy
He asked me
Now this kind of axiom
Or ELF
It's actually a
The relationship between the measurement and the photon coupling
And its mass
Then it's a bit like a positive relationship
A value relationship
It can be extended indefinitely
But how heavy can it be
If it is a document
It can be very heavy
Even the weight of a moon
Then my idea is
It's just very heavy
If it's very heavy, it's very big
Then we should have seen it earlier
But I got an answer
It seems to be
Large-scale structure
There is a constraint
Thermorelic can't be light
Or non-thermal can't be heavy
This is actually
I know a little
You see this in the picture
The quality of the axiom
I just drew this range
In fact
You can't be too light
That is, its current lower bound seems to be
Negative 22eV
This will correspond to
The so-called Fuzzy document
Fuzzy document
This seems to be done by some groups in Taiwan University
In other words, if you
If the document is too light
What to do with this
It's not easy, this material wave is too long
That is, you will become
The magnitude of the universe
These quantum effects came out
Then they do astronomy
It seems to see these
Some small-scale
Differences
So if you
Some constraints
So this
Document can't be too light
Light to negative 22eV
It has some lower bound
But I don't really understand
Where is the upper bound of the axiom
Oh, I know, I see
Basically, as long as it exceeds 10
Negative 10.5
Negative 11
It's all ruled out
Cache
OK, I see
Of course you can lower
This can be very low
But as I said, it can't be too small
it is good
This is actually a very good question
Back to action
Elp
Originally from this
Theoretical theory
For example, we are in the theoretical theory
They predict a lot of action particles
Then we call these action particles
Action light particles
That's the same as taking this
Then I'm in my back pocket
I'll use this
代表
Its nature is exactly the same as this
Just say it
Because it has nothing to do with qcd
So its quality is not from qcd
It's from another
Like the so-called hidden qcd
I don't know how to say it
Hidden is
It's another qcd
Its quality is not direct from this
Our general standard model qcd
That's the same
It can't see the light
Then it can also be
This dark matter candidate
The formula is basically
Very similar to the qcd action
So basically it's exactly the same
It's exactly the same as qcd
The difference is that it
This is with this qcd
The effect has nothing to do with it
Ok
So basically I'm q
Elp's introduction is only one page
It's quite simple
Then we will calculate this
This one
Action with this photon coupling
Then I found that his
It must correspond to this on the map
This brown
This band
So obviously this brown
It's much smaller than this qcd
So of course we hope
If we don't see qcd action
Then there are some extra particles
We can measure
Because it has some motivation
But you have to believe
You have to believe that this theory is right
Of course
Of course it is
That is to say
That is to say you can
Allow this particle to exist
OK
Is there a problem here?
If not, I will
In
So far, it's basically
Action's introduction
That is to say, this thing is basically
Everyone knows
So i
I will start my research later
How to connect action
qcd action with qcd
qcd action
The relationship between qcd and qcd
This is what I will talk about later
Before I finish
Everyone may have a question
Why is it called action?
This is a very interesting story
Does anyone know?
I'm not familiar with action
In fact, I also
I'll check it out later
Because it's really weird
Basically, this story is very simple
Maybe everyone is watching me
My friend
Huang Zhong helped me make a promotional poster
He put a poster
Something like a drink
That's not a drink
That is a cleaner
Why is it called action?
This has a lot to do with this cleaner
That is to say the first
You can see this
I divided this action into two parts
The front is axi
That is to say
We just saw this
qcd
Why does it appear?
Mainly with us in theoretical
ActionCurrentAnomaly
Has a relationship
You just need to know
Connection with
ActionCurrent
You also know
Physics likes to put the name of Paracord
What is it called?
Or Positron
That's the end of ON, right?
So this
What about the Nobel Prize in 2004?
The Wheeljack
He is because of this so-called
Progressive Freedom
This is like
I just quoted his article
He said it directly
Maybe a few years ago he went to the supermarket
He saw this
Cleaner
It looks like a washing powder
He saw the box
Many colors of this
Washing powder
Then he called this washing powder
I immediately realized that this may be a good name
Because the first one
It's the end of ON, and then there's AIX
That has something to do with the axis
The point is that we just introduced the action
The purpose is to put this
qcd
So he wrote here
When I notice a new particle that
Clean up the problem with an action
So he realized that this is a very good name
So he took it
Of course there are other
Others
Think of other names
Like this Weinberg is also a Nobel Prize
He thought of other names
But later this Weinberg also agreed that this action
It's closer
So it's been applied until now
He called it action
Okay, that's just an exaggeration
Just explain a little bit
You will find that physicists
There are quite a few stories about particle names
For example
There is a quark in this table
Does anyone know how quark is named?
Quark is also a Nobel Prize
It's Gilman
He came up with an idea
Then he thought about it for a while
Later he found that it was like reading a novel
This duck in this novel
It seems to be called quack quack quack
He thinks it's good, so he took it
So this
This particle is called quark
Yes, this is very
Very interesting
I can only say that physics sometimes
It's quite unexpected
Then I will put this
The basic introduction of action is finished
If there is no problem
I will introduce the research directly
I will bring the research part very soon
Because it is more detailed and related to time
I'll just talk about it
Just say
It can explain
Can explain this
At the same time
If you believe
Then
Assuming they exist at the same time
In our natural world
We predict what kind of phenomenon it should have
OK
That
If we assume that there is a so-called quality mixing between them
What kind of effect will it have
This time I will give you
Give this answer
This is called level crossing
What is the Chinese translation of level crossing?
Level crossing
This picture is
Assuming that QC action
There is no so-called mixing with this alpha
Without mixing
Green and red lines on the picture
It represents the evolution of their mass
You will find that
This is the first one
Green is QC action
I just said that when it is very low temperature
It has quality, but there is no quality at very high temperature
So its quality evolution
It should be like this green picture
Then alpha, because it has nothing to do with QC effect
So its mass
Let's assume it is constant
Here I have to assume
The mass of alpha must be less than this
Action
At a very low temperature mass
The reason is that
If there is no maxmixing
Nothing happens
If you turn on this maxmixing today
You see this picture
There are some changes
You will find that this green line
It should be going up
It is at a certain time
It suddenly turned to the original
The direction of the alp
The same alp
This is at a very
At a very high temperature
This is its original evolution
But it is still at a certain time
It will run up
Run to the action part
Then we call this phenomenon
Level crossing between QC action and alp
Then this phenomenon
Actually not
Only appeared in my research
If you do
Neutrino mass physics
It is very similar to the so-called Neutrino vibration
Neutrino in matter
There will also be this level crossing phenomenon
Then this is the answer
If you put this maxmixing today
If you turn it on
Then its
There will be a so-called level crossing phenomenon
So if there is a level crossing
We mean
This
QC action and alp
There will be a so-called heat transfer
The so-called heat transfer is
Its particle
Density
Is small
From A to this
This
Diabetic conversion
In Chinese, it may be translated as the heat transfer
There are some conditions
I may need to mention it later
So if this
Ok, this is the answer
So I won't repeat it again
If there is this
We will predict that
The energy density of this action
It will be suppressed
By this maxmixing
Because this
Its energy density is with this
Quality and its particle
The product is the product
So if you have this today
Level crossing
Your QC action
It's very low temperature
It's more like an alp
The alp particle is in front of us
Its energy density is less than this ma
So you can predict that its quality will be
Suppressed by this ratio
Then it's obvious
You will open up some new space
In our research
OK, this is the model part
That's the same
This
On the left of the first line
QC action potential
It's a cosine potential
We just saw a few in the front
It's like a positive potential
Mathematical description
On the right, it's like a description
How to make this action
There is a maxmixing
OK, if you have maxmixing
This
It's not a physical state
We have to do a cross-section
The cross-section process is below
You can see that it is through a rotation matrix
Then this is their eigenvalue
Maybe everyone does
Maybe you are more familiar with eigenvalue
This is the true value
Although I just saw this on the picture
The red line and the green line
The so-called eigenvalue evolution
Then we have to assume
mphi is less than ma
Because it's obvious if you
If this condition is met
This green line
What about this line
Or this red line
Less than this
Green is
Green at
The part of this line
It will have this level crossing
In other words, if the red is far above the green
Obviously, there will be no level crossing
Happening
So this is
eigenvalue evolution
Here I have a special assumption
This
Elp's decay function
To be smaller than this
Qc action
A little bit
This is some mathematical definition
Hello
it is good
Let's talk about the assumption
If you assume
mphi is bigger than ma
You will find this
eigenvalue
There will be a big splitting
In some sense
There is no level crossing
it is good
The picture on the right is
Dynamic
Because of time
This is just a mixed angle formula
You don't have to look at it
Its evolution
This is the evolution of mixed angle
Obviously, you can see
Assuming that the conditions we just talked about
This mixed angle
Just at this level crossing
It will have a big change
On the other hand
In other cases
Did not happen
So we say that the level crossing is in this condition
In this f5
It will have this
Level crossing
Hello
Is there a problem
No
This is a mathematical definition of level crossing
I won't talk about it
Some noise
Is it ok
Ok
Let's talk about this
To meet some of the conditions of absolute conversion
This is qcd
Before that, I will pay attention to qcd
Some of its dynamics
This
On the picture, its equation is
This qcd
Its equation of motion
Its dynamic equation is
Basically, it is a two-dimensional equation
Two-dimensional equation
Ok
On the picture
This is the so-called Hubble parameter
Maybe everyone has heard of this
Hubble constant
Basically, it has something to do with Hubble parameter
This ma
The same is the qcd
Its mass
It has something to do with temperature
At very high temperature
This Hubble parameter is relatively large
So you can ignore this third item
Then you solve it, you will find that it is a
Over-damping solution
That is, at high temperature
Its mass is almost constant
At very low temperature
You can put this second item
This Hubble parameter is ignored
If you ignore the second item
It is a very simple so-called
Over-damping solution
Its equation is getting smaller and smaller
Because the universe is expanding
That's like this picture
For example, when it is very low temperature
It will continue to vibrate
Then its equation is getting smaller and smaller
This is what I just said
When it is very low temperature
It will oscillate near the potential mirror
Roughly speaking, this qc action
Start oscillating
At this Hubble parameter
Roughly equal to this qc action mass
Yes
it is good
If you want to
Calculate this
qc action energy density
Generally, we will define this
So-called actual number
Then calculate it
Actual number is conserved
If it is conserved, it is very good
Because you know that mathematicians like to use this energy to calculate
Anyway
We can solve the equation of motion
We can calculate this
Actual number density
We find that it is constant at very low temperature
That
The reason it is constant is because
It is a
Because this vibration is a decoupling process
The condition of the decoupling process is to satisfy
Its
External time scale is bigger than
Internal time scale
In our system
External time scale is
The oscillation rate of the universe
Or
Or Hubble time
The time of the universe
Internal time scale is
Vibration
Vibration cycle
In other words, if you today
What about this oscillation cycle
For example, this
This
What about the expansion speed
If it is still slow, it is
It is a decoupling process
In this case, this
Actual number will be a conserved
Quantity
Ok
In our system, in our research
Because we have introduced two particles
So the decoupling condition will be a little different
Because
I just said that in level crossing
You will have a big
Big change
Mixed angle
So in fact, we will have an additional internal time scale
We use delta t to represent
Yes, you can use this formula
Write down
What about the so-called internal time scale
In addition to the single action case
We only have one
It's just a
Vibration cycle
If you have two particles
You naturally predict that there will be two oscillation cycles
In addition to that, we will find
We found that there is a third cycle
In other words, if two oscillation cycles today
In the same phase
We identify this as the third cycle
Yes, you can calculate
Is 2π ÷ this mass difference
Between this mass eigenstates
Ok
Then we will require this condition
That is to say
This internal time scale is much larger than this
Internal time scale
Then we can find out this condition
You may not need to remember
Anyway, we can solve this
This in our model
Action number density
This is the result
So
Let's read this picture
Hello
Can you go back to the first two pages
Ok, which page
Go back one page
Next page
Is it forward or backward?
I think we are talking about different directions
I want to ask you
Basically
Your cycle is
Contrary to the mass difference
But the mass scale is already very small
So the mass difference should be smaller
So this thing
Actually
The phase of these two states
For us humans
The time of this experiment
This time
Is about the scale of the ear
It is constant phase, right?
You said mass difference?
You said this mass difference
What is the value of this value?
This delta t
You said this delta t?
How small is this delta t?
I said the oscillation cycle
This cycle
I said this ELP is
EEV
For example, the current universe
For example, 3K
This happened at level crossing
Because we want to discuss
Will there be this so-called absolute conversion at level crossing?
But isn't it still oscillating now?
Or did I misunderstand?
But his mass
We use this picture
For example
This one
For example, you see this green
This is corresponding to
Light mode
It's close to ELP mass
And this heavy mode is close to QCD mass
So it's still vibrating
But there is still energy density
But the vibration is very small
So it's basically just a constant
So you can adjust
It's smaller than QCD
Even if it's QCD axion
You have to move down
Wait for that one
The green one
Is that M5?
The horizontal axis is mass
The vertical axis is photon coupling
The vertical axis is mass
The density is lower
First, density
You are talking about
photon coupling
With mass
I'll mentioned it later
You are talking about
how it can enhance
Because the quality is low
I will see
If you scan out in parameter space
The decay constant
Can be smaller
I'll show the conclusion
Is it an hour?
Anyway, this is
The two actions
The evolution of number density
If you have absolute process condition
I just defined gamma
If gamma is greater than 1
You can have absolute conversion
If you
If gamma is less than 1
You will find the green one will suddenly become
The red one
In this case, the absolute conversion
Is not perfect
You can skip it
Anyway
The result is
If we impose the density
To solve the parameter space
We find
The decay constant of the ELP
Divided by the MFA
In this graph
It can be smaller than 1
The MFA
Can be smaller than
If the MFA is 10 to the power of 12
As I said
If you want to satisfy the density of the object
It should be 10 to the power of 12
In this case, the GA gamma gamma
The front coupling is 10 to the power of 15
So today
The MFA
If the MFA is smaller than 1
It means we will have an enhancement
As we know
As we can see
The coupling is
The decay constant is inversely proportional
So if you can
Reduce the MFA
We expect to have an enhancement
So basically
This is our final result
The result is the color contours on the graph
We found
For example, the red bar
Corresponds to
The MFA is equal to
3 times 12 square GEV
We can
Have a bigger MFA
Because we just talked about
Mass suppression
If you have mass suppression
The MFA can be increased
At the same time
The MFA
The
Elbow decay constant
It can be very small
So it will have an enhancement
It will be higher than the
The middle band
Enhanced by
1000 times or 100 times
This is good
This mechanism
Can be
Measured by
Solenoid action
It can be measured
This is our model
Advantage
This is the conclusion
I think
This is a more detailed part
That's about it
Any questions
Before you ask questions
First of all
Let's applaud
Thank you for your speech
Do you have any questions?
You can ask questions now
This is a theoretical thing
Can you hear me
Yes
Then
Your theory is very interesting
We have an experiment
About two or three years later
There may be some preliminary results
Which experiment are you doing
We have an experiment with LC circuit
Can you hear me
Can you repeat your question
No
Just a little bit
Try again
Sorry
Your theory is very interesting
We have an experiment
At Los Alamos
Can measure your 10 to 7
To 10 to minus 10
EV range
Maybe two or three years later
Yes
Your value range is also
Just your range
10 to 7
10 to minus 10 EV range
My question is
Is your value range the same as the picture?
Almost
Almost the same
That's not bad
You can test your theory
But I have a question
Do you consider
If it is two
Then you will have like
Neutrino oscillation
Yes, there will be such a phenomenon
This is also a possibility
I mentioned this to the boss
But he probably means
It should be the same phenomenon
If you add one more x
Like particle
You said it wouldn't change
Will there be a stronger enhancement
There may be a stronger enhancement
Yes
Our mechanism is
But we didn't say
You can consider more complex models
I agree
OK
Thank you
Do you have any questions?
Hello
I have a simple question
Just now
You were talking about
Axiom can handle CP
Strong CP problem
My network is a bit of a problem
So I don't seem to hear it clearly
Can you say it again?
Sorry
You said how to solve strong CP problem
Go back
This is strong CP problem
This is
In QCD, we can choose this term
Yes, basically
Just add a particle
In this term
And then
When it's very low temperature
This
Axiom will fall to this potential minima
This is called
It's also vacuum
It's the vacuum of the axiom
This vacuum can just cancel out this CP term
So this will disappear
If this disappears
It's very small
So it can be explained
Why the upper bound is so small
10-11-2
So it's very simple
Just a cancellation
I see
I'm from NingTai
Now there are many
People
They said they want to be in NingTai
Find this axiom in the range
They mainly do
What I want to do is
Find a normal insulator
And a topological insulator
On their boundary
Their
Maxwell equation
There will also be this theta term
But
On the boundary
Theta term
Must be integer or semi-integer
This is
For this integer semi-integer theta
Does it make any sense in high energy?
Or is it actually
It's important
How much is this theta
It doesn't matter at all
Because this theta is a
How to say
You can't say it's not important
But some people know this
You said it's 2π or 2π
Yes, it's integer semi-integer
Think about it
Ok
I can't think of anything special
Let me see
But here
This is a different theta
There is another theta here
Confused
This is a different theta
Not this
Different theta
This theta is basically
Is to cancel something
In high energy
Axiom can also be seen as
Boundary
Is it related to boundary effect?
Um
Wow
There is
Related to boundary
But it should not be your
Topological boundary
Why is this theta term
Because I just talked about
Axiom
For example, the electrical effect is
Vector current
Do you know
Axiom current
Passive integral
Boundary term is
Non-managed
Um
So it's actually related to boundary
But not your boundary
Oh ok
I'm sure
I'm not familiar with
Your boundary
Yes
Actually
There should be a correspondence
But I'm not familiar with your boundary
Anyway, this term is actually
From that you
That
Passive integral
EMM
What is EMM
This is QCD
QCD
That
Volume
You can change it to a surface
Yes
Ok
Thank you
Do you have any questions?
That
Say something
I used to be with
Teacher Cui
That
Sorry
I want to interrupt you
You might want
Do you turn on the sound at the same time
Then turn on the microphone again
Because your response is quite big
You may have to adjust it to see if you know
What's the situation
If you are using headphones
You can turn it into a standard headset or not
Try using headphones or something
Otherwise you can't hear it
Can you try again
Sorry
I'm trying
Ok
It's almost the same
You can only hear it if you speak a little slower
Sorry
I mean
That is
I am also in Taiwan University
That
So let me add
That is about
The best quality
Can you tell me
Hey
Actually, I didn't hear it clearly
it is good
Hey
That response is quite big
I didn't hear what you said
Hey
Let's give him time to adjust
Or you can also type
Does anyone else have a problem
Of course
Wait for me to talk a little
I don't know where it is
But this kind of thing
This concept has been developed for a long time
This is not a new thing
But in recent years
Maybe Wimper's experiments
May be recorded in the future
I guess
Do you have any comments
Don't say that
We don't want to lose our jobs
Isn't your philosophy to explore
No
Just kidding
I personally have no opinion
I personally feel
Things that can be tested should be tested as much as possible
This has data
I think so
Just now
Please say
Hey
Did someone talk just now
Let me talk
Because
It seems that Action has started to pop up again in recent years
Experiments seem to be
Because I remember that there were quite a few experiments at the German conference
Improving their sensitivity
Japan has also started to do it recently
Because the mainstream in Japan
Is Sucy
But because of LC
Can't see
So now
Sucy
Start to be more visual
Of course people are still doing it
So Action may be
In the next few years
A public topic
Just now
The previous
Collaborator
I may not have heard it clearly
Hello, can you hear me now
Try again
You say
You just say
Let's see if we can hear you
So
I want to talk about
Action
OK
Thank you
Just say
Like this
You can measure
Your
Things
How many
If the mass of Action is too low
His
Will smooth out
Smaller
So
It will be measured
It's not the same as the actual measurement
So
The mass
Is not
Oh
I remember it wrong
Do you say 10-24 EV
I heard the speech
10-22
Because
Other
A little bit
Alpha
You can use
Galaxy
Measure his mass
This is another observation
Some other observations
The output is like this
OK
But
The
Low limit is
24 or 23
24 or 23 OK
Thank you
OK
Do you have any questions
You say
I want to ask the question
Is with the other
Do you have any questions
You ask
I heard you ask
He just said that
What is his material
There will be
U1
The battery
That's why
High-end words
Is the battery
There is no
He is U1
U1
You can
There is no
Do you have any simple views
Wait a minute
U1
Is it related to the battery
Wait a minute
Battery
Are you Li Zhaolong
Yes
I think it should be
Because this question seems to have been discussed with you before
U1 can give
What do you say
U1 can
U1 does not have this
Only
I don't know if this is
Related to others
U1
U1 can take it off
I can ask
The neighbor
The question
Is that student still there
I want to ask
Hello
I am
You just said that
Is in the material
There will be
E.B
Related to Torb
That object
Why in that case
Abelian
Why is this car still there
Should be
I'm not very clear
But in that
Topological insulator
Boundary
It is indeed
Non-Abelian
The reason
I'm not sure
You really look at those
It's the Hamiltonian
Those
It is non-Abelian
It should be related to this
If I remember correctly
But
I'm doing experiments
I'm not very clear
Why is this
Thank you
Ok
That
I can trouble
Can you go back to your first page
The first page of the video
This
It's really a cover
That
Because
Most of what I said today is
Then there is a framework
In fact, the details
He has already voted in the archive
1806095551
Of course you can go
Look at this paper
You can also find the way to contact He Shuyu
So if you want to contact He Shuyu
Is to discuss the details
Then please contact him in person
Then our speech today
Everyone applaud again
Thank you He Shuyu
That Tina
You can stop recording
If you are still there