Hello, everyone. Welcome to this week's TerraTalk.
I am the host for this week, Lin Yu-Wei.
I am very happy to invite our speaker today, Zhou Zhijie.
He obtained a master's degree in electrical engineering at NTU,
and is currently a doctor of electrical engineering at the University of California, Lincoln.
Under the guidance of Professor Dai Yu-Chang,
he has been conducting research on wearable devices and biomimics for medical purposes.
Today's topic is the application of wearable technology and personal health management.
Let's give a round of applause to welcome Zhijie and his speech today.
Remember to turn on the microphone.
Now let's give the microphone to our speaker today, Zhijie.
Thank you, Yu-Wei, for the introduction.
Hello, everyone. I am Zhou Zhijie.
Today's topic is the application of wearable technology and personal health management.
Without further ado, let's get to the topic.
First of all, I would like to introduce to you
why wearable devices have become a hot topic in recent years.
Basically, it can be divided into several aspects.
The first is the concept of non-invasive.
The concept of non-invasive means that the device does not need to enter our body.
You may have been to the hospital for injections or blood draws.
Once something enters your body, the first reaction is pain.
In addition to the pain, the immune system will also react to foreign bodies.
For example, some white blood cells or other immune cells will attack foreign objects.
Basically, it will cause a lot of inflammation, swelling, pain, and heat.
Therefore, wearable devices basically avoid such risks.
Many technology giants like Apple and Fitbit
want to study non-invasive devices first
and see where their limits can be pushed.
Then they will consider the so-called minimally invasive devices.
In fact, there is a huge barrier between non-invasive and minimally invasive.
Whether it is from the perspective of devices or from the perspective of government agencies like the FDA,
the biggest barrier is still entering the body.
Once you enter the body, there is a lot of risk.
Stay outside the body is a very low-risk device.
Basically, wearable devices have become so popular recently.
Next is the so-called big clinical data.
I believe everyone has heard of big clinical data.
The meaning of big clinical data is that this device can provide some diagnostic information.
This diagnosis is also a bit tricky.
How can we determine the value of the diagnosis?
What metrics are really useful?
The third part is the so-called Autonomous Sensing.
Autonomous Sensing is not as complicated as you think.
Just put the wearable device on your body and it will automatically start to measure.
Then you don't need to intervene.
Then it can continuously send this data out in a wireless way.
The advantage is that even if you are not conscious, for example, when you are sleeping,
this device can still continue to measure and send the data out.
So it can let us see some things that we couldn't see before.
For example, when you are sleeping, it can help you measure the cycle of sleep,
or the heartbeat when you are resting, and so on.
The fourth aspect is that it is very easy to compare with portable devices,
such as mobile phones, smartphones, or even tablets.
Basically, these portable devices can be used as a relay station.
You can imagine that your wearable sensor is a bit like a place to send signals.
Then store these signals in the portable device.
Basically, the computing power of these portable devices is relatively strong,
and the bandwidth to upload data is relatively high.
On the one hand, it can be used as a relay station, and on the other hand,
it can be used as a place to send signals.
There are a lot of benefits that you can think about.
Next, I will talk about the logic of why we want to use wearable devices
to monitor the health of our body.
There is a study in Stanford,
which is called digital health.
It is a comparison of regular visits to the hospital
and digital health.
The so-called digital health is actually
collecting all the data that should be collected at the hospital,
digitizing it,
and then processing these digitized data.
This study is actually very simple.
There are only two main variables.
One is to measure the skin temperature,
and the other is to measure the heart rate.
If I put the sensor on the patient
for a long time,
the patient will inevitably get sick.
The heart rate and skin temperature
when the patient is sick
are basically the same.
The heart rate and skin temperature
The wearable sensor has some information in it.
How do we get this information out?
We have big clinical data.
It takes about 24 hours to get this data.
It can be useful when you sleep.
Heart rate...
It's basically when you wake up.
Can you tell if a person is healthy or sick?
It's from the data we get from these sensors.
For example, a disease has a certain distribution in the data space of this sensor.
So this is a very interesting question.
Before wearable devices appeared,
it was basically completely blank.
The information we can get in Sleep is very limited.
However,
there are some privileges at this stage of sleep.
For example, when you sleep, your body basically doesn't move.
It's great for sensors.
Because you have less noise in your daily life.
For example, your motion noise.
Or when you do other things during the day, your heart rate suddenly changes.
But when you sleep, it doesn't.
Some wearable sensors are already measuring
heart rate during rest and sleep.
I'll show you some data later.
Location
It mainly depends on where our sensors can be placed in the body.
This is a research done by Georgia Tech.
It looks at how the motion impedance is affected
when your sensors are placed in various parts of the body.
The motion impedance is when your sensors are placed in a specific body location.
What impact does it have on your activity?
On the left is the male, on the right is the female.
You can see that the range is a little different.
You can see where our wearable devices are often placed.
For example, the bowl.
It's a good place to put it.
This is another metric.
It tells us
what sensor is most suitable for measuring
when it is placed in a specific location.
For example,
the red bar
is used to measure whole body motion.
It measures the movement of the whole body.
You can imagine that your limbs are often moving.
But if you want to track the center of the body,
the red bar is used to measure the center of the body.
For example, the joint stretch
is measured by the elbow and the knee joint.
The last one is
where the sensor is placed.
This is interesting.
You can compare it with the two pictures.
For example, many devices are placed in the wrist
or ankle.
Next, I will talk about
the future of wearable devices.
The trend is like this.
From the era of personal computers,
the market trend is to reduce the size of the computer.
From personal computers to portable devices,
to wearable devices.
The so-called computing unit
is getting closer to the body.
The advantage is that you don't need much delay
to make computing.
This is the size of the market of wearable devices.
At first, the market size was the largest.
But when Apple Watch appeared,
it appeared around the middle of 2015.
It immediately ate up the market share.
From 2016 to 2017,
the largest was Apple Watch.
The largest was Apple Watch.
The next is the trend I imagine.
From 2000, the so-called smartphone has appeared.
In 2010, the first generation of wearable devices began to appear.
PPG is a method of optical heart detection.
Motion is basically an accelerometer.
ECG is a heart rate map.
Blood pressure is basically easy to get information.
In the next 10 years,
there may be some new wearable devices.
Although it is a class 2 device,
it is not the simplest medical device.
It is not the simplest medical device.
It is not as invasive as class 3.
In this case,
it is not suitable for medical use.