Hello everyone, my name is Wu Mengchang, and I am a student at Mata University.
What I want to talk about today is about 4-way mixing and squeeze light.
If you have any questions at any time, you can ask, just turn on your microphone.
My field is in the field of atomic physics, which is relatively low-energy physics.
Our research unit is JQI, which is the United States Department of State.
It is a rather special institution, which is under the Department of Commerce in the United States.
Although they don't sound like they are doing this kind of specialized research,
they have actually won four Nobel Prizes in atomic physics.
So it's a pretty special national standard.
My instructor is Paul Leitz.
Our main source of research funding is from the Air Force in the United States.
At the beginning, I want to let everyone know what squeezing means.
We want to compress all the information into a better measurement.
After watching the video, let's get down to business.
The experiment we are doing now is using laser light.
The characteristic of laser light is that it is a coherent state.
What is a coherent state?
I don't know if you've heard of it.
I'm sure you've heard of the non-coherent principle.
The non-coherent principle tells us that we can't...
We used to think that the results of delta x and delta t must be greater than h-bar.
We can imagine that our laser light has a so-called non-coherent property.
Non-coherent property means that it has its government amplitude and its horizontal axis.
Both of these can't be measured very accurately in practice.
That is to say, it has its limits.
You can see that when our laser light is in coherent state,
Basically, it's always in coherent state.
When it's in coherent state, you'll see its...
Its FN or phase fluctuation is actually...
Its result is in...
That is to say, the curve on the left represents the line that meets the non-coherent principle.
Mathematically, we know that when your delta...
My y-axis is delta e, and my x-axis is delta phi.
If these two variables are in the minimum value,
When the two are equal, they are actually in their so-called minimum value.
Laser light is when these two values are equal.
Then it presents such a coherent state.
So what is Squeeze state?
Squeeze state means that you can...
That is to say, we don't need to measure all the information of laser light very accurately.
We can say that we just need to measure the phase very accurately.
Or we can measure our government very accurately.
When you see that your phase is measured very accurately,
In fact, it still meets its non-coherent principle.
Then it will lead to the inaccuracy of your government.
It will become very large.
Then your phase can be measured very accurately.
So a while ago, probably the year before last,
Isn't there a gravity wave measurement experiment?
It is to use this Squeeze light to throw away your impurities.
I will talk about quantum impurities.
Because you are in coherent state.
Then go to the limits of quantum mechanics.
Then push it to compress it so that you can measure the phase very accurately.
Then they may have a so-called interferer.
Then the interferer can measure the phase of something.
If the gravity wave passes over the earth,
Then you can measure the phase of this gravity wave.
There will be some changes.
As long as you have a way to enter this Squeeze state,
You can let a certain frequency of the phase be able to measure it very accurately.
Because the gravity wave passes through like this,
So its frequency will be very weak.
If you are very weak, your impurities will be very strong.
You need to have a way to get rid of this impurity.
Then measure to the phase you want.
But what we did in the experiment,
We did another one.
We are so-called Two-Mode Squeezing.
Two-Mode Squeezing is to say,
I'm producing two intangles of light.
That is to say, I now have some special light and non-linear effects.
Then produce two intangles.
What about these two intangles?
Some of their signals are exactly the same.
So if I input a light,
That light is called Probe.
Then it will produce its oscillation.
It uses a Twin Beam.
These two lights have each other.
For example, there is quantum co-relative.
That is, quantum co-relative.
Quantum co-relative.
So when I can put these two lights together,
I can get another one called Intensity Difference.
That is to say, I can let my Intensity Difference,
to measure the noise of this two-mode intensity is the lowest.
This may be a bit abstract.
I'll show you some data later.
If you don't quite understand, you can ask me again.
The preliminary introduction is,
I spent 20 minutes to introduce what happened.
I have introduced the background knowledge needed at the beginning.
If no one has any questions, I will continue.
OK.
How do we make this?
Excuse me.
You just said that the intangles,
How is it produced?
Is it also produced by something?
Is it produced by intangles?
We don't use intangles.
We use Rubidium Vapor.
Rubidium is a 2A group.
The Rubinium Nitrate.
Rubinium Nitrate.
We will hit a very strong laser beam.
This strong laser beam will have a non-linear interaction with a very weak beam.
Then produce another conjugate,
another intangle beam.
How are they produced?
I will introduce a little later.
How do they produce this twin beam?
I want to talk about 4-Way Missing.
4-Way Missing.
Total is 4 beams.
But we only put 2 beams in.
Then 3 beams will be produced.
There will be a more detailed explanation of the pattern later.
How is this produced?
Thank you.
Can I ask a question?
What is 4WM?
4 is 4.
W is 4-Way Missing.
Or translated into Chinese,
it is 4-Way Missing.
4-Way Missing.
I should say that it is the abbreviation of this.
My standard abbreviation.
Does it mean that 4 waves are mixed together?
Yes.
But you only have 2 beams.
I will show you a picture of the conjugate later.
Then everyone will be confused.
Did you just say that these 2 beams are added or subtracted?
Added.
Because they are...
Actually, they said that the intensity of the beam is 1.
Then the intensity of the beam will have a magnification ratio.
The magnification ratio is G.
So the light coming out is G.
Then the other conjugate beam is G-1.
So they even put that...
Originally it was Coherent State.
If it has a magnification effect,
it will become Thermal State.
That is to say, it is no longer the original laser beam.
It is a very messy light.
After the two conjugates are subtracted,
you will see the effect of the twin.
They become very messy together.
But when they are subtracted,
they will see that they are actually very beautiful and become messy together.
OK, thank you.
May I ask a question?
So what is the power of these laser beams?
My pump power is about 750mW.
It's quite big.
Of course, it can't be compared to super fast light.
We are continuous wave.
OK, you also answered my second question.
Sorry, let's continue.
The result we did is...
There is a relatively influential improvement.
Our previous records have always been in the range of Kilohertz.
When you want to look at the magnification compression,
the lower the frequency,
the greater the interference in other environments.
For example, you walk over there.
Or you have a call coming in.
These may have some interference in your system.
Then it will cause you to be unable to see the so-called squeeze light at a very low frequency.
That is, the compression of the magnification.
Even if there is a car driving on the main road,
it will have a great impact.
So our lab is doing experiments in such a deep basement.
Our result is...
Anyway, our previous records have always been in the range of Kilohertz.
In recent years, we have broken through the following three orders.
From Kilohertz down to about 1,000 times to a few Hertz.
You can see the effect of the magnification compression.
Especially like the gravitational wave measurement I introduced at the beginning.
It must be seen at a very low frequency.
Because theoretical mathematicians have calculated the magnitude of the gravitational wave.
So if you can only see the squeeze light of Kilohertz,
you can't use it to do these gravitational wave measurements.
So in the past ten years,
this squeeze light has been developed in such a way that it can still have this effect at a very low frequency.
In the future, it will be possible to measure the gravitational wave.
In the result of our experiment,
there will be some applications in image processing.
Because you want to see if you can pass the image through a very weak light.
Then maybe you can do some biological experiments.
A lot of low light hits your sample.
Then you can get rid of these impurities.
Then you can see the signal very clearly.
So it has some applications in biology.
Then it can even do some correction.
And it's a quantum correction.
Then I will continue to introduce it later.
This is our 4-way missing.
So on the right, we are.
This is our wafer cell.
I drew the picture like this.
The length of this wafer cell is about two centimeters long.
Then the diameter is about an inch.
Anyway, it's a very small cell.
Then you put a very strong pump beam in.
Then the strength of this pump beam is about 450 mW.
Then it will interact with the other very weak beam.
Then you look at the link map on the left.
There are a lot of links in it.
But we only care about the link that we will call.
This lambda type link.
It should be quite common to do quantum computing.
There may be something very famous in quantum computing.
It's called EIT.
Slow light storage technology.
Basically, it's quite similar to that.
For example, you hit a very strong pump beam.
Very strong pump beam.
Then it will interact with your probe beam.
Then this very strong pump beam.
It also interacts with the ground state on the other side.
Then because of energy conservation.
So it releases the fourth conjugate beam.
So you only hit two beams in.
But in a continuous operation.
It actually acts like there are four waves interacting with each other.
Two of the four waves are the same pump beam.
So this pump beam is at the same time as these two ground states.
What you want to see is that.
In addition to energy conservation.
It actually has to meet the other momentum conservation.
Then we usually don't talk about momentum conservation.
We also talk about phase matching.
In other words, this wave pump beam.
In addition to interacting with the probe beam.
The momentum inside.
That is to say, the pump beam and the probe beam have a very small angle.
About 0.3, 0.4 degrees.
Then we have four waves.
So the total momentum of this pump beam.
There will be two.
Then it will produce another conjugate beam.
So it's in the other direction.
Then you see.
When you have any phase fluctuation.
Or any frequency fluctuation.
It has to meet this.
Momentum energy conservation rate.
So any fluctuation has to make it consistent.
So this is a bit.
This is a more general way to explain.
Because they have to be energy conservative.
Momentum conservation.
So any fluctuation.
The fluctuations must be consistent.
In order to meet this condition at the same time.
That's how it produces the twin beam.
This is some of our experimental conditions.
Then you will see this delta.
Big delta.
This big delta is about 1.3GHz.
It's a pretty far detune.
Because of our experiment.
In fact, our entire group is called.
Laser cooling and tracking.
Our group is called.
Laser cooling and tracking team.
Research team is like this.
One of us.
Our big boss is.
We have a big boss.
Then there are four teachers below.
Then I did this.
The only thing is to do it with heat source.
This heat source is about 120°C.
We have to heat it up.
Then let it become a vapor.
So at the beginning, someone just asked.
Are we using crystal or what?
We are not using crystal.
If you use crystal.
There are other.
Also doing.
Or doing that kind of twin beam.
In fact, they are doing single mode.
Anyway, crystal can also be used to do that.
Squeeze line.
But.
Anyway, some principles are still a bit different.
We might use.
K3 is the third stage.
If it is crystal, it may be K2.
There are some differences in nature.
That's right.
Then the next one is.
We are several.
This one is about ten years ago.
Experimental results.
That.
You will see that.
Ten years ago.
We actually used TESAFA laser.
To do this experiment.
That.
TESAFA laser is.
Its feature is that it is very expensive.
That's about.
One or two decades ago.
We.
Buy a TESAFA.
About.
More than 200,000 dollars.
Then now it is more than 200,000.
Or its.
Power becomes stronger.
That's right.
You see.
The company is doing this experiment.
You need to have one.
Very expensive.
TESAFA laser.
More than 200,000 dollars.
This.
This is not practical at all.
So.
We started to develop.
Cheaper.
Then again.
It is a dilutable.
Laser light source.
That's it.
What about the TESAFA laser we used at the beginning?
Go again.
When doing this low-frequency quantization.
There is a.
Ah.
Should I talk about this first?
Experimental map.
What does it mean?
That is.
Here you will see the blue line here.
The blue line here is the so-called shot noise.
Then I just started.
Not to say.
Laser light.
It is coherent state.
What about coherent state?
In fact.
One of its features is that.
Its impurities.
Will not change.
According to the frequency of your measurement.
That is to say.
You are measuring.
You are now inserting a light.
This.
This picture has pink.
This light.
Insert.
Then you use this photodial.
To detect this.
Then send it in.
Spectrum analyzer.
That is.
Spectrum.
Spectrum analyzer.
That.
This spectrum analyzer will tell you.
This.
How much is the impurity of the frequency of this light?
If you insert this light.
It's a laser.
It's a coherent state.
Its impurities.
Will not change.
According to the frequency of your measurement.
Just like this blue light.
The blue.
The curve is like this.
We insert a light.
Then use a beam splitter.
Divide this light into half.
Then divide it into half.
Then subtract these two.
Then do the measurement of this impurity.
Then why do these two subtract?
Because.
You can also.
You can only measure one light.
That is.
You can also get a similar answer.
It's just the impurity power.
If you measure one light.
The impurity power will be halved.
If you measure two lights.
The impurity power will be doubled.
That's it.
There is another one.
The reason we want to divide it into two lights.
That is.
In fact, although the laser light is a coherent state.
But it's in the low frequency.
There are all kinds of impurities.
Will come in.
If you don't use two lights.
You can't put those.
The so-called classical impurity.
Or the technical impurity.
Eliminate it.
So you have to use.
Use one light.
Divide it into two.
Then do the subtraction.
Then measure the impurity.
This is the so-called.
I will talk about it later.
It is the so-called shot noise.
It's called the mega shot.
Its frequency.
It should always be flat.
This is a.
Our field is a very.
Ah.
I didn't know this was a common thing before I came in.
Then now.
Okay, this is the coherent state.
The impurity must be.
The so-called.
The so-called two-color frequency has changed.
So it's the so-called shot noise.
What about the red light?
This is what I just produced.
Glow beam.
I am not.
I am now.
To be more specific.
The setting of our experiment is to say.
I hit a pump beam.
Then.
Hit another glow beam.
Then these two.
Intensity.
The pump beam.
Its intensity is about 10,000 times as strong as the glow beam.
Yes.
Then it goes through this non-linear.
Element.
The element plus.
After the effect.
It will produce this glow beam.
This glow beam is amplified.
Yes.
Then it will also produce another one.
Conjugate beam.
So they are a twin.
Then after these two lights are cut off.
I call it.
Intensity.
Difference.
Squeezing.
Or in other words, it is squeeze.
In other words, it is squeeze light.
Then these two lights.
That is to say.
We will.
To control the light of this input.
Then let the power of the output light.
With these two lights.
The power of these two shot noise lights is exactly the same.
Then you will see.
When we.
If I have the so-called.
Squeeze light.
My two intensity.
Difference.
This is weaker than my shot noise.
Sorry.
Let me ask.
So the frequency of your four lights should be.
What is the range?
Because.
So the frequency below you should be.
The frequency of the big noise.
Right?
Ah.
It should not be called big noise.
Because these two.
The frequency of these two lights is different.
Yes.
You look at the left picture.
Have you seen this cross-section?
Yes.
So you have two pink lights.
Is it a wave of visible light?
He.
In fact, he is a distant infrared light.
Light of 795nm.
Ah.
Yes.
So that.
That is also right.
A few hundred terahertz.
Right?
Yes.
So you.
So you just.
The next page.
That one.
Um.
The following frequency is kilohertz.
Is it the difference between the two?
My.
The problem is.
Is.
The frequency on both sides.
You.
You want to see.
You have a side wave now.
Correct.
Then this side wave has a side wave frequency.
Right?
But I.
I am now.
I.
I'm talking about.
These noise.
To do.
Negative analysis.
Of.
Noise frequency.
Not to say.
My whole side wave.
What is the frequency?
Not this frequency.
But this noise.
He has his own frequency.
He has.
So.
So you just.
Your next page.
The noise.
Spectrum is.
These noise.
Spectrum.
Not the light itself.
Yes.
That is.
His noise.
Just make sure.
Um.
Good.
Thank you.
Continue.
Because like.
Light.
Light has his.
His distribution.
So.
Anyway, he.
He actually.
He.
There will be a.
Distribution of noise.
That.
If it is.
His distribution of noise.
That is to say.
His frequency.
The noise.
The power should be the same.
This.
That.
Uh.
Here.
For missing noise.
That is.
I.
I do.
Intensity difference.
When.
The noise.
That.
Uh.
Db to.
Units.
Every three db is.
Cut in half.
That is.
So that means.
You look at this.
Red.
This.
Blue.
The 8db that is.
Every three db is cut in half.
These 3db is half.
Another half.
So, the rest of the 8th.
is.
About.
10 percent.
The noise only.
That is.
If i originally had.
This.
The noise of the laser beam.
If i was 1.
That red.
The noise of this kernel.
Only left.
Original.
Only 17%.
That is.
Its noise is.
In fact, it is very weak.
That's right.
The focus here.
Is to say.
You can see that.
Hey.
At low frequency.
There are some small peaks here.
In fact, this small peak is.
This.
Very expensive.
There is a very stupid.
The disadvantages of the TESLA-5 laser.
Because it has cavities inside.
That this cavity will.
Causing it to have these resonance.
The noise comes out.
So.
When you are at low frequency.
Will be affected by these cavities.
You can't see it.
Very low frequency.
The compression of quantum noise.
That's right.
Let's say.
Ah.
We are.
When doing experiments.
Sometimes put the laser.
Will lock the laser.
What does it mean to lock the laser?
Is to make its frequency fixed.
Will not float around.
Or.
Is to make its bandwidth narrow.
The meaning of narrow bandwidth.
That is to say.
I have a sine now.
Is your sine a very simple sine?
Or is your sine.
Sine or.
There is a flat sine.
That is to say.
This flat.
That's what I'm talking about.
Right.
This is flat.
Correct.
Ah.
Probably like this.
So.
There is a picture here.
That is to say.
Let's measure the TESLA-5.
More than 200,000 dollars.
TESLA-5 laser.
When the line width.
You will find that.
This blue dash 9.
Is.
That is.
When we do experiments.
We just.
Anyway, just hit the light.
Hit in.
Fiber.
Then go.
To measure its.
Line width.
Correct.
You will see that it is probably.
Maybe a few.
Hundreds or dozens of kHz.
Ah.
The blue dash 9.
Its width is probably.
Maybe dozens of kHz.
So.
So narrow.
It's pretty beautiful.
But.
When we lock up the laser.
It becomes.
More noisy.
This is.
The disadvantage of TESLA-5 laser is.
You lock up.
In fact.
Your.
Your frequency is fixed.
But.
The quality of your laser.
Is getting worse.
Correct.
Then you have to put it.
Line width becomes narrower.
In fact.
It will be quite complicated.
Then we look at another.
Red curve.
This red curve is.
The red line is.
2G TESLA.
Then you haven't locked up.
It's like this.
It's dash 9.
Red dash 9.
Is.
About a few.
Megahertz.
So wide.
But when we lock up.
After.
This is the red line.
It becomes very narrow.
It's probably a few.
Probably.
Even less than.
A kHz.
So narrow.
Line width.
So.
For 2G TESLA.
It may be.
Our TESLA.
2G TESLA.
Probably.
So.
Relative to.
Compared with TESLA.
It's a lot cheaper.
Probably.
One TESLA.
You can buy.
About nine.
2G TESLA.
Like this.
But 2G TESLA.
It's actually.
Its.
Light is weaker.
Correct.
Then this is another team.
In.
Australian.
Experimental research.
Then he is.
I just forgot who asked.
Is.
They are using.
Crystal.
To do.
Then their method.
Not called.
O.
P.
What is it?
Important.
Correct.
This is.
Another way to use.
To do.
Squeeze line.
Then they.
This.
This picture on the left.
You see this black.
This.
This straight line.
The so-called.
Shot noise.
I just said.
Laser light noise.
Then you see.
There are other.
Very messy line.
There are red lines.
Blue line.
Red line.
Black line.
Blue line.
Then you see.
There is a power here.
That is to say.
His power.
From 6.
Microwave.
Down to.
0.7.
Microwave.
Down to a few.
Power.
When.
You see.
His.
Miscellaneous.
Low frequency.
When.
Getting weaker and weaker.
Correct.
That.
In fact, this piece of paper.
He.
I don't know.
Why.
Will be like this.
They are.
A record.
That is to say.
They can.
Do.
Squeeze line.
Then.
It's under 280 Hz.
That.
In fact.
We already know.
Why.
Correct.
Then he.
Here because.
It's also his own problem.
So there will be some.
Some.
Peak.
Noise.
Is particularly strong.
Of course.
These are not important.
The point is.
He can be very low.
Very low frequency.
More than 200 Hz.
Can still.
There is.
The effect of compression.
That.
Blue line.
With.
Not.
The red line and the black line.
Is.
At low frequency.
Because there are a lot of.
Classic noise.
Basic noise.
It's hard to see.
Noise compression.
Effect.
Especially.
When he.
When the bubble is very strong.
Correct.
That.
This.
Next.
These are.
That.
Is.
Go.
To.
Next weekend.
To go to California.
The meeting.
The main content of the report.
Correct.
That.
Is.
Our.
For missing.
Setup.
Is.
The device of time.
We have a.
Second-level thunderstorm.
That.
Is very cheap.
Not very cheap.
Is about.
$20,000 to $30,000.
Then we put.
Part of the light.
Out.
Then.
Double pass LN.
Why.
Because.
This LN.
Is.
About 1.5GHz.
He will put.
Light frequency.
Shift.
1.5GHz.
That.
You put it.
Reflect it again.
After coming back.
You will get.
About.
3GHz.
Shift.
That.
3GHz.
Shift.
With me.
The front.
This connection.
You see.
Pink.
This is my original light.
Pump beam.
That.
I double pass LN.
Then I got.
Pump beam.
Then.
We can start.
Experiment.
But.
This is just my.
In fact.
Pump beam.
Generate.
The way.
Then we put.
Part of the light.
Out.
That.
Part of the light.
Is.
To lock the laser.
That.
This is.
Variation.
Spectroscopy.
One.
Locking the laser.
Light wave.
The way.
That.
You may.
More often.
But.
It's another way.
In fact, this way.
Variation.
Spectroscopy.
Is.
Very easy.
That.
It's very simple.
You can go.
Your laser beam.
That.
Light wave.
Make it.
Very low.
Low to.
Hundreds of.
Hundred hertz.
Right.
That.
It's pretty good.
The way.
That.
If you have any questions.
You can.
You can continue to ask.
Anyway.
We put this.
Locking.
Signal.
Send it back.
Secondary laser.
Control current.
Then you can.
Its.
The thread of the laser.
Shorten it.
That.
In fact.
These are not difficult.
This experiment.
Probably.
If you want to set it up.
As long as.
One.
Month.
You can set it all up.
Right.
That.
Like our group.
A lot.
Doing PTC.
That.
Probably.
More than three or four years.
Not necessarily.
Right.
So this experiment.
Relatively.
Very.
Very simple.
Then we.
After the laser is locked.
We're going to take.
Another one.
Light.
There are about 30.
Minimum.
Light.
Put it in.
Amplifier.
This amplifier.
Also.
Relatively.
Very cheap.
This amplifier.
Only.
$3,000.
Right.
So.
The whole laser system.
Less.
Less than $30,000.
Right.
So.
For.
Taiwan.
Want to do this experiment.
Actually.
Is.
It's very likely.
That is to say.
You don't have to.
Spend $270,000.
To send.
One.
You can do this experiment.
Right.
Then you usually have to do.
Non-linear.
Light-emitting experiments.
You usually need.
Very strong laser light.
Of course.
Then the light source is good.
Then you will use.
Laser.
But.
We don't need it now.
We just need a.
Diode laser.
This magnifier.
This magnifier is called.
Tap Amplify.
You can get it.
Like.
Like the old TESLA.
The same strong light.
Is.
The light of 2W.
Right.
Then we put.
Just now.
The light of our double-paste LED.
This is called.
Probe.
Hit in.
Our.
Lubidium cell.
Then there is.
120 degrees C.
So high temperature.
Then combine.
This magnifier.
Tap Amplify.
The light released.
Then actually.
I just said.
This magnifier.
It is.
2W.
Output.
But.
In fact.
We really send in.
Only 750 mW.
0.75W.
Light.
0.75W light.
In fact.
It's enough for us to do experiments.
Then why.
Will lose so much.
In fact.
We.
Is.
Most of them.
Their difficulty is.
This magnifier.
Although.
Only 3000.
But.
The light coming out.
Is a square light.
You can't.
Take it to do experiments.
Then you.
You have to.
Do some shaping.
These shapes.
Is.
From our high school.
Those light.
Is.
One-third.
Plus one-third of Q.
Plus one-third of F.
This light.
Concept.
You know.
How to put this.
Square light.
Form it.
Into.
A.
High-spin.
Correct.
So.
After the formation.
We.
Put the light into Fiber.
Like this.
Then come out.
Only about 750 mW.
Then these two lights.
Pump.
Plus pull.
Then there will be pull.
Conjugate.
That is.
This is our tradition.
Do.
That.
Pull and missing.
Then do.
Their.
Intensity difference.
Correct.
That.
The point is.
How to do it.
Very low quality.
Magnifier.
Then you will see.
This way.
Same.
This.
Dash 9.
Red Dash 9.
Is.
Shot noise.
Blue Dash 9.
Also shot noise.
But these two lights.
The.
Power.
Is different.
Red Dash 9.
This total power.
Is.
About.
130.
That.
About 130 mW.
Blue.
Dash 9.
Its light.
About.
Only 17 mW.
That.
These two lights.
Why.
I want to do this comparison.
That is to say.
You see.
When its high frequency.
When dozens of TOS.
You see.
The quantum noise you see.
To say.
Is.
Quite consistent.
But when it's low frequency.
It's different.
Why.
Because.
You think about it.
That is to say.
When your light.
Getting weaker and weaker.
In fact.
It is.
When it's low frequency.
It will have a lot of.
classical.
Noise.
Or some.
Technical noise.
That.
You think about it.
Ah.
I just didn't say.
One thing.
Is.
What is vacuum.
Vacuum.
It is.
Powerful.
That.
Remember.
That is.
Simple harmonic.
Oscillation.
Didn't I tell you.
What.
N plus.
One-half.
H8.
Omega.
That is.
That.
SHM.
The energy.
That.
When N is equal to 0.
When vacuum.
There is still a power.
That.
When there is this energy.
It has its noise.
And.
Especially.
It is also a coherent state.
So.
When.
You don't have any light.
It is also a coherent state.
Because it is a very pure.
Very pure.
Coherent state.
Otherwise.
You just think about it.
When your power is getting weaker.
When it gets weaker.
Is it.
When it comes to the end.
Is it to be confined to vacuum.
When.
It.
There can't be any other noise.
Hello.
I have a question.
Okay.
You ask.
Um.
That is.
Although these four lines are different.
But he actually has a complete.
That is.
His four lines.
In the end at that.
Low frequency.
All over again.
That.
It looks a bit like.
That is.
You can still excite a lot.
Vacuum.
The mold is there.
That.
I have always had a question from the beginning.
Because I was just thinking.
Listen to see if you will speak.
But I really want to ask now.
That is.
Why do you use high temperature.
Not high temperature cavity.
Just use high temperature.
That.
Medium gas.
If you make it.
Cloud.
Will it be suppressed?
This.
Listen to sure to that.
I think.
That is, ah.
The one.
Pro memory element.
Is there one easy way.
Erm.
The sensor you.
Sense...
Essence...
That's the sensor lightning.
It can hold thepot.
It can hold pot.
I.
Yeah.
The projector.
To the power to the power.
To the light source.
The crow.
The camera, the night...
You kinda.
The lighting, right.
Camera and настро the light.
The lighting and the smoke.
So.
The light sources.
The destination.
And the plus.
Is also the usual Three...
The.
Resolution.
Is your.
The bandwidth.
Low.
This will move backwards.
Keep moving backwards.
So if I can adjust it to a few hertz.
When.
Then you'll be in.
In.
About one or two hertz.
You'll see this.
One over F.
The noise.
So.
So this.
It doesn't really matter.
That.
That's your resolution.
Is related.
Oh.
With your resolution.
The bandwidth.
Is related.
Okay.
So.
So you can see.
The red line.
At low frequency.
Its value.
The noise.
Is only up to.
One point.
One point five kilohertz.
When the blue line.
This.
This will be.
One kilohertz.
That's the one.
That.
The Australian.
Paper.
That paper.
Is.
Is the same effect.
That is to say.
When your.
Your light source.
Getting weaker and weaker.
When your seed light is getting weaker and weaker.
It's getting closer and closer to your.
Coherent state.
It is.
Shut noise limit.
But.
Is.
Coherent state.
The real coherent state light.
No other.
Other classical noise.
Because any classical noise.
Will.
Disturb your.
The.
Squeeze light.
Yes.
So when our light is getting weaker and weaker.
We can see.
More.
Better.
Low frequency.
The.
The light is getting weaker and weaker.
That.
This.
This looks like nothing.
Because.
Because only.
Only.
One kilohertz.
Then we.
Let's look at another way.
That is to say.
We.
This.
Is.
The.
So its.
The more its coherent effect is.
It's.
The amplification efficiency is.
What you hit a.
You.
You've got a probion.
In.
This.
Atomic substance.
It will produce 25 atomic.
The 25 light particles.
That is to say, its magnification ratio is 25 times.
Yes.
Then you want to see.
That is to say.
When my.
My game.
The bigger it is.
That means.
The seed I need is getting weaker.
That's what I need.
When the seed is getting weaker.
I can see it.
Even lower and lower and lower.
A few hundred hertz.
I can.
I can see the effect of the light particle.
Yes.
That.
That this.
This is already us.
About two or three years ago.
The result of the cause.
But our boss insisted at that time.
Is.
No.
There's nothing to publish.
Yes.
That.
Recently.
China has a.
The research result is that they have.
Down to 700 hertz.
About.
700 hertz.
Then.
Send it out.
But then.
Our result.
The result we want to publish is.
We have.
Down to about.
About.
The result is 10 hertz or so.
That is.
We.
We have.
One order.
Another order.
Going down.
That.
That is.
Here is what I want to share.
Actually.
Sometimes, there is.
It takes some luck.
Yes.
Some ideas are very sudden.
So.
Was.
One day last year.
I went to my boss's office and said.
Why don't we add the second one?
Come in.
That is.
There was only one light coming in.
Then.
Pro 1.
Country 1.
Then.
Why don't we add the second one?
Yes.
The boss said.
Because the second one is added.
It will become.
It's like doing another experiment.
That is.
Our lab is not just doing this.
Do another experiment.
Is.
Take.
Two.
Pumping.
Then.
Form a.
So-called single mode.
Squeeze.
That is.
Anyway, it's another experiment.
It's a bit.
A little comparison.
It seems to become that kind of experiment.
But.
After the boss finished explaining.
Anyway.
Just try it.
No difference.
That is.
Take a.
This.
Maybe a few minutes or a few hours.
To try it.
Then.
I saw that.
A different result came out.
That is.
Our record is like this.
Pushed down another order.
To.
Nearly 10 Hz.
That is.
So.
Good.
Hey.
This video should be the last one.
That is.
Anyway, we are now.
Which one is your latest result?
Ah.
All.
That is.
This result is used.
We hit two lights.
Go in.
That is.
I just.
I only showed.
The experiment in the front.
Only.
The first light.
Pumping.
With pumping.
Do.
Interaction only.
That.
All the following data.
Are two lights.
That is.
Most of the data.
Are two lights.
I.
Use a beam splitter.
You all.
Can you all see my shoulder?
That is.
Oh, yes.
This is the beam splitter.
Divide it.
Will divide.
Half of the light.
Finished.
Yes.
You have the second probing.
After the second probing comes in.
It will produce another.
Conjugate.
That is.
That.
Then you will see.
Hey.
Our experiment result is.
When your.
Ah.
This red line.
Are all shot noise.
But I am from.
100 kHz.
Draw to.
1 Hz.
That is.
That red line.
Is shot noise.
That.
Blue line.
Is.
That.
Oh.
I will talk about it later.
That is.
Anyway.
Blue.
These blue lines and black lines.
Are our new.
Our new experiment result.
That.
This picture.
Just want to tell you.
A phenomenon.
That is.
We.
In practice.
That is.
We.
Before.
Break through to a few hundred Hz.
That.
The main.
The limit is.
It has a background noise.
That.
Where did the background noise come from?
From this pump.
After this pump is hit.
We are using.
A beam splitter.
Filter it.
But it still has.
Its.
Correlation.
Not so pure.
So it will have.
So-called leakage.
That leakage.
Will.
Will pollute your.
Probe and.
Conjugate.
Will cause.
You will see this green line.
The green line is.
We put.
Probe in.
Blocked.
So we only have.
We.
We can't measure anything.
But wrong.
You still have to measure.
This.
Green line.
What is this green line?
It's your pump.
The leakage.
Run to your probe.
And.
Conjugate in.
So.
So this.
Limits us.
Our technology.
That is to say.
We could.
Our original technology is.
From a few kHz.
Then.
Compressed to a few hundred kHz.
That.
Why can't.
Compressed down.
Because.
We have a background here.
Pump.
Flash.
Light.
Will pollute.
Your.
Green beam.
That.
Of course.
The story is not like this.
But anyway.
We just go.
Just.
I don't know why.
I just put that.
Adjusting that light.
I don't know why.
Then.
Adjusting.
That pump.
It becomes weak.
And then.
To measure this.
It turned out to be.
I made the angle bigger.
Just like this.
Make the angle bigger.
That.
Pump's leakage.
Will become.
Gray line.
So beautiful.
So low.
So.
We.
Just like this.
As long as we make the angle bigger.
Then.
You will see the black line.
That squeeze light.
Will.
Drop to about 10 kHz.
That.
Anyway.
This.
So.
I mean.
This.
This experiment.
That is.
Blue.
Red.
This blue line is all.
Shot noise.
That red line is to say.
We only hit one light.
Then.
We.
We put Probeam.
Put.
Put it.
A little lower.
Let Probeam and Country Creeper.
The pump is the same.
Then.
To measure the squeeze light.
It's so scary.
Right.
Then if we hit two lights in.
After.
This.
You don't have to lock the laser at all.
The laser is not locked at all.
But you can also lock the laser.
After you lock the laser.
Your laser line.
From a few megahertz to.
About a few hundred hertz.
Or kilohertz.
Then you will see.
Just that one.
One light.
Will become.
You.
You can see.
Better.
Magnetic field effect.
But.
Two lights.
Still more.
More perfect.
Then we can even do it.
About.
Six hertz.
This is our current.
Then.
Then this is of course.
We still have some.
Dust in the air.
Fall into your.
Light path.
Will interfere.
Your beam.
So we will.
Do some.
Cover it.
Then you can.
Make it beautiful.
I don't know.
You can make it very low.
Like this.
Yeah.
That.
This is.
Can go back to the next one.
The next one.
Hey.
Method 1.
Method 2.
In fact.
I just saw you.
Because you are.
There's an ice.
Split.
So.
For example.
Your method 1.
With method 2.
Probe.
The total energy is the same.
I think so.
Is it right?
Yes.
That is to say.
Your method 1.
Your terminal.
Maybe.
The terminal is.
10 microwatt.
That method 2 is.
Five.
Five microwatt.
Yeah.
What's that?
Physics.
Principles.
Can you explain.
It's in.
Let him.
This.
Is it so different?
Why?
Because I think.
Method 1.
Method 2.
His.
This.
Angle.
It should be harder.
The same.
I.
I mean.
That is to say.
Why can he.
Causing.
Such a big difference now.
Yeah.
Do you know?
This method 1.
That is.
I hit the light.
The terminal.
The terminal is 1.
And then after this magnification.
After the ring.
The light coming out is G.
Right?
That's my country.
This curve.
It's G minus 1.
Because he doesn't have a terminal.
So his power is G minus 1.
For him.
There has always been a power difference.
That's the E.
The difference of that terminal.
But.
Your frequency.
If Zhang Yuan.
Piao.
That is to say.
If you don't fix its frequency in the laser.
Your.
When your frequency is floating.
Your game.
Your magnification.
The magnification ratio is always floating there.
So you will get a different magnification ratio.
At different times.
As a result.
You will have additional noise.
Yeah.
But method 2.
That is to say.
You hit.
0.5 in.
He came out G times 0.5.
That.
His country can be 0.5 times.
G minus 1.
Right?
But.
Your other light.
It's also the opposite.
There is also a G generation.
That you originally here.
G minus 1.
With your G.
Add up like this.
The power difference on both sides.
It's zero.
No matter how your frequency floats.
Your.
Total.
Power difference.
All the same.
You.
You have.
You have understood.
I'm not talking about this point.
There is.
But I'm thinking.
That is.
You do this experiment today.
The main purpose.
Is to get.
You.
The last.
This is produced.
Conjugate.
This is a perfect.
Not.
Ah.
I just.
Let me.
Because.
We.
We here.
This.
Conjugate.
There will be a power difference.
Then.
I just want to put this.
The power difference.
Eliminate it.
Then you can see.
At.
Very low frequency.
I can still see.
That is.
You.
Also.
At the time of input.
Already.
The so-called classical noise.
Eliminate it.
This classical.
Or the mechanical noise.
Because it will be.
You.
You two.
Pro beam.
Pro 1 and Pro 2.
Both.
The same classical noise.
Then you.
The same.
As soon as you go in.
Already.
Eliminated.
So you come out.
Also very clean.
There are two.
Enlarged.
Total power.
It's exactly the same.
Even your frequency.
Your laser light.
Did not shrink.
His.
Total power.
Always fixed.
Correct.
It's a bit hard to imagine.
But.
Oh.
Can.
This.
Continue.
No, it's.
Okay.
You.
You continue to finish.
No.
Actually.
I'm almost done.
That is to say.
We.
This time is.
There is no.
Capacity inside.
Like I just said.
Some.
Opio.
Capacity.
So the light they emit.
Not.
Multi-spatial mode.
So it can't be used.
Image processing.
Correct.
Then.
We are almost ready now.
We are even.
Below 10 Hz.
We can all see this.
Volume noise reduction.
What is this?
What is the importance of this?
I'll tell you later.
Correct.
Then.
We will now.
That is.
Low frequency noise reduction.
Can only do.
About 6 Hz.
The main reason is.
We still have other.
Laboratory.
Light.
Light table.
Or what.
Stability.
The problem.
Correct.
Then we have this laser.
For missing.
Squeeze line.
It is.
Portable.
It's not a big one.
It's a diode laser.
Then again.
Compared to.
It's a lot cheaper.
Correct.
You can do it for $30,000.
Then.
We.
We will use it later.
Do.
Image experiment.
Then this image experiment.
That is to say.
We will have a mask.
This.
A mask.
Will put a laser beam.
Use a.
A mask.
Block it.
Then.
It will produce.
A.
Totoro.
Conjugate Totoro.
Then this is.
Conjugate.
So they.
Go.
Turn it.
About 180 degrees.
Something like that.
Then they cut each other.
You can see this.
Image.
The.
This.
This is called imaging.
That is.
Quantum quality imaging.
That.
Because.
You.
If you can't.
In all frequencies.
When you see this quantum noise.
That is to say.
If you are in low frequency.
When.
If there is a lot of physical noise.
Then you.
When you are doing.
Image experiment.
You are.
Open the shutter.
So open the camera shutter.
It is to put all.
Frequency.
Noise.
Collect it all.
So you are in low frequency.
If you can't see the quantum noise.
It will destroy your whole image.
So.
Our previous.
The.
Can't do it.
This.
This imaging.
The main difficulty is that.
We can't do it in low frequency.
This.
The quantum noise.
That is to say.
That.
Another application is.
Absolute correction.
That.
That is to say.
If this.
The light.
Is coming in one by one.
That.
It.
Once enlarged.
Double.
Ten times the light.
That.
You will see probing.
The same.
Also.
The same number of.
The light comes out.
So you.
This.
Dictator A.
And the following dictator.
They must.
The same light.
And so.
The time.
The position must be the same.
So when.
The above.
The dictator.
Receive my.
When the light.
It will tell you the following.
I received one.
Did you receive one?
Correct.
If I received.
100.
I told the other party.
I received 100.
You.
If you only received.
97.
That's when.
Your quantum efficiency.
It's only 97%.
Correct.
So.
That is to say.
The traditional quantum.
The traditional.
Calibration.
The proof is.
I have.
In addition.
Another.
Dictator.
That this dictator.
I already know.
What is its efficiency.
Then I compare the two.
I can compare.
What is my relative efficiency.
What is the relative quantum conversion efficiency.
So.
If you have one.
Already know.
And then know the relative.
Then you know.
This.
Calibration after.
What is the result.
But.
This.
The way is to say.
I don't have to know the above.
Or the following.
Quantum efficiency.
I can all.
Get.
Absolute.
Calibration.
That quantum efficiency.
Correct.
That is.
We can use.
To do.
To make up.
So.
That's about it.
Thank you all.
If.
Any questions.
Welcome to ask.
Does anyone have a question?
Hello.
Hi.
Do you want to ask first?
You ask first.
I actually.
Because you just mentioned that.
Gravitational wave.
Is this LIGO?
Yes.
But I think this thing.
Than.
It's a hundred times better than LIGO.
I think.
Okay, I'll say it like this.
In fact, there is no.
LIGO.
They are an international.
Many countries' plan.
So I think.
We use a very simple way.
I immediately thought of one.
Application.
That's it.
LIGO.
Its frequency.
In fact, it is much higher than here.
That's a lot higher.
The reason is that he can only do that.
Ah.
If you do that.
He can only measure.
It's close to the earth.
It's also the red.
Reddish.
Smaller.
Gravitational wave.
So he can only measure.
The so-called contemporary universe.
The occurrence of phenomena.
For example.
Planet collision.
Black hole collision.
Those.
For cosmology.
Or high-energy physics.
Very interesting.
Is the ancient gravitational wave.
Then they happened a long time ago.
Then it has been.
Very big.
Redshifted.
To.
Very low frequency.
Yes.
Then this thing can be used.
That is to say.
Now.
I know China.
Japan.
India.
They are all developing.
Just like LIGO.
Of.
This kind of interference.
Ah.
We.
This method is.
Twin beam.
Of course.
LIGO.
They hope to be single mode.
Just a single light.
Um.
But we can also do that experiment.
No problem.
Yes.
But the other point is.
LIGO.
They only want your wave.
Not.
Ah.
1024.
No meter.
It seems that as long as you are not that wave.
They.
They don't want it.
Anyway.
You.
All their devices are for.
1024.
That wave.
So.
Our 795 wave.
It's far from them.
So they don't want it.
But actually.
Basically physics.
There is no difficulty.
So you can only.
As long as you find.
That frequency.
The light source.
It's OK.
I tell you.
You can check an experiment.
There is an experiment called LISA.
L.I.S.A.
That is a.
LIGO in space.
I think that thing.
May be for this.
It's very.
Is.
It's suitable for use.
But.
This.
I think I.
It's more important to do it first.
So.
Of course.
They.
They care.
I don't care.
Oh.
OK.
I think it's very good.
Thank you.
Hey.
I want to ask.
It's your last one.
Uh.
In the next one.
So.
Do you want to do it?
Like a single-ray experiment?
So.
You like this.
The setup is very similar to that.
Red capital.
H.O.M.
The experiment.
Do you want to do that?
Or you.
Actually.
This is just a demo.
I want to tell you.
How did he.
His.
His idea is to make it.
With respect to.
That is to say.
It.
The two are unknown.
The two emitted efficiency are indecisive.
So.
It's like I give you a ball.
I said at the same time.
Give one ball to another person.
Then you two can interact with each other.
Do some coexistence cornets.
The co-efficient of yourselves.
This.
This is a demo.
But the real garbage has grown this way.
He gave it to the patient.
Then test its co-efficient relationship.
Get.
The so-called quantum quantum.
That one.
Dictator's quantum efficiency.
Then we.
This experiment should.
To get a.
Very.
The reason to use low-quality quantum compression is because.
We.
To be with.
The national standard group.
The already known co-efficient should be compared.
Then.
Then I.
The boss gave me the goal.
That is.
As long as we can get.
Below 1 kilohertz.
That.
1 kilohertz is about the same as 200 hertz.
But we keep doing it like this.
Keep doing it to 10 hertz.
So.
We will become.
Any.
Almost any frequency.
We can.
Just do the quantum correction.
Correct.
That question is.
Is.
Maybe it has nothing to do with what I did.
Hello.
I didn't understand.
Say it again.
Oh, that's your question.
Ah, actually, I don't understand it either.
Because.
Because we.
We are just very simple.
To measure his.
Co-efficient.
Then go to his.
That.
Dictator's quantum efficiency.
That's it.
No.
Nothing else to do.
Oh, no.
Because of that.
Hey.
You just said this.
This experiment.
Then.
From this.
With.
This has nothing to do with China.
There is an experiment called Hong.
I know you said that Hong.
Right.
HOM.
Yes.
That.
I look like.
Is.
Should be.
Conceptually very similar to that.
Right.
Yes.
But we.
Mainly to measure his quantum.
Is.
Not.
Measure his.
Yes.
I understand.
Hello.
Hey.
I want to ask a question.
Uh.
Is.
You produce here.
Uh.
This is your program here.
This.
Conjugate disease.
They.
After production.
They are still.
They are coherent.
Uh.
No.
They are thermal.
This is a coherent disease.
Still.
Squeeze.
Uh.
Just.
Only.
Proceed.
Is.
Coherent disease.
It produces.
Is.
Thermal disease.
The noise.
Is.
Coherent disease.
Hundreds of times.
Is.
It is.
Very.
A.
Thermal noise.
Is.
That is.
He.
Than the original.
Coherent.
Coherent disease.
About.
Square.
So.
Big.
Probing.
These two lights.
Reduce.
That is to say.
They are magnified at the same time.
They are.
Quantum.
Co-related.
Then.
When I.
Although it is 2.
5.
Square.
More.
Magnification.
But when the two.
After reduction.
We are.
Get a.
Very.
Clean.
Intensity.
Difference.
Squeeze light.
This is.
Coherent.
Still.
Magnification.
Light.
Is.
Also.
Thermal.
OK.
Then.
The reason is because.
You are using.
Atom.
That is.
It has a lot of.
3D scattering.
Just.
Because.
As long as you magnify.
Should say.
Any.
This non-linear magnification.
After magnification.
Is.
Thermal disease.
OK.
That is.
But.
Second harmonic.
Or.
General.
Forward mixing.
Is it?
I actually don't know.
Their.
OK.
Second harmonic.
Is it?
I don't think so.
Maybe.
Because they are.
Second harmonic.
Can also be used.
Just like.
Some.
Do.
They are.
What frequency.
To use.
Second harmonic.
To.
Create the next frequency.
Higher frequency.
That.
Is.
It must be.
Laser beam.
To do some experiments.
If it is not.
Laser beam.
Then.
It's useless.
So.
Second harmonic.
I think it should be.
Coherent beam.
Yes.
It should be.
Your probe and conjugate.
Is thermal.
Yes.
But I.
This is.
Power magnification.
I guess.
Second harmonic.
It.
Its power is still.
Conservation.
Still forward.
But.
You put.
Probe and conjugate.
You will.
Get one.
Is amplitude.
Squeeze the light.
Is it?
Is.
You can't.
Conjugate.
Is.
You can't.
Amplitude.
Is.
Its intensity.
Difference.
OK.
Yes.
Then.
I have a question.
Is.
Your.
Weak.
Is.
There is an experiment.
You put.
Probe.
Seed.
Intensity.
Strengthening.
And.
Angle.
Yes.
Then.
You said there.
Will.
Is.
The frequency.
Will.
Go down.
Why.
Because.
I.
I have to have a seed.
I need to have a seed.
Come in.
That is.
You.
You see.
Method 1.
After I come in.
Then.
If I have a seed.
Not.
Cohesive state.
Low frequency.
Not.
Cohesive state.
Because.
You.
Your laser is low frequency.
In fact.
There are many.
Other impurities come in.
Do.
The effect of low frequency.
When the effect.
My AOM has given him another impurity.
And.
There are more.
More.
Very scary impurities.
Like this.
But.
More than 10 dB.
Yes.
So.
When you.
You.
You hit this light.
Getting weaker and weaker.
When.
These ancient.
Impurities.
Will be.
Non-linear.
Take it.
Cut off.
That is.
These ancient impurities.
Not with you.
The power is.
It's a.
It's a non-linear way.
Cut off.
When vacuuming.
You don't have any impurities.
Because vacuuming is.
Cohesive state.
So.
It has a non-linear.
Take it.
Into a.
A.
Cohesive state.
Effect.
Oh.
I mean.
Just.
Ancient impurities.
Will not be.
Will not be magnified.
Then.
Quantum impurities.
Will be magnified.
Ah.
I mean.
Ancient impurities.
You can use.
Reduce the power.
Green it off.
OK.
Yes.
That.
Quantum way.
You can't.
Green it off.
OK.
Yes.
Then.
Uh.
The last question.
It's.
Now these.
This.
Dicephyl laser.
With.
Dial laser.
To compare.
It's.
Who is it?
Uh.
It's.
I'm.
Is.
It'
Still.
Net.
You.
Still.
It's.
Too.
Still.
Not just now.
So yes.
That's.
Equal good, Yuk.
It's.
Quite.
Iya.
Time.
Better.
Speed telekinesis better.
Do you know?
It's.
Deal.
Why?
Is.
Questions.
Are.
You.
Your corners.
Girl.
Yet.
Don't assume it.
Because that's partner.
Web-site.
Okay.
Don't assume.
Right?
See a second.
There's.
The coordination.
Right.
I'm.
It's.
Tight.
So.
plus or minus.
Is.
Okay.
Oh.
Good.
Hello.
How are you?
My name is peter.
When will you start the team.
Yes.
Uh.
So I.
My mood.
Uh.
Yeah.
Time is expensive.
Uh uh.
And.
Uh.
You can ask me or I'll be in California next week.
I'll be in California next week for a meeting for a week.
And I'll be reporting the results.
If there's any place you'd like to recommend, you can tell me.
Thank you.
Are you going to Clio?
Yeah, I'm going to Clio.
Oh, okay.
Are you going too?
Yeah, I'm going too.
Oh, we'll see each other on Saturday.
I'll be reporting on Sunday afternoon.
Oh, okay. I haven't seen when I'll be reporting.
Oh, really?
Actually, our idea of two lights
also solves another problem with Dialazer.
If I keep talking, I won't be able to finish.
So, it's also in Clio.
We'll be doing the same experiment on Sundays.
I'll be reporting on Sundays.
I'll see if I have time to listen.
Okay, welcome.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
So, that's it.
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you.