Okay, let's start the game.
Wait a minute, someone told me that he wanted to come in, but he couldn't.
Examining Transfer Credit Mobility and Baccalaureate Degree Attainment
Before we start, do you have anything you want to share with us?
Do I need to speak in English or Chinese?
You can speak in English.
But I think most people will speak in Chinese.
I know some people will speak in Japanese, but you can also speak in Chinese.
We'll give you some time to speak in Chinese.
Let's start.
Thank you.
Can I share my screen now?
Hello everyone, I'm Shelly.
I'm very happy to have this opportunity to share my research with everyone.
My research is related to my current work.
I'm discussing transfer students from 2nd year colleges to 4th year colleges in California.