Welcome everyone to today's TARA speech. First of all, welcome everyone to listen to Huang Kun-hsieh to tell us about Python to play with particles physics experiment.
TARA is an online platform. Our goal is to use a free and cross-border way to connect young people all over the world who are engaged in research.
We can quickly share each other's results and ideas. We have a website and a fan group. The name of our fan group is Project TARA.
You can find us on Facebook.
Let me introduce today's speaker. Today's speaker is Huang Kun-hsieh.
It's quite interesting. When I was preparing to introduce the speaker, I did a little calculation. I think we have known each other for 10 years.
Huang Kun-hsieh studied at the University of Taiwan Physics Department and the University of Taiwan Physics Institute.
When he was in the doctor's class, he went to the University of Kyoto. During this period, he was engaged in the study of micro-needle telescope.
Later, he did T2K at the University of Kyoto. So Huang Kun-hsieh can be said to be a micro-needle expert.
After Huang Kun-hsieh got his doctorate, he went to Bell Institute to do hardware development. He is now a post-doctorate researcher.
The topic he will talk to us today is to use Python to play the particle physics experiment.
An example of using a convolutional neural network to correct gamma-ray energy measurement.
Without further ado, let's give a round of applause to welcome Huang Kun-hsieh.
Sorry, I forgot to say one thing. Please mute your microphone if you don't want to speak in the speech.
But when you want to applaud, you have to turn on the microphone so that our speaker can feel your enthusiasm.
Let's welcome Huang Kun-hsieh.
Thank you for the introduction. I have been a speech therapist for a long time.
I am very happy that you gave me the opportunity to speak here today.
Actually, my speech was shot in Taiwan.
So I'm sorry. If you have been to Taiwan, you may have heard the same thing over and over again.
My name is Huang Kun-hsieh. I am a post-doctorate student at Taiwan University.
I am currently working on a project called Bell 2.
I am currently doing a particle physics experiment.
I am studying the field of particle physics.
In the particle physics experiment, you may take a lot of data.
If you take data, you may need to do data analysis.
If you do data analysis, it is a very good language.
If you want to download it, you can download it here.
This is my own photo.
I am currently doing post-doctoral research at Taiwan University.
I am currently doing research in the field of particle physics.
I also like to use my voice.
What is my research?
The screen you are sharing is your PowerPoint.
It's not the part you play. You may have to re-share it.
Then choose that.
Oh, okay. Let's do it again.
Is there such a thing?
Choose the screen.
Yes.
Yes?
Okay.
What I'm doing now is in a Japanese studio.
There is an organization called KK.
If you want to listen to Japanese, it's Koe-nen-ruki-kasoku-ken-kyu-kiko.
It's simply called KK.
There is such a big research device called Bell 2.
It's a detector.
Mainly, we use Python to simulate and analyze.
There is also some data storage.
And even push the data to the whole world.
Because we have Google Earth that pushes the data to the whole world.
They will provide their computing resources.
Then I will talk about how to push the data to the whole world.
The first thing to talk about is particle physics.
I'm sorry.
Because the data I prepared is scientific.
Some people may not know what particle physics is.
So let's talk about what particle physics is.
At the beginning, for example, water molecules.
You must have heard of water molecules.
High school physics should have heard of water molecules.
There will be atoms in it.
Atoms will have electrons and the nucleus inside.
Electrons are the so-called basic particles.
In addition, you will find neutrons and neutrons in the nucleus.
Neutrons and neutrons are composed of quarks.
In fact, the most basic discovery is that there are electrons and quarks.
To form the universe we see in our daily lives.
Particle physics is to study the interaction between these basic particles and their group.
And how to form the law of the universe.
How do we study particle physics?
We usually do one thing.
We will use the accelerator to accelerate the particles to a very fast speed.
For example, like this animation.
Let the particles and the antiparticles accelerate to a very fast speed.
Then there will be a collision in the middle.
After we let it collide, it will produce a new one.
We rarely see this example in the current universe.
It's a more unfamiliar example.
In our daily lives.
It's not like that kind of thing.
We rarely see this kind of thing in the current universe.
So we study these new examples.
And see what their interaction is like.
Neutrons are one of them.
In fact, we have a lot of large-scale particle physics experiments.
There are many large-scale physics experiments in the world.
The first is the collision experiment.
For example, if you have heard of similar LHC.
What kind of experiments are there under LHC?
The biggest three experiments are actually four.
The biggest four experiments are CNS, ATLAS.
The other experiment is not included.
CNS, ATLAS, and LHC-B.
In addition, our protagonist today is BELL-2.
It is also a collision experiment.
It's about electrons.
It's about electrons and positive electrons.
That is, positive electrons.
Electrons are negative electrons.
Positive electrons are negative electrons.
It's a collision experiment.
There are also other kinds of experiments.
For example, T2K, which I used to participate in.
And then the pressure back in China.
Or SNOPLUS in Canada.
There are other examples.
For example, alpha in LHC.
Alpha in SNOPLUS.
And the Koto experiment in Japan.
I am very happy.
When we received the number on April 26th.
BELL-2 is the first operation.
This is a report at the time.
This is the release press.
And the first collision event.
That's why we're doing BELL-2 experiments.
Please give me three minutes.
At the beginning, the BELL-2 detector.
Actually, it's a detection of B particles.
B particles are rare in the universe.
We will learn about CP-Violation.
That is, the universe is not uniform.
With other new physics.
What is the universe not uniform?
If the universe is not uniform.
It will be with us.
That's why we only have materials now.
Related to our universe.
I have a YouTube video.
Please take a look.
I don't know if YouTube is okay.
Wait a minute, I'll play it again.
This is the theory of the Big Bang.
The universe after the Big Bang.
At the time of the Big Bang.
Matter and antimatter.
It should be the same level.
Now there's only matter in the universe.
Other antimatter has disappeared.
Matter and antimatter.
There should be a difference.
So they say.
In addition to the difference between the electron box and the symmetry.
There should be other differences.
Other differences are called CP-Violation.
Now known as the Kobayashi-Masukawa Theory.
It was a revolutionary theory.
Which introduced a model that contained six quarks.
Even though only three quarks were known at the time.
In 2001.
The Bell experiment successfully measured CP-Violation.
In B meson decays.
As predicted by the Kobayashi-Masukawa Theory.
There are six quarks.
Three or four quarks.
Three or four quarks decays.
They should have.
Matter and antimatter.
An asymmetry.
Later in the Bell experiment.
It was confirmed.
Now it's more accurate.
In 2008.
30 years after their theory paper was published.
Professor Kobayashi.
And Professor Masukawa.
Won the Nobel Prize in Physics.
Experimental confirmation of the Kobayashi-Masukawa Theory.
By the Bell and Babar experiments.
Greatly contributed to their Nobel Prize.
It's easy to get the Nobel Prize.
Electrons and neutrons.
Accelerate to the light.
Let them collide.
Then they will.
If the antimatter is converted to the electron.
They will produce.
Other kinds.
Heavier particles.
This annihilation.
Transforms the electron and positron.
Into a pair of B mesons.
Which consists of bottom quarks.
Two B mesons.
B mesons.
These two B mesons.
Will decay.
Because they have a lot of life.
They will decay.
Into other kinds.
Other kinds of particles.
Usually negative.
In your detector.
Measure their decay.
After the example.
Then calculate.
It should be B mesons.
Particles then pass through.
The central drift chamber.
Here they ionize the gas.
Which fills the detector.
In this way.
A particle's trajectory and momentum.
Is obtained.
Next comes the top counter.
And the aerogel rich counter.
A charged particle.
Emits Cherenkov radiation.
When it enters these detectors.
The timing and pattern information.
Of the detected Cherenkov radiation.
Tells us what kind of particle it is.
Then there is an electromagnetic calorimeter.
This detector precisely measures.
The energy of photons.
Electrons.
The outermost detector.
Is the long living neutral.
And muon detector.
It detects muons.
Which penetrate most of the detector.
And neutral chaos.
Which cannot be measured.
With the inner detectors.
It does not have an electrolyte.
Because the light does not have an electrolyte.
So it is in the middle.
Before it touches the ECL.
From the point of collision.
It will not be detected.
Why is the ECL detected?
Because it is denser.
So it is easier for light.
It is easier to produce a reaction.
It will be here.
After the reaction.
It will be broken down into many kinds.
These electrons.
In the crystal.
It will glow in the crystal.
This crystal.
Will add a light sensor.
Photosensor.
You can look at the photosensor.
Its energy size.
The light on both sides.
The intensity of the light.
The intensity of the gamma radiation.
All the detectors.
This is the most important thing today.
If you want to go in.
I have a link here.
You can go back and see for yourself.
This is the history of the universe.
At the beginning of the big explosion.
The universe is very hot.
The universe is very cold.
Relatively cold.
In the primordial universe.
We have a lot.
There will be a lot in the universe.
In real life.
In the cold universe.
There are many strange examples.
In the universe.
Our accelerator.
Super KKB.
He knows.
What we are not familiar with now.
Strange examples.
It often appeared in the universe.
These examples.
We can understand.
From the past to the present.
What happened.
There may be some.
Strange behavior.
The universe.
Only matter.
Still very mysterious.
OK.
CP violation.
Not familiar with the universe.
In 1960.
These two people.
Not discovered.
In the K-on ring.
Found in the K-on ring.
Xiaoling and Yichuan in 1973.
They.
Established.
Three quarks era.
Six quarks.
In the standard model.
But.
We will.
B quark decay.
There will be a CP violation.
In 1980.
These two people.
There will be a CP violation.
In the K-on ring.
OK.
You may not know.
Simply put.
Quarks and.
Quarks.
In fact, most of the quarks are the same.
In addition to.
They are not the same.
Correct.
These two.
Charge and parity.
Quarks and quarks.
Different.
There is another.
In addition to these two properties.
Other different properties.
Will be called by us.
CP violation.
For example, like life.
Or like.
Decay branching ratio.
Only here.
B quark situation.
Of course there are other CP violations.
That kind.
Only here.
Life or decay ratio.
What is B quark?
This is from the website.
Take it over.
B quark.
It is actually a B and a D.
To constitute.
It has B 0 and B 0 bar.
It has B plus and B minus.
Now the universe is.
The left side is more material.
The right side is less anti-material.
Of course now.
B quark is very rare.
Then.
How do we measure.
CP violation in B quark.
For example, life.
After the confrontation.
They will fly in the same direction.
B quark and B quark.
Will fly in the same direction.
The longer the life, the longer the flight.
The shorter the life, the shorter the flight.
That is.
Use this to measure B quark or B quark.
Life difference.
Of course there are some decay modes.
B is more.
But this.
At the same time to verify.
They should be.
It's different in life.
OK.
It has a lot of new physics.
For example, like.
Some of you may have heard of.
Maybe it's too difficult.
There will be some.
Intermediate particles.
It may not be.
The example we know.
So it will be different.
And the other one is.
Of course it's not just.
This is.
Yan Yong is also.
Researched.
His research is.
Direct detection.
The method.
B quark.
It's also direct detection.
OK.
Physics is over.
You should be blind.
Then.
It's more interesting to talk about this.
Because I am.
Most of them are.
People who do software.
So the next thing.
Should be more.
Talk about software.
And some examples.
For example, like.
You know this is.
Our Bell 2 detector.
It's actually.
Its channel number is very amazing.
There may be one.
One million pixels.
That.
You have a million pixels.
Then every time the collision occurs.
Then there will be a lot of B.
The event is to remember.
Of course, in addition to B.
There are a lot of background events.
So add up.
Very, very much.
Then our data size.
Then of course this is.
You are in the inside of the FPGA.
Then put this one million.
After throwing away the things you don't want.
Then the data size.
The size is probably one megabyte.
Then the trigger rate is your event rate.
If the accelerator is running.
Probably.
Maximum is 30.
30 kilohertz.
Like this.
This is the maximum.
Of course, it's not that high now.
The maximum is like this.
So the maximum data rate is probably.
34 gigabytes per second.
Of course, there are only two or three gigabytes now.
When running now.
Because we are not so high now.
That is to run.
The accelerator is not fully operational yet.
It's not fully operational yet.
So it's not as much as 30 gigabytes.
Then there are probably only two or three gigabytes.
A lot.
That.
But in fact, two or three gigabytes.
Then add some of your simulation.
The data produced is actually a lot.
Then this page here.
It's like this.
How much data does it have?
That's it.
The data is about 30 times a year.
Petabyte.
Up to 50 petabytes.
That's the data.
If you don't change the simulation.
It's probably 50 petabytes.
That's the experiment.
If you add the simulation.
It's about 200.
You can see that Google is about 98.
Then Google's search is 98.
Then Facebook Upload is 180.
Then Google's Internet Archive is 11.
11 bytes.
Petabyte.
It should be petabyte.
I forgot how to read it.
Then you can know that Bell can actually be with.
Google, Facebook.
Their data can be compared.
It means it's really big.
Of course, it's bigger.
We're really doing big data.
Then the following words are talking about.
It's more in-depth.
Because we're big data.
We need a set of processes.
To analyze our data.
This is how we do it.
Analyze the structure of our data.
Where do we put it?
Then we save it.
The data format is called MDST.
It's called Mini Data Summary Table.
We want to start with this MDST.
There are a lot of unorganized files in MDST.
For example, we just saw that.
There's no track in detail.
There's something else.
There's this one in ECL.
That's it.
We haven't sorted it out yet.
Particle or something.
Actually turn it into a particle.
Or something.
We haven't sorted it out yet.
We've introduced a module chain.
There's a data store.
These are a few things.
We're basically.
We're input data.
Put it in the data store.
Then put it in the data store.
We'll use the module.
Then use a path first.
Then put in what you need.
Put it in.
It's called a module.
It has different functions.
It's actually written in C14.
It's written in C14.
It's what you just did.
What's the track?
Then make it an example.
The example we see.
Then this path.
How to put this module in.
We use Python to do it.
There's something else.
After we're done.
We output data.
We have a root.
Our own format.
We'll develop a root format.
We can also use Python.
Analyze this root file.
An example like this.
For example.
We're done with the experiment.
We're going to put the NDST.
For example, module 1 is low.
NDST.
And then the particle list.
Take it out.
There's a track in there.
We'll put it in.
Turn it into a proton.
Or turn it into an electron.
Then there's a particle list.
And then put that.
Some particles.
For example, I'm going to make it a bmeson.
bmeson will change.
Many kinds.
It's his daughter's particle.
Then put these daughter's particles together.
Then combine it into bmeson.
Then there will be a new bmeson.
That's right.
Then we'll make some more choices.
It's bmeson.
The bmeson he made.
The quality is with us.
The bmeson we know is too far away.
So we don't want this bmeson.
Just make some choices.
And then write it out at the end.
It becomes a root file.
The function of Python is.
The first aspect is.
Build this path.
Build this module chain.
And then the other one is.
You're in the back of the root file.
You can use PyRooter to analyze.
Or use other packages.
Python packages for free.
What packages can be used?
I'll talk about it later.
Two more pages.
Let's start with what Rooter is.
If you're interested in what Rooter is.
Rooter is.
It's a way to do data storage.
Data analysis.
In Hynology Physicist.
Hynology Physicist.
You can go to his website.
I'll write some.
Installation instructions here.
The most important thing is.
Although it is written in C++.
You can also use C++ to do it.
But you can integrate with the other languages.
Such as Python and R.
Python is much more resourceful than R.
So it's better to use Python.
If you don't want to use C++.
There's a choice here.
You want to use.
You want to use Rooter.
Then Rooter is in C++.
You still use Python Rooter.
It's Python by default Rooter.
Then there's another option.
For example.
Rooter on NuPy.
Interface between Rooter.
Numerical Python.
Then there's another one.
Rooter Pandas.
You can put Rooter's file format.
Write it into Pandas DataFrame.
The easier one is.
Rooter Pandas.
Rooter NumPy.
You know it doesn't have.
It can also be used.
But I'm more used to Rooter Pandas.
With Rooter.
I like Rooter.
I use Rooter most often.
Then we build.
In fact, many people started to use Rooter Pandas.
There are some here.
It's the same installation instructions.
If you are interested.
You can install Rooter Pandas.
The installation method I wrote.
I've tried it myself.
Of course, there are other suggestions.
For example, PIP.
I've tried PIP.
I can't install it.
I think I can install it.
For example.
Then.
Like LHC.
Those experiments.
The four experiments.
We actually started.
Use Jupyter Notebook to start training.
It's our new energy.
To write analysis programs.
We call it StarKit.
It's usually three days.
There will be three days in about four months.
We'll have a meeting in four months.
The meeting is held once.
Then everyone gathers to have a meeting.
For new energy.
In the first three days of the collaboration meeting.
Then there will be a training.
Called StarKit Workshop.
Then there will be a meeting for three days.
In fact, everyone sits down.
Then teach the new energy.
How to do our direct analysis.
Data processing.
Then we use Jupyter Notebook.
To do this thing.
You can see Jupyter Notebook.
Its characteristics are unmistakable.
You can see it directly.
For example.
If you use Lulupandas.
You can make it into a table.
Then count, min, etc.
If you draw a picture.
You can keep it on top.
Then it's easier for people to see.
Of course, this is actually production.
You may not need to use Jupyter Notebook.
The big advantage of Jupyter Notebook.
If you are.
Teaching.
Or some.
After the root analysis.
After.
If you want to call the picture again.
It will be better.
There are some.
This picture is.
How to do software training in high-performance.
Basic C++.
Basic Data Science.
Programming.
For example, RootData.
Python, Git.
Then there are some training.
For example, Advanced Root.
Then there are others.
Then even someone.
I want to write NVIDIA.
OpenCL.
CUDA or OpenCL.
There are some.
The right side is the training course.
For example, like Bell 2 training course.
With Atlas CNX HCB.
Then there are some advanced training courses.
For example, I went to INFN last year.
SDC School.
That is.
After you finish learning.
But.
Everything is a little bit like this.
Then.
There is.
Here is also possible.
Software people may be more interested.
Maybe it has nothing to do with physics.
I am also participating in this area.
In the Bell era.
Is.
K1K.
About ten years ago.
We are using Cluster.
Central Cluster.
Provide everyone Central Cluster.
Then everyone comes in.
Calculate.
But Bell 2.
It is obvious.
Its accelerator.
Already 50 times.
So it will.
It will be more even rate.
Backlight rate will be more.
Even rate.
Will be more.
So of course.
There is a lot of backlight.
Then we need more.
CPU and memory.
If it is only K1K.
Maybe you only give him money.
Then ask him to pay for it.
Maybe not.
But we have 25 countries.
Then 100 institutes.
100 institutions participate in this experiment.
Then each institution.
A little machine to do it.
But each institution.
It may have different Cluster.
Then it may have different grades.
Even some institutions.
It may be from Amazon.
Or Google.
Then buy their Cloud Service.
That's all right.
Then we are very welcome.
They do this thing.
Then we need to say.
There are two important things.
So we have to find a way.
For example, everyone.
Still want to log in.
K1K Cluster.
Then we can put the job.
Is what we need to calculate.
We spread all over the world.
Is within these 100 institutions.
What they provide.
What each institution provides.
Calculation resources.
Then of course they are.
Their resources are different.
For example, some Cluster.
Then of course.
Our information will also spread all over the world.
Then here.
Then we say.
How do we do it?
There is a software.
Then from LCCB.
This experiment.
LCCB developed this experiment.
Our opponent developed it.
Then called Dirac.
Called Distribute Infrastructure.
With Remote Agent Control.
When he developed it.
He also considered.
Everyone will use different things.
It's very simple.
User Interface.
Then you are below.
All kinds of Cloud Cluster.
If you are interested.
GitHub is here.
If you look at it yourself.
Then everyone will notice.
It's all written in Python.
In GitHub.
100% is Python.
I plug my mouth.
Kun Xian's speech.
The link of the video.
I put it on the side.
The place to chat.
There is a link.
If you want to see those webpages.
Go back and look at the webpages.
I just didn't copy it.
You can go and see.
Build Dirac.
Build is.
Bring LCCB Dirac.
Then put your database in.
This way.
The picture on the left.
Data transmission.
Green is successful.
Red is a failure.
You can see the Japanese team.
To the United States has been a failure.
I don't know what happened.
Have been a failure.
Other places are successful.
More.
The prototype is a success.
The ratio of failure.
Basically we are.
We did the experiment.
After.
Because we are at the end.
Will save a copy.
Then we will.
Push to the United States.
BNL.
Blue Heaven.
In New York.
There is a copy.
Experimental data.
There are some others.
Do you have 100 institutes?
100 institutes.
Every institute.
There are a few more.
A few more.
There will be a total of three.
After we do the experiment.
We will put two copies of data.
Push out to BNL.
With other sites.
So every site will have.
Their own.
Data copy.
Of course.
This is actually the data of the experiment.
For example, the simulation.
Put it on BNL.
Or put it on KK.
Put it on other sites.
For example, Taiwan also has.
In the computer.
We also provide resources to them.
There is also a storage unit.
It will be stored there.
Then.
For example, I submitted a job.
I may need a certain file.
He will go to the database.
I submitted a job.
This job.
For example, Italy.
This is a job in Italy.
For example.
In Bologna.
He will look for nearby.
For example, I want a file.
Where is the file in the database?
Where is it?
He will look for nearby.
Nearby storage unit.
See if he has it.
This is pretty much the case.
This time frame.
Time relationship.
I do not speak in great detail.
It is probably such a frame.
To do the analysis.
OK, then the last thing is.
To support.
The spirit of implementation.
So I say.
A case of NNW.
In fact, in the high-end.
We also started to try.
Now we continue to learn to do it.
This is the first thing.
Then it is just mentioned.
EHOMEDIC CHROMETER.
This.
You can see that it is in.
It shines here.
Then it is the same.
After the gamma ray hits in.
It will be decomposed.
This is a CSI crystallization.
CSI crystallization.
Then the decomposition will shine.
Of course.
It is impossible that only one will shine.
This is BELL VR.
Everyone is interested.
You can download it.
The download is here.
VR.
It has VR.
For example.
A gamma ray runs in.
Then it will.
It will decompose a lot of things.
Run out.
Of course it decomposes a lot of things.
It can not only be in one ECL.
It is distributed in several ECLs.
This VR is really interesting.
That.
Yes.
You can download it.
Then.
For example.
A gamma ray runs in.
It will decompose.
Then decompose into other things.
Then.
This is CSI.
It is our luminous body.
Then it will be divided.
Then here.
Because.
This luminous body will shine.
It actually supports the structure.
For example, like steel.
Aluminum plate.
Then it will not shine.
So you can't measure it here.
Because it may be outside.
Lack of energy.
It is anyway.
Electrolytes in matter.
Loss of energy.
This is called CSI leakage.
Then it may leak to the back.
In fact, there will be a leak.
What is it actually?
For example, like this.
The simulation is actually like this.
A gamma ray comes in from the right.
Then there will be a lot at the back.
Leakage.
Leakage out.
The structure will also have some.
Leakage.
What will this cause?
For example, there is a mode.
It is called B plus to low plus.
I do not know.
Anyway, the back will become.
A lot of gamma rays.
Then there is a pi plus.
Anyway, I remember a lot of gamma rays.
Then we are from this.
A lot of gamma rays and pi plus.
Then we combine it into B plus.
Of course, our B plus.
The energy of its low mass.
Is from this pi plus.
Combined with a lot of gamma rays.
Then we.
If there is a leakage.
You will find that OK.
B plus energy.
It will not be a good one.
That is.
For example, like the standard.
Standard distribution is not.
It will be like this.
This curve is like this.
It will have a tail here.
It has a lot of low energy places.
Event here.
Because it is inaccurate.
It will have leakage there.
That.
This problem appears.
Let's take a look.
What is ECL?
ECL is like this.
Eight thousand.
Arranged mess.
I think it's hard to do.
So let's do something simple at the beginning.
Do something simple at the beginning.
30x30.
Crystal array.
Because this is my special.
It is done by PyCon.
Then this simulation.
If you are interested, you can take a look.
Here.
For everyone.
If we measure the energy.
In fact, it is the energy of each individual crystal.
Then put it together.
Just add it up like this.
Is that OK?
This is the traditional way we measure energy.
OK.
After the gamma ray hits.
It has energy for each crystal.
Measure the energy.
Then we measure the energy of each crystal.
All add up.
This is the way we measure energy.
Like this.
But it will leak.
For example, like this.
The gamma ray hits in.
Hit here.
Some leaked.
It will become OK.
Energy is gone.
For example, we hit.
Gamma ray energy.
Is 200mEV.
Then we hit 10,000 times.
Then we measure the energy.
How is the energy of the gamma ray?
Its distribution will be like this.
Yes.
Of course, there are also 200.
Most of the words.
Will not reach 200.
Even some words.
150, 125.
It will not be able to measure all.
Measure the energy.
Is not accurate.
Measure the energy is not accurate.
How to do it?
Just add it up.
Not good enough.
Then we.
This question.
Is a return question.
Your true energy is 200.
Then your prediction.
Is.
Your prediction.
You want to measure now.
How much is the energy?
Is a return question.
Yes.
But now you have total.
Other crystal patterns.
In fact, I thought later.
A method is.
For example, you go to see alone.
The energy distribution of the crystal.
Then this is.
Gamma ray energy.
Is a crystal.
Slightly to the right.
Its energy distribution.
It's a little different.
Then we suspect.
Is not hit in the middle.
The energy distribution.
Will be different from the middle.
Then he measured.
The degree of leakage.
Should be different.
This is.
Our energy distribution.
Pattern.
Is a picture.
The picture inside.
The picture inside is different.
For example, people are different.
Animals are different.
If the distribution is different.
That means.
Energy will be different.
That's simple.
That's OK.
Then we.
There should be.
There should be a way to do this.
Then we think of.
CNN.
If you have time.
You can go to see.
Course.
CNN.
I think.
The most detailed should be him.
CNN.
Different patterns on the map.
Find some characteristics.
Then use the machine learning method.
Find the characteristics of the machine.
Then do it.
This is the actual simulation.
Result.
Hit the energy here.
There is a pattern here.
If you have learned.
Machine learning.
Our target is.
Y2.
Usually use this.
What we want to do.
We want to predict.
How much is the real energy?
We use.
This energy.
Put it at the bottom.
Total energy.
We just.
Put it on top of the energy.
Y2 is like this.
The advantage of doing this is.
If you look at the front.
Because it is less than 200.
Between 0 and 1.
Our prediction.
Prediction is the result of our CNN.
Then we put the prediction.
Divided by our Dtotal.
You can get our.
The energy predicted by CNN.
The loss function.
Prediction minus Y2.
If you know.
What is CNN?
If you want to know what CNN is.
You can also ask me in person.
Our neural network.
The structure is like this.
I'm sorry.
Because I put it directly.
Production neural network.
Put it in the simulation.
It's a bit too complicated.
After the image.
We use.
I want to.
My idea is to use that.
Google has one.
There is a competition called Imagine.
There is a.
The method of Inception.
He used.
He used parallel.
Then use three different sizes.
3x3, 5x5, 7x7.
Then start to layer by layer.
I only use one layer.
Inception, I only use one layer.
Use this method.
Find characteristics.
Is different.
Size of things.
Why do I.
This 30x30 also uses this method.
Because this method is actually.
Use real ECL method.
I'm sorry.
Use it directly.
Then at the end.
Then pull it.
Then convolution.
Below.
Then pull it flat.
Then get it at the end.
Use Sigma function.
My target function.
My target is limited to 0 to 1.
Then do it at the end.
If you go.
I'm going to hit 4000.
I'm going to hit 10,000.
10,000.
4G EV.
4000 EV Gamma Ray.
I originally got.
The energy distribution should be like this.
Red like this.
Very ugly with a big tail.
Now it's green.
I feel.
You see the middle is back to 4000.
It seems a little bigger.
Although the tail is still there.
But there are tails on both sides.
Not so long.
Then the last result here.
Although a little bad.
Because I didn't go all the way.
OK.
This is.
The picture on the left is.
How much is the real energy?
From 500 to 5000.
Then.
The axis is your real.
Total energy minus your true energy.
Then divided by your true energy.
The more absolute value.
It means that you make more mistakes.
Absolute value means that you make more mistakes.
Then we are in high energy.
Not bad.
You can see.
Up to 2000.
It's almost the same as the original method.
Low energy is a little worse.
Sorry.
I didn't finish persuading.
Really want to persuade.
More than a week.
Then you can persuade it.
I didn't optimize it.
Low energy is not very good.
Then on the right.
If you look at it.
It will have that.
This peak will have an rns.
Mean square root.
nse or nse.
Sorry, rns.
Assuming you are normal distribution.
Then look at it.
Uh.
Sigma is its rns.
Then look at rns.
Red is the original method.
Green is my method.
Green is OK.
High energy is better than them.
Low energy is not very good.
This is my temporary persuasion.
Sorry.
Simple CNN is still not good enough.
So.
We are.
I did a lot of modifications in private.
For example, the target function has been modified.
When there are some patterns.
We split it into several.
Neural network to train separately.
Then put it together at the end.
This is another way.
We hope to use this method.
To solve the real.
Fail2 problem.
Of course, there are other problems.
For example, every csi crystal.
Assuming.
This simulation is the same.
But in fact.
Fail's csi crystal.
There are more than 100.
Although 8000.
Then there is.
The shape is not like 2D.
Weird distribution.
It is 3D.
It is also 2D.
But it is a cylinder distribution.
Then there are some.
There are some.
For example.
Or.
There are some.
Weird gamma rays.
That thing.
Need to overcome.
So we have a long way to go.
Thank you for your participation today.
If you use neural network.
Google DeepGin.
Can put the wolf.
Or put the little flower.
There are some references today.
You can take a look.
If it's just Bell.
Bell 2's predecessor.
It also has open data.
You can play if you are interested.
Bell 2 is also planning.
Open data.
It's a pity.
There is not so much open data.
That's it.
Thank you Kun Xian.
Does anyone have any questions?
What is that?
More than 100 kinds of CSI.
Is it different in ratio.
And there are impurities and so on.
It's a little different.
So what is it with him.
The ratio of CSMI is different.
It's all the same.
But it's a little different.
Hello.
I want to ask a question.
I just saw you write.
When you are in TransCNN.
Your loss function is used.
That is.
That is the ratio.
MSE.
Is there any special reason?
Because intuitively.
I think you want energy.
Not the ratio.
It's a good idea.
Thank you.
Uh
Your question.
Recognition, recognition.
Recognition, clear information already working.
Know trigger
Trigger.
Sorry. Are there are other?
I heard that you will have the
Ooooo.
Ooooo..
Like the middle finger and keon.
No, no. They are similar.
Middle finger and electron.
They are obviously different in pose shapes.
Or gamma ray.
Middle finger and gamma ray have different pose shapes.
They can be divided by pose shapes.
Because one is fully battery.
And the other is
Hedronic shower.
I'm sorry for those who
don't have time to make examples.
One is Hedronic shower and the other is Hedronic shower.
I've heard of it.
So that's how they can be divided.
If both are gamma ray
and you say this is backlight gamma ray
and this is signal gamma ray.
Of course, if it's Hedronic shower,
it can be divided.
Just look at it and you'll know.
Anyone else have questions?
Let me talk about it again.
We'll post this video
on our website.
You can find the link
on our fan page.
If you want to review
or want to see the links
or information in Kun's video,
that's what we'll post.
Q&A