I'm very happy to have you all here today for Lin Bo-xuan's talk.
Let me first introduce our speaker, Lin Bo-xuan.
She studied economics at NTU, and is now a sophomore at NTU Economics.
Currently, she is an intern at a startup company called ModLab in Pasadena, California.
Her main topic is game-related data analysis.
Today, we are very happy to invite Lin Bo-xuan to give a talk
about how to use class experiment data to test the stability of the final window match
and the results of the double-sided auction experiment.
Let's welcome Lin Bo-xuan to start her talk.
Thank you, Director Lin.
Without further ado, I'll get started.
Today's topic is very simple.
I'll just ask one question.
Are the results of the economic experiment we see on paper stable?
To be honest, in the field of economic experiments,
people are the ones doing the research.
So, if you want to say that a result is stable,
you can't just say,
if I were in Taiwan, I'd do this result.
Or, if I were in a victim group, I'd do that.
Often, we need to do a lot of different victim groups.
If we were to say that this result is right for all humans,
then it should be right to take the same result
and do the same experiment in every place.
But in fact, we often know that
this situation is often not necessarily right.
For example, let's say we measure the risk.
In Taiwan alone,
if you only measure the risk for men or women,
the set of risks may be different.
So, in fact, if we want to measure stability,
that is, if we want to do the same experiment
in many places, the result is wrong.
But often,
what we want to do
is actually very difficult in the experiment.
First, because economists know
that our research funds are limited.
Second, our time is limited.
So, often, it's hard for us to think about
whether we can do the same experiment
in every corner of the world.
So, this is a very difficult thing.
Because, mainly, there is a big limitation in economic experiments.
In fact, we hope to provide real benefits to consumers.
Because of this,
we need a lot of money and a lot of time.
We need to have a good enough time design.
Basically, it will be impossible to measure in every place in the world.
So, because of this,
we did not give up
to test whether our experiment results are stable or not.
So, there are two main ways
to do this on our website.
First,
for example,
in the case of Ultraman Game,
in fact, in the past 50 years,
there have been a lot of studies on the series of Ultraman Game.
So, basically,
there is a method
that we take the previous experimental data
and break it into a very large database
to do some meta-analysis here.
Just like what Usterbeck did in 2004.
But, like this,
there is a problem.
In fact, many times,
all the previous studies of Ultraman Game
are the same game,
but their context is a bit different.
So, in practice,
many times, your usage is different,
or your context is different,
which may affect the result of the experiment.
So, when we use this method,
we have already lost the control
of our experimental design.
Although this method
can make our database very rich.
The other way is that
we control the same experimental design,
but go to other places
to do the same experiment.
Just like Roth,
he has been to four countries in the world.
One is the United States,
one is Slovenia,
one is Israel,
and the other is Japan.
He went to these four countries
to do the same final analysis
and market game
to see if the results of these four countries
were stable or not.
This is the largest experiment
so far.
But, from this point of view,
even so,
we can only do it in a small number of places.
So, in this way,
although you can
control your experimental design,
but you can't make
your database very large.
So, today,
what we are doing is
using the third method.
It's like
you want to test the stability
of a result of an experiment.
There are three things to do.
One is the real sound,
and the third is to have a large enough sample.
The first two methods
are to give up
and control the experimental design.
The other is to give up a large enough database.
But what we are going to do today
is to have a large enough database,
and the design
is exactly the same.
But what we give up today is to give up
and control the sound.
In this case,
I can only say that we are the first article
to do this.
We have a lot of data.
But when we give up
and control the sound,
our experiment
will be done in a very
no-easy situation.
So, if we can
reproduce
all the experimental results
in the lab,
it means that the experimental results
are very stable.
As I said,
what we are going to use today
is MobLab.
MobLab is an experimental platform
for all class economics experiments.
If we take all the data from the class,
it is actually good and bad.
Of course, the two biggest concerns are
that all the students in the class
do not use money
to provide their sound.
Most of the time, they just use
the grade of the course
or other random numbers
to provide their sound.
This is what we have lost control of.
The two biggest concerns are
that many students in class
may not necessarily be
the representative sample
of the culture.
However, there are still
a lot of benefits
for us to try this method.
First of all,
there is no publication bias
in our database.
For example,
if you take the results
of the previous article
as a meta-analysis,
you may get too good results.
This is called publication bias.
However,
all the results, good or bad,
are recorded in our database.
Another thing is that
our company is
at least in the class of
experimental economics.
If you want to do a class experiment
in the world,
you basically use our company.
In fact, our sample is very diverse.
There are many different areas.
This gives us a lot of
variation to test.
Thirdly,
the environment in which our data is generated
is exactly the same.
The interface, language,
and the entire experiment process
are exactly the same.
This means that we have
completely controlled
the process of their game.
These are the three advantages
that we think
are very important.
Before talking about these two areas,
I would like to talk about
how big our dataset is.
First of all,
we can see that
this table is a total of
10 areas in our dataset.
You can see that
this data is across North America,
Europe, and Asia.
In Ultraman Game,
we have more than
15,000 sample points.
For those of you who do not know
the economics of time,
the data in Ultraman Game
is about 10 times more than
a normal article,
or 0 to 2.0.
In DoubleAction,
there are basically 2.0 more.
This is a very large sample
that we can test.
Next,
I will talk about these two areas.
These two areas are actually very simple.
The first is Ultraman Game.
In addition,
why do we choose these two areas?
The first is because these two areas
are the most abundant in our database.
The second is that these two areas
are basically the origin of
the economics of time.
In Ultraman Game,
there are two people in this game.
One is Proposer,
the other is Responder.
Proposer can decide
how much to give to the other party.
This game is very simple.
There is a ball in the middle.
You can decide how much to give to the other party.
You can pull the ball
and decide how much to give to the other party.
If you decide,
you can press Submit.
In this way, the other party can see
how much you gave to the other party.
Next,
suppose I decide to give the other party $45.
In this way,
the other party can see
that this is
a Proposer you have provided.
Proposer can decide
how much to give to the other party.
If you decide to give $45,
the other party can see
how much to give to the other party.
If you decide to give $45,
the other party can see
how much to give to the other party.
This is a very simple game.
It is like a simple negotiation
in a simulation game.
For example,
when you go to a night market
to buy vegetables,
don't pull the ball.
It is like a simulation game.
This is the game interface
of the Ultraman Game.
Next, I will talk about
double-sided auction.
The most classic example
of a double-sided auction
is like Wall Street.
They are selling stocks.
You may often see some pictures
or news photos
that there are many machines
and many traders
raising their hands and shouting.
This means that
everyone is shouting
how much to give to this person
and how much to give to that person.
Double-sided auction is like
Ultraman Game.
Ultraman Game has only one side
and you are given a Proposer.
In Double-sided auction,
no matter which side,
the buyer or seller
can shout at the same time.
One is the buyer, the other is the seller.
If you are the buyer,
you want to buy something.
We are buying oranges.
In this game interface,
the first thing you can see is
how much satisfaction you will get
when you buy an orange.
Next, you want to bid.
You can pull a slider bar.
You can move left and right
to decide how much you want to bid
to bid for this orange.
If you buy an orange,
the benefit is
the value deducted
and how much you spent to buy it.
If you are buying,
there are two ways to buy.
One is to bid here.
The other is
if there are many buyers
and they are already bidding
so you can also buy
at the lowest price.
The next one is
the seller.
The seller actually has the same
interface as the buyer.
If you sell an orange,
you have the cost
so you can see the cost here.
Next,
you can pull a slider bar
to decide how much you want to bid.
You can ask the price here.
Or you can decide
to sell the highest price here.
So I can sell it here.
Please note that
there is a special design
here.
When you decide to
ask the price here,
if the price is
negative,
I will change it to red
to warn you
that
this transaction
may result in a negative price.
So this is the double option
game interface.
Let me introduce
the game settings here.
This is because
in such a simple game interface,
many teachers
can adjust the game parameters
by themselves.
But in most cases,
many teachers use the pre-set options.
In Ultimatum Game,
the pre-set price is $100.
In the case of double option,
the pre-set market is
5 buyers
and each buyer
can buy 3 items.
In other words,
there are a total of 15 items in the market.
If we draw the value here,
the black line
is the demand curve.
The gray line
is the supply curve.
Before I start,
I want to talk about
the theoretical prediction
of these two games.
In Ultimatum Game,
the theoretical prediction is very simple.
If we look at it
from the perspective of the respondent,
the balance of a game
is basically
that if I do this option,
the reward is higher than the other option,
I should do this.
So if you look at the responder,
no matter what positive reward he sees,
I should accept it.
If I take $1, it's better than $0.
If I take $2, it's better than $0.
So in this case,
if I get a positive reward,
I should accept it.
If I get a negative reward,
If I get a positive reward,
I should accept it.
This is the theoretical prediction of Ultimatum Game.
However, in the past 50 years of research,
we all know that
this theory is basically written to be overturned.
Because a lot of times
when we do research,
we will find that
basically all the recipients
will not only give the other party $1,
because a lot of times you will be very unhappy.
This is Ultimatum Game.
In Double Option,
this is like the high school science textbook,
you will see Supply and Demand Curve.
If you want to solve this game, it's actually very simple.
You have to find a price
to clear all the markets.
So if you are here,
this gray curve is our
theoretical prediction price,
which is just the intersection of Supply and Demand Curve.
If this price
is higher,
if it is higher than the balance price,
it means that
there are more sellers who want to sell things at this time,
and fewer sellers want to sell.
So if the supply and demand are uneven at this time,
this force will force the price down.
But if the price is lower,
then there are more people who want to sell,
and fewer people want to sell.
So this force will push the price back.
This is also the intersection of Supply and Demand Curve.
This is our balance price.
Then in our predicted market,
the number of balances is 13,
and the price of the balance is $112.
So this is our game setting.
I want to stop here for a while.
Is everyone OK?
If there is no problem,
I will continue to talk about the results.
Wait a minute,
let me confirm first.
So here
the buyer's demand price
is $150.
The forecast is $150, $145,
$140, and so on.
Then it is reduced to $130.
So $150
and then $130.
What is the last one?
The last one is
$120 and $117.
Then the other side is from $50
and then continue to add $50.
Then I will continue.
First of all,
let's talk about
the overall result.
First of all, I want to show you
this table.
To summarize,
we mainly looked at the five outcome variables.
What are their numerical statistics?
First of all, in the Ultimation Game,
we mainly looked at two outcome variables.
One is how many proposals you give to the other party.
The other is how much your acceptance rate is.
First of all, we see the first one.
In the case of $100,
on average,
you will give the other party about $36.
This number is actually
very close to the result of our experiment.
For example, if we take
Rock's article in 1991 as a benchmark,
the average of the article
is 40.
So our difference is only 4%.
So I think it's a very close result.
Then the second one we looked at
is the acceptance rate.
What we are looking at now is unconditional.
If we look at
the unconditional acceptance rate,
the acceptance rate is 66%.
Rock's result is about 73%.
So the difference is only 6% or 7%.
But because our offer
is relatively low,
I think our result
is able to reproduce
Rock's result on the aggregate level.
Hello, I have a question.
You just said
he made 40 and then 36.
Or let's just say
how much is the experimental
and how much is the theoretical expectation.
I think it's very close.
I want to ask
what do you think?
Because you didn't show
your uncertainty range.
Maybe it's actually a very stable difference,
so it's not very close.
This is
what I will continue to talk about later.
Because I'm going to show you a statistic now.
I'll show you an approximate
numerical statistic.
But actually you're right.
If I have to do it,
I have to look at whether there is a significant difference.
But actually
the first one is
this is one point.
If I want to do an assessment,
there is another problem.
Our sample number is very unbalanced.
Very unbalanced.
So it means that our sample number
is about more than 10,000 points,
and their sample number is only more than 1,000 points.
So in fact, when you do an assessment,
sometimes there are some
bad points.
You need to pay attention.
But in fact,
at least in the case of showing data now,
I can only say it out loud.
I can only say it out loud now.
It depends on whether it's close or not.
Next,
the other three are
the results of the double option.
For the double option, I'm going to use three indexes
to talk about whether this market
has been able to
refine
the prediction of the theory.
The first three indexes we look at
are the average error.
The definition of the average error is actually below.
DQ is the price of
each unit
of each contract.
Subtract it.
This means
how much is the difference
from our theoretical prediction.
Next, I look at the average.
Because we often have
about 800 different market configurations.
So in order to make everyone
comparable, I use
the average price to standardize it.
So we can actually use this index
to see how much is our accuracy.
The next one is
our
Smith Alpha.
Smith is to commemorate
Brown-Smith, so that's why it's called this name.
Next, this index
is actually very simple.
It's the distance between
my price and
my theoretical prediction price.
So I take the square here.
Then I take another one.
Next, I look at the average distance.
Then I open a number.
So it's actually very similar to
my standard error.
But what I'm doing today is not average.
What I'm doing today is
theoretical prediction.
Next, I still use
my average price to standardize it.
So I can use this index
to measure the fluctuation of price.
The next
and the third index is Efficiency.
For Efficiency, I want to use
the above graph to explain.
So in this
market balance,
if this seller
makes a deal with this buyer,
then in the middle,
the upper part
is the
profit I make.
It's the buyer's profit.
The lower part is the seller's profit.
So that means
the total length of this segment
is the
profit I can make
from this deal.
So I take the
supply curve and demand curve
and divide it by the area.
So in theory,
how much surplus
can I get?
So the efficiency
definition is
the efficiency I achieve
in this market
and the efficiency
I expect in theory.
How much can I get?
So what I can see here is
first,
my average error is about 6%.
That means my average price
is about 6% higher than the theory.
Next,
my Smith Alpha,
my price fluctuation
is about 30%.
Next, my efficiency
is about 84%.
So in theory,
these numbers
are significantly different.
However,
this is related to another problem.
In our lab,
we usually let our customers
play the same game for 10 or 20 rounds.
At this time,
after more than 10 rounds,
the price will become very stable.
But here,
if we play 10 rounds,
the customer might have already
played 2 or 3 rounds.
This is why the price here is unstable.
But later on,
I will try to show
if
our students can play
enough rounds,
where will they end up?
This is the result of the double option.
I will show it.
Let's continue to look at
the whole distribution.
Sorry to interrupt you.
This has nothing to do with your speech.
I don't know if you have noticed
the Chrome dialogue next to you.
I don't know which computer
you are using.
I don't know what to do.
Thank you for reminding me.
I hope you don't interrupt me.
I don't want to leave the group.
Thank you.
Let's continue.
First, let's look at
the whole distribution of Proposal Offer.
Because
in our game design,
the teacher can decide
whether to play 1 round, 2 rounds,
or how many rounds.
If you play more than 2 rounds,
it will become a repeated game.
If we divide the data
into repeated and repeated games,
we can see
that
the first point
is
the theoretical expectation.
This is the theoretical expectation.
This is the theoretical prediction.
So here,
whether it's 1 shot game or repeated game,
only about 10% of the audience
play on the theoretical prediction.
Then we have 50%
of the audience
play on the theoretical prediction.
Next,
let's look at
the distribution.
The first observation is
that we have a lot of proposal offers
which means
I play on the whole number.
I play on 0, 10, 20, 30.
This is the first observation.
The second observation is
that only about 6% of the audience
play on the theoretical prediction.
I give myself less
and I give myself more.
In this game,
there should be a first-mover advantage.
I should give you 50%
if I'm great.
I shouldn't lose to you.
I should give you more.
This is the first observation.
Next, let's compare
the distribution with ROC.
This is ROC's distribution
in 1990.
As Zhang said,
we didn't do a statistical assessment.
So we can only see
whether we can catch the distribution.
The first observation is
that the density
is about 50 to 40.
We can capture this.
At this level,
we can replicate their results.
At this level, we can replicate their results.
In fact, the biggest difference
between our distribution and their distribution is
that almost no one here plays on
the theoretical prediction.
But about 10% of people
play on the theoretical prediction.
In fact,
at least me and Colin
are not sure.
Maybe this is the prediction option.
In the beginning of a game,
the prediction ball
is placed on the theoretical prediction.
If the student
doesn't think about it,
I will throw it away
without any strategy.
So 10% of people
may play on the theoretical prediction
and may be affected by the prediction option.
But this is...
Do you have response time here?
I will show it later.
According to your hypothesis,
the response time should be the lowest.
But the response time is very high.
But I will show the result later.
So it's not necessarily the predicted result.
But...
Sorry, can you show the previous video?
OK.
Because I was thinking
if you said it's because of the default option,
I can see...
Because there are very few people
who mentioned 1 in Rose's data.
But the people who mentioned 1 here
seem to be
significantly higher than 0.
But the people who mentioned 1 here
seem to be
significantly higher than 0.
So although 0 is so high,
it may be the effect of the default option.
But it seems that there are more people
who seem to be significant.
If you look at the balance behavior as 0 or 1,
there are more people who seem to be significant.
There are more people who seem to be significant.
That's what I think.
Thank you for this comment.
It should be said that
it should be said that
there should be quite a lot of people
playing with the theory.
But it is true that the effect of the default option is a confirmation.
But I will continue to talk about it.
Next, this is our acceptance rate.
Because I think this result is very cool.
It doesn't matter if I talk about it later.
I must make this result clear.
First of all, because what we talked about earlier
is the unconditional acceptance rate.
What is more interesting now
is to measure the conditional acceptance rate.
Unconditional
is the number of offers I see.
That is to say, because we measure
the expected value of the conditions.
This is actually a function of an offer.
So on this graph, my X axis
shows how many proposal offers I see.
Then my Y axis shows
what is my average acceptance rate.
In this graph,
the black dot represents the information of one-shot game.
The orange dot represents the information of a repeat game.
Next, the size of each point
represents
the density of the
histogram we saw earlier.
So if you put
the size of the size of the ball on the X axis,
it becomes the full
histogram.
Next, because
when I was checking the data,
I found that between 49 and 50,
there is actually a
20% jump.
So I think it's weird.
So I used a specification
to measure
the P-splice linear
specification.
So what you can see is
that if you are
less than 50,
you see that your acceptance rate is this curve.
When it is greater than 50,
there will be a big break point here.
This is completely obvious.
It is very obvious.
When we measure the standard error,
we also use
cluster. Then we have a cluster
at the session level.
We use the most conservative calculation
to estimate our variability.
So in this case, it is also very obvious.
If we put all the data
together, there is about
20% to 21% jump.
If we divide it into one-shot game and
repeated game,
one-shot game is about 16%.
Then again, in repeated game,
this jump becomes 26%.
First of all,
this phenomenon has not been seen in the first 50 years.
So I think it's a very
cool discovery.
Next, let's talk about 1.
First of all,
this interpretation is actually very complicated.
Because we have a lot of confounds here,
which our database can't detect.
But what we can be sure of is that
the source of this point is not
the difference in your payoff.
Because you can see that when we come from the left
B, you can come from 49.99999.
Then the next step is to come from the right B,
which is about 50.0000001.
In fact, this gap is less than
how small your Epsilon should be.
So the effect of this is definitely not
from monetary payoff.
Or even if you are in a hypothetical state,
it is basically not from
how much your payoff is.
So it is very possible that this point is
your other regarding preference.
That is to say, at this time, you must
consider what other people
in this proposal offer.
What does it look like?
Next, there are many ways to say
that we can't uniquely pin down.
It may be like
because you are from 49.999 to 50.
You have a big gap here,
which is equality.
Because this paragraph can also mean
that I may be very, very care.
Am I equal to you?
Or this is the first one.
Or the other is to say that
if you don't give me 50,
I may have to punish you.
So this is why this paragraph may be
10% more in the repeated game.
It may be that this 10% is more
and I have to punish you.
Or I may care about my fairness.
Or I just say that since
we are not playing real money,
I just don't want to lose you.
So it means that if I am below,
my acceptance rate is relatively low.
So basically it's the same as
you and Yuqi.
This is what we see in the data.
I would like to ask
what your thoughts are.
Actually, I don't know.
Before you do this,
there is a question.
Although you know a lot,
but in fact,
even if you just showed us,
there are very few offers
that exceed 50.
There are about 600.
If you look at the group,
there are 600.
For example,
your estimate of acceptance rate
because you are not using strategy method,
you are showing offer.
So it means that
you are now running this break point return.
I think that
when it is below 50,
the variation is actually better.
But the part above 50
is probably more unstable.
But it looks like
this break point is really interesting.
Because
I think about it.
Have you ever tried
you don't use
in the part below 50,
you don't use linear return to run.
I haven't tried it yet,
but I want to try quadratic.
Because there is another possibility
that it is actually not
presented as a break point,
but a more complex
non-linear.
Just because you fit linear,
it doesn't look like a break point.
Because if you look at the data directly,
it looks at least
I think it's quite linear.
If you look at the part of the orange repeat game,
it looks like
it's actually
a strange fall first,
but it's more stable
when it reaches 40.
This may be more like quadratic.
If you only look at black,
it looks like
it's a
between 20 and above
50 is a shakier
drop, but
below 20
it's more stable.
So
it's possible here,
just because
you fit a one-point
linear relationship.
Anyway, I will try quadratic.
But this is
what I estimated.
I think it's quite interesting.
If this is true,
how do we
at least I think
how to reproduce this break point in the lab
I think it's quite interesting.
Let's look at the results of ROS.
If we look at the data of ROS,
this break point is completely invisible.
So
this result
I think it's quite special.
This means that we have a lot of work hypothesis
running here at the same time.
However, we have tried
a power test.
This means that if we only draw 10%
because our sample number is about 0.
So if we only draw 10%
can we estimate this break point?
This means that we still have a way to estimate this break point.
So it may not be because
the problem of power in statistics.
Then another
our work hypothesis may be because of
hypothetical stake.
Is it because it's all
invisible?
So I care more about the ranking between you and me.
At least I don't want to lose to you.
So
this is my current work hypothesis.
This may be
the next article that can be done
is how to reproduce this break point in the lab.
I think it's quite interesting.
Can you remind us again
about the population composition
of your data?
For example,
the proportion of each state or
province?
We have seen that
in the United States, there are western states,
central and western states.
Then there are northeastern states.
Then there are southern states.
Then there is Canada.
Then in Europe, there are
the United Kingdom and Spain.
Then in Asia,
there are China, Japan and Singapore.
What about the proportion?
About 80% of the data is in the north.
Then about 10% in Europe
and about 10% in Asia.
OK.
So overall,
this result
is more conservative.
It is the result of the main cultural circle
in North America, right?
Yes.
OK. I just want to ask.
But I want to add
that the problem is
that all the results of the lab
are not in North America.
Yes.
This is true.
OK.
Then I will...
Bo-xuan,
if you want to compare with
Ross's work,
Ross's work is mainly not in North America.
Then the data of
the other works,
such as Madden Game,
can you observe?
I have almost never seen any points.
Yes. OK.
OK.
Because of the time...
Let me continue.
I have a question.
This article was made
about 20 years ago,
right?
Yes.
Do you think that the evolution of time
has a big impact on the data?
Of course it is possible.
Because a lot of social preferences
may follow the evolution of time.
For example, the value of Taiwanese
has changed over the past few years.
So it is true that this may be
different.
But we can see that
the social preferences
have a big impact on the game.
If this has any impact on the data,
it may be OK.
Because the data may be a mirror effect.
But this is a big problem.
We can talk about it later.
Then I will continue.
Finally, the teacher just said
that we need to show the reaction time.
Our server does record the reaction time.
Then...
Because
OneShotGame and RePDGame
have similar patterns.
So I only use OneShotGame
to show the result.
First of all, the black line
represents the reaction time.
The black line represents the reaction time.
The black line represents
the lowest estimation.
The orange line
represents the acceptance rate.
Then...
This is also my lowest estimation.
The X-axis represents
my offer.
If you don't have any concept,
the lowest estimation is
the return time
in each section.
This means that
I am fitting the data
when I am close to 0.
It is close.
So what the teacher saw at the beginning
is that
he spent a lot of time
to make the decision.
He spent almost 20 seconds to make the decision.
But you can see
that 50 is very short.
There is a drop.
It only takes about 8 seconds to make the decision.
This means that
50 is a very special allocation
for the number.
At least for them,
if I see 50,
I don't need to think too much
to make the decision.
Another thing is that
we see a sharp kink
in the acceptance rate.
This means that
it is possible that
no matter what the
probability is,
at least we can still see something.
This is the data
on the reaction time.
However, the interpretation is
quite special.
At least for the show data,
we can spend very little time
to make the decision.
Bo-xuan,
is there no way to record
the time for the proposer to enter the game
and his proposal?
Because if you want to see if it is D4...
Let me think about it.
What we can see is that
we only start to calculate the time
when we enter the game.
Because it depends on whether
the effect caused by the default option
causes many people to raise 0.
Right.
You are right.
We do see the time for the proposer.
However, I remember that
it took a lot of time.
OK.
This is...
Hello?
Let me answer.
At the time close to 0,
you said that
it took a lot of time.
You mentioned that
you were thinking...
At the beginning,
you said that
there were many results at 0, right?
Yes.
At that time,
you thought that
the starting point of SliderBar was 0, right?
Yes.
In fact,
they spent a lot of time thinking about it.
It seems that
it is not because...
I think it is like
canceling the explanation
you mentioned at the beginning.
Is it because
they just accepted it?
That's right.
However,
it took a lot of time.
It took a lot of time.
I should show you the time for the proposer.
The time for the proposer.
However,
the explanation of calling is quite interesting.
Why did it take a lot of time
to think about it?
Many people were reluctant to accept it.
It took a lot of time
to accept it.
That's right.
Bo-xuan,
you can split the responder
into accepted and unaccepted.
OK.
This is a special point.
I will split it.
I will write it down.
Next,
I still have some time.
I want to talk about the result of double option.
Double option is...
Sorry, Bo-xuan.
Before you talk about double option,
can I talk about the point of
Automaton Game?
I was just thinking that
you just said that
one possibility is that
everyone cares about fairness.
The other possibility is that
everyone cares about
not losing.
Is the acceptance rate
particularly high?
Yes.
Or is it a whole point?
There is a point that goes up
and then forms a square curve.
If you care about fairness,
maybe 50 is particularly high,
and then 51, 52,
there will be another point.
One-shot game is like this.
There is no repeated game.
OK.
I will continue to talk about it.
I'm afraid I don't have enough time.
Next, double option is...
First, I want to show you
what the data looks like.
This is our predicted market.
Next, the whole price changes.
This is just an example.
I have 10 regions here.
I choose a market for each region.
I draw it out
to show you what it looks like.
You can see that I only draw four levels.
Because the length is about four levels.
If you look at the first level,
everyone may be very noisy.
Next, look at the second level
and the third level,
the price changes less.
In the fourth level,
the more you play, the more stable it becomes.
What we want to see here is
that under the market mechanism of double option,
as long as you play about three or four times,
consumers can find
a balanced price, even if I don't tell them anything.
Next, another thing,
as I said before,
the market is very short.
So we want to estimate
what it is like.
If it can play a lot of games,
where will it end up?
We spent
about a month
to come up with this.
First of all,
let's talk about intuition.
Let's talk about an example.
Let's say
a lot of people here have the same experience.
When you apply for a PhD,
I want to know
what this student will do
in the rest of his career.
But the only thing I can know
is what his GPA
will look like in the next four years.
So at this time,
for a school,
if it wants to estimate
what will happen next,
the only thing it can do is
to increase his GPA in different periods.
So it's possible that
I put more weight on the GPA at the end
You can look at two parts.
The first one is
the Dependent Variable on the left.
On the right,
if we look at T as 1,
this means that I am in the first period.
In this case,
this is back to the simplest return.
This is very common.
In the first period,
if you use the example of GPA,
your first semester
is likely to have a lot of variables.
Maybe it's because you're a middle school student
and you don't know what's wrong with your GPA in the first semester.
However,
in the second period,
I only give you one-second weight
to explain your starting point,
such as building a house or something like that.
I only give you one-second weight.
I also give you one-second weight
for your GPA at that time.
This means that your GPA at this time
may be only half of the population
in front of you.
In the third period,
I put two-thirds weight on your GPA.
In this case,
I only give you one-third weight
for your starting point.
So you can see that
if I can make T
as large as infinite,
then my beta2
is actually
the progressive estimate of
our dependent variable.
In other words,
if we put this Y
on all the indicators of the first three markets,
then where will this market end up?
If consumers can play enough,
then we put this Y
on all the indicators of the first three markets,
then we can see that
the first one is mean error deviation.
Its final price is only
1% higher than the average price.
It is not significantly different
from the theoretical estimate.
Then the final price change
is reduced to 11%.
Although the estimate is a bit big,
it is also not significantly different
from the theoretical estimate.
The final price change is reduced to 97%.
It is also not significantly different from the first one.
So these results are basically
completely the same as the results of the lab.
So at least
we can prove that
double auction is a very stable
price mechanism
to reach 100% efficiency.
So we can see that
our data also shows the same thing.
When our students can play enough,
all of our welfare
should be exhausted.
Can I go back to the last page?
Yes, you can.
I want to confirm
the quantitative model.
Why is there no variable
next to Beta 2?
Because this means
what I want to see is
where your final GPA is.
What I bring here is a constant.
What I multiply here
is a constant.
The point is that I am
multiplying your
current GPA
with your original demographic
variation.
Is it OK?
It doesn't matter.
If you don't understand,
I will discuss with you later.
I will continue.
What we see in the end is that
although we can basically
get the theoretical estimate,
what we want to see is that
where your final GPA is.
What we see in the end is the amount of transactions.
The horizontal axis
is the theoretical estimate amount.
The vertical axis is the amount of transactions.
The horizontal axis is the amount of transactions.
The point is that
if the market is not balanced,
we are often under-traded.
It is possible that
the last one or two transactions
may bring us only 1% or 2% of efficiency.
In this case,
it is possible that
I am too lazy to make the last 1 or 2 cents.
This is the main result of
the double option.
I have about 10 minutes left.
I want to talk about
what I said earlier.
We have a lot of
variations in different countries.
I want to use some
meta-analysis tools
to analyze
the composition of these variations.
First,
we look at
the variations between countries.
Basically,
we need to use
a
meta-analysis
to calculate
I squared.
If you look at
this graph,
you can see that
these are
the average variations of the proposal offer.
Next,
we have all the variations,
the variations between countries,
and the variations within countries.
What we want to know is
what is the proportion of
the variations between countries.
We calculate I squared.
Since we don't have much time,
I won't talk about
how to calculate I squared.
What we can figure out is
the proportion of
the variations
within countries.
We can see that
86.6% of the variations
in the proposal offer
are significant.
Although we can't say
that this is a cultural difference,
we can say that
the variations within countries
are significant.
From the same perspective,
we look at the acceptance rate.
The acceptance rate is special
because we look at
the shape of the probability function.
In order to make it comparable,
what we can do is
we look at
a logic regression.
On the left, we put 0 and 1 variables,
which is whether you accept or reject.
On the right, we put
10 dummy variables
in addition to the offer.
The result is that
the dummy variable
is the shape of the probability function.
We take the coefficient
to measure the variations.
We can see that
only 30% of the variations
come from countries.
This is not significant.
We can see that
in the Ultimatum Game,
the proposal offer has a significant
variation between countries,
but the acceptance rate is not significant.
This also responds to
Roth's conjecture in 1991.
Roth proposed a hypothesis
in 1991.
In the Ultimatum Game,
the cultural difference between
countries should be
reflected by
the proposal offer,
but it does not affect
the acceptance rate.
This is a very good
evidence
to respond to
Roth's initial hypothesis.
Next, we look at
the variation between double options.
We take two things,
the first one is the price.
We look at the first round
of each market.
Then we look at
the first and last price
in the predicted market.
We want to know
how the market price
is balanced.
First, we look at
the first price of each market.
We can see that
the first one is
only 27.3% of the variations
are not written.
The second one,
we can see that
the first price
is very noisy
in some places
like Spain or Singapore.
Although the number of variations
is small,
it causes the standard error
to be large.
However,
in other countries,
the standard error bar
is very small.
Moreover,
every country can
predict the market price.
Next,
if we look at
the overall price distribution,
the first price
is about 0.33%.
The second one is
only 14% of the overall price,
so it is almost 60%.
This tells us that
you may not know
the market price,
but you can
stabilize the balance.
This is the reason
why many economists
like the market.
Even if you don't know anything,
the market will tell you
what the balance looks like.
Finally,
I want to summarize
with this video.
In this project,
we use the lab data
to predict the market price.
In Ultimate Game,
we can see that
more than 94% of the proposals
are below 50%.
Many proposals
are above the natural
poker point.
In terms of acceptance rate,
we see a 20% breakpoint.
In the reaction,
we see 10% more breakpoints.
In response time,
it is the lowest
of the three.
Finally,
no matter which of the three
we use,
accuracy,
fluctuation,
or efficiency
will all be calculated.
Finally,
we can see that
in Ultimate Game,
the proposal offer
has more breakpoints
than acceptance rate.
This is in response to
Roth's 1990 contracture.
Finally,
if we compare Ultimate Game
with Double Option,
we can see a big difference
between the two countries.
This is in response to
Double Option is a very stable mechanism
in all countries.
I think this is all
I want to say.
I will show my email.
If you have any questions,
we have about 5 minutes left.
Let's see what questions you want to ask.
Mr. He,
do you want to comment?
Mr. He, please comment.
I want to ask
if you have any questions.
I will ask first.
Wait a minute.
The first question is for Mr. He.
Do you want to estimate
the result of long-term training?
There is a way.
You can show us
the data
in the lab.
If you only use the previous few rounds,
then you can estimate
the result of long-term training.
This way,
you can estimate the result of long-term training.
I'm not sure
how you estimate the result
of long-term training
in the country.
I'm not sure
how you estimate the result of long-term training.
I will talk about it first.
No, no.
What I mean is
what is the hypothesis
you want to verify.
If it is a double auction,
why do you
say that
Asians are more polite?
No, what I want to say is
double auctions
in different places around the world
have similar results.
However,
there is a big difference
between each country.
That's what I want to say.
Let me think about it.
There is a problem here.
You think the market
is universal.
However,
there is a problem here.
There is a problem here.
If you don't use the strategy method,
you can't see
the complete strategy
of the respondent.
You think
what you see is
acceptable or not,
you can only explain
30% of the variation.
However,
what is the actual strategy?
I'm not sure
where you can check.
It is possible
that because
different countries
have already explained
most of the proposal
that is,
everyone
has proposed
a social standard
that meets
the social standard
of the proposal.
But that part
may be because it is all
hidden in the
proposal.
This is also the point I want to talk about.
OK.
Can I ask a question?
Hi.
0 and 100
I agree with what Meng just said.
The default reaction time
is a test
to see if it is a default effect.
You said you have
experimental instructions.
Can you tell
which ones are
really incentivized?
Can you tell which ones are really incentivized?
Usually, the incentive for
an experiment is
how many points I give you
if you take part in the experiment.
But I don't know what their design is like.
Some may be related to
your test result.
a participation experiment.
But the result is not affected by it.
You will see more than 100 points.
It may be normal.
Because the result may be
a naive or unexpected behavior.
About the more than 0 points,
I think
it is a
inherent problem.
In general, those who do experiments with
telecom all use
Marbled.
I don't know whether it is right.
But, I think it is.
What about after-graduate students?
What about after- graduate students?
The third option is
the course of
Ultimatum Gate.
The third option is
the course of Ultimatum Gate.
The 3rd option is
for example,
after-graduate students finish the course,
the theoretical prediction of Ultimatum Gate is 0.
Then, they do the experiment.
Or, they do the experiment before the theoretical prediction.
There is a difference.
Because, after-graduate students do the experiment,
the 3rd option
is the default of many people.
I know.
We have seen
different courses.
The smallest course is the course of Game Theory.
OK.
This is a sample.
You can imagine
the degree of
interaction between
the scope of each course,
this is Ludger' class.
Because we have a class name,
So, we may roughly know the degree of interaction.
The only difference is
after-shared theory prediction
of Ultimatum Gate is 0,
I can't see it.
For 0 and 100,
in the data of Google Earth,
the two peaks
are very different.
So, I think
if you can
clear those data,
or find the way
like just now,
and then compare with the kink,
OK.
Maybe it will be closer.
I don't know if it will affect.
OK.
I have a notebook.
You ask first.
OK. Thank you.
This is not a question.
It's more like a comment.
Since
you have the default option
bias,
it seems to be a very serious thing.
It will make your two curves
and theory different.
My idea is
whether you can...
I don't know if it will be too difficult.
When you change your program,
when you change your game,
you make every starting point different.
You can choose a starting point
to solve your next problem.
Let me respond.
This is technically
very simple.
But there is another problem
in economics.
There is a friction effect.
I'm afraid there will be an anchoring result.
So...
Oh.
If
your starting point is a very high offer,
it is very likely that people will be affected
by that point.
OK. My offer is higher.
If my starting point is lower,
I may be affected by this point.
So we are...
About this,
we can't control
the standard time.
Usually,
the way to control the prediction effect
is to put $100
directly on the table.
Don't put it on both sides.
Put it one by one.
OK.
But
in their operation,
they choose
to put it directly at the beginning.
So there will be a prediction effect.
But in terms of reaction time,
the effect should be very small.
I have a response.
Or just change the interface
to fill in the numbers directly.
Don't use the LaBar method.
Of course,
this is also possible.
But this may have to talk
to the engineer.
But this is also possible.
But we want to change it.
We want to use LaBar mainly to
make the picture interesting
and make consumers want to buy it.
I don't know why.
Everyone thinks LaBar is fun.
Everyone likes LaBar.
But there will be a lot of problems.
Of course.
LaBar is because
a lot of people are operating
with a tablet.
This is also...
I have a question.
You say.
Hello.
This question is like this.
You know that Zhang Anping
is studying social psychology.
They often play this kind of
game.
But they like to do one thing,
which is to manipulate the victim.
For example, let you play the game first,
then teach you game theory,
then let you play the game,
then look at the difference.
But what they do more often is
to let you play the game first,
then let you watch Hitler's documentary,
do you try to manipulate the victim?
This is what we can't do.
Because we...
Because it means
different treatments for the victim.
We can compare the experimental group and the control group.
But we are basically because
we don't have an experimental group and a control group.
So this is what we can't do.
There is no way to look at this information.
But of course, if we are in the lab,
it can be done completely.
But you can sell the product to the psychology department.
This is what I am sure of.
So now we are going to hire a psychologist.
I think this will be a pretty interesting tour.
Because they are indeed writing.
And they are going to write the first book
by themselves in MATLAB.
In fact, I think the meeting is ugly.
That's what you're doing.
So I think there is
marketing potential.
I should tell the boss about this.
And science, in terms of science,
is actually interesting, I think.
I want to tell the boss about this.
And Bozun,
let me ask you again.
As long as you can see
all the regions,
you should be able to see which schools
use MATLAB, right?
Yes.
Do you have a proposal for
the education level or the income level?
No income.
But we have a division
for each school.
I want to say that the school itself is an income proxy.
It must be some library.
Yes.
But I haven't connected yet.
I haven't connected with the income in that area.
I propose that you can
take a look.
Because you have income data now.
You have similar income or education
level data.
You should be able to find it up there.
But don't give me homework, please.
OK.
In fact, if you have any
questions, I can't think of it now.
You can e-mail me.
Or you can find me on Facebook.
Then...
The small question I just wanted to ask is
that you said that
ROTH is between
the proposer and the responder.
You said that the variation comes from the
proposer, which is the ROTH hypothesis.
Does this hypothesis come from
the observation of its data or from
some theory?
It comes from the observation of its data.
Because there are only four
countries, and each country basically
compares the last round of data.
So you're talking about
comparing 100 data points.
So
for ROTH, it can't do
statistical analysis. It can only say
what the four distributions look like.
And what my observation looks like.
OK.
So are there any questions
from the audience?
Our speech time is
almost over.
Can you stay for a while?
I want to talk to you.
Sure.
OK.
That's all for today's speech.
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you.
Applause, please.
I'll pause the recording.