Q&A
Today's speaker is Dr. Wu Xinmei, a Ph.D. student at the University of Utah, majoring in geoscience.
Before coming to the U.S., she was a graduate student of the Department of Geosciences at NTU.
Xinmei and I have met in many areas that are not overlapping.
I met Xinmei when she was a Ph.D. student at the University of Utah.
My wife and Xinmei were classmates in college.
After coming to Caltech, she met another Taiwanese friend in the Department of Physics, and turned out to be Xinmei's classmate.
She will be talking about Anatomy of Ophethal in Yellowstone from Seismic Observation.
Let's give her a round of applause.
Oh, by the way, you have to turn on the microphone to hear the applause.
Thank you for the introduction.
Today's presentation is a relatively easy one.
There won't be a lot of formalities.
I will focus on the concepts.
Because people are not familiar with geoscience or geophysics,
I will focus on the concepts and focus on Ophethal Geyser.
Ophethal is a very famous geyser in the U.S.
If you go sightseeing in Yellowstone Park, you will definitely go to Ophethal.
I hope you will find this topic more interesting.
First, let's talk about Yellowstone.
Yellowstone is on the left of Wyoming, Montana, and Idaho.
This is the intersection of the three states.
This is the area of the National Park.
Ophethal is on the right of Wyoming.
Let me introduce Ophethal first.
Ophethal is a place where people rarely go to sightseeing.
People usually go sightseeing to Ophethal.
Because it takes about five hours to get to many national parks.
So if you drive from Ophethal to Yellowstone, it will take about five hours.
If you have a chance to visit, you can come and visit.
Yellowstone is famous for its volcanic activity.
People have heard of Ophethal.
But if you come to the National Park to sightsee,
what you see is not volcanic activity.
It's more like a geyser, a hot spring, or a hydrothermal feature.
I'll go into more detail later.
If you drive from West Yellowstone to Ophethal,
it will take about 30 to 40 minutes to get to Ophethal.
So, after you drive in,
you will see the National Park,
and then you will see Ophethal.
So, after you drive in,
you will see parking lots,
and then you will see the Visitor Center.
And then you will see Ophethal.
If you are going overhead,
you will see a typical geyser hill,
because it has the highest density in the world with a hydrothermal feature.
If you zoom in, you can see a lot of things smoking on the roadside.
If you can experience it,
I would recommend coming here.
You will see colorful platforms
anywhere when it rains.
This is the Geyser Hill trail.
You can see a lot of hydrothermal features.
You can see the Old Facebook logo
in the distance.
There is a video on the right.
We go there every year.
This is the video.
I thought Americans knew about it,
but they didn't.
They were surprised.
Old Facebook is a great place to experience.
It's a great place to experience.
You can predict when it will be blown up next time.
There is a 10-minute error.
I heard that a lot of people like Geyser Hill trail.
You may Google that if you're interested inrians effect.
You may Google that if you're interested in irians effect.
While we're outside the historical community,
while we're outside the historical community,
you can see the Eruption Interval.
You can see the Eruption Interval.
You can see the European expansion.
Existence of Eruption Interval will show whether loop time when Eruption Incurred will be close or not.
Eruption Interval will show whether loop time when Eruption Incurred will be close or not.
Would you like to ask something?
Have you ever seen the Eruption Interval?
What's infrastructure?
Hello.