Welcome everyone to today's TerraTalk. We are approaching the end of the year, so we may not have a speech next week.
Today, we are honored to invite Dr. Yang Yaolun to tell us about his doctoral research.
Dr. Yang Yaolun is now a doctoral candidate for the Department of Astronomy at UT Austin.
In fact, he is about to graduate.
When he was in college, he graduated from the Department of Astronomy at UT Austin, and then came to the United States to study astronomy.
His specialties and research interests include early-phase star formation, including observations and simulations.
In his doctoral research career, he has used various telescopes such as Herschel, ALMA, and SOFIA to do his research.
What is interesting is that he is also the host of Astronomy on Tap at UT Austin.
What kind of event is this?
They will regularly give speeches to the public on astronomy at the bar.
They have now grown to more than 250 people attending each time.
Dr. Yang Yaolun is the host of Astronomy on Tap at UT Austin.
Today, he will talk about the topic of the birth of solar-like stars and the inseparable entanglement of dynamics and chemistry.
Let's welcome Dr. Yang Yaolun to give a speech.
Thank you.
I have been involved in this project for a long time.
I am very happy to have the opportunity to talk to you.
Over the past few years, I have been doing research on star formation at UT Austin.
I am a 6th-year PhD student at UT Austin.
My main advisor is Neil Evans.
We mainly do various observations on star formation.
We use models to explain the physical and chemical phenomena observed in early star formation.
Dr. Yang mentioned SOFIA observations.
What is SOFIA?
SOFIA stands for Stratospheric Observations for Infrared Astronomy.
It is an astronomical observatory for infrared.
Why do we use SOFIA for infrared observation?
Because there are a lot of water vapors in the atmosphere.
These water vapors emit a lot of infrared rays.
When we observe on the ground, we only observe the water vapors on the earth.
So, many times, we use a telescope, such as Spitzer or Hubble, to observe infrared rays.
If I remember correctly, we can avoid 95% to 99% of water vapors by using a telescope.
This is SOFIA.
You can see that SOFIA is a modified Boeing 747.
You can see that there is a bulge in the middle section of the tail of the plane.
It is not very clear here.
It is a hole in the middle section.
A 2.7-meter telescope is placed in the hole.
When the telescope flies up, the door will open.
This is how it is observed.
Astronomers and technicians discuss how to make the observation easier to achieve and adjust the strategy in time.
This is how my advisor and I are going to get on the plane.
It is very different.
This is a military airport.
When you enter the airport, you will go up the stairs.
There is a B-2 bomber in the same airport.
This is the inside of SOFIA.
The blue part is the instrument.
The other side of the closed cabin is the telescope.
The other side of the telescope is the mirror.
The other side is the instrument.
There is a balance on the weight on both sides.
Different instruments, telescopes, and mission operators monitor the observation on these stations.
This is a very complicated task.
NASA considers every flight of SOFIA as a mission.
There is a mission director.
There is a mission briefing before departure.
This is the route we flew that day.
We flew from Palmdale, California, about an hour and a half north of LA.
You can see that the route is very strange.
Basically, the route is determined by each arc.
One arc is for a target.
Here we have six or seven targets.
The longer, the longer you stay on the celestial body.
Let's move on to today's topic.
Today's topic is mainly about star formation.
How do we understand the dynamics of early planetary orbits and the corresponding chemical changes?
This is a picture of our galaxy.
You can see a lot of these black irregularities in the middle.
This is what we call Darkland.
It has a lot of dust.
It is also a higher density place.
It is also an area where stars are forming.
If we zoom in to one of them, the Molecular Cloud,
It is mainly a star-forming place.
These black areas are also the so-called dust gathering areas.
It is a place where stars form early.
If we switch to infrared light,
You can see that there are a lot of these pillars or even what we call filamentary structures.
These are from what we imagine as a celestial sphere on Earth.
It's like a sphere in the sky, but it's not a ball or even a block here.
It's more like a texture or a filamentary structure.
Then through these filaments,
The gas and dust will be pulled to the middle through this filament.
Then pull to the middle and then reach a high enough density.
Then trigger the activity of this star formation.
This is when the star formation occurs.
You will have a lot of.
Basically, the density will be from 10 to 3 or 10 to 5.
This is the mole per cubic centimeter.
It will be quickly multiplied by 10 to the power of 9 to the power of 10 to the power of 4.
This is a very large number of changes.
In the process, if you have, um.
At the beginning, um.
When the collapse, um.
You're going to have a little bit of, uh.
The angular momentum is in the outermost part.
If you have this smaller angular momentum, it's in a very small area.
It's going to be a lot of rotation.
At this time, the degree of rotation is likely to make this.
The collapse of the star formation is not very effective.
That is to say, your, uh.
The gas becomes itself to rotate there, not to continue.
Continue, uh.
It's sucked into the middle of the star.
In the process, there will be a lot of.
We call outflow, and then go.
Go to these, um.
The high-speed rotation of the matter is released.
And then go in to reduce.
The angular momentum of the whole system.
You see the green ones here.
The matter that looks like a jet is the outflow.
Now, this is a simulation.
That is, um, a simulation.
Roughly describe that we are from a filament.
And then slowly, uh, develop into.
It will start with a filament, and then zoom in.
And then you'll see a star.
The early shape of the star.
The situation is a lot of molecules.
Very, very fatal molecules.
How to be in that state.
And then, um.
Collapse and then erupt.
That's what you saw in the picture just now.
This kind of outflow.
OK, so you can see this whole process.
Is very, very.
Very big change, and then, um.
It's going to take a lot, a lot, a lot.
Irregular structure.
So.
We also found in observation.
That's what it is.
You can see here, this one.
The picture behind this black and white picture is.
Uh, the distribution of molecules.
This is.
And then the different symbols in front of it.
It means that we are directly observed.
Early star.
Uh, where it appears.
You can see most of it.
Early stars are in, um.
These molecules.
Uh, it's also a more fatal place, so it's produced.
So, um.
We can probably get one of these.
Uh, scenario is to say that you first have a lot of very fatal clouds and dust.
And then through.
Um, these clouds and dust may slowly or even quickly.
Um.
It will collapse to the middle and then become.
Uh, a star or a few stars, I don't know.
So in this process, a very important thing is to say.
Oh, this is probably a very simple one.
Uh, cartoon pattern to express the words is that we have a, uh, a core at the beginning.
We call pre-stereo core.
Simply put, it's the core before the stellar.
So it's called pre-stereo core.
And then you start to collapse.
These core collapse to the middle and become, uh.
Uh, in the early days, it was called pro-star.
So we called this core pro-stereo core.
At the same time, it may, uh.
Um.
It produces a lot of, uh, these.
These flow, this orange side is called the flow.
What about the evolution?
These substances.
The surrounding matter is either sucked into the middle and becomes a part of the star.
Or.
It will be affected by a lot of feedback.
And then it just.
It's just slowly, uh, dissipated.
And then the rest of you are left with a disk.
Because.
There's still a lot of matter, um, in the middle.
The middle part of the high-speed rotation.
There's no way it's very direct.
It's sucked into the middle, uh, on the planet.
So there's a disk.
What about this side?
This disk is, um, planet.
It's where the stars are produced.
So gradually, this disk will slowly evolve into, uh.
Generally, we recognize the planter system.
Just like.
Our solar system, we may be somewhere here.
Okay, um.
So we, uh.
There's a pretty important one.
Uh, the question is, is this.
In the early days of this info, from this.
When you want to produce a pro star.
What?
Uh, it's like a process like this.
How much is his time scale?
Okay, um.
In the pre-status evolution, it's not quite certain now.
So basically.
Um.
If a core starts to collapse.
To become.
Uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh.
Um.
It's about.
2 million years.
Relatively short.
From disk to disk, it's about 10 million years.
So then a, like our sun, our sun can probably live.
10 million years.
So this is probably their, maybe 1% of the time.
1% of the time.
Then I have another question.
Uh, that's it.
How do you say this?
Such a process.
With the limit, for example, is Modern Universe.
Or, for example, Z3, Z5.
Or something like that.
Or these things will only happen in the near future.
So there is no difference.
I'm going to ask you to go in.
Well, it's actually happening, but it's also happening in the early days.
There are even a lot of active research areas that are doing so-called first star, which is the first star that starts the earliest.
The biggest difference is in.
Uh.
It's in the cold, it's.
Um.
This core, a dance core, he wants to collapse, he doesn't need.
Uh.
It doesn't have to be dynamic.
If he is.
Uh.
The temperature is very high, he is very, his thermal motion is very strong, so he.
His thermal pressure, he can easily be greater than this gravity to him.
This middle attraction, so.
Um, when the temperature is very high, it is not easy to collapse.
So he has to be cold enough for him to collapse.
Of course, in the early universe.
Um, I should say, um.
So how do you make this core cold?
Usually a very important mechanism is called, uh, radio cooling.
Basically, uh.
Your energy, uh, is absorbed by molecules, and then molecules, molecules, decay, connect, decay, and then turn into radiation, radiation, and then your energy leaves this system.
So you, you will slowly become cold.
That molecule or.
Um.
It's more, except for hydrogen and hydrogen, all of them are quite useful for cooling.
That's relative to the early universe.
You will be weaker.
So, in the early universe, everyone will think that you can become very, you can become very big.
And then, and then it's easy to form a super big quality, etc.
And so on.
I believe that we haven't observed anything yet, but there should be a lot of simulation to do this part.
Okay, thank you.
Okay, so, um.
So, from an observational point of view, we want to know, uh, how does this collapse happen?
What kind of mold does this material go through?
From the outside of this core to the area that is transferred to the inside.
So, like, in this simulation, it's simulating.
How does this core collapse?
And then, in the end.
You can see that this middle collapse is very, very short at the beginning.
Compared to the time point after that.
So, uh, you can see that this is the same as the previous one.
You can see that it is very irregular.
And so it means that there may be a lot of structures in it.
Different structures, different modes.
Depending on the angle you look at, there may be an outflow.
Other places may see info.
So, um.
For this info measurement, we mainly want to know how this info started.
And then how did he do it?
For example, how far is he?
How big is it?
What kind of size scale starts?
What kind of characteristic?
For example, how big does this core need to grow at what temperature?
He will start to have info.
So what's his process?
He's with, uh.
Uh, the radius is getting smaller and smaller.
How fast is it increasing?
Or even not increasing, so the radius is getting smaller and smaller.
It may be slower or faster inside.
So how did he evolve in the end?
It becomes the inside.
This rotation dominates the region.
It's like saying, uh, this disk, the early disk.
A region like that.
How did he go from the original radio info motion to the rotation?
So, uh.
Through this view, we want to know what the model of this info is.
We have a way to write a very good model.
To simulate this part.
And then there's this chemical change.
How to change with this info?
I'll talk a little bit more about this later.
So now I'm going to mention it.
And then in a bigger structure.
Uh, this info is actually for our so-called initial mass function.
Very important.
What is the initial mass function?
It's a bit like saying.
Uh, we're going to build a galaxy now.
Build a star.
The star of different quality, how much is the ratio?
So it's called initial mass function, and it's less likely to be large.
Small quality stars are more that this one.
Uh.
Mass distribution is the initial mass function.
But these initial mass functions are mainly referring to the stars that have already been generated.
So we're in the early days.
In the morning, we really want to know, OK.
If we have all of these, big, big, small, small, different sizes of core,
What kind of traces will these cores become?
The core mass distribution between them and the initial mass distribution and the star mass distribution.
Uh, what's the change?
So we hope to get to know this model in the future.
Can be.
There are some hints that say, OK, if we have a core, it may be a solar quality.
That may be how much of it will become, uh.
How much of the middle star will be 3?
So, do we hope that we can use this model to do this research?
Go to approach the problem.
How do we go from this blue core mass function to this dash line, all kinds of different dash lines?
Uh, initial mass function.
The other thing is that we're in the early days.
Uh, these are a lot of binary systems.
And in the general, uh, already formed, we know, uh.
Most of the stars are binary, that is, uh, double stars or more.
Uh, multiple system.
So we saw that in the early days.
So you want to know how this early star is how to form this kind of binary system.
So what's the impact of this binary system on this info?
Or what kind of criteria do you want to reach?
What kind of threshold will trigger this kind of fragmentation?
Fragment into different two or three or more sources.
So we want to know.
Uh, this initial condition, what is it?
How big is it?
How much is its quality?
So I hope we can get to know how much.
How much mass will be in the middle?
How much will be in the middle?
Okay, so this is another one.
This is a very neat system.
It has three, three, three stars in the middle.
And then you look at the structure.
So we still don't know why it's like this.
Okay, the other part is.
Hey, we're like this, this MWC480, this, this disk.
You see a lot of this kind of structure.
Very neat structure.
But we also see a lot of different, uh, more complex molecules.
Like this CH3N or this is different.
Um.
Uh, more large-molecule organic compounds.
So, uh, we were in the early, uh.
The core stage also saw a lot of these, uh, organic compounds.
So these.
Organic compounds, because organic compounds, ultimately, they will become.
It will enter the interstitial atmosphere, and then it may be.
Trigger, uh.
The main part of the life cycle, because these organic compounds are.
Maybe it's just.
In addition to speaking more broadly, it may be.
Even the first step of life, or even the seed of life.
So we want to know that in the early star evolution process.
How do these chemistries change with the information?
Um, the same, I'm going to do a lot of explanation in the back.
Okay, so our goal is to find out how this information happened.
Then we are in our current method.
We are, uh, want to measure, uh, through the distribution of molecules to measure, uh.
Uh, the performance of, uh.
Kinematic structure is simply through.
Its distribution of, uh.
To analyze that in the end, his, uh, we look at this.
The path of the movement of the gas inside.
What does it look like?
Here, if we look at it from this antenna,
This is a very simplified one on the left.
Um, the look of the core info.
One of the more common models is the middle.
Info's velocity is higher, and the outside info's velocity is lower.
So you can simplify this thing to the right.
This picture is like this.
Uh, the red one is, um.
This, uh, the red one is, um.
We've seen the path.
Because he has this radio motion, so you can.
Um, you can draw a circle like this.
A trace, and then they, um.
The line of sight above the two points is the same.
It means that you will have two, you will have two groups of gas.
And then they, for you, his, uh.
What is it called?
The speed is the same.
But they are in different places.
Uh, this will cause, uh.
He will look like he's on the left.
A profile like this.
Um, yeah, that's about it.
And then, and then the middle of this, this is the dip.
It's just, it's just, it's from the outside.
Um, gas in your, maybe it's a cold gas.
It's a strong radiation that comes in behind the absorption.
Because you're cold in front of you, so you're more likely to be excited.
Then you will be absorbed by this cold material.
So you see a dip.
Um, if you have a higher resolution.
You can see, uh, like this.
It's like this, if this purple, this.
Shady area refers to our telescope beam.
Uh, you can see the cold gas outside.
Uh, gas, but it's still, uh, moving to the center.
It's still falling on to the center.
That kind of, uh, cold gas will give you one.
It's not in the deep, it's not in, uh.
Source velocity of an absorption.
Because he's still far away from you.
And then he's going to make this redshift absorption on the right.
That's basically the profile we want to see.
We want to measure a profile like this.
And then, um.
And then when you, uh, in the back, we have this in the middle.
Every collapsing star will have one in the middle.
Um, continuous source, he might be.
Uh, this is the hottest place in there.
The temperature is very high.
Maybe it's a few thousand degrees.
Then he just gives you a very strong black body radiation.
So if you put it on, this radiation, this, um.
Radiation continuous radiation will also be absorbed by the cold material in front.
It's the radiation that's going to be absorbed.
So in the end, you're going to get something like this.
This kind of continuous, originally your continuous may be flat.
But in the middle of this part, uh, because you have material in.
Away from you in this velocity, so you'll be a part of it.
It's absorbed, so you actually see it.
Uh, observation is observed in your telescope.
It will probably look like this.
So, of course, if we're in, uh, according to this.
The two front and back ends of the continuum.
Go to it.
When you correct the continuum, you'll get this.
It's a strange one.
We'll see, uh, the middle absorption is.
Less than 0.
That's actually not because we assume the continuum in the middle.
Still, uh.
On the surface, it's part of it.
So we basically want to measure a line profile like this.
And then analyze it like this line profile.
To understand that we, uh, uh.
I've seen the inside of this line of sight.
Uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh.
I want to ask a question.
Hey, that.
Why is that profile?
That is, these profiles are not symmetrical to that.
OK, OK, this is the part I just skipped.
Uh.
OK, if we go back to the two circles on the right, this picture.
Um, in the middle, I write this high high temperature.
The place is more central.
And then on both sides, uh.
Large radius is the place where the temperature is lower.
Then you can imagine it as, um, in this.
Uh.
In your foreground, in front of you, your foreground is your red.
The foreground material is basically redshift.
That is, it is falling to the center, so it is redshift to you.
But in this redshift part, you will have.
Um, high temperature is behind.
Low temperature is in front.
It means that you are more like you have a cold thing in front of a hot thing.
So this cold thing will absorb the back.
The hot gas gives you the radiation.
Uh, but in the blue shift part, it is in the back side of the envelope.
You will, you, you don't have this situation.
It is the cold material behind the hot material.
So you don't have this kind of self-absorption.
So this is why the redshift peak.
Will be lower.
Why is that the same shape in Continuum is not symmetrical.
Because continuum is continuum, only in the middle.
If you imagine it is a radiation from the very last look of the Curtain.
I went to the middle, so I got the continent.
So continue only in, only in RTS part is absorbed because of the continent.
In front of it, there is no material of BlueSchi Photo.
Oh, I see.
Ok, thank you.
Yes, so about 20 years ago, people started to measure this kind of profile.
Then this is usually measured with a radio wave network.
That was usually used in the past.
It's like the small ears we usually think of.
Or is it bigger?
Maybe it's a 10-meter network mirror or a 10-meter dish.
Then measure these different molecules.
Then try to measure the profile just now.
Then you can see here.
The first one, in addition to the sensitivity, is not very good.
There are a lot of different structures.
It has a lot of this kind of broad profile.
Or even you don't have a very obvious absorption.
Even the most important thing is that you don't have less than 0.
The so-called no less than 0.
The most important thing is that this absorption is very likely to be.
Uh, you're in front of this source.
Other completely unrelated clouds to you.
Caused absorption.
You can't test it.
Uh, is this absorption real?
It belongs to what you see now.
If you can see this absorption.
Uh.
Drop to 0.
If it becomes negative.
You can find a way to move your telescope's beam.
Then you can say, OK, if I move away from the middle.
This has a continuum source.
See if there's any change in this absorption.
You can be more sure.
When is it confirmed that this absorbent material is associated with?
The audience is the core that you can see.
So that because the relationship between decisions and the ability to ask.
Uh, this question, about 20 years ago, was studied widely, and maybe 5 to 10 years later.
Everyone thinks this okay, it's almost done.
You can't just keep doing it, so just wait.
Um.
Uh, new generation, the voltage waves of thisicated.
Power garage to not be able to have a better optimization result.
So what is Oma?
Oma is, uh.
Uh, Akitama Large Millimeter Sub-millimeter Array.
It is a wireless wave array on the Akitama Desert plateau in Chile.
Then.
He mainly.
There should be 66 antennas, which is probably like the bigger antenna outside.
Each antenna is a 12 meter antenna, and there is a smaller one in the middle.
Another, uh, separate array.
Uh, it's 7 meters.
Then he is.
Uh, he's basically a whole world.
A collaboration, the United States is NRAO.
Oh, that's not NRAO, that's NRC.
NRC is Canada's National Research Council.
Then Japan's NLJ, Europe's ESO.
Taiwan is A, the Chinese Academy of Sciences.
Uh, there's participation.
And then there's Chile.
And then this is open to the world.
Um.
Astronomers can apply to observe.
Then he mainly.
Uh, the biggest bonus is that he can have a very, very good resolution.
His.
He can see very, very small things.
Then basically the array is.
Uh, the telescope is, uh, your resolution is proportional to the wavelength divided by.
Uh, you, you.
The diameter of your telescope.
The wireless wave array is simply a mirror.
Cut.
Cut into a lot of little ones.
Uh, a different telescope.
Then, so you can pull the two telescope very far as a telescope to use.
So, like this, the biggest of this.
Uh, baseline is called baseline.
Simply put, his diameter can be up to 15, 15 kilometers.
Yes, it can be analyzed to a very small area.
Ok, then, at the beginning of this, we started with two more similar profiles that we just drew at the beginning.
Like the left side, this is a.
This is a, uh, organic molecule, uh, Chinese, what is this English Miso?
Uh.
This is the appearance, you can see, if we, uh.
After taking the continuum off, you can see this absorption is enough, and then you can see his, uh, absorption.
Redshift.
And then in the same way, in this other source, we also see the same thing.
Uh, but in these two cases.
These are still relatively small, because the first one, like the left one, is an organic molecule, so his.
He may, uh, in those early stars, uh.
The abundance is not so high.
Uh, not much, so the image is relatively weak.
Then, like the source on the right, it is a relatively, uh, darker source, so his continuum is not so high, so his absorption is relatively small.
Then, in my main research, I mainly want to use, uh, the target, the other, which is the B, H, R, 71.
Then go to understand, see if we can measure a better, uh.
Uh, the signature of the infor, which is the double peak, and then analyze it.
Then he is also a very isolated, uh, early, uh.
Uh, and then if you look at it in the optical band, it's a black thing, basically all of it.
Uh, all kinds of dust, uh, and gas.
Then, in the infor, you can see that he has a beautiful outflow.
In the radio, you can also see a beautiful outflow.
He actually has two sources in the middle.
Then, here, we just focus on the RS1, which is the main source.
Ok, then we are in Alma cycle 4, so we propose, and then we get our data.
It looks like the right side, which is very much like the way it was drawn before.
Especially this HCL plus, this curve is basically the same as the front.
Then you can see here, although, um.
This absorption is very wide, but you can probably see that he is actually in, uh.
Redshift velocity still has a lot of absorption, which proves that he is actually part of it.
It comes from, um, the middle, uh, those who are really falling in the gas.
To produce absorption.
That, uh.
Ok, then we need to analyze this curve.
We actually need to use one.
We can't just read it out of this.
Absorption is in, maybe it's in 0.5 kilometers per second, and then you'll know.
Uh, I, you might know there's something in 0.5 kilometers per second falling in.
But you don't know if he's in, you've seen this line of sight in which place.
That, uh, because you have absorption and emission mixed together.
So we have to, um, use a very common technique in astronomy.
The technique is ready to transfer the calculation to find a way.
Um, to model the curve we see.
That way to transfer, simply put, uh, if I'm here now, every one of these, this, this.
The shape is a, a, a, a gas.
All right, you may have radiation on the left.
Come in, and the radiation will be in the gas, it may be absorbed by the research, your research will become weak.
Or after you have been absorbed, or you, you, this, this gas is actually very hot.
So he has some, uh, he has some black radiation, or he has some of his own radiation.
So you, he may have, there will be a mission.
So, in these energy transitions, he may be part of it.
It becomes the temperature of this gas, or, uh, inside the excite.
The level population of different molecules.
Your mother from the beginning to the end, and then you can know from the inside.
Uh.
Radiation to the end, uh, we observed what it should look like.
And then, uh, through, uh.
The process of more than once, and then to get a better model to explain what we saw in front of us.
So, in fact, what we do is very, um.
It's tedious, but it's also, um.
Um.
It's actually okay, it's actually not that tedious, but it's a lot of iteration, a lot of iterative process.
Basically, after we have a model, we can get it, we can say, okay, our, our.
What does the density of the envelope look like?
Um.
Info this, uh, velocity should look like.
We can throw it into, uh, different radio transfer models to do.
Uh, this is where we separate gas and dust.
Because basically.
Um.
First of all, we use, uh, dust.
Uh, it's the continuation of the part of the register.
Go to, uh.
To constrain this whole envelope structure.
For example, this envelope.
Uh, his, uh.
What is the density?
So, uh, what is the change in the radius?
How much does he stand behind this?
His.
Uh, what is the angle?
How much is it?
Then, when we determine this envelope structure.
Let's put it in again.
And then we'll figure out that we're okay.
If we follow this structure, we'll get the spectrum.
What should it look like?
Okay, so, uh, this is what we did before, uh, the model.
And then here, uh.
See this is, uh.
That is.
The spectrum of BHS 1.
That's behind this.
The gray line is the spectrum.
And then this is probably.
Uh, 2 microns, 3 microns, up to.
Up to 1 millimeter range.
And then.
Uh.
The blue circle is our model.
And then the red square is the observation.
And then you see most of us.
We just fit through this.
To fit, we put the model fit to the observation.
And then we'll get a.
Uh, a better model to describe this envelope.
For example, I drew it like this here.
But actually, how do we construct this?
How much is his output angle?
What is the density distribution of the envelope?
Okay, so you don't have to say.
It's more like it's coming out of the outflow.
And then the long way is coming out of the envelope.
Okay, and then.
Uh, I said earlier that we're going to take this envelope structure.
Plus, uh, we can think of a way to model this.
Uh, but in fact, one of the very, very important.
Uh, the factor is chemistry.
So the chemistry is not.
Uh, well, so the chemistry is not just thinking, okay.
What are you going to have?
And it's this kind of molecule.
Is it possible to exist in that kind of condition?
In the atmosphere, you can see it, especially in.
Um, these dense core, the density in the middle is very high.
And then the temperature is quite low.
So it's possible to be frozen on top of these dust.
Then if it freezes, you, you, you.
You can't do it in him.
You expect the atmosphere to give you a curve.
And see that this is.
So there's a different chemical abundance profile.
You might be out there, you might have.
Uh, the radiation from other places might take you.
By H, this is an example of H.
You might let him.
It's a separation of two different things, or it's.
In there, he might be frozen on top of the dust.
Or in this one, he's going to be with some, uh.
Active molecules interact with each other, and then.
Produce fat particles, and then he disappears.
So you can't measure it.
So in the middle, we're going to.
Mainly, like I've been in.
Uh, it's been a long time.
It takes a while to say what we're going to do.
A relatively good abundance profile.
To explain our data.
So, uh.
Basically, we need to understand this kind of info profile.
Uh, we're going to take our dust model.
You can get density, temperature, and velocity.
And then we add our.
Chemical abundance.
The, uh.
We're going to find a way.
Uh, get a spectrum.
If you don't feel good, we'll go back.
Modify and change, so this is very.
Uh, a long one.
Uh, the process.
Uh, this is us.
Uh, hey.
Um, uh, yeah, that's good.
The front is almost the same.
That's my question.
Um, like this, like this, like this.
It's a relatively small system.
Uh, that kind of info.
Or the final outflow.
The distribution of gravity.
It's all about, uh, normal.
That matter is good.
If there is a dark matter, he has a way.
It doesn't really matter.
And.
I'm not sure if it's early.
Early universe will be affected.
But at least in the modern universe.
Uh, the general assumption should be dark matter.
Mainly in the outer galaxy.
It's in the black building.
So I rarely.
I heard that.
Uh, dark matter will affect.
It's the evolution of these.
At least in the.
In the region.
So I don't think there's much.
Big impression.
Uh, because I.
My idea is like this.
If today, in some of those.
Dark matter can be strong with them.
Interacting, then there will be some small.
Small structure, for example.
Is a relatively clumpy phenomenon.
Uh, maybe.
Can be constrained, but I don't think so.
I can't see it.
Yeah, I guess I can't see it.
If you have a big.
It should be very, very small.
That's probably like a micro lens.
You're looking at things.
So.
Uh, so I'm going to be like this.
A system should be able to see it.
The current observation.
The relationship should be.
Very far away.
Maybe there will be, but it's hard.
Yeah.
Okay, thank you.
So, uh.
Like this, like me.
This model is our latest.
This is the latest model we got.
Actually, it was about two days ago.
Uh, uh, on the right.
Uh, blue is our data.
Then orange is our current model.
Then you see our model.
Roughly capture is data.
The feeling.
But you can see, for example, in Russian.
We still miss a lot of emissions.
So, uh.
This is this is actually.
Now.
In the future, we should continue to do more.
Uh, different tuning, and then even.
To understand that there is no way to make up.
Uh, to make up for this part.
Missing mission.
Uh, to understand that it is possible to say.
Um.
Of course, our current model is very, very.
Symmetry is basically a.
Symmetry model.
Um.
The first one is to understand that, okay.
Under this very strong assumption.
Is there any way to make this model better?
What if it doesn't work?
How do we break this?
This assumption.
And it won't cause too much.
The freedom.
Okay, you can say whatever you want.
Um.
So, uh, this is probably the future.
The main thing to do in the next month or two.
That's on the left.
This picture is.
Basically, it's like.
Uh, if you look at.
The mission map.
Then if you take the middle continent.
It's like this.
The dark place in the middle is the continent.
After being removed, it causes a very strong absorption.
Just like the right side, you see this very strong absorption.
So when you get close, you will become negative.
And then up and down like this.
This bright spot is because.
Uh, you have all flow, so all flow is up.
Uh, up and down, this, this, this direction.
So, uh.
Uh.
Uh, the density is relatively low, so it is easier to be heated.
So it's brighter.
Ok, then.
Why do you say this?
Info will affect this chemistry?
That is to say.
Uh, simply put, if there is a group, a group of gas.
Now he, he is from.
Um, this envelope.
The outer circumference keeps traveling.
You are affected by the infogravity.
You can't travel to the middle.
And then falling to this star or disk.
It will pass through the middle.
Different temperatures.
The middle may be getting hotter and hotter.
Basically, it's getting hotter and hotter.
Because there is a pro star in the middle.
Pro star is emitting a very strong emission.
That, but this info.
This chemistry is determined by.
Say, ok, I have this, this group of gas.
This group of gas will be at different temperatures.
How long will it take?
If he is very slow.
Then he may spend a long time in every place.
That or even.
He may spend more time in the lower temperature.
Or at a higher temperature.
That will affect.
Uh, at different temperatures, it will affect.
Um.
It should be said that at different temperatures.
The chemical reaction you can produce is different.
That, and every chemical reaction.
The time scale is also different.
If you are at low temperature, although you have a lot.
Low temperature chemical reactions can be produced.
But if you just spend it at low temperature.
Very short time, then those reactions.
Will not be for, um.
The chemical state of these molecules.
Uh.
The state has caused any change.
What about the other way?
To see is to say.
Um, we are actually using these molecules.
The.
The radiation to go.
To trace this.
The envelope inside the dynamic.
If we don't understand which side of the road.
These molecules are sometimes our interpretation.
It will become incorrect.
That.
Another point is what I said before.
Uh, the evolution of the dynamic code.
Will affect you.
What is the chemical reaction you can produce?
So these two are a bit like interaction.
It's like being tied together.
It's hard for you to separate one from each other.
That's to say here.
At different, for example, at low temperature.
You may have a lot of free.
You have a lot of deterioration.
H will become very low.
Then, more.
So-called medium tension.
You will have a lot on the surface of this dust.
Different chemical reactions.
That will cause the chemistry.
The people who do the chemical model will tell you.
That this may produce different species.
Different species.
Now, at high temperature.
When it comes to Kelvin.
Uh, you used to be.
The ice is frozen on the dust.
These molecules may all come out because the temperature has risen.
So it will affect us.
What you see is different.
Or at different temperatures.
There will be different changes.
Well, basically, uh.
There will be two in the early stars.
There are currently two different types of observations.
Uh, source, one is called.
Uh, the other is.
One carbon molecule source.
That's basically it.
His original meaning is.
It represents his small hot core.
What is the hot core?
It is a relatively large-capacity source.
He may be.
100, 1000, even a few thousand.
Uh, the sun.
A source.
Uh, we've been observing for a long time.
Oh, in these sources.
You'll see a lot of mess.
Different organic molecules.
So this kind of.
The source is classified.
It's classified as a hot core.
Because he doesn't have to be hot enough.
These molecules will become gas.
Let you be observed.
So the hot core is.
We observe similar chemical states.
A lot of organic molecules.
It's a relatively low quality.
Little quality.
Uh, 0.5 to.
Uh, 10.
Uh, range.
That's another one.
One carbon molecule source is.
Uh, in the same process.
We found.
Uh, there's another kind of source.
Um, he doesn't have a lot of this.
He still has a lot of organic molecules.
It doesn't look like this.
Uh, so-called.
Uh, long convention means that he has a lot of carbon.
One by one.
So you might see something like C2H.
C4H or something.
C7H.
These carbons are both.
Maybe it's a double or three.
Three pieces together.
He can have a lot of carbon stuck together.
And then you don't have any other hydrogen atoms.
Or other different atoms.
That, um, in.
Hot core, you know, these saturated molecules.
It means that these points.
The square or triangle is opened to pick up different functional groups.
Then produce different organic molecules.
That's in chemistry.
Um.
Their, uh, their formation path is different.
So now it's.
Uh, everyone.
From the model, from the control.
Try to characterize it.
Is the first one really true?
Or is it just that we see two different extremes?
In fact, there are a lot of overlaps in the middle.
Or say.
Hey.
In terms of models, how can we produce a lot of long carbon molecules?
How can we produce a lot of, uh, these saturated complex molecules?
That's the same source.
In the same observation.
We measure a lot of, uh.
Uh, organic molecules.
Like the middle one.
This is very high.
This is outstanding.
This is more than this.
This is the four panels in front of it.
I'll show you.
Uh, four panels.
This is the four main lines.
But we also found that in.
The other places of this spectrum.
We see a lot of weaker emissions.
And then we identify them.
In fact, uh.
Most of them are from organic molecules.
And then we identified it.
There should be 14 different organic molecules.
On the right side.
Some of them are quite complicated.
There's alcohol, alcohol.
Or some different, uh.
Calcium, different.
Uh, his isotope.
And then we found that in different sources.
Inside?
Like here, we have three different sources.
That.
Basically, they are, uh, these three sources.
Their, um,
Luminosity difference will be more than 10 times.
So the so-called luminosity is basically.
Uh, depending on the control.
How much of the radiation can be released in the middle?
How bright is the star in the middle?
How bright is the process in the middle?
That's the difference in brightness.
So in such a big different source.
Inside?
We found that his organic molecules.
For methanol.
Uh, the abundance is about the same.
That is to say, you can see these three symbols.
Basically, they are all quite close.
That, uh, that means.
Um.
The middle of this.
How much is the luminosity?
How strong is the radiation in the middle?
It doesn't affect the production of these complex molecules.
Well, since it's not.
The middle, uh, this radiation.
If you say carbon, that means it's in front.
These, uh.
In the early days, these complex molecules.
It's already formed.
He might be in, uh.
When it freezes on the ice.
Through some of the relatively low temperature.
Some reactions are formed.
When he travels to the middle, it's relatively high temperature.
He was released.
To the gas station, and then you see it.
So he didn't have too much.
Processing produces different.
So this is a very small sample.
But I.
It's just a hint.
This is actually with, uh.
The prediction of the chemical model is quite close.
So, in addition, we found that we can do this.
Uh, complex molecules can also give us some.
Uh, can imagine the signature.
Uh.
Let's look at the cartoon on the right.
Simply put, if you have a structure like this.
The middle of this gray ring.
The middle of this gray ring represents a disk.
And then you might have an info outside.
Now we have, like, we're going down from the top.
This, this disk.
If you look at it from the left.
If it's yellow, this disease.
You can see, uh.
On one side, there's a red shift emission.
It's far from you.
It's a red emission.
But at the same time, you can see it in the back.
Uh, blue shift, the info.
So you become one of the same.
There's the same offset inside.
You can see at the same time.
There's a blue shift and a red shift emission.
It's not the same as if you're just a disk.
If you're just a disk.
Your left.
It's all going to be, for example, it's all going to be a red shift emission.
It's all going to be a blue shift emission on the right.
In this case.
You'll see two different kinds.
At the same time, you'll see a blue shift and a red shift emission.
So this is our left.
We're in, uh.
What you see in the observation.
Offset you can see.
If it's 0.1, we can see it at the same time.
You can see the blue shift and the red shift emission.
So if it's.
It's just a desk.
You'll see two triangles.
It's in the upper right corner and the lower left corner.
So that's what we're talking about.
Um, and then at the same time, this.
If you go in and analyze it.
A morphology like this.
Or what kind of structure is it?
We found that he was in the middle.
It's 50 to 100.
It's a disk.
Uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh.
Uh, uh, uh, uh, uh.
This is the mission.
I found that we can use it at the same time.
Hcl plus.
That's the mission to trace.
Um, the info of the envelope skill.
Um, the info, uh, the same complex.
A lot of molecules can give us some.
Uh, more central information.
So the goal for the future is to figure out a way.
If we can put this big tree, we should say.
Envelope skill and desk have two different dynamics.
Let's see if we can get a better one.
Uh, info model.
At the same time, we see a lot of different structures.
This is the other thing we can do.
We see a lot of different outflow structures.
It's just a school picture.
Um.
So, um, it means that we're actually this observation.
There's only an hour of observation time.
But he probably can bring it to us.
It may be more than three projects.
Um, so, um, so, um, so, um, so, um, so, um.
Um, so, um, so, um, so, um.
Um.
Ok.
We're going to ask again.
Um, you can go back to the first two.
In the front page.
Uh, just, uh.
Uh, uh, next page, next page.
There's one.
That's right, this page.
Just.
It's just that I just missed it.
Why is there only a complex?
You can do this thing.
Then you before.
It's the few lines that are very bright at the beginning.
Why can't I see this?
Um.
Basically,
the front.
Those in the front, for example,
it may have some.
It may have some destruction in the middle.
But even if those models don't have destruction,
it's relatively simple.
It may be.
It may be in the middle.
It's very high, but it's because of its.
Um.
It may be at the same time,
from 10 to 2000,
all of them.
So in terms of analysis,
it causes a lot of complexity.
The advantage of the complex model is that
the first one, most of the time,
it's in the state of defrosting.
It may have to be more than 100 Kelvin.
The temperature, it will go to the gas phase,
and you can see it.
That's a relatively simple model.
It may be 20 K, 40 K,
you can see it.
So, um, this kind of temperature
constraint, let the complex molecule
basically gather in a very
compact center,
or this scale place.
So basically,
its existence itself is self-selected,
so that you can probe
a very well-defined or
very compact region.
So, of course, other simpler
molecules can also be traced in the middle.
You can find other molecules in the middle,
but it's relatively difficult to analyze.
Oh, okay.
Got it. Thank you.
Okay, so
we basically, so maybe we have
a case now, that is, this source, we can
derive an info model,
and then we can connect from this core
and then draw a line to trace
its evolution from core to
a star case.
But in the future,
we should
pursue more samples,
so this observation is actually
very simple.
15 minutes on source,
the rest is actually calibration.
you can measure so many things.
So it should be very,
if we have a good argument,
it is actually
relatively easy to push
more samples,
maybe 10 or even 50 sources,
you can probably know, okay,
the evolution of different mass sources
So this is more of a future
direction.
Then I will put my summary here,
and then if you have any other
questions, you are welcome.
Thank you.
Then
please turn on the microphone.
We are now applauding,
thank you for
giving us a speech.
Thank you.
I don't know if you have any questions.
If you have any questions,
remember to turn on the microphone.
I will ask another question.
Okay.
Just stop here.
The picture in the upper right corner,
you just said you are
using your
radiative transfer model
to fit your
observation data.
So
you
will use, for example,
like MCMC,
you may run one first,
and then compare the observation,
and then come back to adjust the parameters,
and then run again?
Or is it
theoretically possible?
Theoretically it is possible, but
the biggest
limitation is that we
are running this 3D radiative transfer,
because this is a very high density
place, so
running a model of realization
takes a very long time.
A realization may take 2 hours, 3 hours.
So if you are MCMC,
you may have to map,
so you have to probe this parameter space.
If you need 1000 models,
it will take 3000 hours
per source.
So we later thought
it was not very feasible.
But
some
other studies do simpler
sources, they use MCMC
to characterize different
parameters. But I think that's
actually very important.
Maybe we can
test, for example,
other things are all fixed,
we will
change the chemical abundance profile.
Because that's actually
a pretty
hand-tuning parameter.
We currently have some ideas
to see if we can
optimize the radiative transfer
calculation. For example,
we can fix the gradient,
some more technical considerations
can be relaxed.
So I think
in the future, maybe I will
do some more
small experiments. But
I think this part
has its own
limitations. So
if you can do MCMC
optimization,
it should be
in a more
special situation.
So
your current approach is
to run one first
and see if it's not
right. Then you probably
know what
parameter to choose.
Yes, it's the brain
to guide the search.
For example,
we have a lot of different tools
to do this. For example,
we have some tools
that can tell us,
in this beam,
as a function of radius,
what our velocity looks like.
If I want to say that I think
the emission at a certain velocity is too low,
I'll see if I can adjust it,
or see
what the reason is.
It takes a lot of time to
model the inspection,
and then think about
how to adjust it.
Got it.
It feels like
a project
that can be used for machine learning.
Yes, I hope so.
Who can help me do this?
Yuting can help you.
She's really good at it now.
Okay.
In January,
I'll need your help.
Before today's speech,
before everyone
came in,
we talked about
the content of today's speech,
which is still being written and submitted.
If you want to discuss,
you can contact our speakers directly.
You can
put your email in the chat.
Whether you want to be contacted
or you want to contact someone,
you can exchange
contact information here.
Or you can Google it.
You can Google it directly.
The recording of our speech will be delayed
until February or March next year
before it is uploaded.
The reason is that it is now
being written.
Do you have any questions?
If you don't have any questions now,
I'll promote it.
I'm going to put
the two main websites
in the chat.
One is our Facebook,
the other is our website.
If you go in,
you can see
the purpose of our project.
We hope that through
young people
working in the research circle,
we can cooperate with each other
and exchange research information quickly,
get to know each other,
and share information.
If you support such a project,
we hope you can consider
joining the member.
I also put the information
for joining the member in the chat.
More importantly,
we are now open to sign up
for the 2019 speech.
If you are in the past year
or expected to be in the next year,
there will be interesting research discoveries
or information or ideas
to share with you.
I also put the link
in the chat.
There are several websites here,
you can go in and play.
I'll ask one last time,
do you have any questions?
By the way,
Yaolun's email is in the chat,
so you can ask him directly.
Thank you.
If there are no questions,
let's turn on the microphone
and thank Yaolun again.