Hello, everyone.
I am honored to be able to introduce Dr. Sun today.
Dr. Sun completed her bachelor's degree from 1999 to 2013
in Plant Pathology and Microbiology at Taiwan University.
After completing her bachelor's degree from 2003 to 2005,
she completed her master's degree in Plant Pathology and Microbiology at the same university in Taiwan.
She then completed her Ph.D. degree from 2005 to 2010 at Purdue University.
Her major is Chemical Biology.
After completing her Ph.D. degree, she went to MIT to do her postdoc.
After four years, she went to UCSF to do her second postdoc and assistant researcher.
This year, she started her new job as a Senior Scientific Researcher at Genentech.
Today, Dr. Sun is going to talk about
Use Single-Cell RNA-Seq to Tackle Complex Biology.
Now, let's welcome Dr. Sun to give her presentation.
Hello, everyone. I am Dr. Sun.
Sorry, my voice is a bit hoarse due to my cold.
Today, I am going to talk in a simple and easy-to-understand way.
Just in case, some of you may not have a background in biology.
I hope you can at least learn about Single-Cell RNA-Seq.
Here is my personal email and LinkedIn account.
Although my LinkedIn account is not up to date,
please feel free to connect with me.
I will be speaking in Chinese today,
but I am not sure what the term is in Chinese.
If you have any questions, please feel free to contact me.
I don't want to make it too complicated.
I will be focusing on technology.
I am currently working at a company,
so I can't really talk about research projects here.
I will try my best to talk about the applications of this technology,
and the principles behind it.
I hope this will be helpful to those who are interested.
Before we get into the technology,
I will briefly review the biology of NTU.
As you may already know, our body is made up of cells.
Many cells form organs,
and eventually form organs in our body,
becoming a functional human body.
An interesting fact is that our body is composed of over 20 different types of cells.
You can see that their forms and functions are very different.
For example, there are nerve cells, blood cells, muscle cells,
and even different types of cells in different organs.
Their functions and forms are very different.
Let's take a deeper look.
As you can see, our body is made up of cells.
Each cell has a nucleus,
which is a red dot.
In English, it's called a nucleus.
In Chinese, it's called a cell nucleus.
In this cell nucleus, there is a chromosome.
This chromosome is made up of our genes.
I think everyone has a concept of genes.
Genes are our genetic material.
Genes are our genetic material,
and they can determine our body functions.
Generally speaking, genes are basically DNA fragments.
They can be converted into useful molecules,
which can perform the functions required by our body.
We usually talk about gene decoding or gene encryption.
The main reason is that DNA is composed of a series of ATCG,
which is a double helix structure made up of four different genes.
Generally speaking, if we talk about gene decoding,
the sequence you get may be composed of four ATCG
in different ways.
This is our so-called gene code.
In molecular biology, there is a so-called central dogma.
It's the principle that we have this genetic material.
Its main structure is DNA,
which is transcribed into RNA.
RNA is further transcribed into protein.
Protein can perform various biological functions.
As time goes by,
the central dogma is gradually extended to more different forms.
We can even find more different directions from the virus or other systems.
Today's technology involves a discovery.
In the past, we thought that DNA was transcribed into RNA.
Later, scientists found another molecule
that allows RNA to reverse transcribe back to the DNA.
Because of the help of this molecule,
many related extension technologies can be built on this basis.
Today, we are going to talk about RNAseq.
In other words, transcriptome analysis,
or gene expression profiling,
we can use genes to understand human physiology.
This picture shows a major timeline and milestone in molecular biology and sequencing technology.
In 1953, the first discovery of DNA double-stranded structure was made.
In 1977, Sanger's DNA sequencing was developed.
Later, PCR technology was also developed.
PCR technology allows us to rapidly increase our DNA in the lab.
Many related technologies can be built on this basis.
In 1990, the Human Genome Project was launched.
After 13 years, the Human Genome Project was established.
At this stage, the sequencing cost was still very high.
It was difficult to operate the sequencing project in the lab.
In 2005, the Next Generation Sequencing was introduced.
Next Generation Sequencing is a next-generation sequencing technology.
This technology has greatly reduced the cost of sequencing.
More and more Genome Projects related to sequencing can be carried out more smoothly in labs.
Up to now, Next Generation Sequencing technology is still widely used.
In recent years, the Third Generation Sequencing technology has been introduced.
When was Single Cell RNAse developed?
Single Cell RNAse was first reported in 2009.
Single Cell RNAse is a technology that is becoming more and more mature.
Many advanced protocols, technologies, and companies continue to develop rapidly in this field.
Why do we need to do Single Cell RNAse?
Before Single Cell RNAse, we can look at gene profiling.
For example, we need to know the difference between a normal tumor and a cancer tumor.
From this heat map, it is still difficult to determine whether a cell is infected or not by these genes.
The single cell measures the distribution of expression levels for each gene across a population of cells.
Thank you for watching!