Okay, let's get started.
Oh, I hear the recording has started.
Okay, so the topic I'm going to talk about today is
Phylogenetic Components with Meta-Optics.
Because my main research background is
the interaction between light and matter,
and then, through this interaction,
we can further manipulate light's behavior.
So the main application we want to do is
how to reduce the size of the current
phylogenetic components on the market.
For example, transparency or bias.
So, what is meta?
I'll talk about it later.
The word meta-optics is actually
the Greek word for meta.
I'll talk about it later.
Before we get into the topic,
I want to share a picture.
I don't know if you've seen this picture.
This is from the ancient Roman era.
The picture on the left is from the ancient Roman era.
This is a wine cup.
What's amazing about this is
you can see that the colors are different.
But they are actually the same cup.
The color is different because
they found that when they put the light source outside,
the color of the cup is green.
But if they put the light source inside the cup,
the cup will turn red.
That is to say, the material on the cup is very special.
If you look at the cup from the perspective of reflection,
it is green.
But if you put the light source inside,
the color you see is transparent.
So after you put the light source inside the cup,
the color you see is red.
At this time, people think this is amazing.
They also use this kind of material
to make church colored glass.
We all know that
churches in Europe
have very beautiful colored glass.
Why are there so many different colors?
The reason is the same as the cup.
The principle of its operation is very similar.
Why does this phenomenon occur?
Later, people found that
there is a thing called localized surface plasma.
What does this mean?
Why doesn't it move?
They found that
if we have a colored light source,
it will interact with a metal nanoparticle.
After interacting with it,
it will accumulate some free electrons
on the surface of the nanoparticle
under the appropriate conditions.
These free electrons
will allow it to produce a similar dipole inside,
an H-ray dipole or a magnetic dipole.
Let it further produce,
let it radiate electrons from other dipoles.
Then we will see different colors.
When will this phenomenon occur?
It mainly occurs
when our nanoparticles
are smaller than the dipole of the colored light.
This thing will only occur.
So the high-angle cup,
the colored high-angle cup,
later they did a further study
and found that the high-angle cup
actually contained a lot of gold particles of different size.
This is gold particle.
The size of these metal particles
compared with the dipole of the visible light,
the visible light dipole is about 400 to 700 nanometers.
Compared with it, it is smaller than the size of the dipole.
So they thought that
the reason for the different color
may come from this
local surface plasmon resonance.
The result of localized surface plasmon resonance.
After this resonance,
what special phenomenon will we have?
It actually has a lot of advantages that we can control,
that is, we can have.
For example, they found that
this resonance has a bias with the dipole of the colored light.
The bias is the direction in which the electron waves resonate.
You can see that this picture may be more obvious.
For example, the color here is very colorful,
very beautiful,
there are five or six colors.
Here you can't see any color at all.
These two pictures are actually the same sample
color.
Their only difference is that
they changed the direction of the dipole of the colored light.
This red and white arrow is the direction of its dipole resonance.
When the direction of the dipole of the colored light
is along the y-axis,
they will see that the chip above
will produce different colors.
In fact, you can imagine that
the chip uses some micro-imaging technology
to make some metal disks
that are smaller than visible wavelengths.
Like this disk.
Then they change its diameter or cycle.
We can see different colors
in the reflected light part.
But when they turn a bias,
the colors are all gone.
So you can use it to do something.
For example, this thing can be used to make
color filters that have a bias control feature.
Another special thing is that
we used to know that
for example,
why are we so interested in this thing now?
For example, we know that gold is often used to make decorations.
For example, rings and necklaces.
But gold,
as long as we use gold to make a decoration,
whether I pinch it into a square,
a circle,
or a ring,
its color is yellow.
But like I just said,
if we put this gold,
all the particles here are gold,
but they are at a very small scale.
If its scale is smaller than the wavelength,
we can find that
as its size changes,
the colors we see are different.
This is very different from the optical phenomenon
that we see on the object.
The main reason for this is because
of the localized surface plasma.
The next feature is that
if the two metals are very close together,
there is a very small nano gap
between the two metal particles,
there will be a very strong near-field coupling.
The two of them will interweave each other.
This interweaving will make them
a bit like the simple electronics we learned before.
It's like the feeling of end-to-end power generation.
Because its scale is very small,
the more end-to-end power it can accumulate,
the stronger the near-field power generation it produces.
If it is very close,
the interweaving between the two
will cause it to have a stronger field enhancement.
Finally, this resonance
has a lot to do with the surrounding environment.
It is very sensitive to the environment.
That is to say,
if the surrounding environment's resolution changes,
its resonance wavelength,
which is the color we saw in the original factory, will change.
For example, this stick now,
if it is in the air,
I see blue.
But if I put it in the water
and look at it again,
it may turn red.
This feature
is also used by some people
to say that we can do some sound sensing.
It is based on the change in color
to judge what is the object
in the surrounding environment.
OK.
After introducing the Localized Surface Plasma,
I will tell you
what is Metamaterial.
As I said,
the word Meta
comes from Greek.
It means the same in English.
Metamaterial is a kind of material.
It has some features.
These features are not found in natural materials.
We call it Metamaterial.
Simply put,
we can use the shape of it
or the distance between the particles
to change its optical properties.
These are called Metamaterial.
Why do we have these features?
It should be said that
we need to produce Metamaterial properties.
What is the strict condition?
As I said,
we generally know that natural materials
are composed of atoms.
For example, CO2, H2O.
Because we know that
the distance between them is very small.
If I take the surface plasma as 500 nm,
which is about the surface plasma of green light,
as an example,
these two
have a very, very big difference in their magnitude.
So its optical properties
are mainly determined by this molecule or atom.
For example, gold is AU.
No matter how I rub it,
it is yellow.
Metamaterial is what I just said.
If we now put the distance
or size between the particles
to be reduced to the original size,
which is the level of the magnetic field,
which is about Lambda over 4 to Lambda over 10,
at this magnitude,
we can use man-made methods
to change the optical properties of the material itself.
Then we can further manipulate
some of the behavior of light or electromagnetic waves.
This can be produced by the resonance
at the magnitude of the magnetic field.
By using this method to manipulate light,
we call it metamaterial.
It is mainly triangular.
Although my structure is very small,
its thickness in the z-direction can be very thick.
My very thick is only compared with the surface plasma of green light.
For example, it can be one or two microns.
Let me ask you a question.
10 to 100 microns?
No, 1 to 10 microns is fine.
It can be several microns.
So 10 nanometers to 100 micrometers is fine.
The magnitude I'm talking about here is a bit broad.
Mainly because the example I gave earlier is visible light.
But the advantage of this thing is that
my work plasma may not necessarily be visible light.
I can even be a microwave wave.
So 10 micrometers is Terahertz?
100 microns.
If it is 100 microns,
it should be 3 Terahertz.
If I'm not mistaken.
It's about the range of Terahertz.
It's far away.
So its work plasma can be very broad.
Here is a very special example.
The metamaterial I just mentioned.
When I first saw this phenomenon,
there was no such word as metamaterial.
It's called left-hand material.
Why is it called left-hand material?
Because they found that
the structure of man-made
can control the behavior of light.
We know that the characteristic of light transmission
mainly comes from the refractive index of the ring.
So they thought,
is it because of the refractive index?
Metamaterial is used to manipulate
the refractive index of the ring.
That's why it affects the behavior of light.
Here is a schematic diagram.
We used to study chemistry in high school.
If a cup is an empty cup,
the air refractive index is 1.
If I put a chopstick here, it will be straight.
If I put a refractive index of 1.3 in it,
it's probably water.
We know that because of the refractive index,
it looks like the chopstick is broken.
But if we put a negative refractive index in it,
the chopstick we see at this time will look like this.
This is actually just an experiment.
This is not the result of the experiment.
Another interesting thing is that
if we have this negative refractive index,
we usually know that the beam of light will be full.
In other words, the beam of light is orange here.
If it is a beam of light,
it is along N1sinθ1 and N2sinθ2.
So it keeps refracting.
But if the material in the middle
is a negative refractive material,
the beam of light and the beam of refractive light
will be located on both sides of the beam.
This makes them very interested.
That is to say,
is it true that because of these characteristics,
we can create some real
boundaries that naturally cannot exist,
and then achieve some
light and snow characteristics that we can't imagine at all?
This kind of negative refractive index,
I am trying to prove it here.
But in fact, there is already an experiment to prove
that this thing is really feasible.
But I didn't put their experiment results here.
It is to prove that by
properly designing the size of this material,
or the elements of the material itself,
they can achieve the negative refractive index phenomenon.
I think I can skip here.
Next, I will talk about
the Metamaterial I just mentioned.
I just said it can be very thick,
it can be three-dimensional.
But in fact, our main purpose is to
control the light.
Can we further reduce the element?
They want to say,
if I make Metamaterial only one layer,
because I just said that Metamaterial can be many layers,
it means that it can be very thick.
If I only have one layer,
can I achieve the same effect?
This one-layer Metamaterial,
they call it Metasurface.
A surface that is the same as a general surface.
Yes, so it's called Metasurface.
Here is an example.
For example, I now have a metal stick.
After I inject a electromagnetic wave into it,
because this magnitude is much smaller
than the injected light wave field,
so I can directly use the concept of
injecting electromagnetic waves to
see the result of this resonance.
So if my injected light wave field
vibrates along this direction,
I can theoretically accumulate positive and negative electrons
at both ends of the stick.
This accumulated positive and negative electron
can make us equivalent to an electrode.
After this electrode vibrates,
another electromagnetic wave will be radiated.
If we take a closer look at this structure
of penetrating light waves and phase light waves,
under a fixed wavelength,
it is obvious that
if the length of the stick changes,
just like I just said,
because this material,
this Metasurface or Metamaterial,
has a lot to do with its
resonance characteristics and size.
So when I make the length longer
or shorter,
we can see that its resonance wave
will gradually be flattened.
At this time,
if I look at a fixed wavelength,
its magnitude or phase
can be changed.
A point that everyone is very concerned about
is the phase.
Is this a simulation?
Yes, this is a simulation.
Both of these are simulations.
If we can manipulate the phase,
we can further manipulate
the wavelength of the electromagnetic wave,
which is the characteristics of its transmission.
For example, if I now have a
sample substrate,
and I record a flat wave,
if I put some of the
Metasurface nanostructure on the surface,
because its size is different,
the phase deviation they feel
will be different.
The different phase deviations
will make the phase delay
of the original wave
different,
which means that after the original interference,
they can reconstruct
another wave front.
And this wave front
is completely different from the Metasurface.
Although this magnitude is less than
the Metasurface wavelength,
we can control the electromagnetic wave
characteristics
with the Metasurface nanostructure.
Here are some examples of applications.
This is probably
to say that
we can not only manipulate the electromagnetic wave
government and phase,
in fact, the wavelength and deviation
can be manipulated
by Metasurface.
For example, they can
do some optical image
or do some deviation conversion,
which I will introduce later.
Here is a very simple image
that is, why this thing
can be so interesting
and help us to design some
flat optical components.
I use the simplest one before
is our deflection law
to explain to you.
For example, if we used
Hagen's principle to explain
the deflection of this thing,
that is, if I have two materials
in the space now,
the deflection rate is N1 and N2 respectively.
After the deflection wave comes in,
every point on this interface
is reflected by the deflection light,
I can think of it as a
two-point light source.
So here is a little bit gray,
gray and white dots,
round dots.
I just split it
into a very small point
in each space.
This small point is reflected by the deflection light
and interacts with the deflection light.
I think of it as a two-point light source.
The deflection wave
coming out of the point light source
will be a circle.
This circle will eventually
reconstruct another deflection wave in the original factory.
Because each of them
has the same surface,
the phase coming out of their radiation
has no delay.
So their
original transmission
will be as flat as the deflection light,
which is the tradition.
How did they explain this thing
with Higgins before?
When I am now in the diagonal direction,
you can see that the red part
is the wave front.
This wave front
touches the time on this interface
will be different.
It will first touch the point on the left.
So after the point on the left is touched by the light,
it will be regarded as the first
two-point light source
to start radiation.
Then this point is touched.
But because it is slower to be touched,
it will produce
this radiation slower.
In this way,
to the end here.
Because the time they were touched
is different, we can think of it as
their radiation
is different.
So you can see that the shape of the radiation
produced by them is different from here.
The radiation is getting smaller from left to right.
This will cause
the wave front to be oblique.
Bing Jie, Zhang Yang has a question.
He has a question.
He said
Transmittance's light source
is mainly a design decision.
What about Resonance's Q-factor?
How high and low can it be now?
This thing?
How high can the Q-factor be?
How is it determined?
Q-factor
has a lot of things.
It will be affected by a lot of things.
First of all, the most intuitive
is its loss.
Because the material I designed here
is made of metal.
The metal in the visible light,
or the part outside the mirror,
after it has been resonance,
because of the dipole,
we can think of it as
a movement of free current.
This part will cause
The second thing that will affect it
is the loss of the original radiation.
In theory, we divide it into two categories.
One is Intrinsic.
One is Extrinsic.
Intrinsic is the heat radiation
that the material itself produces.
The other is the loss of the original radiation
caused by the original radiation.
I classify both of them as the part of the loss.
This part will reduce my Q-factor.
The other part is whether my cavity
is strong enough.
Because my current structure
is based on the loss of the original radiation.
So even if there is a shock
on it,
I can think of it as a movement of free current.
But this movement of free current
cannot be perfect
because this cavity is not very strong.
If I want a very strong cavity,
in theory, we should have
almost 100% reflectivity on both sides.
At this time, my Q-factor can be very high.
But because of my current structure,
I just wait for it to accumulate
and let it accumulate radiation on both sides.
But this cavity is not that strong.
So my Q-factor will be reduced.
These factors
result in the
Plasmon Resonance
produced by this kind of metal.
Its Q-factor will not be too high.
As far as I know,
if it is made of metal,
without considering
any cavity,
that is, without considering any mirror,
that is, the perfect mirror in this system,
its Q-factor
can only reach a few hundred.
This is already the highest.
But usually it is only a few tens.
He said he understood.
OK, thank you.
Then,
if I have the
nanoparticle I just talked about,
I am now
in the same direction.
But because of my nanoparticle,
each nanoparticle has a different size.
The size is different,
just like what I just showed in this picture.
Under the same wavelength,
the phase delay
felt by each different size will be different.
At this time,
it works as if
each particle,
although they both feel the
electromagnetic wave,
but after their resonance,
the radiation phase will also be delayed.
This is very interesting.
It allows us to achieve
transparency.
In theory,
I am transparent.
But if I design the structure
appropriately above,
I can see that it is written out.
I can use
Momentum's picture to explain it.
I don't think it needs to be explained.
Basically, it is the phase delay.
Here is a simple experiment result.
If I design a stick
of different lengths on the surface,
you can see that
Can you go back to the page
and explain Momentum? I don't quite understand.
Momentum, in theory,
we know that its K
is 2π除λ.
If I have
different structures here,
in theory, I can equate it to
each structure
can provide a
horizontal momentum.
How does this horizontal momentum decide?
This horizontal momentum is determined by
2π除λ.
What does this λ mean?
This λ of 2π除λ
means that my structure
has a phase delay
from 0 to
the minimum length of 360 degrees.
That is, I can see it as a
pixel of light.
A pixel of light.
If a pixel of light is λ,
we know that its K is 2π除λ.
Because I have a
phase change of T,
I can equate it to
the horizontal momentum of
2π除λ on this
surface.
And these two
Momentum boxes
can let us see through the light.
These two boxes
are obviously in this direction.
This is why we can
achieve the phenomenon of
paranormal penetration.
This is a
simple experiment result.
After designing different
lengths of sticks on the
surface, if my light
is perpendicular to the light,
I want to see if it can
reflect back in the opposite direction.
This is the result of the experiment.
This is the result of the calculation.
The curve of different colors represents
different angles of light.
Black is when the light
is perpendicular to the light,
and white is when the light
is perpendicular to the light.
The reflection angle is
about 45 degrees.
This proves that we
give it a horizontal momentum
in the horizontal direction.
Why don't I see through the light here?
Because the structure of this design
has a thick metal at the bottom.
This thick metal helps
us block all the light.
So we only see the reflected light.
Why do we only see the reflected light here?
You can also see that
when the light is perpendicular to the light,
if you look at the scattering,
you can see that the light
is perpendicular to the light.
Let me ask you a question.
What wavelength is the light
reflected?
The working wavelength is
about 780 nm.
This is the boundary between
the reflected light and the reflected light.
After doing this demo,
we also want to demonstrate
that its efficiency can be very high.
You can see that the efficiency of the calculation
can be more than 90%.
The experimental beam is also 80%.
I'm talking about the time when the reflection was recorded.
So why do we have to choose this wavelength?
Because the inter-beam scattering
is at 550 nm,
so if we use gold to make
the inter-beam scattering,
its resonance will never happen before 550 nm.
Because the loss is too big.
So the farther we work from 550 nm,
in theory, its efficiency can be better.
Of course, this is just the characteristic of the material itself.
Other factors also affect
its efficiency, such as
structural design.
This is the final optimization result.
I want to share with you
most of my work.
The first part is that we want to use aluminum
to make a visible Metasurface,
and then make some
flat components.
The other part is that
we want to make a transparent mirror.
Why do we want to make a transparent mirror?
Because what I just said is
that the most important thing
about Metasurface now
is that it can greatly reduce
the size of the components
we can buy on the market.
For example,
the simplest
and most impressive
is the iPhone
or our smartphone
camera lens.
After the iPhone 6,
you can find that
its body is actually very thin,
but its lens protrudes a piece.
This is because
when the body becomes thin,
it has to maintain
the resolution of the image
it takes
.
This premise
will cause it to
not be able to greatly reduce
the size of the mirror.
It has to insert a lot of different mirror groups
and stack them up,
so that the image produced after taking pictures
will be clearer,
so that some contrast and color difference can be eliminated.
I will introduce this later.
I don't know if I have enough time,
so I may be a little faster.
In fact, if you
take a look at the
current direction of the
battery wave,
we call it bias.
In fact, whether it is
the linear bias of the y-direction
or the linear bias of the x-direction,
or when it rotates,
it produces a circular bias.
No matter what the bias is,
I can split its positive and negative
into three components, x, y, and z.
I can easily stack
these three components
in the same way.
I should say that I can split
any bias light into these three components.
So our future design
will be based on this logic.
Bias is actually quite useful
in life.
For example, 3D images are the most common.
If you go to see a 3D movie,
it will give you a 3D glasses.
These 3D glasses are
what the left eye sees
and what the right eye sees.
Its bias is also perpendicular to each other.
When it causes this illusion,
the image you see will look like a 3D.
So why do you see
that the image is foggy when you take off your glasses?
Because your two eyes
detect the image of two biases at the same time.
Or
we often see that
some people who play photography
will know that
they will put some filters related to bias
in front of the lens,
which can shoot some light
on some slower
or stronger surface
to make
them more clear.
Or
do some
biological or chemical molecules detection.
Because some biological or chemical molecules
will take the initiative
to bias
the bias of the light.
Different molecules
have different angles of bias.
Some are big and some are small.
Some people use this thing
to make chemical molecules
detection.
What are the
most common
ways to manipulate
bias on the market?
Let me give you three examples.
The first one is linear bias.
For example,
if there is a dirty battery,
the battery factory is messy.
If you want to turn it into a pure
battery factory,
for example,
the battery factory is a
horizontal wire.
If the battery factory is along this wire,
it will be absorbed.
The volume of the battery
will be penetrated.
So it uses this method
to filter out the bias it doesn't want.
This is what I found on the Internet.
You can buy it on the market.
Because we need to effectively
absorb all the light in the x-direction.
So its thickness must be thick enough.
Usually this thickness is about a millimeter.
This diameter is one inch.
This diameter is half an inch.
Another one is that after we produce
linear bias, we want to do
a rotation of bias light.
For example, the linear bias of the
green light is 45 degrees.
If I want to rotate it to negative 45 degrees,
we will use 1 in 2 waves.
The main thing is that this material
itself can provide different
phase differences
in the x- and y-directions,
so that when the light penetrates,
the bias of the x-direction
slowly slows down,
and the y-direction slowly speeds up,
so that the x- and y-directions
of the green light are in the positive direction
respectively.
After coming out, it will become
a negative and a positive,
and then use this method to rotate it.
Because it has to accumulate
enough bias delay,
so its thickness must be thick enough.
Or to produce linear bias light.
This is to give the
x- and y-dimensions
an additional bias delay,
so that the angle of the bias delay
is large enough that the
x- and y-directions of the x- and y-directions
are exactly 90 degrees.
Then it can become the original bias light.
It also has to have enough bias delay,
so its thickness must also be very thick.
What are the benefits of using linear bias light?
We don't need to use the thickness of
the minimiter level,
we can produce any bias light we want.
For example, we provide a
design method called
Geometry Faced Metasurface,
which is a superimposed interface that combines
the positions of the x- and y-directions.
What does this mean?
For example, if I have a stick now,
I record a right-handed light
and look at the penetration of the left-handed light.
At this time, because the
bias light of the penetrating light
is different from the recorded light,
so I call it conversion efficiency.
We can see that the conversion efficiency is here.
Then I look at the x- and y-directions of the
bias light, and I will see a value.
At this time, if I rotate it
a theta angle, this theta angle is
the angle with the y-axis.
We will find a very magical thing
that its efficiency will hardly change,
and its
position will change to 2 theta.
Then,
as long as I let it rotate
at the same angle
on this surface,
I can make
its position change from 0
to 2π.
Every time I rotate a theta angle,
its bias delay will become 2 theta.
Another interesting point is that
if the same structure,
the direction of my rotation is exactly the same,
but at this time I turn into a left-handed light
and look at the penetration of the right-handed light.
At this time, I will find a
more interesting thing,
its bias delay can reach 360 degrees,
but it is from 0 to 360 and becomes
0 to negative 360.
This thing can help us design
some components that can be manipulated by bias.
For example, if you look at it with the right-handed light,
it will become a focal penetration.
If you look at it with the left-handed light,
it will become a scattered penetration.
In other words, I can combine
many different optical functions
on the same optical component,
and its
magnitude is very thin.
The thickness of this metal is only
50 nanometers,
so it is much smaller
than the previous
50 nanometers.
This is what we are talking about,
because its magnitude is very small,
so the concept we propose here is that
we can integrate all the different chips
on the same sample.
Then after I enter the color light,
I hit different chips
and the reflected light can produce a different fragrance.
Compared with the general traditional components,
I want to produce the original light,
for example, I at least need a
linear light,
a linear polarizer,
and a quarter wave,
to produce the original light.
But now if I only use our metasurface,
my thickness only needs about
dozens of nanometers to complete
this thing.
Let me tell you
why we use aluminum,
because I just mentioned that gold,
because its intervention coefficient is around 500 to 550 nanometers,
so it is impossible
to work on the entire optical spectrum.
Silver can work on the entire optical spectrum,
but there is a big disadvantage of silver,
which is that it is very easy to oxidize,
so the components cannot last long.
So we choose aluminum here.
Here is a demo for everyone,
that is to say,
we use LISO to pattern
some different aluminum sticks
of different lengths and sizes,
and its color will change drastically.
This is its tradition.
Indeed, its resonance can
expand from 400 nanometers of blue light
to 750 nanometers of red light.
Here is the design of the component.
I won't talk about it.
Simply put, we optimized
its structure dimension
so that it can produce the highest
work efficiency.
Next, I will tell you
how to use the same component
to achieve the production
of any parameter.
First of all,
after I design a stick here,
as I just said,
I make it rotate
in the direction of change.
I can let it produce 0 to 2π
and I can produce an abnormal reflection.
The interesting thing about this abnormal reflection
is that my rotation angle is fixed,
so if I enter the color light
at this time,
it will produce an abnormal reflection
of the right light here.
Conversely, if I enter the color light
and it is the right light,
it will produce an abnormal reflection
of the left light,
but it is on the other side
and it is already achieved.
If I enter a linear parameter light,
which is horizontal,
I mean the x-parameter light.
Because the x-parameter light
can be regarded as the addition of
the right light and the left light,
so it can let me produce
the left and right parameters at the same time.
So I use a simple rotation
to achieve the adjustment of the original parameter light
if I enter the color light as a linear parameter light.
How do I produce any linear parameter light?
We introduce another
parameter light that looks exactly the same as it,
but the rotation direction of the structure is opposite.
The first group of rotation is clockwise,
and the second group of rotation is counterclockwise.
In this case,
when I enter a linear parameter light,
I can achieve the reflection of
the right and left parameters at the same time on the same side.
Then I make a spatial parallelism
between the two of them.
This parallelism will make a difference
in the position between the two of them.
This difference in the position
can be determined by this d.
As mentioned earlier,
the difference in the position
can be equal to 2πd divided by Lx.
Lx is the length.
So you can see that the difference in the position
can be changed by the change in d.
So after the two of them interfere with each other,
they can be multiplied into
different linear parameters.
For example, if d is 0,
it means that the difference in the position
between the two original parameters is 0.
At this time, their reflection light
will also be an x-parameter light.
It's a bit like a mirror.
If I let its d
be designed to
have a difference in the position
of π,
it will become a y-parameter light.
That is, Lx's reflection light will become y.
In this way, I can make it
a positive 45-degree linear light
or a negative 45-degree linear light.
So it's all reflected.
Now there's no way to do the refraction.
Isn't it just a projection?
We can do projection here,
but the efficiency of projection will be very low.
Because I just said that the loss of metal is relatively large.
So our demo here is mainly reflected.
The work I will do later will be projected.
But our material will be converted from metal
to electrolyte.
OK, good, continue.
Then here is its SEM map.
That is, we integrate
the six samples together.
Then the optical system.
Here is a test result.
We usually use
this POSCALISphere
to show
what the
refraction of light
is.
In fact, this map is very simple to see.
If this map is the earth,
its north pole represents the purest right-axis light.
The south pole is the purest left-axis light.
The four points on the equator
represent the
linear light.
The four points in the east, west, south and north
represent the purest
x, y, positive 45
and negative 45-degree linear light.
And these three maps are based on
the experiment results of these three
green light wavelengths.
The black dots are the theoretical results
of ideal prediction.
And the
black dots with colors
are the results of our experiment measurement.
It can be said that they are almost very match.
Some may have some miscalculations,
but they are still quite close to our theoretical prediction results.
Then it proves that we can
achieve different equilibrium states
based on our experimental results.
This is an acoustic-optic modulator.
We can use a lot of aperture in our lives.
For example, a microscope or a camera lens.
At present, there are many problems
with the so-called aperture.
One of them is the differential.
The difference between the different approaches
will be focused in different places.
There is a great influence
when I want to do full-screen images.
The difference means that
I use the same aperture,
but it will be focused in different places.
This will also make it impossible
for us to do full-screen images.
So in order to meet this requirement,
they will stack two apertures
to compensate for the difference.
So that they can be focused
at the same point in different places.
This will make it possible
to do full-screen images.
That's why we can't do full-screen images.
So that the difference between the different approaches
will be focused at the same point in different places.
In theory, if you add one more aperture,
you can only do one more compensation.
For example, if I want to do full-screen images,
you can imagine that
I need at least 10 or 20 shots.
It may not be enough.
Here is a picture of why
our smart phone's aperture is so thick.
It is because there are many different
apertures in it.
In order to meet the compensation
of these differences,
the resulting image will not have distortion.
Or the color will not run away.
It's the same as what the eyes see.
That's why we want to use
MetaServer as a lens.
As mentioned earlier,
we want to do high-efficiency processing.
If I use metal,
all the examples I just mentioned are only reflective.
On the other hand, if I want to do a penetrative,
I have to convert it into an anodized material.
Because the anodized material itself
has no distortion,
no heat loss,
it can greatly reduce
the efficiency of work.
Here is a history.
This may also be skipped.
First of all, we use GetInNitro as a material.
It has a high reflectivity in visible light.
We want to use anodized metal
to do MetaService.
The prerequisite is that its reflectivity
is at least greater than 2.
Because anodized metal is not like metal,
it has a free electron accumulation.
So its resonance must rely on the membrane current.
If the membrane current has resonance,
it means that its reflectivity
must be large enough to compare
with the surrounding environment.
Only then can it produce a strong enough
membrane current to produce fragrance accumulation.
At least as far as I can see,
if compared with air, it is at least 2.
Similarly, we use PPFace,
which is the MetaService of GeometryFaceFace,
which is the rotating method I just mentioned,
to adjust its fragrance.
This is called focusing.
Focusing means that I am now
injecting a flat light into it.
The light in different positions
will feel different fragrance delays
before it can reach the same point.
So this is the fragrance distribution
that I have to satisfy in different structures
in the space.
This is the final design result.
If I inject an experiment,
this is the experimental electronic microscope photo.
This is the MetaService lens we designed.
We call it MetaLens.
In order to detect its focus,
when we inject light into it,
this super photoreceptor will focus
on a certain point in a certain space.
We use a flat platform at the back
to detect how well it focuses the light.
You can see that
we just match
a very beautiful green light spot
on its focusing surface.
I injected green light and laser light.
If I stay away from it,
it will not focus.
In addition to green light,
we can also do different things.
How far is the distance?
How far can it move?
You mean this stage?
Yes.
This stage can move up to 7mm.
What about its step size?
Its step size can reach
500nm.
OK.
Thank you.
Not only green light,
we can also do red, blue, and green.
Just change its size.
Regularity depends on its size.
Next,
in addition to doing positive focus,
we can also do oblique focus
on a flat surface.
But this is very difficult
to do in traditional photoreceptors.
Because traditional photoreceptors
mainly use manual grinding
to achieve the surface frequency I want.
A photoreceptor is a glass with a curve.
Different thicknesses will cause
different fragmentation.
If I want to use traditional photoreceptors
you can imagine that
this is a curve.
It becomes a curve on one side.
This is very difficult
in terms of technology.
Our technology is very simple.
I just need to change the distribution of the surface structure
so that its center
slowly deviates a little to the left
or a little to the right.
Then I can do oblique focus.
For example, this picture.
Here is the experiment result.
You can see that red, blue, and green are focused.
This refers to the position of the lens.
The focus is in the upper right corner.
We designed it in the upper right corner.
We proposed an application.
If we integrate all of them
on the same chip
because it is very small
we can easily integrate them all together.
After I insert a wide-screen light source
I will see a different color distribution.
I can use it to divide the light.
For example, this is the photo of our sample.
If I insert a red light now
I can see that the focus is in the upper right corner
of the same sample.
If I insert a green light now
I can see that there is a focus light on the upper left and lower right.
The blue light is in the lower left.
If I insert three wavelengths at the same time
I will see the effect of division of light.
The biggest application of this thing
is on CMOS.
CMOS is currently
an important component
in the image sensor.
Traditionally, you have to do a
micro lens, which is what I just said.
You have to focus first
and then go through a filter and a detector.
Because the detector can't
distinguish colors,
that's why it has to put a filter here.
It has to make sure that
this filter can only receive blue light.
So it has to put a blue light filter
to filter out the white light, red light, and green light.
This causes
the red light and green light
to be wasted
and so on.
But our sample
can put all the white light in
and divide all the red light here.
The green light is in the middle, and the blue light is on the other side.
We can effectively use
all the energy of the green light
to greatly increase its S-N ratio.
The other biggest advantage
is what I just said.
Our thickness is only 600 nanometers.
Traditionally, it's about 1 to 10 microns.
So we can shrink down its physical dimension.
The other thing
we want to do
is to eliminate
the difference in color.
As I just said, different wavelengths
will focus on different positions.
This is the work of the people in the past.
But this is our work.
Traditionally,
different wavelengths of green light
would focus on different positions in the space,
so it's hard to make a full-color image.
We designed
some special designs
to provide different flavor compensations
in different positions
to create a white light focus point.
This is a demonstration
using a metal part as a reflector.
This is the design principle.
I won't talk about it.
This is the sample photo.
This is the measurement result.
This is the calculation result.
You can see that my wavelength
changes from 1.2 to 1.65 microns.
Basically, its focal length
has hardly changed.
If I do a different
lens measurement,
I can see that
the focal length
is almost the same.
If I compare it with
a traditional metal lens,
the deviation is quite large
in the same wavelength.
This proves that
we can completely eliminate the color difference.
This is another example.
I skipped it.
Another example is
that the biggest use of transparency
is to make a full-color image.
Transparency is actually very difficult to make a full-color image.
So our work here is to
make a high-efficiency
focal length transparency
and further apply it to make a full-color image.
What I just said
is why we can use
metal materials to
adjust the angle.
The main reason is that
there is a big difference in the refraction rate,
so it can produce a cavity-like resonance.
So different wavelengths
can produce different
cavities.
Here is our photo.
This studio is
located in the visible light,
so the refractive spectrum
ranges from 400 to 640.
We can actually eliminate it to 660,
but because of the deviation here,
I only fix it to 640.
The last is to make a full-color image.
After I use a photo to come in,
we want to be able to
make a full-color image
through our metalance
analysis.
Here is a full-color image
made with our lens.
You can see that
even white or yellow
have very clear colors.
Compared with the original photo,
there is not much difference in color.
It proves that we can
eliminate color difference in the entire
refractive spectrum and make a full-color image application.
That's about it.
Sorry, I talked a little too fast,
because the time is a bit delayed.
This is my report for today.
Thank you everyone.
I don't know if there are any questions.
If I talk too fast later,
I think it's good.
Do you have any questions?
Can you hear me?
Yes, we can hear you now.
Thank you.
What is this?
My question is
basically
your device
is roughly scaled
as the working
frequency.
Basically.
Yes, it should be smaller than the frequency.
I mean it should have the same effect.
If you want
the working frequency
to be doubled,
the length,
the scale should be 2.
So the area should be 4.
No,
it's not a linear scale.
It's not a linear scale.
It's not.
Because of the resonance,
it's different from the material.
For example,
this thing is very intuitive.
I just talked about this thing.
For example,
if we have resonance,
we can think that
it produces an equivalent
resonance here.
So if you say
my working frequency
is doubled,
in theory, the length should be doubled.
The premise of this thing is
that the scale of the structure itself does not change.
Oh.
In different wavelengths,
the scale of the material will change.
So its equivalent wavelength,
the effective lambda is actually
lambda over n.
This n is also the wavelength function.
Oh, yes.
So it's not a linear scale.
Now for this kind of material,
can you do it
in
millimeter wave
or infrared
or deep IR
devices?
You can do it in Terahertz or microwave,
but most people do it in microwave.
Now there are several companies in the United States
that have established this principle of doing it in microwave.
Because microwave is easy to do
and the loss is super low.
And
military use is the widest.
And its materials are basically
aluminum or some
silicon base, which are cheaper
and easy to make materials.
Yes, that's right.
Although we have been talking about metal for a long time,
the main reason why
there is no commercial product for metal
is here.
Because metal is not yet
silicon path fabrication compatible.
These CMOS semiconductor companies
are compatible.
I see.
So why do we want to do gallium nitride later?
Because gallium nitride is at least
a semiconductor company.
The current manufacturing can be compatible.
Let me talk about
Maybe you can think about it.
Because we are looking for
Terahertz absorber,
but it has to be very, very
low radioactivity.
So we have very, very
restrictions on materials.
We can't use some
very fancy elements, you know.
So if you can do this thing,
it should be usable.
And it's quite complicated.
What do you mean by Terahertz?
What are the requirements?
We need it to be
able to adjust its optical quality
in Terahertz.
It's EM wave quality.
But all the materials it uses
have to be very low radioactivity.
In other words,
its natural isotope
has to be very low.
So there are not many materials we can use.
So if you can use some pure elements,
such as silicon
or aluminum,
not alloy or super heavy metals,
or super heavy metals,
you can do it.
That's a very good choice.
For example, can you accept gold and copper?
Yes, gold and copper.
But what do you want to use?
For example, silver.
It's weird.
If it's Terahertz,
gold and copper
can be used.
These are very common materials.
On the contrary,
it's rare to see
low radioactivity.
In Terahertz,
it doesn't seem to reach
such a high value.
Because usually
the radioactivity of
natural materials
decreases as the wavelength increases.
So its visible light
has the highest radioactivity
and decays slowly.
So in my mind,
I haven't seen anyone
use Terahertz materials
such as silicon,
gallium nitride,
or germanium,
such as silicon nitride
to make Terahertz components.
But there's a lot of metal.
Like I said, there's a lot of copper and gold.
Okay, thank you.
You're welcome.
What kind of radioactivity
did you mean
when you said
radioactivity?
No, I mean
the radioactivity of the material itself.
Like bananas
also have beta decay.
Oh, okay.
So you mean like tin
has a higher radioactivity?
Yes, if you want to use
something below the
elemental cycle,
it won't work.
The reason why it doesn't work is because
it naturally has the same value
and it's easy to change.
So if you put in a particle,
the particle will affect the quality
of the particle detector.
Because it will become noise.
Okay, got it.
Let me ask,
I didn't understand
what kind of materials
are usually used
in the microwave range.
Aluminum or gallium nitride?
No, if it's microwave,
the most common thing is copper.
Because copper can print
very cheaply.
So the printed pattern
is like the nanostructure
you just made?
Yes, it may not be nanoscale,
it may be millimeter scale.
Because the wavelength of microwave
may be dozens of millimeters
or even centimeters.
So it's actually easier to do.
Yes, so it's very easy to do.
And what they print
is a large area.
Maybe you can stick it
on the whole wall of your house.
Oh, got it.
What other materials
are also very effective
in doing the same thing?
The most common metal
we see right now
is
gold, silver, copper.
No, not copper.
Gold, silver, aluminum.
These three are the most common.
Oh, thank you.
Thank you.
And if it's...
No, you go first.
Yes, and if it's
electrolyte, it's actually quite a lot.
There should be more choices.
For example, as long as the resolution is high enough.
So silicon,
gallium nitride,
silicon nitride,
titanium oxide,
and gallium phosphate.
But gallium phosphate has
absorption, so the effect may not be as good.
You have a video
where you hit the light
and there's a left and right
rotation.
This one?
Yes.
No, the previous one.
The one you just mentioned.
The one you just showed.
Oh,
so how efficient is it?
If you hit the light
and it's linearly polarized,
it will be left and right
rotation.
In our experiment,
let me see.
it's about
30 to 50%
efficient.
Okay,
so this is its wavelength.
Yes, the next one is wavelength.
Theoretically,
we expect it to be
about 70%.
But after we published this,
there's one thing
we didn't consider.
In our calculation,
we know that aluminum oxidizes easily.
So when it oxidizes, there will be 3 to 5 nanometers of aluminum on the surface.
This will affect its resonance
efficiency.
So this picture is about this.
This is someone else's work.
He's talking about the average pure aluminum.
If I design it,
its resonance is this high.
And then after the oxidation,
it will slowly
tilt to the right a little bit
and the efficiency will drop a little bit.
This is what we saw in our experiment.
Indeed, our simulation hopes that
its peak is here,
but our experiment results
show that the peak is
a little bit lower.
So we speculated that
the efficiency of this result
is not that high
because we didn't consider
the oxidation rate
when optimizing the structure.
The question I want to ask
is,
assuming that
the positive light
keeps decreasing
the energy,
how many lights
will it reflect?
Will there be
a state of
entanglement
when the light
is reflected
at the same time?
Or you don't care about this?
We don't care about this.
But what you said
is actually
what I want to do next.
Because
the most common
entangled photon source
is BBO,
which is a non-linear crystal
to produce entanglement.
But it is a entanglement.
So I thought about this
at that time.
If it is an entanglement of
both H and V,
I will pass the light
through this source.
What is H plus V?
H is horizontal, V is vertical.
This is the entanglement of X and Y.
If the reflected light
is H plus V,
can I have
a special entanglement
at the same time?
I'm not sure about this.
But I want to do this.
Because I'm not sure
if the reflected light is H or V,
I can't be sure
if the reflected light
is right or left.
If the reflected light is H,
the reflected light is left or right.
If the reflected light is V,
I think
this is possible.
Because this kind of source
has already been done.
We mainly use a bunch of photons
to integrate with this structure.
If I only have a single photon,
it will also work.
If a single photon
also works,
it should be possible.
It should be possible.
We should work together
after you finish this.
What I'm going to do next
is to transfer
the entanglement photon
to the spin of the quantum dot.
So you're doing quantum mechanics?
Yes.
My next project
will be
what I just said.
But the entanglement
is one is vertical
and the other is horizontal.
But if
we can make entanglement
of left and right,
we should
make it first
and think about it
after it's confirmed.
Okay.
Is there any question?
Audience?
It seems like no.
Thank you, Bing Jie.
Thank you.
You did a great job.
You have a good grasp of the time.
I talked too fast
at the end.
If you have any questions,
you can tell me.
Right.
I want to ask
if you really made this
or you didn't
do this in Caltech?
I didn't do this in Caltech.
But...
Don't ask Cai.
Because if
we make this...
Yes.
We should...
We're planning to
make this
recently.
Yes.
Do you have a good approach?
Or you already have some approaches?
Like you said, BBO.
But BBO can only generate
linear light.
So I said it can only generate
Yes.
If it can generate...
If you want to generate
spin, you need
circular polarizer.
Yes.
That's what we're thinking.
No problem. We can talk about it.
Okay.
That's all for
today.
Thank you.
Thank you, everyone.
Bye-bye.