Hello, everyone. I'm the host for today. I'm Lin Yuwei from UC Irvine.
Our guest for today's TerraTalk is Lu Kefan, a Ph.D. student at Fairbanks University of Alaska.
His field of research is very interesting. It's about Arctic Ocean Sea Ice.
He was a Ph.D. student at Tsinghua University. He was also an intern at ZTE.
He was a Ph.D. student for three and a half years.
He is expected to graduate next spring.
You can visit his defense course and see the aurora.
Let's welcome Lu Kefan.
Thank you, everyone.
I don't want to bore you, so I'll introduce the Arctic Ocean Sea Ice.
I'll talk about my field of research.
At the end, I'll talk about my work in the Arctic Ocean Sea Ice.
At the beginning, we saw a video.
It's a popular video on social media.
It tells us how to reduce sea ice in recent years.
It's about saving polar bears, protecting the earth, reducing carbon, and protecting the environment.
It's a similar title.
For me, this kind of video doesn't have a wrong direction.
But from a scientific point of view, we have to be very careful when we see a similar video.
What does the color in the video mean?
I think you may intuitively think that the white part is the size, volume, or thickness of the ice.
But in fact, this video is from NASA's Scientific Visualization Studio.
It calculates the age of the sea ice, which is the length of time the sea ice stays in the ocean.
Why do we look at the age of the sea ice?
In general, we will divide the sea ice into one-year ice or multi-year ice.
One-year ice is the gray part.
You can see that there is a big shock every year.
Because it melts in summer.
In winter, when the sea water reaches the freezing point, it freezes again.
In fact, the thickness of the sea ice has nothing to do with its age.
The average thickness of one-year ice is about 2 to 3 meters.
The thickness of multi-year ice, which is the ice that has not completely melted in summer for more than a year, is actually about 3 meters.
The thickness of one-year ice or multi-year ice may be more than 5 meters.
So when you see a video like this, especially a large-scale video,
Because the thickness of the sea ice is very difficult to measure from the air,
So if you see such a large-scale video, it is usually not discussing the thickness of the sea ice, its size, or volume.
Next, let's take a look at the winter of 2016.
Take a closer look at the gray part.
For example, as I just said, one-year ice is also 3 meters.
Multi-year ice is also 3 meters.
Then you will see that the whole piece is white.
Even the east coast of the United States still has sea ice.
Then visually, you will not feel so deeply that our sea ice is declining.
But NASA made this video not to intimidate everyone.
This video has several points.
The first point is that we can see that most of the sea ice flows out of the Atlantic coast.
This is the first point.
The second point is that if we look closely at the gray area,
Or look at the statistics next to it,
In the summer, the gray area is the part of one-year ice.
Indeed, there is a gradual decrease in the trend.
Then I would say that it is a decrease in the trend, not that it is really decreasing every year.
But overall, it is gradually decreasing in the past 40 years.
The countries that are concerned about the study of North America are the neighboring eight countries,
Including the United States, Greenland, Iceland, the Nordic countries, and Russia.
In addition to the neighboring eight countries,
There are also countries such as Europe, Germany, France, East Asia, Japan, South Korea, and China.
The reason why they are so concerned about the study of North America is because
Everyone wants to take advantage of the lack of ice in the summer to use the fishing rights and navigation rights in the Arctic Ocean.
So these far Eastern Asian countries can use this red line,
This red line is the Arctic Ocean's North East Line,
It is now being used.
If the East Asian countries use the North East Line to travel by sea to send goods to Europe,
Its navigation will be only one-third of the way to the south.
So for them, the melting of the sea ice in the summer or the gradual reduction of the sea ice area,
For some countries, it is not entirely a disaster or a bad thing or something they want to avoid.
Then there is no need to say that the United States, Norway, and Russia have very large drilling projects along the coast of the Arctic Ocean.
It's not like what everyone sees.
Greenpeace has previously stated that they have used a method to prohibit Shell from drilling oil, and they have won.
It's not like that.
The reason why Shell stopped drilling oil in the Arctic Ocean is because they hired a large number of scientists to do research,
They found that if they wanted to deal with the subsequent oil problems and consolidate the ecological balance,
The investment and their income were not worth it, so they decided to withdraw.
But in addition to Shell, there are quite a few oil companies in the United States, such as ConocoFlips or BP,
They continue to drill oil along the coast of the Arctic Ocean, and there is no need to say that the entire north coast of Norway is a drilling platform.
These countries' attitude towards the reduction of sea ice is to treat it as a natural phenomenon that is already happening and is almost impossible to reverse.
Their research focuses on how to deal with what has already happened.
For example, researchers at the National Institute for Oil and Gas Engineering in Austria and Norway are now working on improving the shape of the drilling platform.
Because we see that if there is less sea ice, the flow of sea will be strengthened, but there will still be some floating ice stuck on the coast.
After these floating ice are affected by strong sea currents, they will hit the drilling platform, which may cause public safety accidents.
So they want to improve the drilling platform to reduce the slowdown of floating ice hitting the sea.
Or like the East Asian countries I just mentioned, they are constantly studying when to enter the Arctic Ocean and which route to take to avoid aftershocks and shipwrecks.
For example, we know that the Arctic Ocean is very famous.
As the sea ice retreats, the water temperature will also change.
So we find that the Arctic Ocean is gradually moving northward.
At this time, they have to consider whether to change the target species or change the area and timing of the Arctic Ocean.
These are all countries that are now working on Arctic research.
They are not completely treating the Arctic Ocean as a disaster to avoid or try to restore to the original state of sea ice.
From this animation, we can see that a lot of sea ice flows out of the Atlantic Ocean.
For this reason, we can see that a lot of Atlantic Ocean water flows from the Atlantic coast of the Arctic Ocean to the Atlantic coast of the Pacific Ocean.
This is because the opening of the Atlantic coast of the Pacific Ocean is very narrow, only about 100 to 200 kilometers wide.
The opening of the Atlantic coast of the Pacific Ocean is very narrow, only about 100 to 200 kilometers wide.
Therefore, Atlantic ocean water continues to flow from the Atlantic coast of the Pacific Ocean to the north coast of Canada.
This is because the opening of the Atlantic coast of the Pacific Ocean is very narrow, only about 100 to 200 kilometers wide.
This is because the change of ocean current in the ocean basin is complicated, and the distribution of ocean ice is also complicated.
I don't understand what you said at the end. Why did you say that the output of the object is your input?
Did you say that the object affects the temperature and ocean?
We don't know the biological information in the ocean, right?
I thought your input was temperature, salt, and environment.
I don't understand what you said at the end. Why did you say that the output of the object is your input?
This is a very important question. The ocean model has a lot of functions.
This is a very important question.
Do you have time? Do you want to hear me talk about the ocean?
I went to the East China Sea when I was in middle school.