Q&A
Hello, I am today's representative host, Zhang Yanyong, because our host, Zhang Jianyuan, he is actually more suitable, because he is doing Qubits, doing condensed matter, but he is now stuck on the road, he has no time for transportation, so I will represent the host.
Let me introduce our speaker today. Our speaker today is Dr. Zeng Yuqing. The topic he is going to talk to us today is ... I want to read it right, wait a minute, I suddenly can't find it, wait a minute, wait a minute.
Topological quantum phase transitions in Haldane spin chains. This is a very popular topic, because in 2016 or 2017, Topological Matter won the Nobel Prize, so we have always hoped that we could invite an expert to introduce to us what topological phases are.
Then, Zeng Yuqing, in 2005, got a college degree from Donghai University, a physics major, right? Then he went to serve in the military, and then served in the military for 1.5 years, but he served in the military at Donghai University. Why?
After I served in the military, I returned to Donghai University as a research assistant.
Then there is a published paper in PRB, if you are interested, because I don't have that number, so you can directly ask our speaker for this thing. Then he transferred to Central University and completed his Ph.D. degree. The main function is also condensed matter theory.
At present, Zeng Yuqing is at the University of Kent in the UK, and he is now focusing on numerical study on the time-reversal invariant fractional topological insulator. This is a very hot topic, so we don't have much to say, we applaud and welcome today's speaker. Oh, if you want to applaud or ask a question, remember to turn on the microphone.
Let's get started. Today I prepared some props.
I have some props. You can play with some props later.
I will talk about some of the things I have done before, which will be more professional. First of all, what is physics?
What we mainly learn in physics is quantum mechanics. Quantum mechanics is like classical mechanics, which is mechanics, or kinetic mechanics of electricity, quantum mechanics, thermal mechanics, and statistical mechanics.
This whole thing is actually studying the interaction between time, space, and matter. The interaction between matter has, for example, strong, weak, electromagnetic, or gravity.
You can take the whole world, these substances, as if they were actors on stage. The stage is the background between time and space, and there will be some interaction between the actor and the actor.
The whole thing will form a movie or a stage play.
What about matter? This is from when I was very young, for example, in high school or elementary school, I learned that we can classify matter in this way.
First, divide it into solid matter or mixtures. Mixtures, such as beer, milk tea, or air, are mixtures.
For example, alcohol, water, and many other substances, such as beer, flowers, and so on.
For example, most of the air is 4 out of 5 gas, and 1 out of 5 oxygen, for example.
Pure matter can be divided into elements and mixtures. For example, the elements in the cycle table, such as gold, iron, oxygen, and O2.
For example, the previously well-known graphene, which is basically carbon.
For example, alcohol is a mixture of alcohol and water.
Alcohol has a chemical form, such as CH3CH2OH, which is alcohol.
Chlorine is also a mixture of pure matter.
Oxygen is also a mixture of pure matter.
For example, ice is water, which is the solid of water.
Ice is also pure matter, which is H2O.
This classification is probably a little bit of preliminary understanding of matter.
To understand this understanding further, we can see that matter has many states.
This state is called phase.
There is a change between the phase and the phase, which is called phase change.
For example, the ice or water we just talked about is under pressure in the horizontal axis and temperature in the vertical axis.
For example, at the bottom of atmospheric pressure, below 0 ° C, it is solid.
This side will be liquid and this side will be gas.
The red line is from here, it will pass through a waste point and then become water vapor.
From here, it will pass through this ice point and solidify into ice.
For example, this picture.
Of course, you can't see the water vapor with your naked eye.
Because the water vapor is transparent and colorless.
If it is connected to this water drop on the glass, it will become a liquid.
You can see that this is water.
This is the water we usually see.
Ice is solid.
This picture is in our present.
It's snowing in the UK recently, and it's cold.
After the snow, many people want to do an experiment.
Put the liquid nitrogen on the snowman and then destroy it.
See what the result is.
In short, this picture of water should have been seen in elementary school.
I don't know if there is any problem.
If not, I want to emphasize that there is a critical point here.
The meaning of this critical point is that if the temperature and pressure are very high from here to the critical point, you will not be able to distinguish whether the water is a liquid or a gas.
After this critical point, there is no red line.
The red line on the left has been extended.
This point stops at this critical point.
So if this side is gas, this side is liquid, this side is solid.
This line completely separates solid and liquid.
But here you can adjust the temperature and pressure appropriately.
Then let it slowly go around this critical point from here.
Then enter another item.
In other words, the phase of the liquid and the phase of the gas are the same phase.
The three-dimensional picture of water here is actually only two phases.
There are only two images like this.
There should be no problem.
This is a relaxing video.
A few days ago, we put the liquid and gas on the snowman.
Many people came to see.
There are about 100 people here.
Other dramas have come to see.
I think this is interesting.
You can see that gas is also a pure material.
Pure materials have three-dimensional pictures of water like just now.
Now pour out the liquid and gas.
The liquid and gas are about 70K.
It's about 100 degrees below zero.
The temperature of the ice is very high compared to the temperature of the liquid and gas.
The temperature of the liquid and gas is very high compared to the temperature of the liquid and gas.
The temperature is lower.
You can see the picture of the liquid and gas.
It is still solid.
That's about it.
What is a phase?
What does it mean?
You have an external parameter.
For example, you just saw that there is temperature and pressure.
What is the state of a huge macro of this material?
What are the external parameters?
For example, temperature pressure, magnetic field, or external control.
You can control the outside.
For example, you add a power plant.
Or you use other elements to replace these compounds.
You do some mixing.
This mixing can also be regarded as an external parameter.
Mainly these parameters.
You made these modifications.
Will affect these.
Because the matter is composed of those atoms.
It is composed of those particles.
You modified these external parameters.
Will affect the interaction between particles.
What about the interaction between particles?
It will have different phases.
The higher the temperature, the more chaotic the material is.
But if you have an interaction, the material may have a different order.
What is a macro state?
For example, the three-phase change just now.
The three-phase change is the solid, solid, gas.
But it's not just solid, solid, gas.
It's a macro state.
For example, conductivity.
Conductivity is also a macro state.
Magnetic field is also a macro state.
For example, mercury.
In 1911, it was discovered by Ernst.
After the temperature dropped very low, it suddenly became a superconductor.
What about conductivity?
For example, the angle is the temperature.
When the temperature is very high.
This temperature is the absolute temperature.
From this place, you can see that there is a conductor here.
Satisfy the Ohm's law.
When the temperature drops, the conductor becomes smaller and smaller.
But there is still a conductor.
But when the temperature is about 4K, about 4.2K.
The conductor suddenly disappears.
There is almost nothing.
There is nothing at all.
There is nothing here.
This can be regarded as a phase change.
Because this is a very macro state.
The whole change.
Because there is a conductor here.
There is no conductor here at all.
Here is the general conductor.
On the left side, it suddenly becomes a superconductor.
The superconductor has great application value.
For example, later we found that mercury is a pure material.
Mercury is an element.
But other compounds may also become superconductors.
Like these high-temperature superconductors.
High-temperature superconductors can become superconductors as long as they are at the temperature of the liquid nitrogen.
For example, these copper oxides.
You will see that there is an X in these different compounds.
There is an X here, right?
This X is when you synthesize this compound.
How much ratio do you want to put in?
How much ratio do you put in?
Then you go to burn this compound.
Then you are equal to saying that this X is your external parameter.
That's your temperature with your axis.
Different temperatures and different cross-sections.
The horizontal axis is the cross-section.
Write a P on the right.
You are the cross-sectional electric.
This is the meaning of the X.
Write an N on the left.
Write N on the left.
You are the cross-sectional electric.
Here is the electron dot and the hole dot.
This place is when you are not in the cross-section.
This is a counter-iron-magnetic superconductor.
When you cross-section to a certain degree,
When you drop to a low enough temperature,
It becomes a superconductor.
So this area is a superconductor phase.
This area is a counter-iron-magnetic phase.
What is a counter-iron-magnetic?
Then go on.
Magnetic.
There are many kinds of magnetic.
The magnet we usually see,
Like this magnet.
When we were in elementary school,
Take the magnet and sprinkle some magnetic powder.
Look at the magnetic field.
The magnetic nature of this magnet is called magnetism.
That is to say,
There are many magnetic poles inside the magnet.
Many small magnetic poles.
These magnetic poles are originally,
If it is messy,
If the temperature is very high,
Then these magnetic poles are messy.
After the mess, the whole is not magnetic.
But if you lower the temperature,
Then because of this magnetic pole and the magnetic pole,
There will be some interaction.
These interactions will make these magnetic poles,
The direction is still in the same direction.
When everyone is lined up in roughly the same direction,
The overall magnetic nature will be displayed.
You will see that it is a magnet.
It is the overall direction.
For example, this arrow here is N-level,
This is S-level.
If everyone is messy,
The whole thing is offset.
I found a YouTube video.
It's probably like this.
Can you see it now?
Should be no problem.
Yes, I can see it.
There is a piece of iron on the top.
Put a piece of iron.
After the magnetic iron below is red,
The red magnetic iron is magnetic.
Its magnetic pole is messy.
Messy, then there is no magnetic nature.
But after it slowly cools down,
The temperature is low enough.
Because it has an interaction between the magnetic pole and the magnetic pole.
When the temperature is low enough,
It will be aligned with everyone in the same direction.
There is a magnetic pole in the same direction.
If there is a magnetic pole,
It becomes iron magnetic.
Iron magnetic is the meaning of this magnetic iron.
There should be no problem.
Another one is that it is lined up well.
But it does not have a total magnetic force.
The total magnetic iron.
Although the super island I just talked about.
When you are not mixed, it is iron magnetic.
What does iron magnetic mean?
That is to say, your magnetic pole.
This magnetic pole.
How did this magnetic pole come?
Part of it is the orbital momentum of the electron.
And the other part is the magnetic circle.
If these magnetic poles are interspersed.
For example, here is up, down, up, down, up, down, up.
Interspersed.
It is also lined up well.
But it does not have the iron magnetic force of the magnet just now.
But it still has order.
This iron magnetic force.
Although there is no total magnetic force.
But it is completely different from the one that was completely messed up just now.
Because the magnetic pole of the burning red iron is messy.
This iron magnetic pole.
The magnetic pole is very well arranged.
After that, I will mainly talk about.
If these magnetic poles are arranged into a chain.
Of course, this is the intention below.
Because you are not taking a magnet.
Then directly this magnet.
Because there are countless magnetic poles in a magnet.
Or there are already a lot of magnetic poles inside.
Then we have to discuss later.
It is said that the magnetic pole is arranged into a circle.
Then the magnetic pole and the magnetic pole next door have some interaction.
Will this cause the whole?
Will there be a state of order?
Or will it be a whole?
What is the order?
Simply put, everything has an order.
For example, electrons also have an order.
The light also has an order.
The magnet also has an order.
Quark also has an order.
Everything has an order.
Order is a basic physical nature.
Quark also has an order.
Quark's order is 1.
But Quark's order is 1.
Its z-direction can only be positive or negative 1.
So we see that light has a polarizing direction.
There is a left-handed light and a right-handed light.
Light has an order.
The order of light is 1.
All orders should be divided into two categories.
One is the order of one-half, three-thirds, five-fifths, seven-fifths.
This kind of half-order is called quark.
The other is the order of the whole.
For example, the order is 0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5.
This is called quark.
Light has an order of 1.
So it is quark.
Electrons have an order of one-half.
Like this.
Sorry.
Go on.
That's right.
Yes.
Is it OK?
OK.
So the spin-chain discussed later is related to quark.
Is it an order or a half-order?
This is a big deal.
These are two very different types.
Before talking about these orders,
what is symmetry?
What is asymmetry?
Asymmetry means that after you have done a certain operation, the result does not change.
For example, as I just said,
parallel symmetry, rotation symmetry, mirror symmetry, time parallel, time inverse,
any kind of operation.
Can you see me now?
Yes.
For example, I take this.
If you don't look at the pattern on this ball,
if they are all the same color,
I just turn 360 degrees like this.
I'll cover it up first.
Then I'll turn a little bit.
Then I'll show you.
Then you don't know.
You will never be able to tell if I'm turning or not.
Right?
So it means that this ball has the symmetry of this rotation.
There is already a pattern on it.
Of course, this pattern will destroy its rotation.
Because if I turn like this, you will recognize this pattern.
You know I have turned.
But if this is all blue,
I can turn this three-dimensional corner.
This is a rotation symmetry.
What about this apple?
This apple, you have an imagination first.
There is a meme here.
And then, here,
So if I turn like this,
Then you will find that it is different.
But if I turn like this along this axis,
Assuming its shape is perfect.
Then you will see that it also has this rotation symmetry.
But this rotation symmetry
Only with this Z axis as the rotation axis
You have this symmetry.
I can turn like this.
I can also turn like this.
The symmetry of this apple is less than the symmetry of this ball.
Because it only rotates like this.
This ball can rotate in any way.
If so, you will see that this and this ring
I made a ring.
This ring is the same.
I turn like this, the result is unchanged.
What about this bagel?
If I turn like this,
You will not know that I have turned.
Of course, if this is the case,
If I put a sticker on it,
Do you know that I have turned?
For example, I'm hungry now.
I'm hungry, I take a bite.
Now after being bitten by me
It has lost the symmetry of this rotation.
This is also the same.
This bagel is also the same.
If I don't bite too big
I take a bite first.
I bought a lot today.
I bite a little bit.
I don't bite this hole.
Then it has no symmetry of this rotation.
In other words, what does this bite cause?
Causing a defect
Defects will affect a lot of things.
What I'm going to talk about later is Torpo.
Torpo
Let's play a little game first.
I have a ring here.
If I use a pen
Many people should know that
If I go from here
Then follow this ring
Go around like this
Go around and pick it up.
Wait for the paper to turn 360 degrees
I'll go back to the origin.
These two are not the same.
One
I do this too.
I am also back to the origin.
But this is not.
When this is done
This ring is very different from these two rings.
This ring is just like this one.
These two rings are very different.
In fact, the same
I twisted it a little bit.
In fact, this ring is just like this.
This ring is like this.
So you see, I just painted black here.
If there is
Usually there is an ant walking up
After going around
You will return to the original place.
This ring is like this.
This ring is not
This ring is the so-called Mobius ring.
What if
I have an ant here
Walk like this
Go go go
Go around
Go
After going around
He will
He actually
I'm going around now.
Go around
As a result, I ran to this path.
Run to the back of this ring
Not the same as this
After two laps
Will return to the origin
This is a
It's completely different from a few boxes.
This thing
And then go back to the video.
That
What I just said is symmetrical.
This is symmetrical.
That
Has been destroyed
With
What does it have to do with the photo?
Because we know
Is
Ah
If you
If
Ah
You have one
Energy or free energy
He
If he is a certain parameter
If the function
Then you basically free energy should be like
Energy is like the lower the better
Will be stable
If your
At first your function is like this
So
If you have a ball here
He is of course symmetrical
Because of this symmetry
Symmetry is of course
Is the lowest point of energy
But if your external parameters
Change
For example, your temperature
Temperature changes
Temperature
Low temperature
Your temperature is getting lower and lower
That causes this function to change
The lowest energy state at this time
Not in this
Symmetrical point
And he might
Will choose to be in
A certain one
Free energy is lower
That place
Of course, every place
This place or this place
Free energy
Energy is the same
Then he has to choose
On the left or on the right
I don't know
He might be him
He might
He
He has a little bit
Direction
A little bit to the left or a little bit to the right
When
He is very natural
He will run to this soon
To a stable place
That's like this place
In this case
You will find that he is not symmetrical
Originally
It was left and right
This has a
Symmetrical
That's not symmetrical now
That's not symmetrical
It means
There is a order
Happened
That's what happened
That's a certain
An image is produced
For example, just now
We just saw that
The experiment of the distance temperature
That burning red iron
No magnetic
Burning red iron
His
The magnetic field is messy
That
When it's messy
Magnetic field
Although he has a magnetic field in every place
He has a lot of this
That order or
Magnetic field
For example, this magnetic field
That
But the temperature is very high
He has a magnetic field
All
Keep doing this
Just keep doing it
Ah
In the disturbance
In the transformation
That causes the whole
You look
That moment looks very messy
That magnetic field looks messy
And positive magnetic field and negative magnetic field
Positive and negative, but in different directions
The whole
Put this whole magnetic field
All offset
That's messy
That messy
How do you say he is symmetrical?
Just when you have this magnetic field
When the magnetic field is very messy
You you
Rotate him
You do a certain area to balance
You have a camera
You you you this camera
Observe and then you balance this camera
Then you find that he is still messy
Just as messy as just now
You can't see what it is
You can't tell
Do you have a rotation
I did not
I did a balance or did a rotation
You can't tell
and so
He
In the video just now
This red iron
What is the symmetry
Just have
Balance symmetry
Also have
Rotational symmetry
But what happens when the temperature drops?
Because of the magnetic field and the magnetic field
His interaction
It's more
More strong
More obvious
What about the thermal disturbance?
Not enough for him
Let him mess up
So he will be the whole
Causing the overall magnetic field to lean towards one
One direction
At this time if everyone
When everyone is leaning in the same direction
At this time you will find
I no longer have
This rotation symmetry
Is my rotation symmetry
Just
I rotate
That direction just now
It was all pointing up
Everyone is pointing up
Then I rotate everyone
Changed direction
You will find that he has changed
That's not symmetrical
That's called
Automatic symmetry
Symmetry
Symmetry is that he has a sequence
Then you say that he is
Change
This is us
The most traditional
Ah
For matter
The most
Ah
One
This is the theory of the blue path
It should be
We have one
Just
There is one
This sequence
What about this sequence
What if he has it
He just has a sequence
That means he happened
A change
But like just now
Excuse me
Ah
Sorry
OK
That
Some things are not like this
Just
Ah
Um
Wait a minute
Will continue to talk
That
Later found
There is a change
Ah
The earliest
A Russian
He found out
He is a model
That later
Because he published
This story is probably like this
The article he published is
Written in Russian and then
Earlier than Kostelis and Solis
That later
No one knows that later Kostelis and Solis
They also counted
One thing and then found out
Ah
There is actually a change
But this model
He did not happen
They do
This model is like this
I just said that one by one
Right?
Each arrow is a word
That seems to be here
One of this amount
This amount is
It's not like that
It's just an amount
That is
It is
I will talk about the amount later
Here
This amount is
There is an xy amount
You are on the plane
Then there is an xy amount
Then you are on this
Every one on this scale
In this square
Square lattice
Each one has a
The corresponding amount
All
Do it
Just write a built-in interaction
That
Look at this model
He did not
Destroy
Rotational symmetry because
I just put it
I am in this
Z axis
For
If you turn, I just rotate
How many degrees
0 to 2拍
0 to 360 degrees
I just turn a little bit
Or turn a lot
Just turn a few degrees
Any angle
This model
This energy is unchanged
This does not change
So he has this
Continuous
This rotation symmetry
There was a theorem before
This theorem is called Mermin-Wagon theorem
If you only have
Corresponding interaction
Then yours
If you have continuous symmetry
Continuous symmetry
That
Below 2
Continuous symmetry
Will not occur
This is
This is his mathematical theorem
But
They found
Even if there is no
Continuous symmetry
It will not occur
Does not mean
It will not change
And this change
Just
This kind of change
Later we
It's called KT Transition
Or BKT Transition
How is he
At high temperature
Because it will not occur
Will not occur
So
As long as you have a limit
He will not
Not that continuous
For example, you
This energy is written like this
There is a symbol in front
If j is j is positive
That
If you have these two quantities
How to
Internal
Will
The answer will be lower
Internal is
Did you learn in high school?
Is
The length of this quantity
Multiply by the length of another quantity
Multiply
Cos theta
If cos theta is
If theta is 0
Cos is 1
If theta is 90 degrees
Positive
That this
Cos is 0
So
There is a symbol in front
So if the energy is relatively low
Of course every quantity
It's best to
The same
What if the opposite
You have the highest energy
The same energy is the lowest
That
So
But if the temperature is 0
That is
It is in
Ground state
The lowest state of energy
Of course it is
But as long as you have a little
Temperature as long as there is a little
Temperature
It won't be
All in the same direction
It is absolutely
Is not
No
Symmetry
That
No symmetry
But there is a change
What is the situation
That is
High temperature
A little
When there is a little temperature
That
These will not
These
These quantities will not be the same
That won't be the same
That can only be formed
Some called vortex
Is some whirlpool
That way
At a very high temperature
What about these vortex
No matter what temperature
These vortex
Because you have to
You must be
You have a vortex
Is
Turn like this
That
In fact, this
Let's make an example
Is that you have a
This vortex
There is another
Reverse vortex
That this
The positive vortex and the reverse vortex
At low temperature
Is two
Tied together
Is paired together
That's like this ship
Two ships are actually tied together
But if it's at high temperature
This one by one
Is every
Every vortex is free
This
This quantity
Main configuration
Run around
That way
This kind of change
It's called
KT transition
It does not destroy any
So there is no contradiction
Sorry
Is there a question?
That is
I remember when I was learning xy model
He said he was different
One is
How to put that thing
Connected to you
That
Um
That is to say
Correlation
Because
First of all
If there is no order
Its correlation length must be
Decay to zero
But
But the way to decay to zero
There are actually two
One is
Decay to zero very quickly
The other one is
Is
It's slow
Outflow decay
Um
I think I think this may be
Carefully pushed down to see
Its connection here
I don't think I can do it directly
In a very intuitive way
To see
This configuration
Uh in this place
Is exponential decay
The other place is power load decay
Um
If you have this feature
Type pair of voltage
You have to use math to show
For example, the amount of matter on the left and the right is different
Represents two phases
Is there anything like
Other parameters
For example
The method of decay is different
Two different phases
This place
Because you don't have
That kind
Order parameter
Um
My question is
Can you define something
For example, the left phase is zero
The right phase is one
So they are different
That's the order parameter
But here
Um
Here you can only count its
Here you should count its
Some decay
Um
This may
I have to look again to answer you
Ok thank you
No problem
You go ahead
I have to review this
Um
That
Of course he should be able to
Calculate one
Is the so-called
Unchanged
For example, this is
I forgot what the number is
Or what
This is the phase
Uh, as far as I know
The number is
There is such a
Decay
It's a
It will correspond to
It's the quantity or the effect
Different
That
I'm just curious about that
Is there anything like this
It's math
You can tell me very clearly
I don't understand this
I remember there is
But not
Because here is only
All are
Spin system
Then you go ahead
I will also study it later, thank you
I may
I can check it later
Tell you
That
Just here
Talked about
Uh
Different
A few boxes and wrong
If it's a few boxes
Uh
You will find
After a bite of apple
That his
His symmetry
Already
It's gone
His geometric shape has changed
But
His
Uh
What about the characteristics
Is unchanged
That's the same as this bagel
Uh
There is a hole
As long as
So this
What about this hole
If you keep it
Like I just said
Inside the equation
If that
Your conductance
With the one you calculated
Torpo
That amount
If it can correspond to
How many holes are you here
If there is a hole, two holes, three holes
Will correspond to you
Conductance is
There is a change in the whole number
Of course I can't find it
Two holes
If you find this
There are many holes in the answer
That's it
Um
Okay, I just said
I think
Maybe not very good
Um
What I'm going to talk about is
The anti-iron
Uh
Eisenberg model
First of all, these equations
Uh
The XY model just now
Is
Only
Which amount
Only x and y
And between this amount
It's just a number
That now
This
What about the amount of this equation
It's not just a number
What about them
Can't be exchanged
What about ax and y
For example, there is this
Is
xy
minus yx
Will equal
Is z
In this case, this is a
The model of quantum mechanics
That
His
This side
Is
If the inner machine is also
x times x
y times y z times z
What about this model
This if x is equal to
One-half
You can use
A mathematical technique called beta ansatz
Solve it
After that
Of course
There is another
This mathematical theorem
Is
Three people
That lsm
Three people's theorem
What about this theorem
He is using
Uh
You define one first
Another operator
Then put it in
Ground state
Then found
He and the original
Ground state is positive
Then found
This positive state
So this positive state
Uh
With ground state is positive
And his energy
To
When thermodynamics is limited
When n is equal to infinity
He and ground state
The energy is
The difference is equal to zero
For example
Of course here
Calculate directly with numerical
Ground state
This is the size
That size
What about this
Is
To find his
Is his
Parity is equal to
Positive or negative
Excited state
Then these two
To thermodynamics
Why do I say
Because there are some
Sometimes
When n is equal to
If n is equal to 4 times
That
10 is p
Equal to positive 1
That excited state is negative 1
But if
n is equal to
Is
Two
2 times
But not 4 times
That is the opposite
In short, there is a positive here
One is negative
One of the two is ground state
One is excited state
That's the end
When thermodynamics is limited
He will focus on this
This is just
That solution
That is to say
This theorem tells you
As long as you are
The number of times
These are the number of times
Is the number of times
Then he has no energy
That's how it works
That but
That
Correlation
Correlation is the power of decay
That guess
That is to say
The number of times
There is a gap in the system
The number of times is different
And correlation
Correlation is exponential decay
You can define
One
The length of the connection
that
What we know now
It is said
This equation equals to 1
What kind of nature does it have?
There is another model
Is spin equal to 1
But you add this
After adding this
You S equals 1
This model becomes
Strictly solvable
After you solve it, you will find that its ground state
It looks like this
This big circle
Is a spin 1 thing
The two dots in it
Is two
You look at it
This spin 1 is actually two
One-half spin
It can be one-half positive and one-half negative
So here it can be
Here it can be
One-half positive and one-half negative
Here it can be one-half positive and one-half negative
So there are a total of four possibilities
These four possibilities
But spin 1, it has
1, 0, negative 1, 3
Three possibilities
You find that
Two spins
One-half
Plus one-half
Is a spin 0 thing
That type
Is called
Singlet
The other three
Is spin equal to 1
That triplet
This circle is
This big circle is
These two spins
One-half
Translated into a
Spin triplet type
That
The blue stick is
This spin and the other spin
Form
Singlet
That way
After all this
If you are
This is the Open Boundary Condition
You find the most
One-half spin
He has no one
Can match him
So it will become a
Free
This
This state is out
You can see it here
He has one
Is the boundary
In this case, it will cause this side
This side can also
Up
Then you can also
The whole thing is
But
If you are
If you make a circle
With this spin
It will form Singlet again
The whole ground state is unique
There is no boundary
But if OBC, it is
Four-layer boundary
such
Um
What if you are
PBC
You can still calculate
Another thing
You put
A circle
A circle and then
Cut into two sides
One side is called A
The other side is called B
Then you
You put this ground state
Trace off the B part
Calculate his
Reduce Density Matrix
This Reduce Density Matrix
Assume it
If he is
One
Uh
Just like
Density Matrix
There is a temperature
You have one
Your Density Matrix should be exponential
Negative beta
H
But you
This H is not
A part
A part of Hamiltonian
That
This H does not know what
A part of Hamiltonian
Generally speaking, you will not just
After you finish
This is just the A part of Hamiltonian
So
The temperature in front
Beta is meaningless
Then put this
The temperature in front is absorbed
Absorbed into this Hamiltonian
Then put this Hamiltonian
Intangible Hamiltonian
What about this Hamiltonian
His
Eigenvalue
That is
This is called Intangible
Spectrum
Omega i is
If the Eigenvalue of rho a
Then you put it on both sides
If you take the log, you will find
I want to know
This Intangible Hamiltonian
Spectrum
That is
Do it like this
Then
You can find out
Because you did this trace
So if you are a circle
If a ring
You will have two
You will have two edges
Two edges
Is a
Your density matrix
Can be written as
This kind of product way
No matter what rho 0 is
Then your
Omega i
Must be
This must be
But if
If you are
What is used
Infinite chain
You don't care about this boundary
Very far away
Then
Then you cut it in the middle
Then go here
Then you will find
At least every word
Because you only cut one
Boundary
If
The first is another parameter
Will talk later
If
AKLT
1 out of 3
If you make it a parameter
Then
If you make it smaller
You will find this ground state
Will be
Adiabatic
Will connect
To this
Heisenberg model
Heisenberg
Model
Is probably
This kind of
Configuration
Then
Intangible
Because you have edge state
So in
Holden phase
If you cut an edge
You are
If you are
Periodic boundary condition
Then you will have
Four edges
If you are in this place
You didn't add
Symmetry
Z2Z this is
This is
The face of the antithesis
That this is
You are the same
There is no here
There is no O, there is no O here
Here
Of course there is O
Here and here
No O
There is no symmetry
Destroy any symmetry
But
But you can see here
Here you can have
Intangible spectrum
At least two-fold
Here
There is no need to
Two-fold
There is no
This is a coincidence
There will be a
But at least there is no
That this
Can be regarded as
He is
Topological face
One
One possibility
Probably like this
That
If you want to use
Intangible spectrum
Is it here
He has a topological
If the face
That is also a problem
Because we don't know yet
How to define
Intangible
That
Maybe i'm
After that, I'll take a look
That
Turn the book over again
Of course
Everyone knows that he took the Nobel Prize
He
Nobel Prize
Of course, Hoden and Kosterlitz
With Solace
The three of them got the Nobel Prize together
That they
Nobel official
Give them everyone
There is a certificate like this
That
Everyone's picture is different
Hoden's picture
Of course, Hoden has another contribution
Hoden's picture is a
This circle
This is a spin
That this stick
This stick is
A single
That
One like this
That aklt
One aklt
That
Material
Uh
But Hoden
Hoden's idea
After that
That
Soon that
Experiment
The material is made
Of course the material is three-dimensional
But this
Is that
It is spin one
Particle
The one next to it is green
Green particles
Green words like spin two
Green words are a
A
That
Through this green
For example, like spin two
This is a spin two
This particle
That through the middle of this green
He
His interaction will be through
Through this green
To reach
That
Super exchange
He might jump in the middle
Then jump over here
Then jump back
That will become
Like this Hamiltonian
Like this material
This
Along this c axis
Is a circle
This is also a circle
So there are a total of four here
Four circles
Inside the circle
Through this green
To reach this interaction
To reach this super exchange
Interaction
What about the different circles?
This one to this one
He's going to
If you want to form this interaction
He
At least
Through the middle of two
Green
To reach this interaction
In this case, it means
Say this J
The size of this J
This in the circle
The size will be much smaller
Much smaller
As if he did not
What about the first word?
Is called single ion
Anisotropy
This one
Here
Basically this one
If it's not too big
What about this circle?
Can be regarded as
Spin one
This material is regarded as
Then later
A lot of materials
Found and did
Anisotropy
Then
It proves that Houghton's guess is right
Spin two
But less
Then
For example, this material
Should
This should still be because
It may be difficult to make
Now
There should still be people doing it
There seems to be some
Dispute
But usually
This one
Is in the material
Will have
The main thing is this single ion
Anisotropy is like this
This is a low orbit
Five orbits
What about the low orbit?
dSyS square
Y square
dZ square
dSyDyz
dDyz
What about the top here?
This side is
You
At this top
Originally should be
Have that
Other
Other orbit
Other electrons
Put these
Are regarded as a dot
If
If there are no such dots
These five orbits are
The energy is the same
Is the same
But now you put this top
After putting it up
Then you will find this energy
There are two types
One type of EG
Is these three
These two
The energy is the same
These three
Because you see
The distance is the same
Just
Just rotate the angle a little
These three energies are the same
These three T2G energy are the same
These two are the same
What if
You
These two above
You are also in the middle
Up and down
Extend or shorten
Extend and shorten
You
This one
This one and this energy
Will be divided
It's different
This one
With
These two
The energy will be different
These two energies are still the same
If it is up and down
This one is different from these two
So
EG will be divided here
Assuming
Then these three
Will be divided
These two are the same
Then dxy
The energy is divided
These two are still short
How to
Let these two not be short
Is
This one
This one in the middle
This one with color
This is a square
This was originally a square
If this square
You
Because of some reasons
Become
Square or not square
Then you will further cause
These two
The energy is divided
Sorry
Wait a minute
Our recording may be
End in about ten minutes
How many videos do you have
Almost
Okay
Control
In the back
Some new results
Let's talk about the results first
We may not understand the results
I don't understand
Actually
I am still
Introduction
Introduce some
Because I think this is
Very popular recently
Not so many people understand
I think the introduction is very interesting
That
Let everyone know
I think we have to talk very well
Some of the previous questions
I don't understand
I understand part of it
Correct
I understand that I have done it myself
This part
That
Then I will speak faster here
If you are here
What about this distortion
This is
Spin orbital coupling
You will become
Similar
It will become like this
Like this
That way ax and ay az
Three parameters
These three parameters are with you
The size of these three parameters will be with you
How to split here
Will be related
What about these three
There are actually three parameters
In fact, there are only two parameters
If it is a square
It is equal to s times s plus 1
That is
You can push it down
This ha can finally be written
Like this
This is a parameter
This is also a parameter
s times s plus 1
s equals 1
s equals 1, then 1 times 1 plus 1 equals 2
So this is a parameter
Only this sz square
With ss square minus sy square
So this parameter has only two parameters
If you throw away those parameters
That single isomers
That you are the source of this parameter
You just follow you
Up and down here
If there is distortion
Then you will
If you are all
Then you will have this d
Isotropic
Then you are here
There is no d and 1
If you have this square
Becomes a rectangle or a ring
You will have this 1
That's it
So my previous work
The previous work is
Go
Use the numerical method
Such
Face diagram
To calculate his face diagram
Then go to see his
The nature of one state
The first is s
s equals 1
This
In the early
Someone has done it
Then I also
Teacher Yang
Some questions
Then put this place
This place is
The middle is the face
From here to the face
Nothing happens
Symmetry
Symmetry is not broken
That is to say this whole
Are all
That if
You are here
The earliest
The earliest classification of the face
You put that free energy
For external parameters
If the division is not continuous
You are the face
That is the face
Then later
After the symmetry theorem
You have those old parameters
You divide it into
You if
Your old parameters
Continuous
Is not continuous
That is not continuous
Then he is a face
If the old parameters are continuous
Then he is called continuous face
Then he belongs to the second stage
The above face
Is called continuous face
Or some people say
These are called the second stage face
But if you want to subdivide
Still can
At zero temperature
You divide the ground state
Then you see him
A few times
That
This one
What if
You go to see the first one
These two parameters
Let me talk about this face diagram first
This face diagram
From this red dot
From here to here
This red arrow
Because there is no
Any
Symmetry
Because if it is
If it is
The value of SZ can be
10-1
That 10-1
His square will become
10-1
So if D is very big
You don't look at the other lines
That is very big
That
If the energy wants to be lower
That must be SZ equal to zero
So it becomes
This large
The limit of D becomes
SZ equal to
Zero
That SZ is equal to zero
Of course there is no
No order
Because you have to see
All of you
SZ you can't measure
You don't have magnetization
That red dot is not here
So I
Actually I didn't say
I didn't say
He actually has a string order
That you put these materials
Go find people to do experiments
This material
It will be very close to here
It still falls
Very close to this critical point
That critical point
What if you have a little bit
You will enter another phase
That these two phases
I haven't found it before
So we think
If it is on this material
Add a little
Distortion
That is very likely to let
Enter
Not enter large
But enter
Y-face or X-face
That's it
Intangible spectrum
Also said
Here is
Self-reduction
First of all, here we do
A periodic boundary condition
Just one
A closed ring
What about this ring
This is the energy
The energy of the ground state is at the bottom
Then
The energy of the excited state
According to your different quantum number
Divided out
Of course this paragraph
Is the magnetization gap
Then when you add 1
This gap
But here
Not
But there is
Another kind of gap
What about this gap
So this place is the ground state
But it still has a gap
If you go here
He just
There is no reduction
It becomes
Sx equals 0
Product state
Not Sz equals 0
Sx equals 0
Intangible spectrum
You will see
Indeed in this place
There are four points here
This red
Then black triangle
Then black cross green
This is a quadruple reduction
Here is a symmetry breaking phase
It is a quadruple reduction
The origin of the quadruple reduction is because
This ground state is double
The ground state itself is double degeneracy
Then you have quantum number
Then it becomes
The ground state you choose
The ground state
Will be with these quantum numbers
That means it is
A certain
Add type
For example, it's all up down up down
Or add up up up
That's a bit like
That Schrodinger's cat type
Cat state
Will cause all
Intangible spectrum
Quadruple reduction
That can be used like this
Quadruple reduction here
Quadruple reduction
No reduction
Here is
Here is Hodian phase
Symmetry breaking phase
Here is trivial phase
Hodian phase is
Symmetry protected
Topological phase
I forgot to say here again
Correlation
Correlation is a more traditional way
Look at those order
I think the focus should be
Why
What is symmetry protected topological phase
Should be
I did not put this powerpoint
It's okay
That is to say
You this
This middle
This Hodian
If this phase
If you
If your Hamiltonian
You did not add
Other items
If you add an item
You keep
Symmetry
For example, this Hodian phase
It has three symmetries
To protect it
The first is
Is parity
Is mirror
Is reflection
Is left and right
Symmetry
The second is time reversal symmetry
Is time reversal
All spin
SxSySy
Take the sub-number
Two sub-numbers
Both sub-numbers will be removed
So
It has time reversal symmetry
The other is more difficult to see
Is Z2
Z2 symmetry
As long as you add
Other perturbation
If there is no destruction
If there are no three destructions
Then
Hodian phase will still exist
This is still
Unless your perturbation is strong enough
It will be destroyed
Just like you added this
D and 1
If you add D and 1
Did not destroy time reversal symmetry
Did not destroy parity
Did not destroy
Z2 symmetry
So
When D is big enough
There will be a
There will be symmetry
That
Correlation skip first
This is
Monumentality
Is to set
I take this amount to set
Critical point
But
What about the critical point just now?
If you are AKLT state
You can use
Twisted boundary condition
That twisted boundary condition
You will let
This side
This spin
This boundary becomes a triplet
If you are
If you have multiple spin 1
If you are in Hodian phase
There will be multiple singlet
Every singlet
Your parity is equal to negative 1
So you have multiple
It is equal to 1
That will be with large D phase
Can't tell
But if you are twisted boundary condition
That
You have multiple spin
You will have multiple singlet
This is a triplet
This triplet is parity equal to 1
This triplet is parity equal to negative 1
So this parity is equal to negative 1
This parity is equal to 1
You can do this level crossing
Is to put this 1 and negative 1
Do cross
That cross point
Just take it as your critical point
Then under the finite size
A critical point
Do finite size scaling
Finally you will get a very accurate
Critical critical point
That's it
Of course you can always use
Spin 2
Because spin 2
In 1992
Oshikawa
He is
I think it should
After you add this D
There may be middle
Middle phase
Not only from Hodian phase to large D phase
First spin 2
His Hodian
This isotropic
Heisenberg point
This phase is also here
This place is very small
That means his
He is very close to the critical point
His correlation length is actually quite long
There are about 60
In fact, if you put the whole image
If you get it out
In fact, this Hodian phase
With large D
This phase is connected
That is to say
Hodian phase
Trivial phase
Not
Topological phase
But you can still
Find one in the middle
Similar to
Intermediate D phase of spin 1
This is a topological phase
Because
This frame is mapped to spin
This frame is mapped to spin 2
And it is Sz equals 0
This is Sz equals 0
Spin 1
That looks like
AKLT state
That
Of course it is magnified
It can be seen
This
This is the way
That's the conclusion
Symmetry is actually
In physics
It's still a very important role
Because if you have symmetry
One is symmetry
Protective
There is another
In fact, you don't need symmetry
It has its own
Topological
That
It's not in 1D
That 1D
Can have
Must have
Symmetry
That
Um
1D spin system
I think there are still a lot of places to do
Um
That's about it
My speech
I think I didn't speak well
No, I think
Probably know the important
Where
From introduction
To the real result
Is
I feel a little bit
I don't know
The link in the middle
Where is it
And you can talk about it
Half an hour you should be very tired
Can I ask a question
Can
I have a question about that
That
That picture
What is your side
Is it
Or you later
If you want to see it here
It's a few lines of words
A method is
Ground state
Just fix a jz
And then
To ground state
To d
Energy
To this
So you're here
The group you gave later
Will also give the same
Is it
In principle
But this is a mistake
The problem
But if the three-dimensional change is a five-dimensional change
If it's a five-dimensional change
Not divided
Three-dimensional and five-dimensional
Because it can't be counted
Because
The number to be divided
In fact, it is to be divided
What about your two-dimensional division
You have to count three points
If you use central
Difference
Then you
One-dimensional division
Then you have to count two points
Do the difference
You have to count three points in two-dimensional division
You have to do this point in the middle
Take two more points
That three-dimensional point to take five points
And your error will become
The error of your two-dimensional division will become
You take the square of the interval
That you three-dimensional
Become
Three-dimensional or four-dimensional
That five-dimensional
So
The three-dimensional and five-dimensional
Take advantage of
Critical exponent
Scaling
Find it out
Someone still counts
This three-dimensional
Five-dimensional
But that's not divisible
We already know
It's not divisible
But there is no serious
Three-dimensional and five-dimensional
I don't think so
Because I
I wanted to do this problem
But you have to find time
The one behind
If you don't consider
The problem of accuracy
You just find a physical quantity
For example, quantum energy
See if he has
You can find out if there is a phase transition
It doesn't matter
For example, you can do that
You can also find out the phase transition
As long as the physical quantity
You can see the phase transition
The first one is in the one-dimensional system
Either there is a gap
Or there is no gap
If there is a gap
Then your volume
Entropy
There is an area
If there is no gap
Then your entropy will follow
Size log
That's what I wrote below
C is central charge
It is inferred from conformal field theory
It has a log
Here is one-third
Because I use
Periodic boundary condition
If there is some amount
There is no way
Detected
That phase transition
Before
Above
These
These two articles
Fidelity Susceptibility
Basically the concept is like this
I calculated
Choose a place
Then calculate the ground state
Then a little near
Calculate a little here
Then the next door is also a little
Two ground states
These two ground states are internal
If these two states
On the same phase
You will think you will
Expect
Its internal volume should be close to 1
If it happens
One ground state is here
The other ground state is in another phase
Then you will expect these two
Ground state
It should be much worse
If it is much worse
It is
Internal volume
It may be very small
Use this to detect
Is there a phase change here?
In this case
In
In this example
Two-stage phase change and three-stage phase change
Can be successful
But there is no way
Five-stage phase change
Especially here
The so-called phase change here
This is the so-called
BKT transition
BKT transition is actually
You don't have to
It will happen
That is to say
It will not happen
In this case
It is difficult to detect
The phase change of this place
But if
You use
You have gaps here
Then only here is no gap
Of course there is a gap
So if you want the whole
In this
For this phase diagram
You have to use monument entropy
To set the critical point
Only here is valid
If you are here
It will be difficult to find
Because there is an xy1 here
There is an xy1 here
There is also an xy2 here
These two are the gapless phase
What is this xy2
It is the kind of quadruple order
I didn't talk about
It should be like
Similar to this quadruple
This correlation
But these two are
Gapless
In monument entropy
All happened
Then you can't see it here
This is ferromagnetic
Ferromagnetic here is
One-phase phase change
I don't know how to use
So I don't know
Scaling here
What to do
Just in this case
This model
Selected
Actually, it's me
I calculated it first
How is it here
Then the last show is that picture
Every phase here
There is a gap
Only at these phase changes
These phase changes are gapless
In this case
Monument entropy
It looks more beautiful
Then you find this
Single place
This is the peak
That's the gap
Then you can do some finite size scaling
This is the finite size scaling
I don't know
Is this ok
Ok, thank you
Ok, today we probably
No special questions
Hello
I'm Ted
I just joined
Sorry
Today's speech is probably
It's over here
OK
Thank you
Very good
Then I'm going to
I'm going to stop the recording first
OK, thank you
Thank you