Welcome to the Terra Talks on September 8th.
Today's topic is Non-Verbal Applications of Hyperbolic Metamaterials.
We are honored to have Dr. Lin Hong-Yi, a Ph.D. student at NTU.
Let me briefly introduce Dr. Hong-Yi's background.
Dr. Hong-Yi is a Ph.D. student at NTU.
She is a non-verbal application of hyperbolic metamaterials.
She is a Ph.D. student at NTU.
Dr. Hong-Yi is a Ph.D. student at NTU.
First, let me introduce what metamaterials are.
You may have heard of metamaterials before.
Metamaterials are objects in the natural world, such as invisible corks.
Some people even use the concept of positive reflection.
The concept of positive reflection is based on permissibility.
Metamaterials are objects in the natural world, such as invisible corks.
The direction I made is called Hyperbody Metamaterial.
It is a Metamaterial, another one of the branches.
What is Hyperbody?
Hyperbody is the color curve.
The Metamaterial color curve is like this.
You can see, like this, double-curve.
Up and down, or it is left and right.
If you open up and down, it is Type I.
Type I like this.
The circle is basically a general material.
My Hyperbody Metamaterial is this up and down, Type I or Type II.
How to achieve the color curve of this Type I material?
There are some simple ways.
Basically, there are two components.
The first one is metal, and the second one is a catalyst.
Metal is a metal nanofiber in a dielectric environment.
This metal nanofiber needs a regular arrangement.
If it is random, its color curve distribution will not be so uniform.
The distribution of Hyperbody.
So, like this metal nanofiber, it can be like a metal nanorod.
Or a metal nanorod in a dielectric, like a polymer environment.
I have seen some people say that this is also the Hyperbody Metamaterial of Type I.
Another Type II Hyperbody Metamaterial is like this multi-layer film.
Multi-layer film is like a multi-layer film of metal and catalyst.
Convex structure.
Then it needs a lot of pairs.
About three or four pairs, five or six pairs or more.
Of course, I have seen some people do more than ten or twenty pairs.
In this case, the quality of the coating is very good.
Otherwise, the coating is not the distribution of Hyperbody Metamaterial.
Basically, HMM is called Hyperbody Metamaterial.
HMM has these two structures.
I often do this kind of multi-layer film.
Because this is very simple.
We use thermal to coat.
Then coat some metal film and catalyst film.
This is a cross-layer film.
There are other ways to achieve this kind of multi-layer structure.
I will also introduce this thing in addition today.
What are the benefits of this HMM?
What are the features?
You can see that this is its Wave Vector.
So it will have a lot of Wave Vector Modes in it.
What are the benefits of having a Wave Vector Mode?
The biggest benefit is that its Density of State is very large.
You can take a look at the Fermi's Golden Rule.
I'll just mention it a little bit.
Fermi's Golden Rule's Transition Rate is proportional to my Density of State.
The Density of State is also proportional to my Wave Vector.
So my Wave Vector Mode is very high.
My Density of State is large.
If the Density of State is large, it means that my Transition Rate is high.
What does Transition Rate mean?
You can take a look at it.
It's like if my PO is a fluorescent molecule.
It can make my radiation more.
So if a fluorescent molecule is placed on top of my HMM, it will radiate more.
Because it's in my Excited State.
Jump to Ground State.
It can store more energy.
So what it means is that it consumes less radiation.
Because it stores more radiation.
Basically, we put some fluorescent molecules or fuels.
There will be a stronger trend on this HMM base.
Let's compare HMM with other materials.
What is the concept of HMM and other materials?
Usually, we have some diagrams.
For example, SL2 or TL2.
Its radiation curve is a very regular linear radiation curve.
Its Isofrequence Surface is like what you just saw.
It's a circle.
Its Density of State is like this.
It's not so much.
You can see this picture.
The phenomenon of Metal Directory is like...
This base is the Directory.
I may have some metal nanoparticles on it.
You may have seen the enhancement of POSMONICS.
It's like I have some metal particles on TL2 or SL2.
Gold particles or silver particles.
It's because the interface of metal and solid electrons will have a very strong local field.
This local field is called Surface POSMON Polariton.
This Surface POSMON can only be activated at a certain ray light and frequency.
So, like this metal or solid electrons.
Enhancement behavior on these large electrons.
This is what we call Surface POSMON Polariton Enhancement.
The one on the far right is Metal Nanoparticle.
This is a metal nanoparticle.
There will be different field enhancement behaviors after the light hits.
But this kind of field enhancement behavior also has a certain frequency.
Or a certain direction can trigger more energy.
So this kind of enhancement behavior is also a kind of separation.
It's not a very broadband enhancement.
The reason why I chose HMM is like this.
The third column is because HMM has a lot of Density of State.
Then different angles can also trigger different modalities.
So it can make my luminous molecules above.
Or other materials or dyes.
It hits the PL enhancement.
PL is Photoluminescence Enhancement.
Or hit the laser enhancement.
All have a certain effect.
I will also introduce you a little bit in the following video.
This is the basic concept of material.
I listed a little bit about what HMM has to do.
HMM has a High Wave Vector Mode.
So the light that comes into the factory can be transmitted to the original factory.
Instead of the electromagnetic wave.
Instead of the evanescence field disappear.
So HMM's early application is to do this.
Far Field Image.
For example, the light that comes into the factory can be transmitted to the original factory.
Not like ordinary metal or other materials.
Decay at the front.
Because the light can be transmitted in this multi-layer film.
So some people used to do waveguide.
I have seen some people do some patterns on the multi-layer film.
Then the pattern is retained.
This is IN and this is OUT.
Can be used as a biosensor.
Then they put some detectors.
Then use the form of light.
Can measure the change of different penetrations.
Then come to a biosensor.
This is published on Natural Material.
Then there are people who use simulation to calculate.
This kind of ring multi-layer film.
It can be INVISIBLE COAT.
For example, the things inside me can be covered.
So I come in from here.
My scattering things go out from here.
The electromagnetic wave will not be affected at all.
So some people use this concept to do INVISIBLE COAT.
But this concept is only at a certain frequency.
May be at a certain frequency.
Can achieve this INVISIBLE COAT behavior.
That may not work in a broadband.
So this is just a simulation result.
I have seen some people use this to say.
This kind of HM energy can be transmitted inside.
So some people say this kind of HM structure.
Like this is a multi-layer film structure.
Then this is the NETWORK.
Plugged in the Type-1 structure.
It is said that it can be used as a light communication behavior.
Because the energy can be transmitted inside.
So they say this.
Maybe this can be used in the future.
Is an optical transmission behavior.
Let's look at the top here.
The top here is this year.
Cai Dingming Laboratory published on Advanced Material.
They use Pattern HM structure.
This is a multi-layer film structure.
Then use FOX-3B to make Pattern.
You can see this kind of tofu-like structure.
Then the top is Multicorner Well.
Then I use a short-wave 266 pumping laser to fight.
Then there will be a long-wave 289.
A long-wave 289 laser comes out.
That 289 is a Deep UV.
So this thing is 266 Pump.
Then 289 Lacing is a Deep UV laser.
The width is only about 2-3 nm.
The result of this HM Pattern.
It can also be regarded as an enhanced behavior of LED.
This is published on Nano Energy.
It was also published by Cai Dingming Laboratory this year.
Because this HM has a large Density of State.
So it can enhance this Light Matter Interaction.
So it can reach the enhancement of laser or LED.
In the early days, there were only two PL enhancements.
PL enhancement is...
This is published on the Nature Nano Technology Shop in 2014.
For example, I patterned a multi-layer film structure.
Then the top is mixed with some dye.
Like R6G or PMMA.
Because the concept of PL enhancement is spontaneous radiation.
Spontaneous Emission.
This year is to achieve Stimulant Emission.
This is published by Cai Dingming Laboratory.
Because of its high purity rate.
So this pattern structure, multi-layer film structure.
I saw someone use it as a color film emitter.
Basically, this is the application of HM.
It's quite a wide range.
It's not just a simple theoretical application.
So now, in addition to doing Biosensor and Laser.
And PL enhancement.
Now more and more people.
Will also use this HM to do different applications.
So now I see that the main thing is to publish this trend.
How to design a good HM?
Usually HM is with me.
Because my HM multi-layer structure.
It's about the thickness of my metal and solder.
First of all, let's take a look at what Feofixion is.
Feofixion is the thickness of metal.
The thickness of metal is the thickness of metal and solder.
This is the thickness of a pair.
So different Feofixion.
In different wavelengths, this is the wavelength.
What you see is different.
This is the fun part of HM.
If it's like this one, for example.
Feofixion is at 0.5.
Its short wavelength is Type 1.
Type 1 is the color curve is up and down.
Type 2 is left and right.
If Feofixion is a little less.
Because Feofixion is less.
It means that the metal component is less.
The metal component is less.
Overall, what it sees is a capacitance.
So it's not HM.
It's elliptical metameter.
Elliptical is elliptical.
It's like the general kind of material.
We call it EMF.
If the metal component is more.
It's a metal material compared to it.
Not HM.
So it's also a type of EMF.
Does EMF have a lot of difference in optical measurement?
Sometimes it's a few times worse.
This is ACS Photonics.
In 2007, it also measured some of Peo's enhancements.
It also put the fuel molecule.
On my multi-layer HM board.
You can see that on the HM board.
Its enhancement is quite strong.
It can be more than 1,000.
If it's on EMF, it's about 400.
So if it's the same multi-layer HM board.
But my metal and fuel molecule thickness ratio is wrong.
The behavior of my enhancement is much worse.
This type of EMF will also enhance.
The reason it will also enhance.
Because it may be the enhancement of effective metal.
That is to say, at least my board will reflect a little.
So it will also enhance a little.
But it's not as much as HM.
This is 2012's Photoscience.
EMF will have a longer lifetime.
HM will have a shorter lifetime.
For a fluorescent molecule.
The longer the lifetime, the longer it will stay in the activation state.
It will jump out.
It will jump to the ground state for a longer time.
For example, if it jumps to the ground state for a longer time.
It means it may be damaged by some other heat energy.
So if I want to enhance PO.
The shorter my lifetime, the better.
That is to say, the shorter it stays in the activation state, the better.
Then it can achieve a lot of PO enhancement purposes.
So when we look at this kind of light-metal interaction.
We all look at the first PO.
Is it enhanced?
Second, does it have a shorter lifetime?
That is usually the EMF's lifetime will be longer.
Then its PO will be less.
This is the basic concept of light-metal interaction.
I'm here with Mr. Chen Yongfang.
Mainly do something called random laser.
Let me mention a little bit about what random is.
Sorry, I have a question.
I guess you're going to talk more specifically about your lab.
So I want to ask a more out-of-the-box question.
Because I don't make materials.
Basically, from the point of view of electronics.
Now the focus of metal materials is on.
For example, you are now showing these hundreds of nanometers of wavelength.
Because basically you have to have a wavelength.
Far greater than a field, a pair, right?
So you are equal to the unequality of the material.
Then it becomes that you can adjust it.
Then let the light see an average effect.
If I want to operate today.
For example, if it is a wave, I can.
For example, a layer is 100 nanometers.
Then pass two or three layers.
Will it have the same effect of metal material?
I have seen this kind of thing at the beginning.
Their thickness is very thick.
You can see it with your eyes.
This kind of multi-layer film.
Unlike our film is more than 10, 20, 30 nanometers.
Unless you have seen, for example, sub-micron.
100 nanometers or something.
Yes, I have seen a very thick one.
Then it may not be the way to grind.
Because the grinding may be 1-2 nanometers at a time.
Because they are all 1-second ENSO.
1 ENSO is 0.1 nanometer.
If I want to do 1000 nanometers.
Then you have to do a lot of pairs.
That is to be very high-strength.
Of course, I have seen someone like Weibo or Terahertz.
Use the same concept to explain.
Then it will also have an effect.
Also have.
Because it was in the early stage.
Such a long wave.
Now everyone is more interested in visible light.
The structure of visible light multi-layer film is very small.
OK.
So there is still such a feature.
I have a second question.
The second question is.
Your metal is basically operating at a constant temperature.
So its skin depth is basically 1 over the square root of the wavelength.
That's right.
If today.
For example, the metal you grind up.
It will become a super conductor at a very low temperature.
That super conductor.
Its skin depth is 1 over the length.
Not.
Wait a minute.
1 over the wavelength.
Anyway, it will not be the same.
But it will have the same effect.
If I want to operate at a very low temperature.
There will also be the effect of metamaterial.
I haven't seen this yet.
But because.
This may also be a good research direction.
Right.
Measure at a very low temperature.
See what will happen.
I guess.
It will be different in terms of brightness.
But it should still have some effect in terms of straightness.
Because it is basically a skin depth.
Here.
Not sure.
Because standing at such a low temperature.
The concept of super conductor.
I remember this HMM.
I don't think I've done this yet.
Because it may be limited to experiments.
I guess this low temperature is also the kind of ethyl chloride.
Very low, very low temperature.
I guess.
OK.
I haven't seen this yet.
But I guess it should be a good topic.
OK.
Basically, this is the concept of my HMM.
Then I will skip a little bit.
Another topic is.
Random laser.
What is random laser?
Then we first introduce.
What is a general laser?
General laser.
I need a fixed rectifier.
Then my quality.
The quality must be very good.
It's a game medium.
In a.
A.
In a rectifier.
Then when I pass the light inside.
Back and forth.
The round trip.
Uh.
Propagate.
When the gain is greater than the loss.
Will be from a certain direction.
Specific frequency.
Then.
Lacing out.
Then this is the general concept of laser.
It can be applied to a lot of things like a laser pen.
Visography.
Cutting.
And light.
A lot of surgery.
This kind of.
Behavior.
On the application.
This is the general concept of laser.
What is it called?
I am now mainly.
Focus on.
HM.
Combined.
The concept of random laser.
What is that random laser?
Random laser.
Also want this kind of game medium.
Like ZMO.
This.
Very irregular.
Uh.
Nanoparticle.
In this.
That.
In this environment.
Then when I am very focused.
Very.
Uh.
Hit me this.
On top of the game medium.
It will be here.
A process of multiple scattering.
Just like this.
That is.
Multiple scattering.
When it comes to this kind of game.
When it's bigger than Rose.
It will also be.
Very.
Very wide.
To reach a type.
The level of laser.
That kind of laser.
Uh.
Because it's this kind of random laser.
So it's light.
Will be inside.
Scattering everywhere.
So the direction it comes out.
Is.
Uh.
We call it both.
Angular.
Or.
Angle free.
This kind of emission.
Unlike general laser.
Only in a specific direction.
Will come out.
So he.
We are this kind of random laser.
It's a different angle.
Can be lighted up.
This kind of laser signal.
So it's a little bit like the general laser.
Not the same.
That's it.
Uh.
General laser.
With random laser.
Concept.
That.
What.
Mechanism.
The random laser.
Is.
It's just like I just said.
It's me.
A pump laser.
And then.
Hit me this.
On top of the game medium.
Then.
When it's bigger than Rose.
So.
There will be a laser effect.
Come out.
That.
We will say.
This is called.
Cross loop.
And then.
Represents its light.
In some places.
The game medium.
Will.
Be very strong.
So he.
The probability of getting bigger than Rose.
Will be greater.
So he.
Can be received from different angles.
That.
We usually discuss with randomness.
When.
We will discuss.
Say he's a.
Scattering.
One thing.
That.
Random laser.
Signal.
That.
Random laser.
Signal.
Probably like this.
This is me.
Peel.
I.
Generally.
If it's like.
I.
I hit it with a laser.
Will get a peel.
A bag.
A bag of peel.
Signal.
That.
When I'm strengthening my power.
I will get.
Amplify.
Spontaneous emission.
It's like this green thing.
That.
I'm strengthening my power.
I will get this.
Random laser.
Peak.
This is a typical.
Random laser.
Peak.
It's like this.
The peak I measured with the next second.
It's a little bit different.
Because he.
The last second and the next second.
Light in there.
Scattering everywhere.
The process is different.
That.
Not all.
The material.
Will hit this.
Random laser.
That.
Need.
Like my material.
Need to have a certain.
Scattering things.
Or scattering.
He will hit this.
Random laser.
The.
Peak out.
That.
The advantage of random laser.
Is that I measure different angles.
You can take a look.
I might be 30 degrees.
Or 45 degrees.
Or 60 degrees.
Different angles of light.
I can get this.
Random laser.
Peak.
Out.
That.
This kind of random laser.
He has his own.
Advantage.
If applied to this kind of lighting.
He is from different angles.
You can have this.
Very strong signal.
And.
Uh.
And he's a very.
Wide-angle behavior.
That's it.
Uh.
Typical.
Random laser.
A feature.
He's a board.
Angle.
Uh.
Emission.
That.
My first.
The first thing I do is.
Here is the combination of the teacher.
HMM.
The board.
There's this mess on it.
This kind of.
Uh.
Zin-R-Side.
Nanoparticle.
His size is very irregular.
It's maybe 50 nanometers.
To.
Maybe.
Two or three hundred nanometers.
There are.
So I use the green light.
If.
I'm going to be in my.
This.
ZMO nanoparticle.
A scattering process.
Then.
Will be different angles.
Uh.
Random laser.
Out.
That.
You can.
Right.
I've seen it before.
The first one.
Uh.
Cai Liming.
It's already been used.
Uh.
Payton.
HMM.
Stemming emission.
He's a single.
That.
I'm using this.
Uh.
ZMO nanoparticle.
On the HMM board.
To achieve a random laser.
Behavior.
That.
This is what I compared.
Different.
HMM sample.
There's my EMA sample.
And my reference.
Reference is.
Control.
Simple.
That's ZMO nanoparticle.
On the general.
Silicon.
That's his original.
ZMO nanoparticle.
He's going to have some.
Random laser.
Peak.
That's what I want.
Uh.
Intensity.
It's going to be a little bit bigger.
He's going to have.
That.
Power.
A little bit.
He's just a general PL signal.
That.
If I zoom in here.
He's just a general PL signal.
That.
EMA sample.
Uh.
I designed this work.
Two.
Different.
Multi-layer model ratio.
One is.
He's in this.
HMM.
The other one is.
He's in this.
EMF.
You can also.
You can see that he's in this.
When this wave section.
His brilliance.
Stronger is a bit weaker.
But he was in hours.
Of this.
amp Wave.
Of the word.
Of his.
Scare him.
Lazys effect.
Is very powerful.
You can see this.
There's a lot of it.
This kind of prickles.
Speak.
The signal.
That is.
La RES一樣不好就是也不重要
It's like this one.
That.
I'm in this design.
At.
AM.
This is just to.
Task.
I'm on this side.
It's at 45 degrees.
Uh.
Angle on both sides.
That.
You can see this intensity.
With.
Uh.
Power density is.
Speak.
At.
AndPlayback.
If it is probably, it doesn't matter.
Uh.
Speaker.
What's going on?
The force should not be heavy.
Once under massage together.
I don't want to fall every time.
Uh.
Come on those days.
Power use guy.
That's all I'm saying wait.
Don't get that.
Just lazer.
Speak.
Scientist.
What's on Picachin night?
That doesn't sound like it's working.
There's my alligator.
And that's how deep it is.
That data is.
You can see that I'm usually different.
That.
I'm different.
Power.
Uh.
In the measurement test, my HM machine board.
He's two.
It.
The enhancement is stronger than the men and the reference.
That we can even see an additional.
What are you looking at?
There will even be a.
The phenomenon of a child on the HMS board.
That I'm a little bit.
I'm going to use a little bit of simulation to explain why this thing is there.
That.
We have different angles of measurement.
Maybe this is the color of the road.
The angle of the road is 30 degrees.
The other one is 60 degrees.
That's basically what my HMS is.
Enhancement will be stronger than others.
That's what this is.
Because it's a random laser.
So I measured it in the last second.
Emission stability.
It's going to be a distribution of the curve.
In other words, HMS.
He may be from more than 800 to about 1100.
That.
We measured it several times.
It's probably a.
It's kind of a stable.
That.
So, on behalf of me, this random laser.
This one.
Zero nanoparticle.
And my whole material.
He won't because.
Uh, the longer it takes.
Uh, uh.
So his, uh, intensity will drop.
So it's basically a very stable emission process.
That's what I'm going to do with a little bit of power.
The laser to measure.
He's going to have a P.O. signal.
That's why I'm going to use the stronger power to measure.
He's going to have a random laser.
You can see his.
Uh, I'm going to measure it with a 3G4 laser.
His.
Well, the energy is.
More than 100 millijoules.
That's what I'm looking for.
The energy is used.
More than 20 millijoules.
Oh, I'm sorry.
This is more than 100 microjoules.
This is more than 20 millijoules.
So he's a very large number.
So I'm going to have to be stronger.
I'm going to be able to get a random laser signal.
So this is the behavior of measuring my life.
So you can see that my HM machine.
My life is probably more than 2 nanoseconds.
That's going to be shorter than my EMM.
The shorter the life.
His.
Uh, uh.
Uh.
That's going to be bigger.
The resolution Ray will be bigger.
That's the shortest I can get.
It's easier to get a random laser behavior.
So this is my FD numerical FDD.
A little run simulation.
This is my input signal.
I can take a look at my.
This is where I put a ZN or NaN particle.
This is my HM machine.
Let's take a look at how he affects the overall.
Uh, what's the effect of the barfield?
You can see my HM machine.
In this area, there is a relatively strong.
A strong barfield.
That's a little bit weaker.
This is what I'm doing.
After a normalization.
So you can see it clearly.
If it's a real machine.
My ray beam will go under me.
That's my HM machine.
He's going to my positive.
A very strong scattering phenomenon.
So this is a very strong scattering phenomenon.
It will also be conducive to my.
A random laser behavior.
So this is the continuation of the simulation.
This is my original distribution map.
So you can see my.
0 to 180 is my positive.
180 to 360 is.
Go down.
So you can see my HM machine.
He's a lot more.
It's going to my original direction.
Positive direction.
It's ZMO.
It's going to ZMO.
So it's going to help me.
One of the ZMO.
Uh, the scattering process.
So this is me.
I ran some simulations from different angles.
So you can see my.
Red is HM.
The red HM.
It's basically stronger than the green EMM.
Scattering is even stronger.
The blue is my reference board.
So I.
Because random laser.
It's a scattering process.
So I did some math.
Scattering efficiency.
So first of all, I.
I put a ZMO nanoparticle first.
It may be a 40 nanometer radius.
The height is 100 nanometers.
Put it on my different HM board.
Or EMM board.
Or reference board.
You can see my HM board.
His scattering efficiency.
It's going to be a lot higher than my EMM.
It's going to be a lot higher.
And my HM board.
He's in.
Especially in the 389 long-wave field.
This one will be more.
So.
I jumped back here to explain.
Here.
I have more long-wave fields.
So.
I was thinking about this thing.
In addition, there will be a phenomenon of redness.
It's because my HM is on the long-wave field.
It's stronger.
Scattering is more likely to result in.
Of course I.
I have a simulation.
ZMO nanoparticle.
If it's round.
He's on different boards.
His scattering.
The effect is probably like this.
Of course.
With this ZMO nanoparticle.
It's hexagonal.
It's a little bit like that.
It's just that the real situation is different.
So this is my.
The distribution of the scattering curve of this HM.
So you can see.
I have this.
ZMO nanoparticle.
The lacing place is probably in this area.
Then I.
I'm on this HM board.
I'm set to be 300.
After 375 nanometers.
It's a.
Hyperbody dispersion curve.
So this kind of thing.
He will be in.
So my multi-layered board.
He can be in my ZMO nanoparticle.
Lacing time.
There will be.
There will be a stronger lacing effect.
Then I.
In addition, I ran some more.
Like Persil Factor.
Persil Factor is.
The value of Persil Factor is.
I have this thing with me.
I have this dipole.
When ZMO shines.
In this environment.
With me in FreeSpace.
FreeSpace.
It's when you don't have this board.
To get along.
Made a pen.
Then you can see my HM.
Especially in the long wave field.
38.
The place of 390 will be longer.
That's with my EMM.
It's going to be a little bit weaker in this place.
In fact, this.
This multi-layered strengthening concept.
He is a.
An action of exponential decay.
The black line is HMM.
That red is EMM.
That.
If it's blue, it's Riffen.
It's a line lying on the ground.
Then you can see.
In fact, this kind of strengthening.
You can see that this is.
Uh.
Within 50 nanometers.
It's probably.
Uh.
For HMM.
It's about four times.
That's EMM.
EMM.
It's about twice.
That.
But if I put this whole thing together.
It's an average.
For HMM.
HMM.
The proportion of enhanced.
Can be up to.
More than 30 times.
But because he.
Enter the field.
The main.
The most enhanced contribution is still in the field.
That.
The original factory is about 50 nanometers.
In terms of words.
It's about four times.
But the previous few nanometers.
It's very, very, very strong.
That I have calculated.
Denser loop state.
That his.
The density.
Will be.
In terms of HMM.
His density.
It's higher than EMM.
So he.
Can reach the optiogame.
Will be more.
That I have calculated.
His decay rate.
Decay rate.
In contrast to.
Lifetime.
So my lifetime is shorter.
My decay rate is higher.
This means he's in.
Excited state.
Jump down.
Time.
Faster.
That's what decay rate means.
So.
That I have run for a while.
For a while.
That's what I'm getting at.
It's.
It's relatively new.
That's what EMM does.
And that's what we're talking about.
It's bigger.
More about.
With.
VVV is the power factor.
There.
The power main quantity is coming.
Uh.
If it's bigger.
Good for him.
The space was getting smaller.
Well.
Power machine causes.
In other words.
The greater the power of the largest power plant.
The meaning is.
I.
My light can be very strong.
Localize in my.
HMM.
Near the zeo nanoparticle.
It's not like EMM.
Or reference board.
It's harder to get my light.
Uh.
In the local unit area.
It's going to be stronger.
So.
The less I touch you.
The smaller.
The stronger I get.
Because the smaller the touch.
The bigger my Perseverance is.
So this is also a.
It's also a concept that can be explained to each other.
Uh.
Then I.
This thing.
The following.
Is.
I can look at me.
I looked at my TV.
In my EMM.
On top of my HMM.
It's going to be a little longer.
And the strength of the resonance is going to be longer.
This is after I've normalized it.
So you can see a clear comparison.
That's what it is.
It's gone in a second.
EMM.
It's also going to be a resonance.
But it's gone in a second.
This time scale is.
The level of Phenosecond.
And then HMM.
Its resonance strength.
Of course, it's going to be better than the other.
Uh.
The other two are basically stronger.
This is.
One of mine.
The first work in the PhD class.
It's the concept of Random Laser Combined HMM.
That was accepted by ACS Photon at the end of last year.
That's what we saw this year.
So if you're interested.
You can take a look at this one.
And the above.
The above data are all in.
On this work.
So this is my.
The first work of the PhD class.
So I'm the first one.
It's the first one.
Combine HMM and Random Laser.
Concept.
And then to achieve a.
Lacing enhanced.
Random Lacing enhanced behavior.
So let me just sum up my work.
So my work is a little bit.
It's a little bit new.
Because he's.
We're using the first one to use HMM.
Random Laser Concept.
Then we'll think it's interesting.
It's because we can enhance.
Random Laser Peak.
And then our measurement came out.
Lifetime is short again.
Then we'll think this is a very.
A very useful concept.
Because we can.
Reduce the Lacing demand.
And then this.
Concept.
This Random Laser is a board.
Angular emission.
Just like me.
This is what I showed you a long time ago.
The work.
Well, basically, this is my PhD.
The first one.
I.
Combine HMM and Random Laser.
So I'm going to give you a little bit of an introduction.
We have other in our lab.
Random Laser.
In this year.
The article published.
So this is a few months ago.
In.
It should be last month.
Or the last month.
Advanced Optical Material.
Accept.
It looks like.
Work.
He's a.
One of our labs.
After a PhD.
That's what he's doing now.
Change to two teachers.
Two labs to continue.
Continue to finish this work.
That's it.
Finished.
Published.
That's his concept.
It's also very simple.
That is.
They are using PurpleSky.
And then use the combined.
Graphene Nanowall.
And then sprinkle some.
Like silver granite.
As a scattering.
So why do this?
The graphene that stands up.
It's because of my light.
It's even more scattering inside.
It's a three-dimensional structure.
And then you can get to.
A very low level of laser.
So you can see.
This is in.
Nanogel.
You can even get to the laser.
Because I'm using the graphene that stands up.
The concept of three-dimensional.
Random Laser.
So you can see.
This is a lot of peaks.
This is a.
This is some random CIs this year.
Random Laser Peaks.
What about last month?
This is a covered paper.
Then this is another one we have in the laboratory.
This is another one we have in the laboratory.
An article recently published.
This article was taken last year.
Last year the end was accepted to publish
In scientiFLEport.
This article is also a very simple concept.
We put three RGBs.
Different materials.
And then the laser meets in the middle.
So it will hit a white laser.
Then I put down the YouTube video.
What is the situation when measuring?
So when the RED light hits
The middle piece will hit a white light.
Random Laser Peak.
Put another one.
So it's like this.
The middle is white light.
If the focus is here.
It's green and blue mixed out.
It's red and green mixed out.
What is the selling point of this concept?
If I want to make a lot of pixel.
Overall, it's a white light.
Random laser.
Then we just mix the demo RGB first.
Mixed into this shape.
Then hit the middle.
It is also a white light signal.
This is the laser peak on both sides.
If I turn on the power,
Of course, my RGB peaks will be displayed.
If we mix out the CIE image.
You can see that it is very, very close to the white light.
This one is also a good one.
In fact, I have another topic for today's report.
This is my HMM.
To combine the concept of up-switching.
In fact, because I will introduce first.
What is the concept of up-switching?
The concept of up-switching energy is.
My YB nanoparticle.
It may have a lot of different chemical elements.
Like my YB.
To absorb the long-wave field.
Like 980.
We usually use 980 or 8080.
We usually use 980.
So after YB absorbs 980.
It will give the energy to other materials.
The other materials are absorbed several times.
After YB gives the long-wave field energy.
It will jump out in a relatively short-wave form.
Because the short-wave field is more powerful.
The long-wave field is less energy.
So this energy transfer process is called up-switching.
Because in general.
The PL or type on both sides are down-switching.
Down-switching is that I give a short-wave field.
The short-wave field means that the energy is more powerful.
The short-wave field is like 266 laser.
Hit my ZMO.
It releases 388.
About 388.
The up-switching is.
Hit 980 and put the visible light.
4500, 300 can be.
It depends on the ratio of my friction.
Basically, the up-switching nanoparticle is.
Different friction ratios.
I just hit 980.
Of course, this is the paper of others.
Just hit 980.
I can see different colors.
The signal of different colors comes out.
So this up-switching nanoparticle.
Everyone is.
It will look like this.
These are all TM photos.
Between different layers.
Because I need different.
A distinction between different elements.
So if you synthesize different dyes.
I need to connect with different ligands.
So that my different elements.
It will be very close together.
Basically, this is a concept of up-switching.
This is the light of 980.
Put visible light.
In fact, my work.
The work I focused on today is also this one.
But because of this work.
This work is still under review.
In ACS content.
I am a co-author with an Indian doctor.
In fact, I thought this work.
Can be accepted in my report today.
But now it's the second time.
So wait a minute.
Because our first reviewer.
There are four reviewers on the first floor.
Later on the first floor.
When we revised.
The editor sent it to reviewer 4.
Reviewer 4.
He said we answered all the questions.
But he suggested that we turn to Advanced Material.
So the editor is looking for the fifth reviewer.
We are now replying to the fifth reviewer's questions.
So wait for it to be accepted later.
I'll show it to you again.
Basically, this work is still under review in ACS content.
In fact, the concept of this work is very simple.
So I didn't show my Lacing Peak today.
Then I'll talk a little bit about it.
How did I do this work?
Also, I need a multi-layer model.
Then put on top of it.
Upgraded Nanoparticle.
Then the upgraded Nanoparticle.
He himself has to have RGB light.
Then we actually want this work.
I want to get a white laser thing out.
Then we actually have three designs.
HM board.
Put it in the same way.
Upgraded material.
That simple upgrade.
He would have his own RGB light.
But he would be more blue light here.
For example, blue light and red light here.
If I want to hit the white light.
I need to go up.
I need a little bit more green.
Then I designed different boards.
The closest to the HM1 board.
HM1 is already very, very close.
This 0.333 0.333 place.
Because 0.333 0.333 is a pure white place.
Because it hasn't been accepted yet today.
So I didn't show the data.
The upgrade mechanism is the same as mine.
As I said in the last video.
I need a YB.
Need different.
Can put out RGB.
These three kinds of dye.
This kind of material.
Then my upgrade is to ask.
Taiwan Chemicals.
YT-TEN laboratory cooperation.
That is also looking for a doctor in India.
Chen Yichong laboratory.
Then there are ER, TM, and EU.
All three will put RGB.
It's hard to get a white light through synthesis.
It's hard because this kind of jumping process.
It's all a nonlinear.
Assuming that my green light is already weaker.
I want to enhance my green light behavior.
Once I can enhance my green light.
I may eat other light.
A thing that eats other light.
That synthesis is also not an easy thing.
But as long as we use this kind of HM1.
This kind of basic enhancement.
It can be very, very close to white light.
That kind of HM1.
You can see that this is my Perseverance simulation.
HM1, then there will be more places to enhance the green light.
Compared with other HM2 or HM3 places.
So I combine this top conversion.
And HM.
I can make my green light stronger.
Then it's very, very close to white light.
This is my other work.
With an Indian.
Now in ACS Neo.
I'll have a chance to show it to you later.
But I want to say.
Since it's not convenient to show too much information to everyone.
I'll show you another one.
This is a topic that the doctoral class has already published.
In fact, this is also last summer.
At this time.
With a student in the math class.
The topic that came to mind in Xiaofu.
Because the math class is mainly to do.
Tension.
This kind of flexible thing.
The photo detector.
Tension.
There is also a flexible photo detector.
On the base of Kerala.
Then I was wondering if I could use this concept.
To do my one.
This is the concept of the novel HM.
This HM.
I did it last summer.
I did it for two or three months.
Then I wrote it.
Then I went to the scientific report.
Do you still remember?
This is my HM.
I need a metal and a lithium-ion base.
A multi-layer.
This is very simple for me.
I use gold and PVA.
As a base.
HM's base.
My PVA.
It's also a polymer.
Its detection rate is 1.5.
Like.
Just like the general material.
That's just the advantage of PVA.
It is durable.
The first one.
It can be melted.
For example, if it is put in water.
It will melt.
So we want to say.
Can you do a tension.
There is also a flexible HM.
That's it.
This is what I have done.
Materials.
I do four pairs.
Because in fact, every pair.
I need to grind once.
Then break the cavity.
Spin coating again.
So in fact.
After a lot of pairs.
This material is not easy to do.
This is the material I just finished.
Put it in the water.
Then after 1.5 hours.
It's gone.
So I.
Tension HM.
This thing is flexible again.
Published this year's scientific report.
This topic is actually.
Last year, with a math class.
Studied together.
Why do tension?
Because tension.
In the early days.
A few years ago.
At that time.
It was also very fierce.
Especially in 2012.
This piece of science.
Is tension electronics.
Is this kind of.
Electronics.
Its material is made of like coal.
The coal melts in the water.
The coal is melted in the water.
So you can see this.
Tension electronics.
Is my one-time.
Or short-term use.
After using it, throw it away.
That.
I see.
I see their old paper.
The introduction says.
This can be used in the future.
Some military use.
For example, after I use it.
I don't want to take it away.
Or what?
Just throw it on the ground.
Solved.
That kind of thing.
Because it can be melted by water.
That.
I see some people are using.
In vivo.
The experiment.
He.
He can point it at me.
One.
A human body or machine.
Uh.
Inside the organ.
Then measure.
After the test.
I don't have to open it again.
Until I take this material out.
He.
In this material.
In this environment.
In the biological body.
It will disappear on its own.
So this is the concept of tension electronics.
Concept of tension optics.
That.
The concept of horizontal optics.
We first issued one in hs-nano last year.
He is very simple here.
That's.
Disori balalasporsp.
Publicity.
Also, we use.
We do this with the topic.
We use PVA.
PVA is.
Shh.
Soil melt.
Ah.
Is the magnification is 1.
Then we mix it with PBA.
Anyway, there are other problems.
Zn or nanoparticle.
There are other.
Uh.
Tl2 nanoparticle.
Then measure the light.
Then this.
This device to measure the light.
The.
The data.
After that, this thing.
You can melt it.
That's basically the concept of this spring.
Spring concept.
That we.
Last year, we put it together first.
Uh.
This kind of random laser.
Then I told the teacher class.
The junior thought.
Can you.
Do a spring.
Spring spring HMM out.
This is my ASEAN photo.
Corsasia ASEAN photo.
I designed a different HMM sample.
The first one is HMM1.
HMM1 is gold and PVA.
Is 25 and 42 nanometers.
That gold.
That's because PVA.
This is more difficult.
Is that he needs to test his parameters.
So we're testing out about four different speeds.
Can reach 42 or 49 nanometers.
Then I can design different HMM.
The color curve.
The sample comes out.
Then we do four pairs.
Then you can see this HMM1.
It's a different wavelength.
It's also this kind of hyperbolic dispersion.
That HMM2.
It's HMM in different wavelengths.
Then he is also EMM.
This is EMM.
So his PL is in this 530.
He will be weaker.
Then we have this kind of HMM.
Sample to measure different fuels.
Then you can find HMM1.
In different fuels.
Because HMM1 is in this place.
He belongs to me.
He's stronger.
Will HMM be a little weaker?
Then you can see this HMM.
It's basically weaker than reference.
So my HMM concept.
I use it here.
Lifetime.
For Lifetime.
It's also a relatively short trend.
Of course, I also calculated the Skeleton cross-section.
Then I also calculated.
I have different wavelengths.
Perceived effect enhancement behavior.
Of course, the closer to the base.
My enhancement ratio will be larger.
The farther he will be weaker.
That.
This is a little demo.
I'm in this trend HMM.
In different like silicon base.
Then the other is like glass glass base.
He put it in the water.
He will melt the same.
In fact, you can see.
After putting it in the water for five minutes.
He will be a little bit broken.
After 1.5 hours.
His material will be melted in the water.
Just like this.
Next to the water.
It's the kind of metal that's broken.
That kind of metal.
The components come out like this.
Of course, we have.
Demo some of his work.
Or on the PET base.
Then he can even stick it on his hand.
As a bending.
Then we even want to say in the future.
This concept can be combined.
That smart phone.
For the future to do this.
Lens may be helpful.
That's just a demo of this concept.
Then we also did some bending test.
That's on a different bending base.
He can also measure a.
Strengthening behavior.
Uh, it's not like that.
He still has a certain.
PL signal out.
That's Fred.
Of course, it will be stronger.
That's in different bending radius.
This is the signal we measured.
That.
This kind of polymer-made.
What are the benefits of HM?
It's that he can bend.
That's not like the usual SL2.
Or what?
Uh, pick a rabbit.
If it's an electrolyte.
He could bend a few times.
It's broken.
It's not a good mold.
That.
This is our bending cycle.
This is a motor that looks like a four-wheel drive.
Give him one.
Go on.
Give him a bending.
That.
After a few thousand times of bending.
He.
His PL signal still exists.
So we feel like this kind of polymer-based.
Uh, HM.
He's a future.
Maybe in Flexible Electronics.
Or Flexible Optics.
It's also one of the moves.
That's what we did before.
He can do this thing.
That.
I.
This is.
I proved that he could.
That is.
Uh, put it in the water for five minutes.
And then take out the sample.
Blow dry.
After taking it out and drying it.
And then the first dye.
Five minutes later.
He's actually going to be DK.
Because the general R6G.
His enhancement is about 100.
More than 100.
So strong.
That.
Soak for 30 minutes.
Take it out in 30 minutes.
Two more PO.
He's a little bit weaker.
He's a lot weaker.
Okay, so I'm going to conclude a little bit.
Uh, I'm just going to conclude a little bit.
This is.
It's the first one to make spring.
And then again.
Flexible HM.
Then he is.
Polymer.
The main material.
That.
We'll find it interesting.
Because he.
It still retains the HM.
The general kind of metal.
The characteristics of the metal film.
That.
This kind of thing.
It's kind of interesting.
Because he might have used it.
After a while.
It's still there.
Maybe it will melt after a while.
That's the future.
First of all.
Yeah.
Environmental friendly.
One concept.
Then he can also retain.
If there is any.
Data in there.
He can.
Uh, go away.
ERS4201
That's the CONCLSIR stream.
It's a flexible.
The conception of optoelectron.
That's the relationship.
So we.
Would you think this is a good job for the future.
I see a lot of things.
A group like Stanford.
Someone calling ESKEET electronic feat.
Then we're going to do this maybe.
In the future, we can do electron.
Optical electronic skin.
An application.
Then this work.
Just a little demo.
This concept.
So this work.
It actually took about 30.
Later.
Uh.
It took about two or three months.
It's over.
Because in fact, this time.
It's all very simple.
Then we're going to measure.
P2 enhance.
Then melt.
Bending.
So this work.
It's almost like this.
Hey.
That's basically my work.
It's probably like this.
Let's see what's wrong with everyone.
That's our lab.
This was taken last year.
Then we are actually a very large team.
The teacher is here.
Then there are other Indians.
Then we will cooperate with other labs.
Mainly like this.
Because.
I'm sorry.
Because this time I didn't introduce too much.
My.
This work.
Because this work is still under review.
So I'll just show you a little bit.
How did we achieve this concept?
And then the next one.
My question is.
That's it.
He is.
You put it in a flexible.
It's kind of like a substrate.
Anyway, it's a flexible film.
PET or something, right?
That's right.
You have a concept.
Your response.
How sensitive is the deformation of this film?
You mean the deformation?
Correct.
In fact.
Uh.
Wait a minute.
Let me see.
In fact, if it is.
Let me see you like this.
Let's say it's like this.
Suppose he's in a bend.
He might have some angles.
It's not H.
M.
Some angles.
Because my concept of H.
M.
To be in.
Uh.
Specific direction.
Specific frequency.
If he bends.
He might not be H.
M.
As for how to bend.
Uh.
I'm not going to prove this thing.
Correct.
Because like this bending.
If you measure the side.
We are bending.
When the surface.
Measure the signal above.
How is it?
See if this thing will be.
Because of the process of bending.
And affect.
My light.
Come out.
It looks okay.
But if I bend.
Like this.
Because what I think of is.
That is.
You are equal to.
It's kind of like.
Just to prove that he said.
You bend.
Do 500 times.
1000 times.
3000 times.
And then put it back.
He will have the effect.
So he can.
He can bear it.
Such.
Is bending.
But.
What I think of is.
For example.
If you take this thing.
Can replace.
For example.
Like a pressure material.
Or.
Like that.
That kind of thing.
You can become.
Super sensitive.
The pressure.
Pressure sensor.
Or.
The change of the sensor.
Uh.
I think maybe.
Just.
It depends on you.
Because you are doing light.
So.
Your sensitivity.
To change.
Just like you just said.
Maybe a little bit of deformation.
He.
Uh.
He didn't have that effect in an instant.
Then you know he's deformed.
You know what I mean.
Then if you choose.
More correct.
For example.
Your substrate.
The material.
Let him.
Hardness.
Just.
That.
It's equal to.
Hardness is high enough.
Then he won't deform so much.
You may be able to slightly increase your.
Dynamic.
Is that you can measure things.
Dynamic window.
Then you.
You can become a super sensitive.
The shape of the sensor.
I think.
I guess.
I don't know.
It must be calculated.
Correct.
Oh.
OK.
Because this is also a direction.
Correct.
Just combine this.
My this.
Flexible concept.
To combine.
This kind of.
Uh.
The software.
The whole thing.
So I'm going to combine the concept.
Uh.
It's piezo.
This.
incidence of kind of concept.
Yeah.
Okay, so.
Basically, this.
I will introduce you to my previous ones.
And this one.
PH.
verbs.
Back to a Louis bonneture.
9889,
says,
Yeah.
Then.
What are the other questions?
Questions.
I am.
Comment.
That word.
That worrit.
Then, later.
I'll tell you about it again if I have a chance.
Because we.
We actually have more.
Do other.
White laser.
Come out.
Then this is still on both sides.
Then we have a work.
Will be this.
The surface is still.
We think it's still cool.
The structure.
Then this is still on both sides.
Yeah.
Tomorrow will be on both sides.
And it is expected to be white light.
Then.
What else do you have?
Questions.
I have a question.
Or.
Yo, yo, yo.
Uh.
Just.
I want to ask.
Is.
Generally put a.
Something that glows.
Put it on.
Metal surface.
It was.
Will be coupled to.
Surface plasma.
Oh, right.
Then.
Its.
Decay rate.
Will be faster.
That's right.
Is.
How do you make sure.
Uh.
Because.
Because your material.
The top is also a layer of gold.
Metal.
How do you make sure.
That is.
Not because of this reason.
But because it has.
HMM.
What caused it.
In fact.
Like doing this experiment.
We will.
With.
Simple.
The same thickness.
Mirror.
Like gold.
To compare.
That.
You can.
If it is gold.
It is.
Where it is strong.
It won't be like HMM.
It is a.
Boehming.
That.
I have seen.
If I.
If I use the same thickness of metal.
Count.
In this case.
Then strengthen.
If it is possible.
It's like this.
It's a very strong.
A rumor.
It's in other waves.
Zengqian.
Just no.
It's not as strong as HMM.
So of course it's right.
Like Xu Yang.
You just said.
It mirrors.
Gold.
The general metal.
Neutron.
It's also a strength.
But if I want to do one.
Boehm.
Different wavelengths.
That is.
For metal.
The particles.
May be impossible.
That.
I can still control this.
It.
Strengthen a rumor of different wavelengths.
About.
Is there any strength?
That's right.
The main thing is to look.
The main thing is to look at the application.
See what kind of application you want.
That's like me.
It's the strength of white light.
So I need to design this.
Different.
Different wavelengths.
Strengthening behavior.
That's simple.
The same thickness of metal.
Uh.
Gold.
It just can't reach.
It's close to a white light.
A strength.
The light.
So simple metal.
It will also strengthen.
Then the other question is.
Is it possible.
It's not.
Then the other question is.
This kind of metal material.
Usually the problem is absorption.
That's.
In.
In these.
Uh.
Lacing.
Or.
You started with.
Enhance this.
These.
In the work.
Will this absorption.
Have caused some problems.
Hey.
I hope your question is.
Will the base be absorption?
Or.
It's still.
Is it.
Does it carry a lot of metal?
Uh.
Yeah.
Because he will absorb some things himself.
But as a whole.
It will make me.
The top.
Medial.
The.
Memory function will become higher.
It's basically a little bit of absorption.
That's right.
So that's.
A little bit.
It's.
It's a little bit.
So.
How much.
But the reflection is OK.
Reflection is OK.
It won't absorb everything.
Of course, I can also design.
At some stages.
It absorbs very strongly.
Its reflection is very strong.
It can rely on me.
Different.
Like.
Uh.
A little bit.
Like.
Different.
Feel Fiction.
Can reach.
Wait a minute.
Like.
Like this.
I can.
Through different.
Feel Fiction.
To adjust.
So.
Not to say.
I.
This one.
HMM comes out.
For all the materials.
Perfect.
I want.
Case by case.
To design.
So.
Basically.
I.
HMM.
If it's different.
My thickness ratio.
It's a little bit different.
Just.
Case by case.
To design.
I.
I have a question.
Is that.
How much is the mold volume?
And that.
Why.
Mold volume.
Just.
Generally its.
MOLD.
How much is the mold volume.
It's like you said it.
It is.
She is very small.
But I don't know how little she is.
Ah.
Right.
I see you here.
HMM.
Um.
But uh.
This is a plane.
So.
That plane.
The height of the.
What is it?
This.
The unit.
What is it?
This unit is.
Uh.
The height of the plane.
I think.
UM3.
It's changed to NANO3.
It's ten.
Multiplied by ten to the ninth.
It should be.
Or ten to the sixth.
So it's this thing.
Multiply it by ten to the sixth.
Or ten to the sixth.
It is.
How many MM3.
So it's actually.
It's a very small thing.
That.
This kind of thing.
My question is.
This thing is a plane.
Yeah.
It's a plane.
If it's a plane.
You.
That.
Uh.
Volume should be a length.
The length.
It's a length.
That.
Unit.
Oh.
Because actually we.
Is.
It's a plane.
But we.
I.
When using.
Calculation.
It also needs a.
The volume to surround it.
A.
An overall calculation.
Area.
Yeah.
So it.
So the volume will bring you.
That.
The size of your calculation.
Inside.
Yeah.
This is.
So.
So actually I.
How much is it?
Do you know?
Hey.
I haven't counted this.
Of course.
OK.
But actually I'm different.
Depends on different.
Uh.
Okay.
Thank you.
No, no, no, no.
I don't know if you have any more questions or comments, yet.
Yes, I think there's a question about a.
Work, this is uh, you're using the.
Uh.
Hi.
Hello.
Um.
All right.
Hello.
Okay.
Um.
Thank you very much.
Bye bye.
Thanks.
Thank you.
Bye bye.