The recording has started.
Good evening, everyone.
Sorry, let me talk first.
Welcome everyone to the Taira Talk on March 28th.
We are honored to invite Alan Xu to give a speech for us today.
Alan Xu was a medical student at Chenggong University when he was in college.
He majored in dengue and other blood-related diseases.
He is now a Ph.D. student at Purdue University.
Today's topic is
Identifying Potential Therapeutics for Modulating Neutrophil Inflammation.
Before the speech, let's give Alan a round of applause.
Remember to turn on your microphones when you applaud.
Please turn on your microphones.
Thank you.
Let's give Alan some time.
Today, I would like to share something different with everyone.
As Jason mentioned,
our research focuses on how to use new methods to get immune cells to control our immune system
in order to reach a low level of inflammation,
but at the same time, to fight against diseases.
First, I will divide my talk into a brief background introduction.
Then, I will talk about the so-called gene selection.
Finally, I will share with you what we found.
First, I would like to introduce Neutrophil.
Neutrophil is commonly known as neutrophil.
You may have seen it on Facebook or YouTube.
In 1953, David Rodgers photographed a neutrophil running after bacteria.
Next to it are red blood cells.
This is the most common neutrophil in our blood.
40% to 60% of the white blood cells in our blood are neutrophil.
Neutrophil is the fastest-moving cell in our body.
It can be seen in real time.
Neutrophil can be followed by bacteria.
Neutrophil is the first cell to reach the infection site.
Neutrophil is no longer divided or separated.
Neutrophil often has these lobes.
How does Neutrophil reach the infection site?
Neutrophil circulates in the bloodstream.
There are some adhesive receptors on the outside of our blood vessels.
Neutrophil will roll on the outside of the blood vessels and stick to the adhesive receptors.
Finally, the adhesive receptors are attached to the adhesive receptors.
The adhesive receptors are extrapolated or transmigrated.
The adhesive receptors enter the stem cell.
After entering the stem cell, we will feel the so-called red hot pain.
These are the adhesive cells.
When Neutrophil reaches the infection site, it will perform many functions.
It will release a lot of cytokines.
These cytokines can let more Neutrophil in.
These cytokines can also let other immune cells, such as macrophages, T-cells, B-cells, etc.
However, cytokines are very important for the transmission of information and speech.
However, too much cytokines can cause hemorrhage and shock.
Neutrophil can also perform phagocytosis.
Neutrophil can directly swallow microorganisms.
After swallowing, Neutrophil will release some free radicals, ROS, to break them down.
ROS can also be placed outside the cell to cause the whole organ to develop and attract more immune cells and a reaction to develop.
However, too many free radicals will cause oxidation.
So, we often say that we should avoid drinking tea, reduce free radicals, and reduce aging.
This is because these free radicals will cause organ damage, which is not good for too many people.
Neutrophil's most famous function is called Net Formation, or Neutrophil Accelerator Trap.
When Neutrophil finds that its own immune response is too strong or too many bacteria are around it, it can't do anything by itself.
When we watch movies, we see this hero or male supporting role.
When Neutrophil finds that there are too many enemies, it will usually hold a hand grenade and directly return to these bacteria, or return to the enemy.
At this time, Neutrophil will release its DNA, which is the DNA in this box, outside the cell to form a sticky web-like thing called Net.
This name is very similar.
It can trap these bacteria or viruses there.
There are also some enzymes on this Net that can help break them down.
This Net itself can also be used as a function to attract immune cells.
However, too many of these Nets will actually cause body immunity.
Because our body's immune system does not recognize DNA as a substance by training, so sometimes it will cause body immunity.
Generally, in the ideal case, Neutrophil does not have excessive inflammation.
When Neutrophil plays its role, Neutrophil will have apoptosis and die.
These impurities will be devoured by macrophages, which is another type of cell.
Then the inflammation will slow down.
Otherwise, Neutrophil can climb back to its blood vessels and continue to circulate.
I hope that through these functions, we can make it easier for everyone to understand.
The first cell to reach the inflammation site, how does it do it?
How does it decide?
Often it will decide the outcome of our inflammation.
Will it kill?
Will it successfully eliminate our foreign bacteria or viruses?
So we have to find a way to study if there is a new way to control the reaction of inflammation.
Why do we need to control the reaction of inflammation?
As I said four times, it is a balance.
It is like the cover of a science magazine.
We need it, but too much is not good.
Because of the recent COVID-19 epidemic, I just took this example to tell you why people die from COVID-19.
This is a lung cancer of our lungs, aviola.
Usually this aviola has air.
At this time, the SARS virus, SARS-CoV-2, will infect the epidermal cells of our aviola.
The epidermal cells will die.
The cells will also send out some life-saving signals.
The neutrophils will run from the aviola to the lung tissue.
At the same time, the inflammation of the aviola will also cause a rise in blood vessels.
Then the aviola will have a hemorrhage.
So a lot of immune cells will eliminate bacteria and kill viruses here.
At the same time, the aviola will have a hemorrhage.
The inflammation of the aviola will cause a positive feedback.
This will cause a lot of bystander effects.
What is a bystander effect?
In addition to killing viruses, it kills the virus-infected cells.
So the tissue of our lungs will be injured.
Injured, there will be a stronger inflammation.
Then there will be more immune cells.
So it will slowly make our lungs water.
At the same time, we can't have enough oxygen.
When there is not enough oxygen, there will be shortness of breath.
It's breathing difficulty.
In the end, lack of oxygen will also cause our organs to lose oxygen.
If you don't get oxygen, you will die from organ failure.
People who die from organ failure will die.
So basically 90% of people who die from COVID-19 are ARDS.
ARDS is an over-infection-induced disease.
But we need it to eliminate the infection of our virus.
So how to balance this is very important.
In our lab, the model we use is an aviola model.
Let me introduce this aviola to you first.
If you are not familiar with it,
What you see in this video is a three-day aviola.
Its neutral field is marked with GFP, a fluorescent protein.
It is found that its neutral field is divided into two groups.
One is in CHT, which is equivalent to our bone marrow.
So it doesn't move much.
The other is in the head.
It will perform some random migration.
It will move randomly.
Why is aviola a good reason to study neutral field?
First, because the whole animal is transparent.
So it's easy to shoot.
So you can see if you make some genetic or pharmacological changes.
You can see the behavior of these cells.
You can see it in real time.
Second, because this aviola lives in the water.
It is a organ.
Because our organs, whether lungs or stomach, are basically soaked in our mucosa.
It is mucosal immunity.
Because it also lives in the water.
So its outer skin is equivalent to the inner skin of our lungs.
So it is also a good reason to study immune cells.
Some important reasons are that its immune system,
Especially the adenovirus immune system.
Neutral field is a member of the adenovirus immune system.
It is very similar to mammals, such as mice or humans.
So its shape, or its evolution,
And some of its functions are actually very similar to our neutral field.
Finally, a more practical reason is that
Because this fish is very small.
Like this whole fish is only about three centimeters.
It's 0.3 centimeters.
So it's very small.
You can raise a lot of fish at the same time.
There is not much space to stand.
And a pair of male and female fish can give birth to more than 100 small fish.
So it's good to do some medical research.
This is just a brief introduction to everyone.
This zebrafish is a neutral field.
This is a zebrafish, a neutral field,
H.E. stain is the color of the blood.
This is a mouse.
This is our human.
So it's actually about the same size.
There is also this so-called cell box.
This is a form of compartmentalization.
This is just a few videos to tell you about the function of this zebrafish's neutral field.
So this red one is the big intestine.
It's in the zebrafish.
This green one is the zebrafish's neutral field.
So he just saw that the green one would come and swallow the red one.
That's what we just talked about.
This is a free machine assay.
So this MPO myoperoxidase is a free machine.
It is marked as green.
And then we have this zebrafish's neutral field marked as red.
So you see that this red and green are intertwined like this.
In fact, it shows that the zebrafish's neutral field is going to release the free machine.
The last example is to talk about this neptosis.
So we just said that we can release the net value of this neutral field.
So this DAPI is a cell box.
This cell box has DNA.
DNA is scattered out of the package.
So at the same time, you can also see the effects on it.
MPO elastase.
So it means that this zebrafish's neutral field is actually quite similar to the functions of humans.
So it's just to introduce to you that it can be used to study a good model or model of neutral field biology.
Let me give you a little bit of a change of flavor.
Let me introduce another thing that we are interested in.
It's called microRNA.
MicroRNA is a very short 20 to 22-digit nucleotide.
It's DNA.
It can exist from DNA.
It exists in exon and intron.
It can exist anywhere in our gene.
When it is transferred by our polymerase transcription to RNA, it will have this hairpin structure.
From this hairpin structure, it will be processed and transported to the outside of our cell box.
After it is transported to the outside of the cell box, it will be processed again.
Then it becomes a single 20 to 22-digit RNA complex.
It will identify the target mRNA, which is our messenger RNA, with its other machinery, which is called Ritz complex.
This messenger RNA is usually used to make protein.
To suppress it.
Either the whole mRNA will be broken down.
Otherwise, it will stop its transfer and prevent it from becoming protein.
So these microRNAs are like a small key.
Instead of controlling whether this gene is expressed or not.
It says it doesn't matter if you express it.
But I can use this microRNA to suppress and adjust the amount of protein it expresses.
Adjust it on the level of RNA.
Because this microRNA adjustment method is often not a one-off.
Because the expression of your gene is a one-off.
Either it's open or it's closed.
Of course, you can adjust how much it is.
But this is still a more absolute.
This microRNA suppression phenomenon can often be adjusted.
For example, 100 mRNAs can only inhibit or suppress half.
So it becomes a fine tuning.
Because we just said that we have to adjust the expression.
We can't turn off the whole expression.
Otherwise, people will die.
So we have to adjust it.
This microRNA actually has another feature.
Because it's a 22-nucleotide.
A single microRNA can become a target for many mRNAs.
In other words, a single key can open many locks.
Or match many transcripts.
In evolution, these microRNAs will often target a pathway.
There are many related genes on a pathway.
It means that I can inhibit you walking today.
It can also inhibit you from eating.
It can also inhibit you from sleeping.
All of these functions can be done by a single microRNA.
To make a person feel uncomfortable.
This microRNA is evolutionary conserved.
It is found in small insects and fruits.
It is found in all biological phenomena.
From cancer to plant growth to cell division.
There are probably microRNAs involved.
Because they have this feature.
It has been reported as the next generation of medicine.
We are also trying to identify some microRNAs.
To adjust or balance the development of neutrophils.
Sorry, I have a question.
Can I go back to the last page?
This may be a very basic question.
But mRNA is messenger RNA.
Is it converted to protein outside the cell?
Yes.
I thought RNA is inside the cell.
Let me explain.
Our DNA is in the nucleus.
It will be converted into the nucleus.
All RNAs are converted into the nucleus.
Some of them will be on the nucleus.
Ribosome will be made into protein.
Some of them will be transported to the nucleus.
There are many ribosomes there.
Most of them are in the ER.
The so-called intracellular network.
It is actually inside another cell.
Can mRNA be transmitted between cells?
No, between the nucleus and the nucleus.
Our nucleus has two layers.
I see.
I understand.
Sorry.
I have a question.
About the next generation of medicine.
How can we avoid the off-target of microRNA?
That's a great question.
I will talk about the next generation of medicine.
There are two strategies.
One is to treat microRNA as our friend.
For example, microRNA34 can be used to suppress cell proliferation.
MicroRNA29 can be used to treat lung cancer.
That's right.
There are two levels of off-target.
One is the off-target of human organs.
MicroRNA can be stored in liposomes or carriers.
It can be used to treat liver cancer.
Liver cancer is easy to treat.
Liver and kidneys are the organs of human organs.
There are many special markers in the lungs.
MicroRNA can be linked to these markers.
It will be enriched in the lungs.
MicroRNA can be stored in other organs.
However, the amount of microRNA will be less than the target.
The question you asked is very good.
MicroRNA therapy in the blood is difficult to do.
Because the blood cells are too complicated.
We can't overcome this.
In other aspects, such as mRNA122.
You can inhibit microRNA122.
You can avoid the infection of HCV.
It's the same as liver cancer.
Inhibition 155.
Inflammation.
Inflammation of the whole body.
Another level of microRNA off-targeting is
whether the hairpin recognizes what you want to recognize.
This can only be confirmed by experiment.
Because each cell expresses a different gene profile.
That's why we have different cells.
Because our dye cells are all the same.
We can only verify and exclude the different gene profiles.
Did I answer your question?
Yes, thank you.
You made it very clear.
Thank you.
This is the part of microRNA therapy.
We can inhibit it.
How do we inhibit it?
It's easy.
If we go back here, we can see that
the microRNA itself comes from a hairpin.
It's a hairpin.
We can give it a complementary strand.
We can absorb it like a sponge.
Then it won't be able to work.
This is a way to inhibit it.
What we are more interested in is
directly using this microRNA to off-target.
Before I start, let me summarize for everyone.
We are going to talk about this research today.
Basically, we are going to identify which microRNA
and its downstream mRNA
can be used for translational inhibition.
That is to inhibit it or
to separate the messenger RNA.
To inhibit Neutrophil migration.
Why do we want to choose Neutrophil migration
as our readout?
First, because
we just introduced that
Neutrophil has too many functions.
It has a free machine, a package, and a net.
So it's too difficult for you to look at it first.
Why don't we
flatten the curve?
It's the same thing.
But on a more human level.
We don't want Neutrophil to enter
as soon as possible.
We want it to enter slowly.
So it's easier for your body to adjust.
Your hair is easier to adjust.
This is our strategy.
So we hope that
at the Neutrophil recruitment level,
we can flatten the curve
to prevent over-inflammation.
Whether it's asthma,
joint inflammation,
or multiple sclerosis.
Including ARDS,
which is also an over-inflammation.
But at the same time,
we still have to keep a function.
Because now on the market,
all the treatments for this immune disease
are like our endocrine
or some corticosteroids.
Or some specific immune suppressors.
But the problem is that
these things will bring
the defect of your immune system.
Then you may have a very serious cold.
So what we are going to answer today is
which microRNA can do this.
Can prevent Neutrophil migration
from being so much.
But at the same time,
it can keep our immune system.
What are its MRNAs?
Maybe we can go and study
which of its lower genes
can control Neutrophil.
So this is the second part.
We are going to start discussing this screen.
Does anyone have any questions here?
So the method we use
is an overexpression screen.
So we are going to sequence
all the two types of cells.
Neutrophil and epidermal cells.
Why do we use this type of cell?
Because I just mentioned
Neutrophil is a type of cell
that has a very large number of
active or unactive proteins.
Or its turnover is very fast.
It is very active.
Compared to our epidermal cells,
like you and me,
the epidermal cells are basically
not very active.
So its cytoskeleton,
the cell skeleton,
is relatively stable.
So we went to see
the microRNAs
between these two cells.
And we found that
there is a difference
in the amount of microRNAs
in the epidermal cells.
So there are
340 microRNAs
in the epidermal cells.
We found that
90 microRNAs are lower in Neutrophil.
Let me explain to you here.
Neutrophil cells
because we know that
in most cases,
microRNAs suppress certain mRNAs
or suppress a certain
biological reaction.
So what we want to take today
is to put it back
so that it can do its function
and slow it down.
So we let it
put something in a faster cell
to slow it down.
So we choose this lower
Neutrophil.
In these 90 targets,
after we classify it a little bit,
we have 50 candidates.
So these 50
microRNA families
are relatively low
in Neutrophil
compared to the epidermal cells.
So now we're going to put it back
and see if we can
slow down the Neutrophil
recruitment.
This is a little bit
more complicated,
but this is our over-expression construct.
How do we
express this thing?
We can't express it in Neutrophil.
So we have to use
a thing called Neutrophil-specific promotion.
This kind of start
will only open and express
in Neutrophil.
This is called Lysine.
We put our
microRNA hairpin
in an intron,
so it won't affect the gene expression.
So it's like Neutrophil
expressing a microRNA.
At the same time, how do we know
this gene?
We designed the exon 1
to splice the dendrite 2 protein.
This is very complicated,
but this dendrite 2 protein is basically
a green protein.
Because it's all
a construct,
it's all a gene
that turns down.
So if there is a microRNA,
this cell will be green
and only occurs in Neutrophil.
This is more complicated.
Then we put
all 50 targets here
into the structure of the hairpin
and replace them one by one.
And then one by one,
this is a single cell
of the hematoma.
This is the hematoma.
This is its egg yolk.
This is its cell.
Then three days later,
we will select
which hematoma
has Neutrophil
and which hematoma has dendrite 2 protein.
After the selection,
we will
inject
pseudomonas
directly into the
hematoma's ears.
This will make it
look at the
green Neutrophil recruitment.
So the phenomenon we see
is like this.
This is the hematoma's ears.
You can see the red bacteria here.
They will come to the ears
to do their immune response.
If we find
a microRNA over-expression,
which is to express this microRNA
by this construct,
you will see that
these Neutrophil
either haven't gotten here
or don't want to get here.
So they didn't
get the successful recruitment.
So from
our 50 candidates,
we sifted out
9 microRNAs
with similar phenomena.
They will have less
to the ears.
So this is
how we
raise these 9 microRNAs
into the so-called
stable line.
Every cell
of this fish
has this construct
at the DNA level.
But only in Neutrophil
will it be expressed.
So these 9
are our microRNAs.
After we have
this stable transgenic line,
we verify again
to infect its ears
or use another
so-called sterile inflammation,
which is
non-infective
inflammation.
So we cut it off
and look at Neutrophil's
recruitment.
You will find that
in general,
it is consistent
with our transgenic screen.
This is the screen
on the page above.
This microRNA199-3
has two models.
Whether it's infection
or tail wounding,
the ratio of recruitment
is this gray bar,
the contrast group.
After expressing this microRNA,
you will find that
it drops the most.
So we want to study
some biological functions of
this microRNA199.
First of all,
we need to determine
the expression of
this microRNA199
compared to the baseline
in Neutrophil.
Because it may only
cause this phenomenon
when the computer crashes.
So we did a
microRNA QRT
to measure
how much microRNA199
will affect other microRNAs.
We found that
microRNA223 and microRNA227
are high microRNAs
in Neutrophil.
But microRNA199,
because we have overexpressed it,
is about 1,000 times higher.
So it means that
it is 1,000 times higher
than other microRNAs.
So we are safe to assume that
the phenomenon of microRNA199
is really caused by
the overexpression of microRNA199,
not because other microRNAs
are all dropped.
At the same time,
we need to see
whether the reduction of
recruitment is caused by
the overexpression of microRNA199
or its own
inability to develop
or functional differences.
So we went to see
that the number of Neutrophils
in each fish
is similar to that of vectors,
which means that
it is not caused by
a total reduction of Neutrophils.
Because the reduction of recruitment
you see today may be
because Neutrophils are less
so you can't see this phenomenon.
So we need to see
whether the Neutrophils
are going to develop
or not.
So this is a zebrafish.
This is what we call a stable line.
Each Neutrophil is green.
This is a vector.
So you can see that
Neutrophils are moving very,
very fast.
You can see that
Neutrophils are moving very,
very fast.
So the question is
when the Neutrophils
are overexpressed,
the Neutrophils will still move.
It's just that
it will still move,
but it will move slower than others.
So it's possible that
it really doesn't want to go
or it just walks slowly.
At least we know that
the zebrafish walks slowly.
As for whether it doesn't want to go,
we will study it later.
What I want to introduce to you
is the zebrafish Neutrophil.
No matter how similar it is to humans,
it is still
not a human Neutrophil.
But in our field,
the biggest problem
of Neutrophil research is
that this human Neutrophil
is no longer fragmented,
so it is difficult
to make any genetic
modifications or mutations.
So in our field,
the zebrafish Neutrophil is a
cell type called HL60.
This cell type
is a Neutrophil's
anterior cell.
In this anterior cell,
it will be fragmented and split.
We can make some genetic
modifications to it,
and then divide it into Neutrophils.
But it won't be a complete Neutrophil.
It's just a Neutrophil similar to humans.
At least it's human.
Because this is a microRNA,
we don't want this microRNA
to be affected
in the process of splitting.
So we had to adopt
an inducible system,
that is, we can use a switch.
What does this switch mean?
It means that we first put this
new construct
into our HL60
cell,
and then make a antigen,
puromycin, to select it.
So as long as there is
an HL60
in its gene,
it can be immune to this antigen.
When we need
this microRNA to be expressed,
we give it a doxycycline,
a chemical substance,
a four-ring type,
which is also an antigen
and an antibiotic.
This stimulates the
hairpin in the middle
and the green one will be expressed.
This is a bit complicated.
Anyway, because we don't want
this microRNA to be expressed at any time,
it will affect its splitting.
So we use such an inducible system.
We can share a few photos with you.
So the normal cell is
dense, and then after splitting,
some of it will die,
but basically it is still splitting.
You can see that this little bit of green
is the doxycycline
to turn it on.
Of course, the degree of green
is different,
but these green cells successfully
split and express the microRNA we want.
This microRNA199
is very important,
and it is very lucky
that its Bermuda microRNA199
is exactly the same as the
human microRNA199 series,
which is the series of 20 to 22
editing we mentioned earlier.
The part I circled
is the 2nd to 8th editing
in the microRNA,
which is called the seed sequence,
which is its core binding.
It mainly relies on this seed sequence
to identify its target.
So if you think about it,
it is actually a series of 6 to 7 edits.
Because we have 4 types of edits,
A, T, C, G,
so it's 4 to 6 to 7 squares.
This is actually quite specific.
So the first thing we saw
was that we chose
this microRNA199 cell expression.
We found that
it was only
when the switch was turned on,
it was only the top line of
microRNA199,
and the other two microRNAs,
the microRNA in the neutral field,
had no effect.
At the same time,
we also used another random microRNA,
microRNA100.
This is not something we are interested in.
It's just because I'm afraid
that this construct itself
will cause a sequelae.
So we put these cells
in a thing called a transwell.
This transwell,
I'll explain it to you.
It's a kind of
nipple groove.
The groove above
is where we put our cells.
At the bottom of this groove
is a small hole.
This small hole is not big enough
for the cells to fall in,
but the cells can squeeze in.
It's a bit like the neutral field
that we introduced earlier.
It can squeeze the transwell
into the tissue.
At the bottom,
we put something that can attract them.
In this case,
we put something called FMLP.
It's a small peptide
that the bacteria release.
We found that
if we
use FMLP
to attract it,
and if we don't activate it,
these three cells
will go down
in the same way.
You can see that the white bars are the same.
Similarly,
if you give it a construct,
whether it's an empty vector,
199 or 100,
but you don't give it
anything that can attract it,
they won't go over.
You have to squeeze this hole
to consume energy,
so it won't do anything meaningful.
However,
if you give it
FMLP again,
you will find that
this random microRNA
is similar to our empty vector,
but only when you express 199,
its penetrability
will decrease.
It's exactly the same as what we saw
in the Bermuda Triangle.
It can't recruit
to the place we want.
This proves that this microRNA 199
is useful in both
human and Bermuda Triangle systems.
Next, we want to ask
what is the target of this 199
to make it useful.
We need to
identify the mechanism below it.
This is a
adult Bermuda triangle.
Bermuda triangle
is different from humans.
Its structure is not in the bones,
but in its growth.
This Bermuda triangle is called kidney marrow.
Let's take this kidney marrow out.
You can see that these green cells
are the neutrophils we saw earlier.
Let's use the method of
eukaryotic cells
to separate the cells.
Because it's green,
it has green light,
let's use RNA
to measure its RNA level.
Let's see
the expression of each RNA.
Do you remember
what I said earlier?
This microRNA will target
the target mRNA.
If it successfully targets,
the mRNA may be reduced.
So the level of expression
will decrease.
Surprisingly,
as I mentioned earlier,
the neutrophils are not
separated.
However,
we can see from the
profile of the RNA
that some cells are
separated.
Some cells
are
separated.
This is very illogical.
These cells are not
separated.
Why are these
cells separated?
First, let's see
if this is true.
Let's verify
its expression
by using RNA.
We found that
CDK1 is a cell cycle gene.
It is not on our
reduction list.
CDK2 and CDK5
are all cell cycle genes.
Indeed, when you express
microRNA199,
the sequence is true.
However, there is no explanation.
Let me explain to you
the cell cycle.
In the case of cell splitting,
there are two
same colored cells.
The DNA replication
will be copied
into the so-called double cell.
The mitosis
will be captured by the
microtubule and split into two cells.
In general,
when we use
HL60,
we will find that
it depends on the amount of DNA.
There is a green peak.
This is the amount of DNA
in a single cell.
The S phase
is the replication.
When we go to the G2 phase,
it is already determined that
it is a double cell.
Therefore, the amount of DNA
in a single cell
is the same.
Let's take a look at
the neutrophil
represented by
the light-C promoter.
Indeed,
the neutrophil is not
replicated.
It is in the case of
G0 and G1.
Before we start
to study CDK2,
we need to understand
the microRNA199 sequence.
This is the seed sequence.
It is the binding sequence
at the core.
In the human CDK2 gene
and the Danish CDK2 gene,
there are places
that can bind directly.
G will bind to C,
A will bind to T, etc.
They are divided into 6-mer sites
and 7-mer sites.
They are
predicted to bind.
We can use
computer algorithms
to predict that G0 and G1
can bind directly to CDK2.
Is it true?
We need to verify it.
Therefore,
we created
two versions
of CDK2.
One is that
the predicted binding site
can be
replicated.
If
G0 and G1
can be replicated,
then the predicted binding site
can be replaced.
If G0 and G1
can be replaced,
then the predicted binding site
can be replaced.
We created
a Luciferase assay.
Let me introduce it to you.
There are two constructs.
First,
the CDK2
3'-UTR
is placed here.
Next,
the R
is placed here.
Finally,
the F
is placed here.
These are the two constructs.
They do not change.
If
the CDK2
3'-UTR
is replaced,
then the R
Luciferase
will be degraded.
If
the CDK2
3'-UTR
is replaced,
then the R
Luciferase
will be degraded.
If
the CDK2
3'-UTR
is replaced,
then the R
Luciferase
will be degraded.
If the CDK2
3'-UTR
is replaced,
then the R
Luciferase
will be degraded.
If the CDK2
3'-UTR
is replaced,
then the R
Luciferase
will be degraded.
The reason why the CDK2
3'-UTR
is degraded is that
the CDK2
3'-UTR
is replaced.
The CDK2
3'-UTR
is replaced.
The CDK2
3'-UTR
is replaced.
When you express
the vector,
we set it as the baseline,
because the vector is empty.
However, when you express
the 199,
the CDK2
3'-UTR
will be degraded.
If you change the position
of the CDK2,
the CDK2
3'-UTR
will be degraded.
The microRNA 199
can suppress
the mRNA of CDK2.
An important experiment
is to see
if the 199 can suppress
the CDK2,
if I put the CDK2
in a version
that suppresses the CDK2,
can I save
or rescue
or restore the CDK2?
So,
we put the CDK2
in the 199
and marked it
with a red mark.
The CDK2
cannot be suppressed
by the 199,
because we changed
the suppression point.
This is
the result.
As you can see in this video,
red or white,
because red plus green is white,
the cells move faster
than the green cells.
The statistics show
that the CDK2
can restore the CDK2.
The CDK2
is not the only
CDK2,
but it is an important
CDK2.
As you can see,
the CDK2
is not the only
CDK2,
but it is an important
CDK2.
As you can see,
the CDK2
is not the only
CDK2,
but it is an important
CDK2.
As you can see,
the CDK2
is not the only
CDK2.
As you can see,
the CDK2
is not the only
CDK2.
As you can see,
the CDK2
is not the only
CDK2.
There is another,
CDK2
elinfo.
The CDK2
is not the only
CDK2.
The CDK2
is not the only
CDK2.
As you can see,
the CDK2
is not the only
CDK2.
There is another
CDK2
that is
not the only
CDK2.
There is another
CDK2
that is
not the only
CDK2.
There is another
CDK2
that is
not the only
CDK2.
There is another
CDK2
that is
not the only
CDK2.
There is another
CDK2
that is
not the only
CDK2.
There is another
CDK2
that is
not the only
CDK2.
The last one
is
basically
the research of CDK2
because it is a very important protein
for cell cycle
or cell division.
So most of the research is on cancer
or cell division
or cell division.
In fact, other aspects
have not been studied at all.
So
the first thing we need to do is to make sure
whether the CDK2
is expressed in the cell of
the protein.
This is a previous study.
They found that CDK2
is not only expressed, but also
if you do LPS, which is the stimulation of the endocrine,
it will still rise.
This means that it is not only functional,
but also
has a reaction
to neutrophil stimulation.
This is the
level of RNA.
If you look at the level of protein,
you will find that most of the CDK2
C is the cytosol, N is the nucleus.
Most of them are in the cell.
Although you may say that
it will be a little bit after eating,
most of them are still in the cell.
In our system,
we
draw blood and then separate
human neutrophils,
such as the neutrophils on you and me.
What we are talking about now is
the cell skeleton of its actin.
It is found that after the cell skeleton
has been stimulated,
there is a single
polarization.
This depi is its nucleus.
You will find that CDK2
is like the previous report.
Regardless of the fact that
there is no CDK2 in the nucleus,
most of the green part and the blue part
are actually a little bit apart.
Most of them are actually in the cell tissue,
not in the nucleus.
This is also confirmed by the previous research.
It also proves that
the CDK2 we see in our system
is actually in the nucleus.
As mentioned earlier...
Sorry.
The time is almost up.
I don't know how many pages you have left,
but you may need to speed up later.
Okay, I got it.
In order to separate
the functions of the traditional CDK2,
because the traditional CDK2 is studied
and replicated in DNA,
we use NU6140 today.
This is the replication of the
replicated CDK2,
and this is the replication of the
replicated DNA.
We found that only when you
replicate the CDK2,
but you replicate the DNA,
there is an effect.
So the role of CDK2 today
is beyond the function of
DNA replication
that we traditionally recognize.
In both of our
research models,
we found that only when you
replicate the CDK2,
there is such a replication recruitment,
which is to replicate its
path to the original place,
and then when you replicate the DNA
replication, there is no effect.
In order to be afraid that
if we replicate the CDK2,
it will directly kill the cell,
we chose two inhibitors
to replicate the CDK2.
It can be
washed away.
As you can see,
the speed of the cell
is still normal.
Once we give it this drug,
it will slow down.
Once we wash
this drug away,
it will return to normal in 1-2 hours.
It means that we just
brake it a little bit,
we don't kill it,
but do some irreversible reactions.
This may be very helpful
in terms of treatment,
we can suppress it
and wash it away.
It can solve
such a problem.
In addition, we need to see
what the function of CDK2 is.
It is a gene model.
If you look at it from the point of view of medicine,
it will often have off-targeting,
which is some non-specific functions.
So we just put the CDK2,
this is CDK2 and its
binding part 2,
on the CDK2.
After the CDK2 is off-targeted,
it will not be able
to neutralize
its target.
The result of this
is that it will
occupy all of its
targets,
because it occupies
the macromolecule.
Second, all the cyclins will also be occupied
by the macromolecule.
So we call this strategy
dominant-negative.
Then we put it in the bimolecule.
You will find that if you express
such a red CDK2 normally,
it will be very happy.
On the other hand, if you express
this dominant-negative,
this CDK2,
you will find that the cells will not move at all.
But the interesting thing is that
when you soak
this whole fish in
a chemical substance
to attract these neutrophils,
you will find that
they will still move.
They will still go to
this macromolecule.
It's just that it's going slower,
and the directionality seems to be lost.
If you compare it to what you saw earlier,
this is normal.
In the absence of speech,
they are lazy and don't move much.
On the other hand,
when they speak,
they are still lazy.
It's just that they move slowly,
and the trajectory is not so straight.
Let's look at this thing
with a higher degree of detection.
Let's look at their cell skeleton.
Generally speaking, in a moving neutrophil,
you will find that its stable actin,
which is a mark
of its actin,
will be behind its cell.
So this green will follow the purple.
So this green is always a mark
of the cell.
But when you express
the dominant and negative constructs
of CDK2,
you will find that the cell is not dead or not moving.
It's just that the green doesn't know where to go.
It's like walking left and right.
It doesn't know where to move.
So this also tells us
that there may be some problems with thresholding.
In order to make sure
that what we see is
caused by
CDK2,
we used
a new cell
to knock off
this gene.
So we found that
when we removed CDK2,
our neutrophils
didn't move much.
At the same time,
in order to make sure that this removal is a deliberate removal,
if we put CDK2 back,
you will find that
there is a rescue
to restore its movement speed.
So when you put
this DNA back,
of course, it has no effect.
So the phenomenon we see
is specifically caused by CDK2.
So what we just mentioned
is that the cell looks drunk
and walks left and right.
So let me introduce to you
this neutrophil.
In order to make it move,
we need to activate
the leading edge
and the trailing edge.
The signaling in the front
uses two proteins
as the readout.
We found that
in a human cell,
if you knock off
CDK2,
not really knock it off,
but just suppress
its expression,
the signal in the front
will decrease.
In contrast,
the signal in the back,
the myosin,
is usually behind the cell,
and the fluoride
will mark the leading edge of the cell.
The leading edge and the trailing edge
are separated,
so we know that the cell is upward polarizing.
But when you take CDK2 off,
the polarization disappears.
This means that this cell
is like what we see in the fish.
Finally,
let's switch to
a mouse model.
After CDK2 is taken off,
the mouse is only relatively small,
and it can't reproduce.
But the problem is that
some of its functions are unknown.
So we did a
post-mortem on this mouse.
We took a post-mortem on it
and then collected its saliva
to see what happened.
Let's skip
the graph first.
As you can see,
in this circle,
when CDK2 is taken off,
there are fewer dots
compared to
the dots here.
This means that
there are fewer neutrophils
entering the germ.
While there are fewer neutrophils
entering the germ,
we found that
in a normal situation,
the neutrophil
in the germ
has a higher proportion.
The neutrophil
in the germ
has a higher proportion than
in a normal mouse.
When it is taken off,
the neutrophil
will move to the surrounding blood
and go to the circulatory system.
That's why you see
this decrease.
However, if there is a problem
with the neutrophil,
the neutrophil will stay in the blood
with a higher proportion.
At the same time,
the neutrophil will be
less likely to be infected.
To summarize,
neutrophils move in
2D and 3D.
One of them moves
on the surface,
while the other
moves on the leading edge
and trailing edge.
We found that
in human cells,
if you suppress the CDK2,
which is a 2D migration,
the CDK2 will move
on the leading edge
and trailing edge.
When you suppress the CDK2,
it will move on the leading edge
and trailing edge.
However, the CDK2
will move on the leading edge
and trailing edge.
This means that
in the 3D ring,
the CDK2 will move on the leading edge
and trailing edge.
This means that
in the 3D ring,
the CDK2 will move on the leading edge
and trailing edge.
However, if you suppress the CDK2,
the CDK2 will move
on the leading edge
and trailing edge.
This is the summary of
the CDK2 migration in the
Bermuda Triangle.
It is a very useful
in human and mouse systems.
It is a conserved feature.
The last data
is the model of
Bermuda Triangle.
It is a model of
a bacteria-type
all-body infection
that will kill itself.
It is a model of
a bacteria-type
all-body infection
that will kill itself.
It also increases
the dose of the infection.
the survival rate
of Bermuda Triangle.
It also increases
the survival rate
of Bermuda Triangle.
It also increases
the survival rate
of Bermuda Triangle.
Before wards
followed by
the hospital ward.
All Wards
are related to
cell migration.
The CDK2
is also needed
by the neutral field.
The CDK2
and its downstream
can improve
the survival rate
of Bermuda Triangle.
We are working on
the CDK2's
downstream substrate,
its target
and its binding factor.
This is our lab.
This is my boss,
Deng Qin,
and my committee.
I have an excellent undergraduate
who has been helping me with experiments.
Thank you.
Let's give him a round of applause.
Remember to turn on the microphone.
Do you have any questions
for Yihui?
I have a question.
It's more detailed.
I don't have much knowledge
about flow cytometry.
You used flow cytometry
to quantify
the amount of RNA.
Is it possible to
label the RNA
using FISH
and then run the flow
to compare
the changes in the amount?
I'm sorry.
I might be talking too fast.
Our RNA levels
are all quantified
using PCR.
We don't use flow
to quantify RNA.
So, in this slide,
you don't use flow cytometry,
but...
We use flow
to separate
the neutral field
from the entire substrate
to do sequencing.
Each red dot
is a cell.
This is a flow chart.
We separate the cells
and extract the RNA
to compare
the amount of mRNA
in each cell.
In this chart,
we only use PCR
to verify
whether the sequencing is correct.
I see.
Thank you.
Do you have
any other questions?
I'm sorry.
I might be talking too fast.
Okay.
If you don't have any questions,
I'll stop the recording.
You can continue
to chat here.
You can email me if you have any questions.