Hello, everyone. I'm your host, Sui-An.
I'm very happy to have you all here today.
The topic is Better Together, Gratitude in Romantic Relationships.
Before we start, I'd like to talk about two things.
First, I'd like to briefly talk about how we're going to do the presentation.
Dr. Zhang will have a few segments in the presentation.
If you have any questions, you can leave them in the chat box.
Or during the presentation, the speaker may pause a few times.
You can ask questions during that time.
During the presentation, because we're live, I'm going to mute everyone's microphones.
Please understand.
Today's presentation is hosted by TAIRA.
TAIRA is a non-profit organization.
We hope that young Taiwanese scholars all over the world
will have the opportunity to share their research online.
Whether you're in the same field or in a different field,
you'll have the opportunity to discuss and learn from each other.
If you're not a TAIRA member yet,
please go to the TAIRA Project website to sign up to become a member.
If you're already a member,
we're recruiting speakers for the second half of this year.
Please feel free to register to become a speaker for the second half of this year.
This is the agenda for today's presentation.
I'm going to briefly introduce Dr. Zhang's academic experience.
Dr. Zhang currently serves as a post-doctoral postdoc researcher
at the Central Institute of Sociology.
Her current research project is called
Unmanned Mobility-Affected Experimental Situations.
Her main field of research is psychology.
Her research topics include emotions, interpersonal relationships, and culture.
Before she returned to Taiwan to serve as a post-doctoral postdoc researcher,
she graduated from the Department of Psychology at the National Taiwan University
and obtained a bachelor's degree.
She then continued to study at the National Taiwan University Psychological Research Institute
and obtained a master's degree.
The topic of her master's thesis is actually a continuation of today's topic.
Her topic is how to express gratitude and adapt to a partner's lifestyle.
After graduating from her master's,
she went straight to the University of North Carolina in the United States
to study for a doctorate degree at the University of North Carolina.
I find her research topics very interesting.
There are several main parts.
For example, if we express gratitude in our daily lives,
does it mean that people from different cultures have different cultural differences?
Or, can gratitude make us a better person, a better version of ourselves?
Or, if we talk about intimate relationships,
what kind of role do partners play in intimate relationships or physical contact?
Another part is the so-called self-exceeding emotion.
What does it have to do with a person's participation in society?
I find Dr. Zhang's research very interesting.
What's interesting is that it's not a research in a ivory tower,
but rather how we can apply theory in our daily lives
to make psychology a very practical and helpful science for humans.
Before I hand over to Dr. Zhang,
I have a personal story to share with you.
Dr. Zhang is a very important mentor who led me into the field of psychology.
When I was in college, I was his research assistant.
I think Dr. Zhang is someone who cares a lot about humans.
I think his research is not just about knowledge.
He really cares about how we can make humans a better human being.
So, I won't go into too much detail.
Let's welcome Dr. Zhang to share his useful speech with us.
Thank you.
Thank you, Yian, for the introduction.
It was a very complete speech.
I feel like I wasn't as serious as I was when I was a host last week.
Thank you very much.
Let's get started.
The topic of Yian's speech,
Gradually Romantic Relationships,
was written by me.
That's right.
You can see it on PowerPoint.
If there is an emergency,
let me talk about it first.
like if I suddenly lose connection or can't see the slides or something,
but I can't see everyone's chat,
Yian, please send me a message.
My phone is next to me.
You can still see it.
If there is something like this, please let me know.
All right.
I wrote the topic myself.
What you see on PowerPoint now
is purely because the word romantic is too long.
It will squeeze the relationship to the next line.
I think it's ugly, so I changed it.
But most of today's content will still be in Romantic Relationships.
Although it's not just Romantic Relationships,
most of it will be here.
This is the first one.
The second one is
I don't have much content to prepare today.
So if you're in the middle,
is there anything you want to clarify?
Or I didn't make it clear.
Then you need to clarify.
Or is there anything you want to discuss?
Some ideas.
In fact, I welcome everyone to put it out in the middle.
As for the method,
Yian has already introduced it.
So you can put it out.
If we have a chance,
we can discuss it.
The third one is what Yian just said.
Like my master's thesis.
It's true that the content I'm going to talk about today
is what I've been doing all the way.
But I'm not going to talk about that today.
There are some other related studies.
But I welcome everyone to ask questions.
We may be able to talk about these past studies
during the time of questions.
I'm going to focus on a few new ones today.
And then we're actually halfway there.
The reason is because I don't want to...
Because I don't know if you've heard of my previous stuff.
I'm afraid I'll repeat it later.
It's a waste of time.
But if you don't know,
you're welcome to ask questions.
Then we can mention it by the way.
Okay, let's get started.
Okay, I'm going to talk a little slower now.
As Yian just said,
a large part of my research all the way
is about the feeling of gratitude.
In interpersonal relationships,
especially in intimate relationships,
there's a lot of influence
between people who are close to each other.
This kind of emotion,
which we usually call emotion,
is generated from intimacy
and how it can be reversed
to influence the quality of intimacy, etc.
In literature,
there is a major theory
that talks about the function of gratitude
in interpersonal relationships and intimacy.
From a functionalist perspective,
we're going to talk about its function.
The conclusion of this theory is actually quite simple.
Gratitude is...
The function of its evolution
is to help us promote
and maintain high-quality intimacy.
To be more specific,
this is how it works.
Let's imagine that
we're walking around like this in our daily lives.
Suddenly, one day,
at a certain moment,
a person,
no matter who it is,
a stranger, a close person,
anyone,
did something to us
that is worth praising.
For example,
today,
I forgot to bring my keys.
Then I called my wife.
She said,
wait for me.
I'm nearby.
I'll send your keys back.
She did this for me.
For me,
it's very...
In terms of evolution...
No, let's not talk about evolution.
For my life,
it's very useful.
It's a very effective thing.
In terms of evolution,
of course,
as an individual,
how can we recognize
that these people
will do something effective, useful, and helpful to us?
Some people won't.
We need to interact with these people for a long time.
Don't interact with another group of people for a long time.
This ability becomes very important,
very functional,
and very effective.
This is why gratitude appears.
Let's say my wife
brought my keys back today.
She just went out
and brought my keys back.
Then I'll have this emotion.
The emotion of gratitude.
It's a bit like
there's a light bulb in my head.
Then it lights up.
That light bulb is the feeling of gratitude.
It reminds me
that the person I'm interacting with
is a good social partner.
He is a person
who needs to interact well
in my future life.
This is the first step.
Okay?
My feeling of gratitude.
But just the feeling is not enough.
What I just said is important.
How do I fix this person
in my future?
So gratitude
will be very natural.
Everyone must have experience like this.
The feeling of gratitude
will naturally
produce a grateful expression.
For example, the simplest
I would say thank you.
This is a very natural expression.
Of course, everyone can think of
many different ways of expression.
This is what I just mentioned.
When I was doing cultural research,
I was doing cultural psychology research.
Cultural research is another
huge field.
So I'm not doing all of it.
When I was doing cultural psychology research,
I was looking at
people from different cultures
expressing their feelings of gratitude.
But no matter which culture it is,
no matter how it is expressed,
it is expressed anyway.
Through this expression,
what I want to do is
let my wife
know that
I am a person
who knows how to be grateful.
I feel it.
I let her know.
This is very important
because it will let my
social partner know
that this person
is a person who knows how to be grateful.
So she can recognize
that I am working hard for her.
My efforts for her
will not be in vain.
In the future,
she will want to
interact with me
in theory.
This is still theory.
She will want to interact with me.
Then we can form a...
I don't know if this example is good or not.
But you can imagine
that there are two atoms
and they are far apart.
It doesn't matter.
But slowly they will
get closer and closer
to each other.
Then they will be fixed
as a pair.
This is the concept.
Then they will be fixed.
This kind of pair
will help a lot
when facing
the risk of evolution,
environmental challenges, etc.
This is the phenomenal level.
On the psychological level,
there is a very important concept
in the literature.
It is used to...
It is a very strong concept
that predicts the quality of the relationship
and maintains it.
It is called
Perceived Partner Responsiveness.
TPRM.
How to translate this?
Actually, I'm not sure
how to translate this.
Perceived Partner Responsiveness.
What does this mean?
Let's talk about the first two words.
It's simple.
Perceived Partner.
I see a characteristic
in my partner.
This characteristic
is called
Perceived Responsiveness.
As a person,
I see this characteristic
in my partner.
The first two words,
Perceived Partner.
Something perceiving the partner.
What is Responsiveness?
Responsiveness is
my partner.
I see that my partner
wants to take care of me.
He wants to meet my expectations
and needs.
This motivation
is called Responsiveness.
If I see
a quality in my partner
that wants to take care of me,
then I perceive
some responsiveness in my partner.
This is it.
This is my subjective
perception of my partner.
What kind of person
is my partner?
This is my subjective perception.
This perception
can be found to be
a strong factor
in maintaining and stabilizing
the relationship.
So,
on a psychological level,
the expression of Gratitude
conveys
the feeling of Gratitude.
As I said,
the feeling of Gratitude
is to let me know
that my partner
is a good social partner.
Specifically,
what kind of partner is it?
It's a Responsive partner.
The feeling of Gratitude
is like
when you book online shopping.
When you book online shopping,
a box will be sent to your home.
The box is Gratitude.
When you open the box,
it's filled with Responsiveness.
It's like a carrier.
When you open the box,
you can see
the Responsiveness of your partner.
On the other hand,
the feeling of Gratitude
when we show it
to our partner,
it's the feeling of Gratitude.
However,
when the box is opened,
it's also the feeling of Responsiveness.
Through the exchange of Responsiveness,
the relationship stabilizes.
So,
I'm going to talk about some...
This is the theory part.
I'm going to talk about some
real-life research
to support this theory.
By the way,
I don't have a lot of videos.
It's usually like this.
I stop for a night
and then I keep talking.
So if you want this,
for example,
a citation
or related information,
you can ask me in person.
No problem.
Okay.
There is a research
that is done like this.
I don't know if you know
the structure of
the American University Sisters' Association.
In the first week
of their freshman year,
at least in Virginia,
in the first week of their freshman year,
at the American University Sisters' Association,
the little sister,
the freshman,
will be assigned
to a big sister,
for example,
a sophomore,
a sophomore in college.
But
these sophomore students
are responsible for
taking care of their little sister.
But
the funny thing is
that the first week
is anonymous.
So the little sister
actually doesn't know
who their big sister is.
Only their big sister
has to take care of her
little sister in silence.
It's like the Little Angels.
This is the first week.
Then,
after the first week,
there is an opening speech.
It's like,
who is your big sister?
Then
they will become
a pair.
This research
uses this opportunity.
I'm going to talk about this research now.
This opportunity
during the first week
to ask these little sisters,
how much do you think
your big sister
takes care of you?
How grateful are you to her?
Even though you don't know who she is,
how grateful are you to her?
How much do you think she takes care of you?
These two phenomena,
one is the feeling of gratitude,
the other is
perceived responsiveness.
Then they measure this thing.
Then,
they use this thing to predict
and reveal
who your big sister is.
Who are the big sisters of these little friends?
After a month,
the satisfaction of the relationship between the two parties.
Then he found
in the first week,
the gratitude of the little sister
will predict
two people after a month.
Two people are
satisfied with the relationship between the two of them.
Then this degree is
the first week
little sister's perceived responsiveness
to terminate.
This is a
display of
gratitude can predict
subjective evaluation of the relationship,
stability,
some degree of stability indicators,
and is a long-term effect of a
related study.
In terms of intimacy,
there is another study,
which is very similar.
He asked the recipient
every day,
I remember it was 28 days,
3 weeks,
21 days,
every day,
he asked the recipient to answer
gratitude,
did he express gratitude to you?
Did he express gratitude to you?
How grateful are you
to him?
Then
thank you?
This degree is a
display.
Finally,
how committed are you
to the relationship?
That is to say,
this is called loyalty.
I think loyalty is a bit strange.
How serious are you?
How convinced are you of this relationship?
Then put in this way.
Then you can imagine,
because it is a long-term
study of 21 days,
so every day,
if the data is drawn,
there will be ups and downs,
high and low.
So to some extent,
this study is actually a bit like
an experiment,
or what we usually call a type experiment.
Because if one day I write high,
that is, I am in the high
experimental group,
and then one day I write low,
that is, I am now in the low experimental group,
high, low, high, low,
I will have
all kinds of experimental situations.
Everyone can imagine this way.
So to some extent it is a bit like a type experiment.
Of course, such a situation is
there are many recipients,
each group will have many recipients.
What did they find?
They found that
the first study I just talked about
was about
grateful, grateful
side, accept the benefits,
grateful to this side of the person.
But my other
study, he found that
when my partner expressed gratitude to me,
I accepted the side of gratitude.
If my partner
expressed gratitude to me,
if my partner expressed gratitude to me today,
at the same time,
today I will have more
commitment to our relationship.
So
on the other hand,
he supported this theory,
Find, Remind, My Theory,
this theory,
it is true that expressing gratitude is effective,
it can help us fix
accept gratitude,
first good to us,
and then accept our gratitude
.
Then I will talk about the last
study,
the last study, it is a complete
experiment, the question he asked
was a little different,
instead of saying that he wanted to
examine the phenomenon of this theory,
that is, on the phenomenon of gratitude,
can it help us maintain our relationship?
What he wanted to ask more was
what kind of way
to express gratitude and maintain a relationship?
He revealed the past literature,
he said, you see,
gratitude can really maintain a relationship,
but what kind of behavior,
what kind of action,
you can even say that it is an action
to maintain a relationship.
In fact, it is a bit like the cultural research I did,
but he did not ask about culture,
he did not look at the difference between cultures,
he looked at whether there was
a general action.
In this
literature on interpersonal relationships,
everyone can try it later,
there is an action in the literature on interpersonal relationships
that can
predict the maintenance of
this relationship,
for example,
when I am talking,
I touch my nose while
I grab my nose like this,
or I will be used to grabbing my head,
or I am used to sitting on the chair,
what I am doing now is rotating,
rotating,
and these are not meaningful behaviors.
Everyone will have something like this
when they talk,
if we imitate this behavior of other people,
for example, I am talking now,
then I will grab my nose,
then you also listen and it seems to be
something like that.
It seems to have nothing to do with what we are talking about.
But they find that
when we have a conversation or
one talks, one listens,
to ask the speaker,
that is me,
for example,
ask me how much I like
the person in front of me
who listens to me or talks to me.
People who are imitated
will feel that they prefer the person in front of them.
It seems that he and this person
have the same pain.
The two people are
relatively close in frequency.
Then this research can
be done in the past.
You call a
experimental group,
then the professor will come
and ask him to give him a manuscript,
casually ask him to speak a little speech.
Then in the process of asking him to speak,
call the experimental group to imitate his actions.
Imitate his actions without discrimination.
Of course, this research will ask
the speaker
to say
how strange you think the other person is,
how deliberate
you have been,
how strange you are,
and if you notice that you are being imitated,
let's delete it first.
We only leave those who do not notice
and do not feel that they are being imitated,
but are actually being imitated.
As a result,
there is another group,
the control group,
which is not deliberately imitated.
The group of people who are being imitated
will prefer the experimental group,
and in the future
they will prefer the experimental group.
In the past research,
I found this.
Therefore,
I want to talk about this research,
probably everyone knows
what I am going to do.
It is to trigger the feeling of gratitude
in the laboratory
,
and then see
if the person who has the feeling of gratitude
will run to imitate other people's behavior.
Use this kind of
secretly imitating, subconsciously
imitate other people's behavior
to promote the relationship between the two people in the future.
Let's talk about the conclusion first.
The conclusion is, of course,
suppose
my wife sent me the key
and I felt very grateful,
then I said thank you to her.
In the process,
I may even forget to say thank you,
but I will start to subconsciously imitate
some of her actions.
After she gave me the key,
she was going to leave,
and I started to feel
that Zhang Yiping was more friendly,
and I felt better.
Something like this.
But the conclusion is this.
I like this research very much.
This is a team from Singapore
in 2015 or 2016.
He did it very,
very carefully.
This is also another feature of
good emotional research.
He will do things very carefully.
First of all,
although you can produce a group of
grateful groups,
for example,
when you give them some benefits
when the recipient comes,
for example,
give him some money,
let him feel more grateful,
then you ask him,
he will feel good,
someone gave me money,
I am very happy,
it feels like one group is more grateful,
the other group is more ungrateful,
but at the same time,
the money is not only grateful,
there must be some kind of luck,
or today the sun came out from the west,
and there are some
feelings of surprise,
but these feelings are not
grateful,
but other emotions.
So this research team
at the same time
created several
different experimental scenarios
to distinguish these different emotions,
the most important of which
is to feel very lucky
and feel very grateful.
The method is like this,
he first invites the recipient
to collaborate with the experimenter,
he tells the recipient that the
experimenter is another recipient,
but he is actually a collateral,
he plays a small game with the
experimenter,
and in the process,
the experimenter and the collateral
can work together to achieve the goal,
or they can compete with each other
and see who gets more points.
Then,
in one scenario,
he makes the collateral compete with the recipient,
so the collateral becomes
a jerk,
so everyone hates him,
this is the most basic baseline.
In another scenario,
the experimenter lets the collateral
cooperate with the recipient,
so the collateral becomes a good person,
but at the same time,
he also distinguishes two situations,
he tells the recipient that
whether the collateral wants to
cooperate with him or not,
he decides,
so if he cooperates today,
he is really a good person,
he intentionally wants to be good to you,
if he doesn't cooperate,
he is a bad person.
But in another situation,
he doesn't have much control,
he just randomly instructs the recipient
whether he wants to cooperate with him or not,
so even if he cooperates with you today,
his potential regret is that
if he cooperates with you,
it's not his credit,
it's just the order he received.
So,
here they have three groups,
the first group is the baseline,
which is a jerk,
you hate your collateral,
he doesn't cooperate with you,
you hate him.
If he cooperates with you,
you will feel grateful,
but if he happens to be instructed
to do good to you,
you will only feel lucky,
you will not feel grateful.
Then they continue to do this,
they tell the recipient that
this time is over,
we will go to the second stage,
it has nothing to do with the first stage,
but you and the collateral
are going to have a dialogue discussion,
then he is going to see
if the recipient is going to imitate
the action of this collateral,
and then he found that the lucky group
actually did not imitate the phenomenon,
only the grateful group has,
it shows that it is not as long as we are happy,
any positive emotion
will produce bonding,
social bonding behavior,
there will only be grateful,
at least luck will not have.
Then,
how do we measure this
imitation?
He asked
this
collateral
to touch his hair
if he had nothing to do,
and then count
the number of times
you touched your hair
during the second stage of the dialogue.
There is a
configuration here,
there are viewers who want to provide
that the experiment you are talking about
has been verified on the operation,
is there a check of manipulation?
Yes,
they just asked,
they later asked
at the end of the experiment,
because sometimes the check of manipulation
will not be in the middle of the test,
they will say at the end
what do you feel about this person,
what kind of emotions do you have,
and then there are about 20 emotions
to ask them to evaluate,
and then it is true that the grateful group
is grateful, the lucky group is lucky,
and then the baseline group
is the baseline,
so there is,
thank you,
and then he went to
count the number of times
he touched his hair,
and then it is true that he
touched his hair more than once,
but there is a confounding,
there is another possible
explanation,
he just feels grateful,
he just can't sit still,
he likes to move around,
so he just touched his hair more than once,
this may not have anything to do with
specifically imitating the other person's behavior,
do you understand what this means?
As long as I become very active,
and then touch my heart,
I will touch my hair more than once,
but it doesn't matter if the other person
is touching his hair,
how do you know that it is because
the other person is only touching his hair,
maybe it's just right,
so they used several different actions
, one group is touching his hair,
the other group is touching his nose,
and then one is touching his ears,
so what we want to see is
if today is going
this hyperactivation,
that is, this kind of
explanation that can't sit still,
then he just has to
touch his ears, touch his nose,
touch his eyes,
all of them have to go up together,
there is no variability,
but if it is an imitation behavior,
then there is also a variability,
that is, there is also a variability,
so much talk,
I found that I talk about this research,
how to the next page,
so much talk,
in fact, the conclusion is that
I just said,
gratefulness will be produced
through behavioral imitation,
this bonding effect,
this is a possibility,
that talk so much,
in fact, just want to demo,
then put it in a variety of ways
to control time,
finally to talk about
our own research,
we can pause
it,
because now just to a section,
then there are
viewers want to ask questions,
I directly open the microphone to ask him,
please,
you say,
he may just become very active,
I keep moving,
but you can not put him
the number of times,
normalize by the total movement,
that is to say,
he changed his hair
in all of his actions,
the proportion of the amount,
that does not matter,
he becomes very active,
this thing,
then you can not put him
the number of times,
then he becomes very active,
this thing,
this is actually a good practice,
it is also a practice that we often do,
but indeed this research,
not this research,
is the same team
of the last publication,
he did this way,
but the next one,
they tried to use the experimental way
to do the effect directly,
not just to control it in a statistical way,
that is,
in theory it is feasible,
but if you can do it,
that is, I am very powerful,
I can do it,
so more of that,
when you see his experimental design,
wow, this is so smart,
but you are right,
indeed a lot of people do this.
Hi,
my name is Steffie,
I am a PhD student at Nanjia University,
but I do not have a background in psychology,
but what I want to ask is,
you said gratitude,
this emotion,
and gratitude expression,
I think they may have a little different definition,
do these two have,
that is, there is research
that shows that they have a proportional relationship,
or is it possible that someone has this emotion,
but actually does not express it,
then it may be more like the definition part,
because I have read some
articles related to emotion,
and their definitions may be
different,
some people are more focused on
physical reactions,
or in the mind,
psychological feelings,
I do not know what you think of this,
and what you think the definition is.
OK,
let's talk about the simple one first,
or let's say the most difficult one,
this is the most difficult one,
because this is the most difficult one,
or let's say the most difficult one,
the most difficult one is how to define the emotion,
then how do I define it,
I think only the subjective feeling,
I personally, I personally,
I believe that many people do not say this,
I personally feel that the emotion is the subjective feeling,
I feel very grateful today,
that thing is called grateful emotion,
I feel very angry today,
then
that subjective feeling,
I call it emotion,
the rest,
you can say, for example,
how do I express my anger,
that is called grateful expression,
how do I understand
the context of my anger,
or the context of gratitude,
that is my perception,
part of the emotional perception,
but I will not put all these things
are called grateful,
are called grateful emotion,
because in fact there is no meaning,
and this is not the same as the general common people
is that there is a gap,
you have to define that word,
I do not care,
but this definition is very strange,
so I would say
only the emotional part is,
so this also,
in a way, I guess I also answer your
other question,
is grateful emotion and grateful expression,
why is it different,
grateful expression is focused on discussing
his physical actions,
but the emotional part is my subjective feeling,
okay,
that two things are not related to it,
I can,
the data shows that
my subjective report,
how grateful I feel,
this subjective report
with my grateful expression of behavior
is really related,
this is probably not very surprising,
and is highly relevant,
this is certainly not surprising,
but I think everyone may not be very surprised,
that is, this is definitely not related to
someone is fake,
in fact, you do not feel,
but you must
elders
give us some
gifts that we do not like,
we have to say thank you to the scalp,
this kind of thing we also have experience,
this kind of thing also exists,
it also explains why it is not related,
on the contrary, there are many times
grateful expression of the situation,
such as strangers do something to you,
then you feel very grateful,
for example, you do not even meet strangers,
for example,
he silently put this
community hall
very clean,
but you do not meet this person,
then how to express to whom,
so this situation is also there,
so there is no emotional expression,
so to answer your other question,
these two things will not be highly related,
whether it is related,
whether it can be divided,
so it is like this,
did I miss any questions?
No,
I do not think so,
I just want to say,
I know they define different,
I also understand those points,
I do not know if there is a overlapping part,
what is the overlapping part,
you are now a bit of it,
emotion is a subjective feeling,
so that person himself
knows if he has this emotion,
then the expression
may be external,
you can observe
behavior,
so the two are completely
completely separate two things,
in your mind,
I prefer to be like this,
I just look at it now,
that is to say, Mark said that emotion
is a system,
I know a lot of people have this
angle, but I do not
say that emotion is a system,
I would say that there is a system of
emotion around
gratitude,
I want to say that gratitude is a good emotion,
there is an expression next to it, there is an observation next to it,
there are cognitive components next to it,
there are context components,
there are even cultural components,
it has a system,
this is what I can agree with,
but emotion is a system,
I want to say this,
many people say this,
you walk on the road,
see how people use the word emotion,
no one uses it like this,
if you don't use it like this,
you have to define it like this,
I think it's a bit deliberate,
and
it's not necessarily helpful,
I think,
this is my own comment,
but I'm sure a lot of people
outside will say that emotion is a
system,
I think it's a bit different.
Yes, I probably understand that angle,
I have seen some related
articles before,
some people will argue that
sometimes emotions
appear subconsciously,
and sometimes they follow subjective feelings,
I have seen this kind of statement,
so I want to ask
what the people in the background really think, thank you.
But I can't
represent everyone
to talk about this matter,
but I personally
always feel that the field of
emotional research is independent
or has relative independence,
because it has feelings,
and it has very strong subjective feelings,
this is why we call it emotional,
if you say there is an emotion,
he can't feel it,
then we say that it is a different
psychological state,
no normal person would call it emotion,
it's weird,
I don't know what I mean,
so next I want to tell you
this research,
this is a more
exploratory research,
we want to
ask a question,
thank you,
indeed,
my partner and I,
both can promote interpersonal relations,
past research has also found,
past research has also found some
physical mechanism,
or
behavioral mechanism,
but these components
between
independence
how about it,
how much overlap between them,
so we have to ask this question,
in this research,
we found more than 200 couples,
I think it's
400 to 500 people,
we both
came early,
then ask them to
record every day,
did the other person
say thank you to me today,
pay attention to this behavior,
did you say thank you to me,
did I receive the other person's
gratitude, both
people hit, so you can see
received by me
and received by my partner,
then there is express,
it seems to be gone,
it's gone,
but I can't see the video,
wait a minute,
OK,
this is a slide,
so
in the 14-day process,
we ask both people
to record every day,
did you express your gratitude to me,
did you say thank you to me,
at the same time,
did you say thank you to your partner,
you can imagine,
I thank my partner,
I say thank you to my partner,
it's a pair,
it's just the same event,
then from two different angles,
two different people's
perspective,
so these four measurements
can be paired like this,
from me to my partner,
and vice versa,
my partner can also flow back like this,
so it's two pairs,
then we take these four
events
to predict every day,
we also ask the receiver
to answer every day,
how satisfied are you with
your relationship with you today,
and then there is,
yes, that's it,
and then we can calculate
ups and downs,
like the design of the experiment,
then we use these four events
at the same time to predict
every day,
ups and downs,
the result can be seen,
that is,
the same one,
let's say it's a gratitude episode,
I thank you,
then you are thanked,
the same episode,
you say I thank you,
I say I thank you,
from the perspective of two different people,
then we found that
this is what I say,
now the green one is what I say,
you thank me,
then I say I thank you,
then this is what you say,
I thank you,
you thank me,
we found that these four
are enough for my
prediction effect,
and it is an independent
what does this mean?
Yes, I will feel better,
my relationship will be better,
what does this mean?
Let's talk about these two green ones first,
these two are more intuitive,
these two are
if you thank me, I will feel happier,
this is a bit of nonsense,
you thank me, I feel happier,
this is very intuitive,
if you thank me, I will feel happier,
because there should be something good happened,
I have to thank you,
so I should be happier today,
but we found that
this green one
means
you thank me,
you say you thank me,
I will be happier,
and this thing is independent of
whether I say you thank me,
although I say no,
I did not notice,
do you thank me?
Although my reaction today is like this,
this invisible thank you
will still reflect
my satisfaction with my relationship today,
do you understand?
This is invisible,
because this thing is independent,
our research has made it independent,
I say you thank me,
although I say no,
the part you say will still reflect
my satisfaction with my relationship,
the more strange thing is that
the audience asked
how to record
or measure
the so-called thanks
, how to do
the more objective part
?
We use binary measurement,
so yes or no,
do you thank others?
Yes or no,
we let both of them answer,
so we can stack their data
from left to right,
it is a binary measurement,
this is more strange,
you say I thank you,
although I say no,
I do not remember,
this is strange,
because it is independent of my expression,
at the same time I will feel happier,
although you say I thank you,
but I say I do not remember,
I will feel happier,
we have an explanation for this thing,
because everyone can see
this relationship,
we draw it like this,
let it become a loop,
you think I thank you,
then you will express to me,
then you will do something
to make you a better partner,
so it will become,
I will get a better partner,
I will feel happier,
this is a long shot,
this is an explanation,
we have not tested yet,
but this is a possible explanation.
At the same time,
I finished this chapter to ask you a question,
at the same time,
we also measured
the relationship between
these beneficiaries
,
the degree of satisfaction
for their own lives,
not for this relationship,
but for the overall life,
there is the same effect,
and this effect is completely
terminated by relationship satisfaction,
here I want to stop
and ask you a question,
we have a question
here,
he wants to ask about the binary part,
then ask Felix directly,
is Felix there?
Hello,
I am Felix,
the question I want to ask
is related to the binary part,
because now the senior
is asking
if they feel it,
my question is
how many times a day
do you throw it out
and ask him
if he feels it?
Or ask him after the day
to recall how many times he received
and how many times he thanked?
This is a good question,
we only ask once a day,
before going to bed,
did this happen all day?
Okay, thank you.
Hello,
I have another question,
where is this done?
What is the background of the object?
These people
are in
Beka
Triangle
,
so the object
is the person living there,
who is it?
Anyone over the age of 18,
basically anyone over the age of 18,
if I remember correctly,
the youngest couple,
the youngest victim
is 18 years old,
our low standard,
we ask them to be 18 years old,
the oldest is
67 years old,
if I remember correctly.
OK, thank you.
I think this should be
supplemented,
you can imagine,
if our age range is so large,
their relationship should be very large,
just started dating for a month,
married for 20-30 years,
so this range is
a nice range.
Is there any question from the audience?
If not,
I have a question myself,
I would like to ask the senior
in this study,
do you have any control,
which is the main
confounding?
Yes,
this is also a very good question,
we ask him every night,
do you thank people,
have you been thanked,
we actually asked a bunch of
different things,
some of them are more important,
in the past, it was also found that
the satisfaction of the relationship
is a very important prediction,
including whether the other party
has done half of the plus,
we are not asking this,
we are asking if there is
a fair amount of plus or something,
anyway, it is a similar wording,
fairness, reciprocity,
this is very important,
this is basically
the most important component of
subjectivity is difficult to say,
but subjectivity and reciprocity are very important,
we have control of this,
the result is the same,
we also have control of
whether the other party is very polite,
how do we say
courteous,
we have control of this,
so gratitude is not
purely fair,
gratitude is not purely
polite,
we also control self-disclosure,
did the other party tell you something,
did you tell him something,
so it's not like this,
because it's not necessarily a matter of gratitude,
sometimes it's just a boss,
but in the past,
it was found that it was quite effective
to do it together,
so we have to control this,
and then we also control
whether the other party
performed very positively today,
in general,
are you a happy person,
control is purely positive,
it seems that any positive
mood is possible,
we control it,
so it doesn't matter,
so gratitude is not just happy.
Thank you, the audience here has a question,
Felix, please ask,
hello, I'm Felix,
I just asked a question,
then I want to ask one more question
for the one just now,
the mayor is now the last day,
the last day to ask him if he is grateful
or grateful,
so I want to ask,
so there is no measurement of the number of gratefulness?
No,
OK,
thank you,
this is a very good question,
because in experience sampling,
because our approach is
more like experience sampling,
that is to say,
continuously and then constantly
for the audience who do not know this method,
I think Felix may know,
for the audience who do not know this,
experience sampling
at what time to measure,
then how densely measured the frequency,
this is very important,
because you will catch
different research questions,
this thing,
I wait a minute,
I can think about it now,
I didn't talk about it now,
I'll talk about it later,
for me, everyone will know
how to catch different research questions,
especially different
temporal scope research questions,
do we still have time?
That is now
about to go,
it's almost 9.30,
see if there is any time
on the senior side
to arrange or think about it.
OK, I will finish this time in 5 minutes,
then we will finish, OK?
OK.
The next research
is very similar
to the previous research conclusion,
we just want to make the effect of gratitude
into an experiment,
not just observation,
in addition, we use
not only subjective
subjective assessment of
relationship satisfaction,
we use a more objective assessment,
that is, how much time
do you spend with your partner
? Why do we choose this
objective assessment?
For this
animal research,
more experienced friends
should know,
we are studying this
mouse, when the mousetrap
this
two mice together,
stay together for how long?
That is, we measure whether they have bonding,
so
the strength of their bonding strength,
human bonding strength,
to a certain extent,
can be measured in this way,
and this can help us pull our research to
animal research,
then this is a second
is that we use the experiment
so this experiment
is the way to measure
the first two weeks,
the first 14 days,
we asked them to go home
and do the same as just
this report,
this report is how much time
you spend with your partner,
how much time you spend today,
no matter what you do,
anyway,
and then go to the lab
to do the experiment,
there are two groups,
one group is that we
remind him to go home
and remember to thank him,
remember to say thank you,
another group is that we
give him a little nudge
I'll talk about later,
but then put them home,
then they record four weeks,
28 days,
every day you spend with your partner
how much time together,
then we want to see
these two groups
after receiving the experiment
from the front to the back,
there is a group that has increased,
a group that has not increased,
or increased not so much,
how do we do it?
We told him that this gratitude is great,
go back and remember to say thank you,
this is the first control group,
the experiment group is grateful,
then you have to remember to say thank you,
in order for you to achieve this goal,
we ask you to help you do a
gratitude plan,
but this plan is to fill in the
following blank,
when if anything happens,
then you write
how you want to express gratitude,
I'll give you an example,
for example,
when he helped me buy breakfast in the morning,
then I want to give him a
kiss to express my gratitude,
I wrote it like this,
this plan is done,
then we look at this
one-line plan,
four weeks after going home,
is there a four-week effect?
It sounds quite incredible,
for some people,
it may sound a bit incredible,
it's like writing a fill-in-the-blank,
and you have to influence how long
they spend together a day,
they don't spend time together,
just follow the plan,
how much can it affect,
I'll give you an example,
this method of manipulation
is called Implementation Intention,
in the document,
it is found to be a very simple
but very surprising effective
way to change behavior,
for example,
in this study,
we divided the subject into two groups,
one group gave them
a reminder,
it is very important to check the
uterus,
their subject is a 55-year-old
or a few years older woman,
British,
remind them that the uterus is very important,
then you have to participate in the
test,
if you want to make an appointment,
there is a phone number below,
remind him,
then you have to make a plan,
for example,
someone will write,
if it is lunch time,
then I have to call my doctor,
then make an appointment,
please help them
have an appointment
plan,
we are exactly the same,
the result found
reminder group,
then participate in
the appointment,
then participate in the appointment,
did not miss their
appointment ratio,
about 70%, 69%
on the left,
but only this one-line plan,
you can add the
attendance rate
to almost 100,
in fact, 92,
but this one-line plan
is very effective,
you can try in life,
I have tried very effective,
it does not matter to us now,
the point is that it is effective,
it is also effective in our experiment,
one-line plan effectively
improved the group of
participants in the
experiment after the
ratio of gratitude,
but this is a manipulation check,
because we want to know
whether the time together
has not changed,
of course, you can imagine
that there is,
of course, it is from the front to the back,
the experiment group increased
every day,
the average amount of time
together every day,
then the unit is a minute,
so it is nearly 80 minutes,
an hour and 20 minutes,
then the gray is the error bar,
then the red is the
control group,
then the control group is basically
the front to the back,
there is no change,
there is no change in their time together,
this is not surprising,
but one-line plan
can increase
the average time of
physical presence
every day for 80 minutes,
then you can see
below,
of course,
we have to break down
and see what you are doing
together,
then across the board,
for example,
they sleep together,
then together,
then share the project,
they are together and do
the same thing,
they are cooperating on some things,
separate project,
they are in the same room,
with each other's physical presence,
but
they are doing their own thing,
for example, you two
work from home together,
they are in the same room,
across the board,
the gratitude group has a noticeable effect.
Finally,
we have measured
a remote communication,
that is, how much time
do you spend with your partner?
Remote communication,
what does it mean?
This is to compare
that they may spend more time together,
but there is no physical presence,
they spend time together,
but there is no physical presence.
Indeed,
in this aspect,
the gratitude group
not only does not increase,
but also significantly decreases.
In other words,
gratitude has a kind of
desire for our audience,
again, this is a triangle,
this is an American,
they will have a physical
contact.
Let's go back to the mouse.
This is very important.
For this
biological research,
it is more experienced,
you may know,
physical contact,
for example, we touch
our partner,
or our partner touches
our body,
it will produce a series of
physiological chemical
cascade.
One of them
is a neurotransmitter
called oxytocin.
What is it?
Oxytocin,
in Chinese,
oxytocin.
This oxytocin
is found in the mouse,
it is actually difficult to predict
bonding.
Let's look at this mouse.
These two mice are
pre-reborn,
their characteristics are that
after mating,
they will stay together
and form an exclusive
monogamous bond.
They are not
so similar to humans,
humans are not so monogamous,
but you know what I'm talking about.
But the relatives of primary
volts, middle volts,
are not like this,
they do not have
exclusive bonds,
they are
mating, then you can change partners,
but their genes are very similar,
but at least
the social bonding
is very different.
Then the study found that
oxytocin plays a very important
role in this.
Indeed,
by manipulating the primary volts
and the middle volts
oxytocin receptor,
we can make these mice
operate from
exclusive bonds
into open relationships.
We can also make open relationships
into exclusive.
Indeed,
because of this reason,
we collected the urine of
these mammals
to measure
their oxytocin
amount.
We have this marker inside.
Now back to the previous point,
why
the daily report method,
if you are in one day,
randomly find a time to BIP your
victim, or you are
the last time to sleep
to a summary,
there is a difference,
because we can imagine
if we do today is
a general biological experiment,
many times we will say,
no, the most accurate draw at the scene,
so you have to know how high
now you have to draw now,
so if you draw out, you will be very
accurate to know
the degree of oxytocin now,
then you can ask
the degree of oxytocin now affects
the human behavior
in this moment.
But we all know,
I feel oxytocin now,
then I have bonding,
I may not have the opportunity to express gratitude,
I may have to spend
you do not know if I am now
you thank me, my oxytocin is about to rush up,
or two hours later
rush up to make me
express my gratitude to you at night?
I do not know, because the time was pulled
very long,
so once you study the problem,
this temporal scope becomes larger,
you may need to measure the way a little change,
such as we use urine, because you do not
urine inside the oxytocin marker
is basically
considered to be a certain extent
or a long period of time
oxytocin level average,
because the urine
to hold for a while in the temporal scope,
so you high, high, low,
then after the average, the amount of marker will stay in your
urine, so it is a relatively long-term average,
with us in front of the
daily report is similar,
so when we ask the question now,
if you spend how much time today,
we may be this kind of measurement
is more
fit measurement.
I'm done, I'm done.
If this is the case,
we are starting at 8.33 today,
I think we
can now open to everyone
to discuss about
9.50,
if anyone has a question.
In addition to the audience
today is the content of the speech
if there is a question, if the speaker
past research or
so on, you can ask
questions.
If you want to ask a question, you can speak directly.
I am Felix.
I have a question about oxytocin.
Because I saw a document a while ago
that said oxytocin
seemed to think in the past
that it can predict a relationship
directly,
but that
study revealed some documents
and found that, for example,
in mice, some oxytocin is very
high, it even has some aggressive behavior,
and then in humans,
it seems to be the attachment
that affects the
effect of oxytocin.
I don't know if you have any
opinions on this.
Have you found that people with high oxytocin
don't necessarily spend
more time on this?
Let's talk about our research first.
I haven't analyzed the oxytocin data yet,
so I don't know.
This is a quick answer.
In our lab, another study
found that oxytocin level
has to interact with social
contacts to have better
predictability.
We found that
if your partner is grateful to you,
but your
expression basically
sucks,
then your oxytocin level is useless.
If you are not a good
partner, what are you playing?
You are playing something, you know,
nothing. So there is an
interaction. Your partner
is a good partner, and your oxytocin
is higher, and their bonding
will be stronger.
Back to what you just said,
I totally agree with
what you just said.
For those of you who don't know
the oxytocin literature
or the social regulation function of
oxytocin literature, a little background.
In this,
a lot of news
in the first ten years,
oxytocin is called
love hormone.
As long as your oxytocin level is high,
you are world peace.
Everyone is a good friend.
They gave it a name
called love hormone.
But in the past few years,
I feel like everyone is moving
in the direction
of what Felix just said.
What kind of behavior
will oxytocin cause
has a high interaction
effect.
Rather than a love hormone,
it is a social hormone.
If your oxytocin is high,
your social sensitivity will be high.
So if you are with a good partner,
you will have a lot of love.
But if you are with
your enemy today,
you will become very aggressive.
It will be more aggressive than
it used to be, because you are now
very socially sensitive.
Rather than a love hormone,
it is a bonding hormone
or a social regulation hormone.
I feel like oxytocin
is more like this.
My own attitude is that
oxytocin should be like this.
So I agree with Felix.
Thank you.
Do you have any questions
for the audience?
Do you want to ask
yourself?
Okay.
There is a question
from the audience.
If you want to follow
the social distancing rule,
if you want to express
gratitude to your family
or partner through
social media,
is it useful
for bonding?
Or do you have
any suggestions
for this special period?
Okay.
I don't have data,
but I think it's useful.
I think it's useful.
The reason is that
you can imitate
other people's behavior
and it will be effective.
But you don't have to
see it face to face.
You can still see it
if you turn on the video.
This is the first one.
The second one is
about gratitude.
There is a similar study
done in our next lab.
It's like this.
It's like
asking a veterinarian
to come to the lab
and watch a funny YouTube video.
You've probably seen it.
It's a funny YouTube video.
At the same time,
there is an experiment partner
watching it with you.
This is another veterinarian.
At this time,
the two people will watch the video
and laugh, right?
Because it's a funny video.
There are two manipulations.
This is an experimental group.
One is
the partner
laughing with the veterinarian
at the time of laughing.
The other group is laughing
when the veterinarian is not laughing.
Then the two people
find out that
after laughing together,
there will be a better bonding.
Even though
their total laughter volume
is not high,
but there is a
countermeasure.
Why am I talking about this?
Because I just talked about this.
The partner is not actually
on the spot.
He actually used Webcam
to laugh.
So there is only one person in that space.
So it's like social distancing.
For example,
your partner is far away.
I don't know about you, but I'm in Taiwan.
Let's say my partner is in New York.
Let's spend some time
watching a funny video
and laughing together.
I think it will have a good effect
on bonding.
The last one is
more abstract.
But
even if there is no video,
there is no
visual information.
Studies have found that
when we hear some sounds,
our visual cortex
will react.
It's like we're going to
visualize what we hear.
So when you read a novel,
sometimes it looks like
there is a picture, right?
Talking on the phone
and laughing together
even if you don't see people
will theoretically have some effect.
And anyway,
in the process of
self-isolation,
there are
interpersonal relationships,
no matter what form, far, near,
visual, no visual, only sound,
or a card, text, etc.,
far better than
visual.
That's my prediction.
I believe there are
a lot of data to support it.
Our time is up.
This is the last question.
I don't know if you have any questions.
If not,
let me summarize
and ask you a question.
I've learned a lot
from your talk today.
As someone
who cares about marriage,
and we're in self-isolation,
we're stuck together
under the same roof.
I've learned a lot
from your talk today.
Do you have anything
to say to people
to help them
implement
self-isolation
after the pandemic
and recovery?
Oh, I see.
I think
implementation and intention
are quite fun.
You can try to write it down
and see what you can do
with it.
I think if you can
use it to help you
pay more attention to
the things you should be grateful for
in your life,
it will be very helpful.
Why am I talking about
the things you should be grateful for
in your life,
instead of the things you should remember to express?
Because
research has shown
that it is easy to express
something that is not sincere.
But
when you are truly grateful,
you may feel
that you are not expressing yourself,
but others can see it.
So for me,
it's about being grateful,
not expressing it.
Implementation and intention
is a very effective
method that I think
can help you achieve this goal.
So you can write it down.
For example,
if he helps me buy breakfast this morning,
I will
say thank you
instead of
remembering to say thank you.
I will cherish this breakfast
that he bought for me.
But today,
if he helps me buy breakfast every day,
I will cherish it.
Next,
my assumption is that
I will express my gratitude
smoothly,
so I don't need to say it again.
But the emotion part is quite important.
Okay, I'm done.
Okay, time control is very good
and very practical.
Thank you Dr. Zhang Yanping for
joining us today.
I hope that everyone
has a wonderful and healthy day
whether it's day or night.
Thank you for your participation today.
Thank you Dr. Zhang Yanping.
Thank you.
Okay, the recording should end here.
Okay.