Welcome everyone to the Taira Talk on April 11th.
We are honored to have Xiao Zhigang to give us a speech.
Today's topic is
Single Photon Emission from Single Electron Transport
in a Soul-Driven Lateral Light Emitting Diode.
It seems to be related to quantum computation.
Our speaker today studied in Hsinchu.
He went to a research institute in NTU.
He said that his research results were mainly in thermonuclear conduction.
After graduating from the institute, he studied in the UK.
Now he is doing his PhD in QTEC at Daft University in the Netherlands.
Before we start, let's give our speaker a round of applause.
Please remember to turn on your microphones first.
Let's give the floor to Xiao Zhigang.
Good morning, good afternoon, good evening.
No matter where you are, I hope you are all safe.
What I'm going to talk about today is mainly my work as a PhD in QTEC.
It was published in Nature Communication in February this year.
The citation is here.
If you are interested in more details, you can refer to this paper.
I'm not sure about the level of the audience today.
Or maybe everyone's field of expertise is different.
So I'm not going to go very deep today.
I will use some more straightforward methods to express.
If you have any questions, you can ask directly.
If you have questions online, it will be more interactive.
Today's main work is to introduce a new or a new way to produce single-ray.
We use a surface wave in a structure similar to an LED to produce a single-ray.
Today's topic is mainly about quantum communication.
Quantum computing is what I am studying and researching in QTEC in the Netherlands.
If I have a chance later, I will share it with you.
Anyway, today is mainly about quantum information technology.
What kind of applications does quantum information technology have?
I believe everyone has seen the movie.
Quantum technology can make people shrink or travel through time and space.
The Avengers tells you that quantum mechanics can achieve these things.
But here I can tell you that these are all nonsense.
These things have nothing to do with quantum mechanics.
Anyway, now the movie is that no matter what it is, if you can't explain it, just use quantum mechanics.
Okay, let's get serious now.
So today is mainly about quantum communication.
The main thing that quantum communication is doing is basically written very clearly in this review paper.
Quantum communication is basically the technology of transferring a quantum state from one place to another.
In quantum information, the traditional quantum state is carried by light.
The so-called light is the basic example of light.
In quantum communication, we use light to carry a quantum state.
So if you can produce a single light, you can use this single light to carry a quantum state.
One of the applications of quantum information is the so-called quantum key distribution.
Basically, this protocol is a person named Alice.
She sends a series of light, a series of single light.
She encodes the quantum information into the direction of the light.
The receiver Bob can get the quantum state of this light.
Then she randomly selects and measures the direction of the light.
Of course, I won't talk about the details.
But through such a protocol, they can establish a quantum key that shares with each other.
After establishing this quantum key, it can be used to encrypt their information.
The advantage of this protocol is that if a third party tries to steal the information in the process of transmitting the quantum key,
they will find out that the communication channel is not safe.
We should stop and try different channels to do this communication.
This is one of the important applications of quantum communication.
More interesting quantum communication often uses a very important feature in quantum mechanics called quantum entanglement.
What is quantum entanglement?
For example, there is a quantum state here.
Its quantum state is a superposition of 0, 0 and 1, 1.
If it is such a superposition, it can send one of the light to Alice.
Then send the other light to Bob.
When Alice goes to measure the information of this light value, it can be measured to 0 or 1.
0 and 1 here is the quantum state of the light value.
For example, we can make it horizontal or vertical.
For example, you can define that the horizontal deviation is 0 and the vertical deviation is 1.
When Alice measures the quantum state, it will randomly get 0 or 1.
When Bob measures the quantum state, it will randomly get 0 or 1.
But because these two lights are in a quantum entanglement state.
So when Alice and Bob compare their results,
they will find that when Alice measures to 0, Bob will also measure to 0.
When Alice measures to 1, Bob will also measure to 1.
The characteristics of such a quantum entanglement are very important in quantum communication.
Using such an entanglement state can achieve so-called quantum teleportation.
The main reason is that you produce a quantum state of light here.
Then send one side to Alice and the other side to Bob.
Alice will do another entanglement at the local stage.
In this way, she can teleport the light on her side to Bob.
In the process, Alice did not directly throw this light to Bob.
But she can teleport this light to Bob.
Another application is that one day we can use a light
as a bridge between two local quantum computers.
For example, we can convert the quantum state here into light.
We can transfer this light to another quantum computer through light or air.
Then convert this light to the quantum state of light on the local quantum computer.
In this way, we can achieve a far-end connection between two quantum computers.
We can also use light as a quantum component in quantum computing.
We can use the quantum state of light to do quantum computing.
This is mainly some of the main applications in quantum communication.
In all these applications, there is a very important...
Can you see the screen here?
Is it blocking the title?
No?
OK, it's fine.
In all these applications, there is a very important component, the so-called single light source.
You must have a light source that can emit a light.
When you want it to emit a light, it will emit a light.
You can trigger it to emit a series of light.
They are separated in space and time.
What is the difference between a single light source and a general light source?
First of all, we can imagine that a classical light emitter is like a water spray gun.
When you press it, it will spray out millions of water molecules.
For example, you can't control that I only spray one water molecule at a time.
But the single light source is a bit like a pistol.
When you trigger it, it will shoot a bullet.
So this is the main difference between classical and quantum light sources.
More specifically, the difference is in their light statistics.
Suppose we have a coherent light source, for example, a general laser.
Its light distribution is positive Poisson distribution.
This means that suppose you have a laser.
Let's say you have a very small hole.
The light can only pass through that hole very little at a time.
But no matter how you reduce the intensity of the light,
you will find that even if your average light number is 1,
when you measure its light distribution,
you will find that it is not all the same light.
40% is 0 light, 40% is 1 light, 20% is 2 light, and 5% is 3 light.
For example, it is not an on-demand single photon source.
The so-called single photon source, a perfect single photon source,
will meet the sub-Poisson distribution.
In a perfect situation, you will find that
the number distribution of the photon in its light source
is 100% when it is under 1.
This is the biggest difference between classical and single light sources.
In general, most of the so-called single light sources
are produced in a very simple way.
Hello.
Can I ask a question?
Yes.
Can you go back to the previous slide?
In quantum mechanics,
we have the uncertainty principle of light.
For any quantity of uncertainty,
you have delta P times delta R,
which is greater than the percentage bar.
I imagine that if you have an uncertainty distribution of light,
which is the standard deviation of light,
what is the corresponding delta something?
Phase.
The phase is completely uncertain.
So if you squeeze the light into a single light source,
the phase will have a very large standard deviation.
Yes.
Oh, okay.
I forgot.
Okay?
Let's continue.
Okay.
The way we produce a single light source on the mainstream
is actually very simple.
You prepare a two-level system.
You have a ground state and an excited state.
But the important thing is that in your system,
you basically can only see at the same time,
or only control one,
you can only have one two-level system.
If you can isolate a two-level system,
then you use light or electricity,
no matter what, to trigger something.
Are you okay?
You trigger it.
Because in your system,
there is only one two-level system,
so you can only produce one exciton.
This two-level system will decay in its exciton lifetime
back to the ground state and produce a single light source.
After decaying back to the ground state,
you trigger it again.
In the exciton lifetime, it will decay again.
Basically, you go through this cycle.
Then you can produce a single light source one by one.
Basically, the mainstream single light source so far
basically uses this method.
Of course, there are some that use nonlinear queries,
which are different.
I won't discuss it here.
A single emitter or two-level system like this
can be found in many different systems.
For example,
let's use a few examples.
For example, we have a trapped ion.
Suppose you can trap an atom in your cavity.
Because there is only one atom,
when you trigger it,
it will emit light one by one.
Or let's say,
in a diamond defect,
a nitrogen vacancy,
such a defect can also be used as a single photon source.
For example,
in the recently popular 2D Transition Metal Dichrogeny,
this 2D semiconductor,
you can also use some of its structural defects
as a single light source.
Another,
currently
the most mainstream method
is to use the self-assembled quantum dot.
The self-assembled quantum dot
basically looks a bit like
you sprinkle some water droplets on a table.
Because of the surface tension,
these water droplets will be connected one by one.
After the connection,
you can cover them all
to form a single quantum dot.
For example,
I am now pointing at a single quantum dot.
These quantum dots
can also be used as a single light source.
Basically,
as you can see in this photo,
there are more than ten quantum dots.
So you have to cover all the other quantum dots.
For example, just look at this one.
If you only look at this one,
you will find that
when you stimulate it,
you will get a single photon emission.
But quantum dots
have some shortcomings.
There are some shortcomings in practical application.
One of them is
because of the way it grows,
it is difficult to control its size.
And it is difficult to control
where it will grow.
For example,
this is an example.
You see that these dots
are randomly distributed.
You can't control
that I want a dot
to grow in a certain place.
This kind of randomness
will result in
a less ideal
composition.
Another point is
when you use light
to stimulate a quantum dot,
you may get
a bi-hexatone emission.
Because of the binding energy of the bi-hexatone,
you will see that
its energy and hexatone energy
are a bit different.
In this case,
you have to use a spectrum filter
to cover the bi-hexatone
so that you can get
a pure single photon emission.
Yeah.
OK.
So this is the mainstream method.
What I'm going to talk about now is
that we want to try
a method that has been proposed
for 20 years
but has not been done
before this paper.
Basically,
what we want to do is
to mix two things together.
OK.
Basically,
you can think of it as
a LED and a wave.
This is a wave.
I'm using a wave now,
but in practice,
it's a wave.
We combine a LED
and a wave.
With some special device production,
we can achieve
a single photon emission.
Yeah.
OK.
First,
let's talk about
what the LED and the wave are.
I'm sure everyone is familiar with LEDs.
In Taiwan,
you can see a lot of advertising boards.
These things are all made with LEDs.
It's easy to find LEDs on the platform.
OK.
The main structure of LEDs
is like this.
It has a P-type semiconductor.
There are a lot of electrons in it.
Electrons are
how to say
lack of an electron.
You can compare it to a hole.
It's like an electric hole.
Here,
there is another N-type.
This section
mainly has a lot of electrons.
If we combine the electron and the electric area,
we will have a P-N junction.
The P-N junction
looks like this
in the conduction band and the valence band.
OK.
When you want them to glow,
what you have to do is
apply a forward bias
so that the electron and the electric area
can overcome
the potential barrier.
When you apply a sufficient forward bias,
the electron will flow to the electric area
and the electric area will flow to the electric area.
Then you can
combine them in this place.
When the electron sees the electric area,
it will decay
and combine with the electric area
to produce light.
This is a very simple
LED
way to produce light.
It's very simple.
Why can't we
LEDs
generate single light?
Because when you
add a forward bias,
you don't let
one electron
combine with one electric area
at a time.
At the same time,
you can't control the number.
Suppose
we can't
make a LED
and
when you
trigger it,
it will only have one electron at a time.
It will only have one electron at a time
to combine with the electric area.
In this case,
you can imagine
that it should
produce single light.
OK
Then
So we talked about
a way to
transmit an electron at a time.
In this experiment,
the technique we used
is a surface wave.
A surface wave
is basically
a wave.
But this wave
will produce a dynamic
electric potential.
This potential
can carry electrons.
It's like a wave.
This wave can carry electrons
to overcome a potential barrier.
After overcoming it,
you can control
the amplitude of the surface wave.
You can control
how many electrons you need to carry at a time.
So
in theory,
if we can
carry one electron at a time,
we can
let only one electron
reach the electric area at a time.
Then we can produce a single light.
OK
What about
the surface wave?
In Taiwan,
we've all experienced it.
A surface wave
is caused by
an earthquake.
A part of the wave
is transmitted by a surface wave.
A surface wave
has a low frequency but a high amplitude.
So it's highly destructive.
It's like
a wave
transmitting on the surface.
OK
As I said,
in general,
we've all experienced an earthquake.
So how can we
produce a surface wave
on a small device?
We need to
use the so-called
opamp.
The so-called opamp
is
when you
add an electric field,
it will cause a change in shape.
At the same time,
when it causes a change in shape,
it will also cause an electric field.
OK
So we
use this opamp
to produce
a surface wave
on our chip.
The method is
as shown here.
We have
a cross section
of an electric field.
The cross section
of the electric field
determines
the frequency
of the wave
when it
transmits
on the surface.
OK
When you have
something like this,
when you send an AC signal,
an RF signal,
and a GHz signal,
when it meets
the resonance frequency
of the transducer,
it will produce a surface wave.
The so-called resonance frequency
means that
the change in shape
produced by
each electrode
causes
constructive interference.
This wave will
pass through here.
OK
So
when we
use this
surface wave,
our material is
gallium arsenide.
Gallium arsenide
has the property of
suppressing materials,
so we can directly
produce a surface wave on it.
We can use this
potential wave
to move electrodes.
An experiment I did
in my previous group
is that we have two conductors,
one on the left, one on the right,
and one on the left.
At the same time,
there is only one electrode inside.
The experiment I did
is very interesting.
I can send a surface wave
in this direction,
and push this electrode
to the left.
I can also send a wave
from left to right,
and push this electrode to the right.
It can move like a table tennis ball.
They demonstrated
that they can
move 60 times.
This kind of technology
is actually
Sorry
Can you hear me?
Yes, I can.
I have a question.
I'm a high-performance engineer,
so I have a question.
How large is the potential
of the electrode
you draw below
the surface wave?
It's basically
gigahertz.
Gigahertz.
Yes, it's gigahertz.
The electrode you carried
is said to be
as close as possible to
the gap between
the surface wave and the electrode.
Is it better
or worse?
You don't want it to be bigger.
You want it to be
just the right size.
Basically, you want it to pass
the steepest
potential barrier.
At the steepest point,
it will only leave one electrode.
It's just right.
It depends on
the size of the surface wave.
Okay.
How large is the scale?
I don't know much about semiconductor.
It's probably
a few
MeV.
It's m, right?
Yes.
Okay.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I have a question.
Okay.
Here,
in the transport
experiment,
from left to right,
what is the
distance
transmitted?
The
length scale here
is one UAM.
So, have they
tried...
5 to 6 microns.
So,
this experiment was done
at low temperature.
Yes.
You have to be able to
define a quantum dot with an electrode.
So, you have to
do it at low temperature
to see the discrete state.
It's probably
I forgot.
It's probably 1K or 200
microns.
Okay, got it.
I also have a
question.
That is,
does this wave
need to be horizontal or vertical?
The second question is
that
the electrode is very small.
So, the electrical field
it feels locally should be...
If your wave is
symmetric,
the electrical field it feels should be
oscillating back and forth.
So, do you need to
make the surface acoustic wave
as asymmetric
so that it has a
directional run?
No.
So, it just followed the first wave?
Yes.
Okay.
Does this
surface acoustic wave
need to be horizontal or vertical?
It produces...
Let me think about it.
It should be
horizontal.
Acoustic should be horizontal.
Acoustic can be horizontal
or vertical.
But it produces...
I don't know.
I don't know
if the transducer
produces a horizontal or vertical wave.
Okay.
I think...
I don't know if I have it here.
So, we can
see it like this.
Actually,
the direction
is like this.
Circular.
Okay.
So, it's mixed together.
Yes, it's mixed together.
It's really like water.
So, it's not just a wave.
Yes.
Okay.
So, I hope
I answered your question.
Yes.
Okay.
Last question.
Can this
produce a standing wave?
Yes, it can.
Yes.
So, if I produce a standing wave
and there is a transducer
on both sides
and produce a standing wave,
is it possible...
Because now
the speed of the wave
should be
similar to
the speed of
the semiconductor.
Yes, but if there is
a transducer on both sides,
if you change the relative phase
on one side,
you can basically move
the wave slowly.
Yes.
Can you do it?
I think I can do it.
Yes.
It won't be limited to this.
Okay.
Yes, I think I can do it.
But...
I think I forgot who said that.
But I don't think I have
done this before.
Yes.
Okay.
I have a question.
Yes.
How do you make sure
that is a single electron?
How do you measure it?
So,
a structure like this
has two quantum dots.
One on the left, one on the right.
But there is
a channel like this.
There is a channel like this.
This channel
has a very sensitive
conductance.
Basically,
if there are 0, 1, or 2 electrons,
it will affect
the channel conductance.
So the way to measure
the number of electrons
is to measure
the channel conductance.
It can
tell if there are
0, 1, or 2 electrons.
Yes.
This is a very
common technology
in gate-defined quantum dots.
It's called charge detector or charge sensor.
Okay, thank you.
Okay.
Is this QPC?
This is QPC.
Okay.
If you want to have another quantum dot,
you can use charge sensor.
But it's easier to do it in this experiment.
Okay.
It's okay.
I just want to make sure.
Okay.
So, I mentioned
that I combined two things.
LED and surface wave.
Let's combine these two things.
We want to
combine these two things
to produce a surface wave.
This is how we do it.
I'll show you an animation later.
But I'll use my mouth to explain.
I'll
make a LED first.
I have electrons here.
I'll make a surface wave.
This surface wave
will modulate
the potential of conduction band
and valence band.
What's more,
an important component
is that
I want to create
a 1D channel
in the middle of
the electromagnetic field.
This 1D channel
can control
the width.
Basically,
you can add two side gates
to control the height of the potential.
You can control
the width of the channel.
the width of the channel
so that only one electron
can pass through.
If only one electron can pass through
and produce a surface wave,
let's assume
that the potential
between the electromagnetic field
and the wavelength
allows the surface wave
to produce a single light
when only one electron
can pass through.
Now I have an animation.
I hope you can
watch it smoothly.
This is my device.
This is the
energy diagram.
electromagnetic field.
This is the 1D channel.
The potential of this 1D channel
is controlled by the side gate.
When I hit the surface wave,
it will start to push the electrons.
The electrons will push
forward.
Because of the channel,
only one electron can pass through.
When this electron is combined
with an electron,
it produces a single light.
The potential will carry
the next electron.
So it will produce a single light
one by one.
This is
how I
produce a single light.
Any questions?
I think you will
talk about it later.
So,
the gate on both sides
control the Fermi level
so that
both sides
are electric.
Yes, I will talk about it later.
I guess you will talk about it later.
Sorry to interrupt you.
So next I will talk about
how to make this device.
Basically,
what's interesting about this project
is that I don't need
a random quantum dot
or a defect.
This device
can be
fabricated
deterministically
in any
place I want.
What it needs
is
very conventional
photolithography and
electromagnetic electron.
You don't need
any random
thing.
This kind of
device is
good for
software integration.
So,
the starting point is
GaN and
AuGaS's quantum web.
I didn't show
the diagram here.
It is
a plane
that allows
electrons and electrons
to exist.
First of all,
the next step is
to pattern
two surface gates.
Here is a surface gate
and here is another surface gate.
These two surface gates
are used
to accumulate
electrons and holes.
For example,
if I want to
generate electrons here,
I just add a positive
voltage to this gate
to accumulate electrons.
Here,
I just add a negative voltage
to accumulate electrons.
When I add the voltage,
I can control
electrons and holes.
What's more convenient is that
electrons and holes
are controlled by voltage.
I can even
swap them.
I can have electrons
and holes on both sides.
This is
a flexible
device.
Next,
I just mentioned
that I need a 1D channel
so that
each time
only one electron
can pass through.
I will make an etch.
Basically, I will use
the method of 10 electrons
to eat up
the electrons and holes
where electrons and holes
can exist.
The dark part
of electrons and holes
can't exist.
Therefore,
they can only pass through
the middle path.
Maybe
the etched channel
is still too wide.
I may need to add
two side gates
to control
the size of
the channel.
OK.
Next,
let's search.
Excuse me.
Hello.
I have a question.
You showed the picture.
How wide is the channel?
Is it sub-micron?
It's about a micron.
I will show the device later.
Thank you.
I will show the actual device.
I want to ask
a stupid question.
The etched channel
has
gallium arsenide and
aluminum gallium arsenide.
It's
aluminum gallium arsenide
and gallium arsenide.
It's a quantum well.
Does the etched channel
exceed
the two-deck?
Yes, it exceeds
the two-deck.
It exceeds the two-deck.
Yes, it exceeds the two-deck.
If you
control
the voltage
below the two-deck,
does it affect
the width
and narrowness
of the two-deck?
I think so.
It's right next to the two-deck.
Yes.
OK.
I just thought of it.
Sorry.
The etched channel
affects the two-deck.
It doesn't affect
the two-deck.
It affects the two-deck.
The two-deck is close to the two-deck.
Yes.
I will continue.
Next,
I want to generate
a surface wave.
I will make a transducer.
It's the one I just mentioned.
It's a transverse
electrode.
After I add
a transducer,
I can
use
the RF frequency
to
generate a
surface wave.
It will push
the electrode
to the
electric area.
When the electrode
is pushed to the electric area,
it will
combine
with
one of the electrodes.
The two electrodes will
form an exon.
After the two electrons form an exon,
the two electrodes will decay
to form a photon.
Basically,
this is how we
generate a single-beam.
I just showed you the animation,
but now I will show you
step by step.
This is
my actual device.
This is my
sole transducer.
I use it to generate the sole finger.
This electrode
is too small, so you can't see it.
But it's basically
a transverse electrode.
The gate
to accumulate
the electron hole is here.
You can't see it now, but you will
see it in the next image.
It looks like this.
This side is for
accumulating the electron, and this side
is for accumulating the hole.
For example,
these black spots
are where I use
VH to remove them.
These
dark spots
are where electrons and electrons can't exist.
The surface wave
will come from this direction.
It will
pass the electrons
to the electron area.
Next,
I will talk about
the results of the experiment.
First, I mentioned
that this is basically
an LED plus a
surface wave.
I need to make sure
that my device
works like an LED.
So,
what I am doing is
I am accumulating the electron
on one side, and then
accumulating the hole on the other side.
Then, I can apply
a source-engineering bias.
A bias.
Theoretically,
you would expect that
when the bias
is greater than
the Gaussian bandgap,
it will
allow the electron
to overcome
the potential barrier.
The same goes for the electron.
The electron can run to the other side.
In this case, you will see the current.
Basically,
the Gaussian bandgap
is about
1.55EV.
So,
you will see
when I apply a bias,
when the bias is greater than
1.54EV,
the current will start to occur.
Basically,
this graph
shows that
my lateral
p-n junction
really works.
OK.
Next,
when we want to create a source-driven
single-photon source,
what we need to do is
make it unable to shine
normally.
So, what we need to do is
reduce the bias
to 1.45EV.
Basically,
if I extend it,
it's about here.
So, basically,
if you don't do anything,
when the bias
is kept at 1.45EV,
nothing will happen.
There will be no current flowing,
and there will be no light.
OK.
When I
add an
RF signal,
an AC signal on the
soul transducer,
at its resonant frequency,
it will produce a surface wave.
Then you will expect that
at the frequency
of the surface wave,
if it can carry
electrons
to the electric field,
you will see the current.
OK.
Basically, it's like
an elevator.
When you draw the potential,
it will look like this.
The blue part is
when you don't add
the soul,
the potential will look like this.
When you add a soul,
it will start to look like this.
The soul will move forward,
and the electrons will move up,
and bring it to the electric field.
It's like an elevator.
OK.
Here,
I'm showing that
when I
add RF signal,
satisfy the soul transducer
resonant frequency,
I will see
something happen.
At this X axis,
I'm measuring the
AC signal frequency.
Then,
at the Y axis,
I'm measuring the current
size.
Basically, you can see
that at about
1.16 GHz,
around 1.16 GHz,
you will see a current
suddenly generate.
Other than that,
there is no signal.
At this frequency,
we designed
the soul transducer's resonant frequency.
So you can see
that at this
resonant frequency,
it seems
that the surface sound is generated,
and the electrons
are brought from the electron field to the electric field.
So we see a current generate.
At the same time,
we can also measure
the light signal.
Now,
the blue part
is the current,
and the red part
is the light signal.
You can see that the light signal
and the current signal
are basically matched.
At the same frequency,
I see the current.
This current
represents the electrons
being brought to the electric field.
Electrons and electrons are combined,
so the light is generated.
You can see that the light signal
and the current signal
are basically matched.
Because the area of light
is only
about a microsquare.
So this is
basically
to scan the light signal.
Then I found that
I saw light in a very small area.
Light is generated in this area.
This area
basically corresponds to
the location of the electric field
we designed.
Okay.
I just
described
that
at this resonant frequency,
there seems to be a wave on the surface
that causes
electrons to be brought to the electric field
to emit light.
But we want to further prove that this is true.
So what we do
is that we have a
time-resolved optical setup.
Basically,
I want to measure
how the light
emits
over time.
How do we
do this?
We have a pulse generator
and an RF source
to drive
the wave on the surface.
First, we synchronize it.
Then,
I synchronize the pulse
with the RF signal.
Then,
I send the pulse
to a
Time-to-Digital Converter.
When the
converter receives
the pulse signal,
it is a stopped pulse.
Then it starts to count.
After it receives the signal,
how long
will my
light detector receive
one light?
Or multiple lights,
as long as there is a light signal.
Once it receives the light signal,
it will send a stopped pulse.
Then the Time-to-Digital Converter
will give
the time delay
between light and pulse.
If my RF source
looks like this,
and if my soul
is the same phase,
then my
photon
will be carried
by the soul's
minimum.
So the moment it is generated
is basically the same as the
minimum time.
If my RF signal looks like this,
then my Time-to-Digital
Converter's
histogram will look like this.
It will be a signal
with a time interval.
For example,
at 0.5 ns,
I will have a very strong signal.
At 1.5 ns,
At 2.5 ns,
I will have another signal.
Basically, it will be the same
as the RF source's
cycle,
as well as the soul's cycle.
Next,
I want to prove that
this signal really comes from
the surface wave.
I believe everyone in Taiwan,
because I just mentioned an earthquake.
As we all know,
an earthquake occurs in Hualien.
When you are in Hsinchu,
when you feel it,
there will be a time interval in the middle.
We can use
such a time interval
to prove that
this signal really comes from
the surface wave.
First of all, my device,
its soul transducer
and my p-n junction,
its interval is about
1 m.
I also know that
the surface wave's speed
on gallium arsenide is
about 3000 ms.
You can calculate
its propagation time
is about 400 ns.
So when you
hit a pole...
Sorry.
We are running out of time.
I don't know how much time you have left.
Maybe you should speed up.
OK. Thank you.
OK.
So we know that
there will be a time delay of 400 ns.
What I do here is
I have a time delay.
I have a pole.
I hit the pole's RF signal.
When the pole's RF signal
is applied to the soul transducer,
I see that
there is no signal.
But interestingly,
after 400 ns,
I can see a lot of RF signals.
This delay
proves that
this signal is really
caused by the soul's
propagation
and the electron's
interaction with the electron.
What's more interesting is
when I zoom in
to these RF signals,
I can see that
they are a series of peaks.
A pile of peaks.
The cycle of these peaks
is exactly the same as the period of the soul.
This means that
we are really using the soul
to inject
each electron
into the electric field.
This proves that this is really
the light signal produced by the soul.
OK.
I'm almost at the end.
In the end,
how do we really prove
that we produce a single ray?
One thing is that
when a single ray
has two cameras,
this single ray
can only be seen
by one of the cameras.
It can't be received
by two cameras at the same time.
So it's not received by camera 1,
but by camera 2.
OK.
Suppose I have
a
time series digital converter.
I go to see its start
and stop.
Because it
can only be received
by one detector
at the same time.
You will find that
when a single ray
is really produced,
there will be no time delay
equal to 0.
Because time delay equal to 0
means that two detectors receive the light signal at the same time.
OK.
So there will be no time delay equal to 0.
Here is an example.
This is a very good single ray on the file.
You will see a signal like this.
When time delay equal to 0,
there is no peak.
There are peaks in other places,
but there is no peak at 0.
OK. Now back to my experiment.
First of all,
when I send
more than one light,
one electron,
through an autocorrelation histogram like this,
I will see that
when time delay equal to 0,
there is still a very obvious peak.
And it's about the same height as everyone else.
However,
when I control the strength of my source
and the height of my
potential barrier,
I can control
only one electron
through each time.
On average, there is only one electron
combined with the electric current.
Then it becomes like this.
You can see that
the peak of time delay equal to 0
is obviously suppressed.
It's not 0.
It's different from the
very good single photon source I showed earlier.
It's not perfect.
I can only say
that
there is still a certain chance
that two light will be generated at the same time.
But the chance of
one light is
increased.
Basically, the signal of time delay equal to 0
is suppressed.
Then I can
do a probability estimate.
I can compare
in the same situation.
Suppose it's a Poisson distribution.
It's a black
rectangle like this.
Suppose
it's my source.
I can see that the probability of a single photon
is increased.
Then the other
states of 0 light and multiple photons
are suppressed.
My experiment
shows that
because of this design,
the probability of
increasing single photon emission
is increased.
OK.
These are the results of my experiment.
Thank you.
OK.
Does anyone
have any questions?
Can I ask a question?
Sorry.
You go first.
I want to ask
how do you think
to correct the imperfect part
you just said?
How do you correct
the imperfect part?
OK.
For example,
I think there is a problem.
The confinement
caused by SOHL
is not strong enough.
So
this
in this
during the transmission of SOHL,
the number of electrons
is not
completely
one by one.
Sometimes it's two or sometimes it's zero.
I should
improve my confinement
so that
the probability of
single electron emission is higher.
That's basically it.
Thank you.
OK. Thank you.
Can I change my turn?
OK.
My question is
I want to
use the
Garmin Ascend to make a
dark matter detector.
Can we contact you later?
I think there are some bad details
and some noise.
OK.
Anyway, my question is
if you don't use
your SOHL to drive
the channel,
it's like
a calibration run.
Will it leak?
Will it leak to the other side?
You can still see it.
I'm not sure what you mean.
You said don't use SOHL.
Yes. Don't use it.
And you keep measuring.
Can you measure anything?
There should be only background.
First of all, there is no light.
Electronics can't
combine with electronics.
There will be no light signal.
So you can see the background
on both sides.
But you can't see
the random event
of your single photon.
The light signal on the other side
may not come from the device,
but from the environment.
Yes. But in my scenario,
I don't know when it will appear.
If I want to use it as a detector,
I need to know
the random event rate.
What do you mean?
If I don't trigger it,
will there be a fake event?
What will the fake event look like?
What is its source?
First of all,
the source of the noise
may be the detector itself.
It depends on what kind of detector you use.
For example,
we use the Avalanche
single photon dive.
Even if you
cover all the light,
there may still be
10 coms
every second.
These 10 coms are all fake.
This has nothing to do with the real signal.
Of course, there are some
fake events.
So you mean
the background counting
comes from your
APD, right?
Yes.
Or if you have a
more powerful device,
it may also come.
I imagine
there must be a pulse tube
in your refrigerator.
If the pulse tube keeps shaking,
it means
you didn't pulse your source,
and there will still be an event.
The frequency
should match the resonance frequency.
Oh, I see.
I understand.
We will keep in touch.
This is very important to me.
Thank you.
I have a question.
Oh my god.
The light coming out now
has no bias.
The bias and phase
are all random.
Is it possible
to hold the gate
and make some micro-structures
to further control
the light's bias
or phase?
Phase may be more difficult,
but if it's bias, it's possible.
There are some ways.
For example, you can do spin injection.
For example, the electrons
you inject
are more of a spin.
For example, a large spin out.
If you use
this method,
if the electrons you inject are all spin out,
it will produce a corresponding polarization.
It will produce a corresponding original bias.
Someone has also
done this.
Maybe you can add
a non-parallel
electrode.
Using its spin-orbital interaction,
you can also use it to
rotate the electron's
spin direction.
You can also use this
to control its spin direction.
At the same time, you can also change
the light's polarization.
Okay.
What about phase?
I think it's
more difficult.
Okay.
Got it.
Cool.
Thank you.
Hello, I have another question.
Okay, thank you.
I'm sorry.
It's a bit like the RLFrequency.
There are two pictures.
One is
the picture with less frequency.
The other is
the light.
Right.
There are
four peaks
in the middle.
What is the corresponding
polarity of these peaks?
This is
because
when you
play RF signal,
Is it the polarity of your pulse?
Let me explain why.
The reason is
when you play the pulse,
you also produce
EM wave.
It's like an antenna.
It also acts as a radio.
These peaks
are caused by the interference
between the radio and the pulse.
I see.
Okay.
I want to follow up
the question of the tab.
You said EM wave is produced
in this.
My question is
what is the impact of EM wave in this area?
Basically,
this is related to
the time result measurement I just showed.
You can see
if EM wave itself can drive
this signal,
you will see that the signal
will produce at the same time
because the speed of light
is much faster than the speed of the soul.
So if there is a signal,
you will see that there is a signal
in this place.
Okay.
Basically,
this tells you that
EM wave itself can't drive
this charge transport.
It can't drive,
so it can't produce light.
Only the soul itself
and its strength
are enough.
This is a very good question.
So
in this experiment,
how much control do you have
on the resonance frequency
of the soul
or the amplitude?
Does it depend on the material
or does it depend on
the transducer you designed?
Frequency
depends on the transducer.
Basically, it depends on
the quality of the transducer.
You can control
how narrow the resonance frequency
of the soul is.
As for the amplitude,
it depends on
how much power
you add to the RF signal.
The more power you add,
the greater the amplitude.
But at the same time,
when you add
too much power,
your sample will heat up.
When it heats up,
the high temperature
for the
transport quantized
charge state is not a good thing.
So
you can't really add
too much power.
At the same time,
we don't want it to be too large
that it can carry more than
one electron.
Then it won't produce light.
I have another question.
It's about the production of components.
Yeah.
When you're using 10 quantum wells,
did you say you're using 10?
Yes.
Why did you choose
10? Because it's not
directional, right?
Yes, that's right.
You mean
if it's dry edge,
the well
will be more...
And like it...
I didn't try.
Theoretically, it should be possible.
But I didn't do that.
Because I just saw
that SM has a lot of residue.
Will it cause some
gradient decrease or even
cause some feedback problems?
It's also possible.
It just so happens that
I didn't do my edge well on this device.
So it's a little ugly.
I see.
Thank you.
I have a question.
I have a few questions.
The first one is,
as far as I know,
there's a very important thing
about producing single photon source.
It's the source's dead time.
How long can it produce
a single photon source?
Because this is very related to
quantum communication.
Even if
you do it very well,
every time there's a pulse,
every time there's a cycle,
there's an electron passing through.
Then the dead time
is about 1 nanosecond.
Because your frequency is 1 GHz.
My frequency is 1 GHz.
Yes.
So its dead time is
about 1 nanosecond.
Is this better than
the general single photon source?
Or is it worse?
Basically,
it's about the same as
the best single photon source's
repetition rate.
The best single photon source
can produce 1 GHz to 3 GHz.
Okay.
So this has potential.
Yes.
The second question is,
I want to know how to
control the
one-time-only electron.
So you have to adjust
the gate voltage.
Is it better to adjust it smaller?
Or is it better to reduce
the number of electrons?
Basically, the less, the better.
In a better situation,
you want to see quantized current.
You want to see
when you change
the gate voltage,
you'll see a quantized
quantum.
Yes.
You'll see a quantum.
That corresponds to
the one-time-only electron.
Okay.
If you can see that, it's better.
My device is not perfect.
I can't see the quantized
current quantum.
I think that's why
my single photon emission
has a peak
that's not really low.
The question is,
why can't you add
a smaller voltage?
Why can't your device
lower the voltage?
If you lower
the electron density,
what happens?
Can't you see the light?
First of all, your signal will be weaker.
Yes.
So you'll need
a longer time
to accumulate these signals.
I think it's okay.
I think it needs to be less.
Yes.
Theoretically, it's okay.
But that means
on average,
the electron density
in the cycle
is 1.
In that case,
first of all,
even if
your source
is a gigahertz frequency,
the light you emit
won't have
light in every cycle.
Okay.
Yes.
That's not
the case.
And then
the brightness will be lower.
Yes.
I think it's okay.
You can still
bring less
electrons
in every cycle.
Of course, it will still emit
light.
So you mean
your experiment
is basically
a one-year experiment.
So if you spend
a year to do this experiment,
the G2 value will be lower.
Yes.
Theoretically, yes.
But...
I think
theoretically, yes.
Okay.
But in practice,
you won't want to do this.
Yes, I understand.
The third question is
the reason why
a single photon source
can become a single photon source
is because...
For example,
when an acetone is triggered,
it can't trigger the second one
because the second one
will have a photon blockade problem.
The acetone binding energy
will be different.
What is the mechanism
of this device?
Your channel is narrow enough
to allow
only one electron
to pass through
at a time.
This is the basic mechanism.
This is very different
from the single photon source
of a single emitter.
Why don't you
use a quantum wire
to do this experiment?
For example, if you use a quantum wire,
it will pass through twice.
Yes.
Do you want to
collaborate with a German team?
This is a good question.
But we...
We want to try it
in the future.
Okay.
That's about it. Thank you.
Thank you.
Do you have any questions?
If not,
I will turn off
the recording.
Thank you.