OK, thank you all for participating in our speech today, I am the host today, Zhang Yanping, I represent everyone with a warm applause to welcome our speaker today, Li Xuanwei teacher, Li Xuanwei teacher, OK, are you shooting yourself?
OK, before I introduce Mr. Xuanwei, let me tell you about some of the events of today's housekeeping, because later when the speaker is speaking, his screen will be a projection of his own projection, so he may not be able to see the dialogue window, if you have any questions, if you want to stick to the dialogue window, if you do not know what the dialogue window is,
now everyone on the right hand side of the BlueJeans may be able to see a row of the audience, and then the second option chat can type, basically a chat window, if you have any questions, you can stick there, but because the speaker will not see, because he is looking at the powerpoint, so if you leave a message, it does not matter, everyone will leave, and then I will find a place to ask questions in time,
either to ask for everyone's behalf, or you can ask yourself, but just stay there, and then I will help the speaker to see, and then I will listen to the speaker today, this time is about 40 to 45 minutes, he will talk so much content, and then there will be 15 to 30 minutes of Q&A time in the back.
OK, so these are housekeeping, and then let me introduce today's speaker, I just said that Mr. Xuan Wei, he is called Li Xuan Wei, today's speaker is called Li Xuan Wei, and then his university is in the Taiwan University Department of State, and then he went to Zhengda Yingshu to read the master's degree, and then after reading the master's degree, his doctorate is in UNC,
the Department of Mathematics at the University of North Carolina, and then the specialized topic is Complex Network, and the topic of Social Network.
OK, after completing his doctorate in 2016, he went to the University of Nebraska-Lincoln to do postdoc, and did it until 2018. Oh, by the way, if I say something wrong, you can correct me directly.
No, this is all public information.
OK, thank you.
I actually saw it on your website.
OK, and then after finishing the postdoc, in 2019, he returned to Taiwan and started his career as an assistant professor and assistant researcher at NTU Politics, NTU Society, and NTU Central Academy of Sciences until now.
Your position should be in NTU Central Academy of Sciences, right?
Yes.
In NTU Central Academy of Sciences, however, there are also students and teachers, and often come and go, on both sides.
In NTU Central Academy of Sciences, Wayne is in the Society, and part of NTU is NTU Politics and Social Peace.
OK, this is the background of today's speaker.
A fun fact is that Wayne likes to eat strawberry cake.
You have to laugh out loud.
That's right, I can testify.
Didn't you get muted?
Actually, this is what we are talking about.
I don't know if he really likes to eat strawberry cake, but if you buy him a strawberry cake, he will be very happy.
OK, let's leave today's event to Wayne.
Let him introduce the topic to everyone.
Let me clap on behalf of everyone again.
OK, thank you Wayne for the introduction.
I am very happy to be able to come to Terra today to share some of the research I did before.
It is also a fun fact that Wayne invited me to give a speech about two or three months ago.
I have heard of Terra before, and now I am very happy to have the opportunity to give a speech here.
It is quite related to Wayne.
We all graduated from UNC Chapel Hill, and we are still colleagues at the Central Academy of Sciences.
We also wrote an article together.
I don't know where the article will be posted.
But I think the world is very small.
We have been in UNC Chapel Hill for three or four years.
I didn't expect to come back to Taiwan and still be in the same place, which is the upper and lower floors.
I can still write articles now.
So things are hard to predict.
There are also many cross-field collaborations now.
Maybe I will share my research here.
Maybe everyone here has a degree or is studying for a degree.
Maybe you are interested after seeing it.
Maybe we can also start some cross-field cooperation in the future.
The time I want to share today is about 45 minutes.
It may be about 11 o'clock in Taiwan time.
I will stay for about 15 to 30 minutes to discuss with you.
If you have any questions, you can come here to discuss.
Although I see 56 pages here, I should say that many of my videos are relatively fast.
Because this is a compilation of two articles.
What I want to share today is within two articles.
So if you are interested, you can go directly to see the two articles.
Whether it is model setting or mathematical inference, I only introduce the concept of these articles to everyone.
If you are interested, you can find articles to read directly.
You are welcome to ask questions, discuss, or write to me after reading the article.
I am looking forward to interacting with everyone.
Okay, let me start by introducing the title of this article.
The title of this article is ...
I have just been responded by two friends that my title is too long and I do not understand.
So I will slowly talk about what this title means.
Using Perceptual Tomography
We want to use something called Perceptual Tomography.
Perceptual is a perceptual thing.
Tomography is a segmented scan.
We will see later why we use the term Tomography.
Of course, we are not really using segmented scanning to do social science research.
We use this Perceptual Tomography to define later.
We want to build a network.
It is a subjective network.
It is not a traditional social network built by the majority of people.
It is a third-party recognition.
What should this group look like?
We ask other people.
We ask some people on the Internet.
Do you think that A and B are related?
If A and B are related, are they close or do not know or are not familiar?
Use this third-party recognition to restore a network.
It is the same as a general social network.
I am talking about the Internet and the Internet.
Sociologists like to talk about the Internet.
Maybe other field scientists like to talk about the Internet.
But it is the same.
We use this third-party recognition to restore a network.
We can try to compare this network in the future.
The way to restore the Internet is different from the traditional social network that everyone likes to use.
The second part is that we want to see if we are in a network environment.
Do some intervention in the network environment.
This intervention may be some policy promulgation.
Or what we are talking about here is a policy promulgation that promotes public health.
We want to measure how effective this intervention is.
Can we use quantification to see how effective it is?
It is in a social network environment.
We can only find some people to participate in this intervention.
It's like giving them some public health education.
But we want to know if these interventions have spread out.
We want to see how effective it is in a community level network.
Can we quantify it?
So this is probably the meaning of this topic.
Then I will continue to go down.
This is the outline of today's speech.
I still divide it into three parts.
The first part is because I received a letter.
I want to know that this may have nothing to do with the speech.
He wants to know why I went from mathematics to sociology.
So I will spend about five minutes to talk about what I am doing during my doctorate.
I originally studied mathematics as introduced by Yanping.
Then I turned to sociology.
I want to talk about the turning point in the middle.
So it will take about five to ten minutes.
The remaining two parts are the introduction of two articles.
The first part is how to go from mathematics to social science.
So I want to talk about two concepts in this part.
The first is social dynamics modeling.
This is social dynamics.
How do we use modelization or form logic to study this matter?
We know that in the real world, there are actually a lot of interactions with people.
Then it is very complicated, but it may be a lot of faces.
Of course, there are ways to study this thing in various fields.
Then we look at it from the perspective of mathematics and physics.
It is a very, very high-dimensional complex system.
Because it interacts too much and has a lot of impact.
Then the things you want to test can be infinite.
You can find things to test.
What should we do? How do we deal with this kind of thing?
We will try to model it.
The way to model is to do some simple simplifications.
You have to look at the most important thing in this system.
What are the driving forces that you care about?
We have to find it out.
The way we do it is to think of it as an atom.
Economists may be called agents or social scientists may be called agents.
We use this very simple simplification to think of it as some examples with the same characteristics or agents.
Then look at the interaction between these examples and agents.
At the same time, we also simplify a lot of things they can do.
For example, if it is an example, it may be left-handed or right-handed.
If it is an agent, it may be happy or unhappy.
This is a very simple two-point method, or it may be a lot of cutting.
We cut these examples.
If we present it in a complex system or on the Internet, it is a point.
We call nodes.
These nodes will have a state.
As I said, it may be a binary, or it may be a multi-state.
It may be that you are in a very bad mood today, and it is very good.
This kind of multi-state, or it may be continuous, may be a continuous change, may be a healthy state, may be a healthy state.
Of course, it can also be multi-dimensional.
It depends on what you are interested in.
The other part we value is the structure of this system.
What kind of relationship do these people have with each other?
You can think of it as a social relationship, such as a family or a workplace.
You can also think of it as geographical.
It may be that if the distance between people is very close, there may be a risk of infectious diseases.
We have to look at these modes, these social networks, and the structure behind them.
How will it affect each of us in the above example or people?
Of course, I listed some of the ways to form this structure.
Systematic is that it has a system.
What we understand here is that it is determined.
It's like a person.
You may know that the grid has four neighbors.
It's like a barbecue net.
One person has about four neighbors.
This may be a systematic network.
Or random.
You may have heard of a very simple random network model.
In the system, any two people have a certain probability of being linked together.
Or heterogeneous.
It may be heterogeneous.
Every point has a different way of being linked together.
Or it can also change over time.
We can study the dynamic system or time series of this system that changes over time.
Our new method is to build a simplified model in this complex system.
But this simplified model has to be able to capture one or two key things that we are most interested in.
As Einstein said, a model should be as simple as possible, but not simpler.
We have to simplify it to the point where we can no longer simplify it.
The tool I use is the network theory in the complex system.
Network theory is a method of expression.
It is also a method of learning.
It is different from the previous research.
It is an interaction phenomenon that attaches more importance to the medium-length.
What is medium-length?
It is a length between micro and macro.
At the macro level, you can see all people as being able to interact with others.
For example, in a group, we see that everyone is the same.
Let's say we have a class of students.
Then we have to study how COVID-19 spreads in this place.
Then we say that every student is the same.
And they can interact with other students at will.
This may be seen as a large group.
This is the macro level.
What about micro?
Micro is another part of the macro.
It just sees everyone differently.
You have to emphasize that its personal characteristics are like its height, age and weight.
It may be different for everyone.
What we do at the network level is not this thing.
At the network level, we assume that everyone is the same.
Unless you want to eat different types of points.
Of course, that can also be extended.
But our basic assumption is that everyone is the same.
What we care about is the structure of this system.
Who has a connection with whom?
Who will influence each other?
Or who will get the message from which side?
So what we see is that the network is a medium-length research method.
It is between large and small.
The subject of my research is social networks.
Of course, there are different kinds of social networks.
Of course, there may be a lot of networks.
In the natural world, there may be biological networks, food chains, bacterial networks, or virus networks.
It may also be artificial, such as computer networks.
Topology is how computers and birds are grouped together.
Or triple-W network.
Or some traffic networks.
In fact, there are many layers of network composition.
The main type of research I do is social networks.
What is the difference between social networks and other networks?
Here I have listed three.
The first is that it has a phenomenon called homophily.
Homophily is translated into Chinese as homogeneity.
You like people with the same characteristics as you.
You have this tendency.
You are also in a relationship with a person.
You would like to say that you are in a relationship with a similar person.
So it is a tree of spines.
Or birds of a feather flock together.
This is the first phenomenon.
This may not be as common as other networks.
The second is high clustering.
What is the meaning of high clustering?
It is the ability to create or store data.
It can be classified as a network or a network.
The second is high clustering.
Watch out for'homoplasticity'.
It means that there may be many Gabrielian stars on the network.
What is small triangle?
Devil's friends.
It may be that you know B.
B knows C.
If the two are in a strong relationship,
Usually there will be a relationship that is at least an identity of 3 to 4.
Therefore, in general social networks,
abc is very rich in the network ratio.
You can compare it with other networks of the public safe outside the movie.
There are many such small triangles.
Third, small world.
Most of people may have heard of the principle of 6-degree approximation.
But in a system or in the world,
The distance between people may not be as far as you imagined.
How?
Influencers,
they come about 5 phase and 6 phase.
Although they may not be aware of the shortest way,
you can see the sky when you open your eyes.
You and a person in Africa,
the distance doesn't exceed 20 steps.
So there are many shortcuts and quick ways in the system.
And that's why the world is much smaller than we thought.
By small scale, I mean that your road is less long than you imagined.
The way we talk here is the shortest way.
There are many shortcuts in the system.
Make it very easy to get close to the goal.
And then we can see the state of the point.
Let's take a simple example.
You may see that your neighbor or friend
has a high infectious disease.
People around him may need to stay away from him.
You need to have social distancing.
Or you let him be isolated.
If he is sick today,
this limit to his surroundings.
This limit to his surroundings.
the overlapping network will be significantly changing.
Because of the isolation,
for the time being, he has lost many connections.
His friends may have lost connections with his friend.
His friends may find others to replace.
Or he has more resources and more time for socializing.
So when a person loses something,
Or when a person loses something,
he is isolated,
But in society,
there are many real-life information.
But we need to reverse the model.
What is it?
I don't know if it's a problem with engineering.
reverse engineering
or inverse problem
How can we measure
We want to know
how can we measure
So I'm going back to my model
I think the process is interesting
good
The first one I want to talk about is
indians
perceptual tomography
both of them
He is in the research
Irish
aboriginal
He is looking for some
fishing village
some
small villages
That place
is Arab
them
That place is
next to the extreme
That is their Så
Is long in summer
Very short in winter
Maybe one or two months
Can't see the sun
That
Our team
I did not go
But we have some
Humanists
Squatting there
They are there
Visit these American aborigines
Looking at their social network
Just ask
Who are you familiar with
Then who is familiar with who
That
And some of them
Psychological research
because
We know that
People near the extreme
Their alcoholism rate is high
Then their
The suicide rate of adult males is high
So we want to see
These
Some negative features
Or healthy behavior
He will
Will it be affected by his social network
Or will he turn around
To affect his social network
So we are from
Humanists squatting to get information
To build a social network
Then look again
It's them
The health behavior of these people
Or some other behaviors
Like these people
Is there any resource
Willing to help others
Or
Willing to provide other people with knowledge
We look at it from the perspective of social networks
Look at the behavior of these people
it is good
The first thing to do
It's us
Of course it is
Get these people's network
We just ask
Who are you friends with
How familiar are you with him
Then this is usually
It's the way sociologists do it
In fact, social networks
From the perspective of sociologists
They started doing it very early
Started doing it in the 1930s
They will draw a social graph
They asked a person
Who are you familiar with
Who is not familiar with
That
Of course we did this part
The other way we did
Is we want
Look at it by sampling
Can I just draw
In this village
Maybe a part of the hundreds of people
Maybe 5%
Maybe 10%
Or 30%
If we only draw a part of the people
Then we ask him
Hey, you think
Who is familiar with whom in this network
Can we restore the entire network
I don't ask everyone
Who is he familiar with
And just do sampling
If you draw a sample
Can you restore the entire network
But this may not be the same
Because if you draw a sample
You may find people
He is to guess
Other people's networks
He is
He is a subjective recognition
Other people's
Exchange status or relationship status
Then we want to compare
Is the difference between these two networks
One is your subjective
Your own report
For example, I am with A or B
I am with these two people
Who is a friend
Who is not a friend
Another angle is
The angle we use here is
I went to see
The first three people
Then I went to see if they had a relationship
If there is a relationship
I report
If it doesn't matter
I also said they had nothing to do with it
So what we rely on is
Third party report
That third party report
He can tell us
Okay, these people are related
Or these people have nothing to do with it
He may be
Presence or absence of individual properties
And pairwise relationships
So he can tell us
These people are related or not
That
According to this third party report
We can build a network with direction
There are positive and negative networks
The positive network is the general social network
He is
Two have a relationship
Give him a positive connection
If it is a negative network
The two should have nothing to do with it
We'll give him a negative connection
And this negative connection is that we believe
These two people
From the perspective of the third party report
They should be relatively unrelated
So we call it robust
They don't have that
Connection
Okay, so this is how we do it
It's actually like I just said
We're on a network
We want to do sampling
Of course, there are many ways to do it
I have a few here
Like Respondent-Driven Sampling
Snowball Sampling
Or Convenient Sampling
Or Web-based Sampling
It's all a way of sampling
So our way of sampling is
We are
Uh, invite people to participate in the study
We're a little bit like a convenient sample
And then let these people come
Provide them with their knowledge
Of course
Of course there will be some
Problems with, uh, we're going to deal with
The first one is us
Uh, it could be incomplete data
It's just that he might
Uh, this guy, he's coming to us
Say he recognizes the social network
Maybe there is
There may be insufficient information
This person doesn't know
Uh, I, we asked him
Does D have anything to do with E?
He may not be familiar with D and E
He may not know
Does D have anything to do with E?
Or he may report errors
Is that maybe
D and E have nothing to do with it
And then from the third party's point of view
He may be related
Or he may be tired
He may have done too many of these questions
Then his quality of information
Or the concentration dropped
He might give us some wrong information
The other one we face
The main risk is
Everyone's perception may be much worse
So this kind of information may be
There is a lot of this variability
Then we have to deal with these problems
Okay, so what we're going to do is
Why are we called
Perceptual Tomography
Tomography is a segmented scan
Is that you see a object
Then you can go from different angles
To do projection on it
Then what you see may be different
So you see this object in the middle
It has four entities
Then you cut from the angle of S1 and S2
It has two different pictures
Then look at it from the angle of P
It also has different pictures
What we want to say
What we want to say is
In our hearts
Uh, we might be in this system
There is a possible
Real social network
A and B are related
B and C are familiar
Then A and C do not know
This kind of real social network is this
We see these four objects
It is real
but
No one knows
What does this real network look like
It's a bit like blind imaging
You just look at it from a certain angle
What you see is what you imagine
So what we're going to do is
Find a lot of people to see this thing
See what this social network looks like
Look at it from different social positions
Or look at it from different angles of the Internet
What does this object look like
Then look at it
Can we finally restore
The social network in everyone's mind
But this social network
It may be with
Uh, the real social network is not very similar
One is subjective construction
One is a collective subjective construction
This is our current way
He is one
Uh, a more subjective objective report
Because this is my own subjective
Okay, I'm with A
With A, with C, with D
This kind of subjective objective report
Then we want to compare these two ways
What's the difference in the network that was built
Okay, so we're going to, uh, find these, uh, in Alaska
These people in the village come to participate in our research
Then, uh, everyone comes to invite us
Uh, we were invited by us
He will go and see the photos of other people
Let's say there are about 400 people in this village
Then we will show him about 40 photos
Is a person to say
Do you know these 40 people
Can you call his name
Do you know the relationship between these 40 people
If you say these people don't know these 40 people
He might not judge
The social status of these people
If you know
Let's see how we should go
Sort out some of these people's social networks
See which people are more, uh, related
Some people are more irrelevant
Okay, so the way we use it
It's the way we use this
It's the way we put these people's photos
We invite the audience to put them in different baskets
What are the conditions in the basket
The condition in the basket is that the audience should think
These people are in the same group
He just put it in the same basket
So, uh, let's say we give him five baskets
We later, uh, said, okay, so you
Of these 40 people
You may know 30 of them
You put people you think are more familiar
Put it in the same basket
If you think it's not familiar
You have to separate these people into different baskets
So this is the main way we use
We give different people
Is to look at different 40 photos
And then ask them to put them in different baskets
Okay, so, uh, what are our advantages
The advantage is that this method is very fast
Is that we show them
A small part of the group
Maybe 40 photos out of 400 people
Then we don't have to let him judge
Two out of 400 people
Because that judgment doesn't matter
The function of the human brain processing capacity
Probably not so strong
Then we only show him a small part of the paper collection
These social relations
Then again, uh, he
It can be used in some, uh, more large-scale data collection
Because we actually don't have too much burden on people
If this group is hundreds of people
Uh, or, uh, thousands of people
Maybe you can do that
What are his shortcomings
One of his shortcomings is, uh, like I just mentioned
Is that everyone's perception may be much worse
Or they may have some mistakes in the middle
Is that he may know
What he knows is different from other people's subjective judgment
Like me, I might know, uh, the first one
But I don't think there's a link between D and E
They know, but they don't know
Maybe, but D and E
Maybe they actually know each other
I might make a mistake
That's another one
I'm from a lot of different, uh, participants
To report the relationship between D and E
There may be a lot of, uh, contradictions
Or it's inconsistent
Inconsistency may be very high
We have to find a way to, uh, create a model
To deal with these problems
Okay, so this is what we, uh, are doing
This real-life study
We have, uh, human scientists squatting
A few small villages in Alaska
Their characteristics are, uh, the summer sun is long
Winter sun is short
And then, uh, there's a lot of pressure
And then the alcohol problem is a little serious
And then their, uh, income
Uh, it's probably not very high
That's just the connection between people
It's very strong
Okay, we, uh, we found a village
To do this, uh, real-life study
That village is probably, uh, about 400 people
And then they're about 95% American
That their median income
The median annual income is about $30,000
So it's just not very rich
So what we want to see is
Some of their mutual help
Who will provide help
Who will get help
And their suicide prevention
It's just over there
I just mentioned that his adult male suicide rate
Will be higher than other regions
Then we want to look at suicide prevention
Then we invited, uh, 170 people to join us
Our research is actually easy to adopt
That they're probably half of the people
Maybe 40% of the people to join this study
Uh, uh, this data collection process
It took about seven days
And then every, uh, participant
It only takes 10 to 20 minutes
To judge some of the relationships between people
Then we give him $20 each time
Then they have a fee
Okay, so this is very similar to what I just introduced
Once we show him 40 people
Or photos
Then he has to do three things, uh, three types
The first one is this person
Uh, he's a victim or a participant
He knows and is familiar
The second person is this victim
He knows, but not necessarily
The third person he doesn't know
Then we, because the third person
In fact, this person can't judge
He doesn't know him at all
So now we're looking at the first and the second
The first person is familiar
The second person is not familiar
The first kind of people are usually family members
Is your parents or siblings
This person, the first class, is much less than the second class
Then we think the first class of information is too strong
Then we only use the second class of information
We ask these participants
Only the second class of people you know
But not very familiar
And then we put these people's photos
And then let the participants, the victims, come to the five categories
In five boxes or buckets
That's what we told him
The same bucket of conditions
It's these people
You think he's in the same social group
Or you think these people are familiar
Okay, so we've done it
Put one and two together
Know very familiar
He knows and is not familiar
I've also done it, just put two
These two results are similar
Okay, so we're still
Uh, to these people
He also took some of his characteristics
It's like he's not going to do this
The community has positive contributions
It's A1
Will he help young people?
It's A2
Does he have a drinking problem?
Or is he causing trouble?
Or is he doing something bad?
So what we're looking at now is
How do we build this social network?
That's the main way we build it
It's based on these victims
To divide people into five groups
This way to build a social network
Our starting point is like this
If there are a lot of people today
He put both of them in the same box
We have a high degree of certainty
We'll take it
I think these two people should be very
It should be very likely to know
It should be very likely to have this positive relationship
So if today
A lot of people report that these two people
It doesn't matter
We divide it into different boxes
Then we have a lot of confidence
Say these two people should have nothing to do with it
If it doesn't matter
We'll give him a negative tie
Negative tie
It's not that they have hostility
It's that they are
We have a lot of confidence
They should have nothing to do with it
So we're going to build this
The basis of the judgment
Okay, so we're going to talk about it
We take it as a random comparison
If you say two people
We'll see
People put
Uh, two people in the same box
What is the probability?
It's completely random
How much
And then we see
He
Two people are put in the same box
How much is it different from random
So we're going to have a
If there's a no model
Let's look at this
And then there's some calculation
Is that people really put this two people
The probability of putting the same box
The probability of putting two people in different boxes
We can use some
The combination of mathematical methods to calculate
Calculate his odds
And this is a false assumption
We want to compare
A reference standard
So we're looking at
How far is he from this standard
The farther away
That means we're going to
This matter
These things
They should have something to do with it
Or it shouldn't have anything to do with it
This judgment
It's going to be more and more intense
Okay, and then it's the same thing
That's what we're looking at
What's the probability
So let's look at this example
There are 393 people in this village
And we've got 172 people
Experimental research
That we
This B is equal to 50
We let him put five boxes
That K is equal to 40
They look at 40 photos at a time
Gamma is equal to 0.76
They know 76% of them
On average, one person knows
Of the 40 people
Maybe 76% of the people
So we're going to look at one
This is from a false assumption
A no model
That's what he is
What we're looking at is
5% of the end odds
If there are two people, three people, four people
Here's a 1.61, 0.1, 0.01 percentage
If he falls in
Uh, more than two people, more than three people
More than four people
If you put it in the same box
We think
These two people have a lot to do with it
Because this is from no model
Let's compare
Let's look at 5% of the end odds
A point
That this is
There are up to 5% of the end odds
If it's more than two people
If you put them in the same box
We think
These two people have a positive relationship
Okay, the same way
We can also make another version
No model is
How many people are there
Put these two people in different boxes
We'll say
These two people should have nothing to do with it
Then we still take 5% as an end point
Start counting from the back
From six people, five people, four people, three people
Stop
That's less than 5%
So if there are three people
Put two people
Maybe it's D and E
Put it in different boxes
We'll think
Okay, that's it
Uh, these two people
D and E should be
There is a significant relationship
Or a significant lack of knowledge
Ah, that's it
This is what we just talked about
Is that you take 5% as an end point
Or 5% as an end point
Then use the way of building the network just now
You can build two networks
The first one is a network with a positive relationship
The positive relationship is black
The second is a network with a negative relationship
We use red to show the negative relationship
So these points are the same
Then we can build
It has two symbol networks
One is a positive network
A negative network
Then we have some data on these networks
The data is that it has
These two networks actually look very similar
That's because there are some points
It's not drawn
So there are fewer points on the negative network
Then its density is very similar
Then its average distance is very similar
Then its centrality is very similar
These two networks actually look very similar
Ok, then we can still follow
Ah, the positive network and the negative network characteristics just now
Sort the network groups
Ah, you may have heard of some
Is to group the points of the network
What does grouping mean
Grouping is
Ah, if you see a network
It has a lot of connections within a group
If there are very few connections between groups
Then the result of this grouping should be good
Just like
Ah, you can use their department to group college students
Or use their hospital to group
The connection between groups should be
Much less than the connection between groups
Much less
So we have this positive network
If you have a negative network
We think
A reasonable classification is a group
There should be a lot of positive connections in the middle
There should be a lot of negative connections between groups
So if we have a positive and a negative network
Then we can group
Then let's see
The final grouping result will be the best
Ah, here
Ah, it turns out that the result of grouping six groups is the best
Its balance score is the lowest
The lowest means that its grouping effect is the best
Then we divide these networks into six groups
Ah, after dividing into six groups
It probably looks like this
Ah, then we can
To these groups
Describe some of the characteristics
Because we just said
We asked these people
Ah, what are the characteristics
He is willing to help others
Then he
Ah, will there be some alcoholism or suicidal tendencies
Then we will do it to these six groups
Ah, like using multinomial
To see what characteristics they have
We will find one
The largest group as the baseline
As a benchmark
Look at the other five groups and the benchmark
What are its characteristics
Ah, the third category is the largest
The third group is the largest
Then we can
Give some connections to other groups
If there is help, give him some connections
The first group of people is him
Ah, if he finds his friend
Ah, make some trouble
The first group of people will help him
Ah, here are some of the characteristics of each group
Some groups have no characteristics
Like the fourth group of people
Maybe it's the same as the third group
It's not on this
Okay, so this, uh, this part
We just look at
Use a network sampling method
Use a third party report
To restore a well-known mainstream network
Then we look at this network
Objective response
Say this person is my friend
This person is not my friend
What is the difference between this network
Then we found that this relationship
About 50%
As for
Ah, what are the reasons
What are the reasons that make a person more accurate
More accurate judgment
What are the reasons that make a person more inaccurate judgment
This is what we need to study later
Then we also put these people
Ah, some of his characteristics
Ah, find it out
Then we also put this subjective network
Do some classification
Okay, this one
Um, the plan can be extended
Ah, some of the possibilities that can be extended
We can change his
Sample size
Is to change the proportion of his sample
Ah, or the number
Then we can change
The number of boxes
We all have to say
These conditions will be
Ah, what kind of impact will we have on the final result
That
We have to compare again
Our subjective social network
With the general traditional
What is the difference between everyone's social network
Some people can see it
Some people can't see it
These are the things that need to be studied later
That
His way of research
He can also be extended to other circumstances
He doesn't have to be in a village
He can be
Ah, some small groups
Just like a company or a university
About hundreds of people
Then you give a part of the people
To participate in this
Investigation
Show him dozens of people's photos
Then let him do similar things
But
He has this extent of restriction
He may be in a city
There is no way to do this
So we are probably a small group
We can do similar things
Okay, this is the first one I want to talk about
That second part is
I want to measure
In this network
We do some intervention measures
I want to judge this intervention measure
Is there any effect of external spread
Or this
This intervention measure is actually useless
He is
Better than we expected
Okay, this intervention measure
Uh, his feature is that he has a social network behind him
That is, we already know that these people
What does the social network look like?
This social network is different from the social network we just talked about
Not everyone
The third party judges the subjective social network
It is the social network reported by everyone
We know these people
Under the social network
We want to see
For these people
Willing to come
Uh, maybe improve your own health behavior
We give him this intervention measure
We want to see
A few months later
How strong is the effect of this intervention measure
Can we quantify this strength
Okay, so
Uh, what we do is still
This
Uh, in this community
We let these people participate in our
This health behavior improvement measure
What about this health behavior improvement measure?
We are going to do some suicide prevention
Behavior
That's what we want to say
Hey, actually your mental state is very important
And then you have to take care of others often
Or you have to know
Your own mental health
Is there any risk?
Is there any danger?
You have to get some support from society
it is good
What is the way we use
The way we use it is
Uh, we first need to have a social network map
Is that we have to know first
Say this
The people in this village
They, uh, people and people are each other
How is it
Uh, there is this social relationship
Then again, we have to look at
Uh, what are we measuring?
What we want to measure is this intervention measure
Does it work?
Then we have to look at
Hey, today I'm talking about
Suppose I'm going to look at smoking
I'll look at smoking
Uh, at the first time
We look at everyone's smoking
Then the second time
Or, uh, other health behaviors
Then look at the second wave
The second time
Have these people's health behaviors changed
Through our intervention measures
Then we have to know
We can only do this
Some of the points in the network
Interference in their behavior
We might be with some of them
To participate in this, uh,
Some education on this bad behavior
We hope to change their behavior
Then we want to see
These interventions
Did it spread to their neighbors?
Because they're a pretty small group
And it's a very tight group
We want to see this intervention measure
The spread effect on this network
Okay, uh, just like I said
We're doing this, uh, suicide prevention research
Let's see
Uh, the main thing is to look at the network
The relationship between a pair of diets
What is diet diet?
Um, if there's a link between A and B
He's a diet
If there's no link, it's a diet
It's a pair of pairs
The main thing is to see if there's a relationship like this
He's on the Internet
His good behavior or bad behavior
Is there any significant change?
In every wave
In two waves
Is there any significant change?
Okay, uh, we're going to build this model now
How to build this model
Because, uh, we know
We only have this part of the people on the Internet
Give them this participatory research
So what about the first variable A?
The first variable A is, uh, we have a picture first
It's on G
G is the name of the network
The meaning of the network is that he has a point V and a link E
That A is a function of V
That is, V is every point
Did he participate in our intervention measures?
Or, uh, the suicide prevention of this behavior
This lecture
If he's involved, he'll give him E
If you're not involved, give him 0
Okay, what about the second part of B?
B is looking at his behavior
Is there any change in his state?
So he has two time points
He's at the zero point
He's not yet, uh, he's not yet involved
His behavior before this suicide prevention lecture
If he has this behavior
Is E
Maybe this behavior is a bad behavior
It's like smoking
Maybe there's a suicide tendency
He's E
So at the second time point
Time point E is that they're already, uh, prevention
The behavior has passed
Intervention has passed
But this person doesn't necessarily participate
But he's still in this state
Change
Zero is not in this state
E is in this state
So we have six numbers
To record the whole process
The first one is A
A is whether he participated in this intervention
B is in under two times
Is he showing this behavior?
So he has four in B
Uh, there are four divisions
If A, there are two divisions
So let's see
He's under two points in time
T0 and T1
We're going to look at his
Uh, all these diets
These pairs of
His behavior changes
So let's make some records
Because we're looking at every one of them
It's diet
It's X and Y
Suppose we're looking at
Uh, UV, this pair
UV, he's on the Internet
There are links
He is
U and V are friends
Then they have a link in the middle
Then we're going to look at
In the way of this record
His, uh, participation
What is the value of this behavior?
So the bottom is
We're calculating this XY PQR
PQRS
What is XY?
XY is this point
Does he participate in this way?
What is the y-axis?
What is the y-division?
The y-division is point B
Did you participate in this way?
What about P?
P is point U
He's in the zero time
He has
He has this behavior in the zero time
That Q is point V
Is there this behavior in the zero time?
R is point U
Is there this behavior in T equals 1?
S is point V
So let's do some
The changes in the amount
This is all
This looks a little complicated
But he's just a
Bookkeeping
He's just recording
XY PQRZ
The amount of this thing
X can be equal to 0
It can be equal to 1
Y can be equal to 0
S can be equal to 0
It can be equal to 1
So we're going to record
The number of changes in these things
Let's give an example
The example is
I'm looking at XY PQRS
But I might be looking at a T
What I'm looking at is a 1 0
1 1 0 1
What does this mean?
This is XY
What about this pair?
X participates in the defense
X is 1
Y does not participate in the defense
Y is 0
X at T time
He has this bad behavior
Is 1
Y at T equals 0 time
He also has this behavior
Is 1
At T equals 1
When T1
X no longer has this behavior
It becomes 0
But Y still has this behavior
He is 1
Then we have to look at this
How many pairs are there?
So we just saw
This has a total of
The combination of 2 and 6 squares
We have to look at 64 values
How many changes does it have?
Ok
Then we can put
Just this thing
Make a table
This is a map
Then we can divide it into
X participates
Y participates
Or X did not participate
Y did not participate in this combination
Then look again
Do they have these bad behaviors?
If there is a bad behavior, it is a black dot
No bad behavior is a white dot
Then we can put
The total of 64 numbers
Recorded on this
Then we have to look at this
64 numbers and time changes
That
Next is the social scientist
Some values of concern
The first one is
We want to see
This intervention
For the participants themselves
Does it have positive results?
Is there a positive effect?
It is direct treatment success
In a social context
Is in this social network
We give it directly
This intervention
For this person
Does it have a good result?
The second is direct prevention
In a social context
If this person
If there is no bad behavior
We give him this intervention
Can he continue to maintain
He did not have this bad behavior
The following m3 to m8
Is similar to some
Some of the values we see
I will not go into details here
Ok, m1 is what I just said
If this person participates in preventive measures
Will he
At the next time
Is to improve
He may have this bad behavior
There was no bad behavior later
This is this person himself
Then we have to look
Corresponding to within those 64 brackets
I have to look at these eight
The change in the value
The left side is red
Deep red
The right side is this pink
Plus the alignment
I have to look at these two time points
Within
The difference between the two numbers
Is there a difference?
Is there a difference between this and no model?
That this is m1
This indicator
That m2 indicator is
If this person today
He was at t equal to 0
At the time
He has no bad behavior
That he is at t equal to 1
After a period of time
His bad behavior
Is it continuous?
Did not happen
Then we have to look at the other two
The difference in value
This is the red one here
Reduce the alignment here
Pink this difference
So we can put the eight questions just now
All of them are drawn as a comparison between two
What is no model?
No model is now
We call it Poisson binomial distribution
It is Poisson binomial
Poisson binomial
It is a binomial
A wide range of binary distributions
That it is every point
Every trial
Every test
Its probability may be different
So we know that the binary distribution
It is every
Distribute its test point
Its probability is the same
But Poisson binomial
It may be different
Then we take this model as our no model
Then we do this bootstrap
Bootstrap means that it is repeated
We may
For this no model
We did this experiment a thousand times
Then we look again
What we really observed
The value of M1 to M8 just mentioned
It falls in our thousand repetitions
Did it fall at the end of 5%?
If there is, we will say
Okay, this thing is conspicuous
If not
Just say this thing is not conspicuous
If it falls in the middle of 95%
Just not conspicuous
Falling at 5%
Whether it is the front or the back
We said it was conspicuous
it is good
So we are based on another
Another village
We do this thing
In the end, we still have some
We have to judge the characteristics
It's very similar to the characteristics just now
It's usually related to suicide prevention
The question is whether he has a suicidal tendency
Then will he help others?
Will he talk about suicide?
Does he have any wine at home?
Do you have any weapons at home?
Then we will follow the eight judgment methods just now
Let's see
They are in the 39 questions just now
Is it clear that the change is good or bad?
The red one is the direction of the change
The blue triangle is in the direction of the change
So some of the effects are external
It's the opposite of the positive
Some of the effects are bad
It's the opposite of the bad direction
So these can be seen from the model just now
Okay, let's sum it up
This is our second project
He wants to look at
A social network
In the relationship of the group
We give him an intervention
Then we can measure
This is a sociologist or a epidemiologist
Or some of the public health scientists
The values ​​they care about
Is there any positive behavior?
Is there any spread?
We can all give a
Analyze the amount
There is a positive relationship
Or no
There is no obvious positive relationship
Then we can see this
Intervention measures
Or the external effect of this public policy
Or
What we care about is
Suicide prevention
Self-protection
The above is my sharing
So I just shared
Basically three things
The first one is
What I care about during my PhD
Is a complex network
A shared network
The second is
Can we have a third party to take the initiative
To build a
A collective subjective network
The third is
If we are on the Internet
Do an intervention
Can we find a way
To measure the effectiveness of this intervention
This is what I'm going to share with you today
Some topics
Thank you all
Thank you for today's speech
Then I represent everyone
Let's give it up
That one
Okay, I have some here
I have collected some
When you were talking
Some questions from the audience
Then there are some here
Is about the first study
Some are about the second study
What do you think
I'm talking to you now
How do you think it should be done
Let's start with the first study
Or from
Just turn it over
Start with the second study
See what you want
All right
In fact, we have no preference
That's good
Once
It's just a discussion
A study
If it's the first study
Answer together
Which one can start first
Okay, let me start with the first study
Just in the process
I have two questions
But wait
Before I ask
Do you want to ask yourself
Because just now
In fact, if you want to ask yourself
You can also turn on the microphone
Is that plus fish?
C H I A Y U N
And Zhang Yong
Two people have mentioned
About the first study
You can open the microphone
Ask yourself if you want
Or
Or I can ask you
See what you think
So
I don't really understand
So what do you mean
Do you mean to ask me to turn on the microphone now?
Yes, just like this
You can start asking
Ok
Ok, then
Then I will ask first
Although I am actually the second
I am also wrong
Because that
Is it plus fish?
Sorry
I don't know how to spell your name
He should ask first
But anyway
Then I will ask first
Otherwise, I have already opened
Just
You are doing like this
Because basically
You can't draw the whole society
Then you can only say
You draw a part of the people
Then go to build
This part of the people
Give you this network
But
We know that
When doing network analysis
In fact
Where is the boundary of the entire network
Then what is its boundary property
Then there is its absolute
Is the absolute dimension
And the size of the entire network
In fact, it will affect
Some emergent property
Even your
Interaction between units
All the same
Then what do you think about this thing?
If you can't draw the whole
Everyone in the network
Any other questions?
Still
It's a question, right?
Do I answer it once?
Then I will ask by the way
Plus fish
Oh, I'm sorry
I really don't know your name
The question seems to be
Because I think it's a bit related
But his question
More specific
Then I will ask together
Then you answer together
His question is
You set positive and negative
Right? I didn't hear wrong
When study one
The first one
Yes
The question is
Then why don't you use 1 and 0
Is there or not
Why do you want positive and negative 1
So this is actually a
I think it's an assumption
So with
Maybe it's a special case
In the question of Zhang Yong
Okay, let's answer it together
Okay, I'm done
it is good
Thank you for the two questions
I will answer the question of Yan Yong first
Is what you just said
The question of network boundary
Is doing social network
A big area
Many people are doing
Network Boundary Research
Because
Network Boundary
Actually look at your research
The group of people who care
Then this thing can be
Uh, written
Some things are not written
But like
The research we are doing
Is written
Is in this village
Because it is between the village and the village
It's just a long distance
He won't have any
Connections between villages
Basically very few
Then these people are
Because they are all big
Ah, these are big
Then we are in this village
Maybe 400 people
Then this boundary is
Very certain in comparison
Then some research
Boundary is very uncertain
Just like
Suppose my other research is doing
New York City's population
Then this is quite uncertain
That is to say, these people are in New York City
Uh, have you been to New York City?
Or he wants
He lives outside New York City
We don't know
Or this kind of network boundary
It's hard to define
But like this research
The network boundary is also very obvious
Is that I live in this village
Maybe more than 300 people
400 people
He is our research range
Then we put everyone
Get the photo or name
And then look at this
What should the network look like
So you just mentioned the problem
It's not going to happen
On this research
Then some, uh, network boundary
It is also a very certain group
He is an organization
The people inside him may be like
A department
He may only accept 120 students
Then this network boundary is also very close
It's very, very, very obvious
Just one grade
Take 120 students
Or, uh, a company
He may have 200 employees
This is also very certain
Then we are in this kind of very certain network boundary
To discuss this matter
His grace is fixed
His grace is his network
Is fixed
Then we do this model again
So there won't be much boundary
The second question is
Why don't we use 1 and negative 1 to record
We don't use 1 and 0 to record
because
The main problem is that our 0 is also used
We 0
I didn't make it clear just now
Our 0 is that he
This relationship is not obvious
What does it mean not to be obvious
Not obvious is that he
There is a connection that is not obvious
Or there is no connection that is not obvious
He is
Uh, it's kind of like we're not sure
Is there a relationship
But 1 and negative 1
1 is that we are sure that we are very
We have this relationship
That negative 1 is that we are sure that this relationship is not
So we actually used 1 0 and negative 1
But we just saw in this picture
Uh, I'm going back to look for it
In this picture
In fact, uh, the relationship of 1 is that the relationship of positive is black
That red relationship is negative 1
He is red
As for the others that are not connected
Their relationship is 0
Because they are us
They are us
It's not obvious in the statistics
He is
We don't
We are not sure he is positive
Or is he
He is a negative relationship
So 1 0 negative 1
We actually all have
I just didn't make it clear
The positive network I just talked about is the network of 1
The negative network I just talked about is the network of negative 1
Then these two networks
Sorry
Did you see my desktop
It's empty
What I see now is a blue base
Hey, what about now
I accidentally jumped out
Hey, it still looks the same
I can't go back a little
I don't know why
If you turn off the share screen and reopen it
How about this
Share screen
Stop sharing
Good
Then reopen the share screen
Review
Oh yes
Is there
Hey now
Uh, wait a minute
Oh yes
Good
Sorry
So uh
Back to the question just now
We actually have 0
I just didn't make it clear
0 is the relationship between the two
We are not sure
The statistics are not sure
Ok
I'll probably answer this
If there are any further questions
You can also continue to discuss
That one
Uh
YUAN
XIE YUAN
Hey, Xiao Yuan
OK
Can you hear me
Teacher
Hey
Hello
Hi, long time no see
Not long
A few months ago
All right
Everyone at home
Thank you, teacher
That was a great presentation
I have a question
It's about that
Co-evolution of networks
Using your tomography method
Because I was thinking
If we want to study
The co-evolution of networks
It takes several network snapshots
If we use this method
Because every time
Participants may be different
Even if we are the same
Will also lead to
Its node distribution is different
Because I think the teacher's method
It seems to be from binomial
A node distribution evolved
That's what you think
If I use this method
And then in several stages
But the number of participants is not the same
That way I can
Compare several different networks
Between
Characteristics
For example, the second stage
Network transitivity
With the first stage
Can I do this
Compare
Do some co-evolution analysis
Or does the teacher think
No, there's no way to compare
Yes, yes, yes
Thank you
OK
Thank you, Xiao Yuan
Question is
Uh, this area is
Uh, I know
I don't know if you've heard of it
Is multi-layer network
Multi-layer network is
In math or physics
Dealing with
This question just now
Like a few waves
Uh, network
He gave a few snapshots
Then he wants to see
His multi-layer can be quite a lot
One is
Uh, every layer of the network
It's all different
Look at different variables
Like this
Uh
Maybe it's the same time point
One layer may be the mood
One layer may be the result
One layer may be healthy
This
Different layers
The other one is
It evolves over time
That is
He can be T from 1 to 10
You give him a live broadcast
Research
Then he will
T equals 1
One layer T equals 2
One layer T equals 10
That
People who study multi-layer network
You'll see
What's the relationship between cross-layers
It's just that
Maybe the members are the same
Some members are the same
But some members
Leave or join
That
In the multi-layer network
Under the general design
You just mentioned
These problems are all
Uh, they have
There are ways to deal with the domain
Is to leave
Or a new member
That
I just talked about this model
I didn't deal with this problem
Because I actually only have two waves of people
Then my model is also very simple
It's just that the network won't change
And then this person
Uh, it's just that the network won't change
That means
They don't have a new point
There is no point to leave
Then
The structure of the network has not changed
So I actually
There are only a few months in the middle
I just assume that his network has not changed
Because we are looking at the relationship network
That we
The assumption is that the relationship between two people
In a few months
Will not change
That
Of course you can do different extensions
You can say
Suppose you want to do 10 waves
That
Sometimes someone leaves
Someone comes in
Then I'm thinking
You have to use the multi-layer network
Structure
In that field
Mathematicians and physicists also deal with this
The problem you just mentioned
They have dealt with
That is, someone leaves
Someone
Someone new
This is all
Um
Some of the scenarios they have dealt with
So I don't think there will be too many problems
Just look at it
What is the study of the multi-layer network
How to deal with
Sorry
Because I
This model
There is no such treatment
But I
As far as I know, this can be handled
Can I ask a follow-up?
No problem
Because
Multi-layer network
Uh, I'm not very familiar with this part
But I'm using
Sienna's study
This kind of joiner and lever
Is a very common way
That is to say, different waves
Its members are different
As long as there is an addition
There are
This is indeed a very common practice
Just say
I'm thinking about the teacher's method
A more special way
Because
Usually when doing joiner and lever
They
He went to measure the network
That
Uh, the existence of the connection
Usually use the same method
That is to say
For example, I name my friend
That part is always
It's always very fixed
But I'm thinking
Teacher
Teacher, your method is to say
You are through
Comparison with a node distribution
Indirectly to deduce
It's these two nodes
Does it have a connection?
Then I was thinking
That's why this is with
General
Uh, the general joiner and lever
The problem is different
The reason is
It's right here
That is to say, it is
Through
Comparison with a node distribution
Then deduced
Yeah, but I was thinking
This
Because it's in
When different waves of people are different
This node distribution will change
Correct
So
Is that right?
Directly above
Compare
Say different waves
To infer
Oh, these two people
These two people are connected
These two people are not connected
Mainly want to ask
This kind of part
Yes
Uh, I actually
Uh, I'm not sure
What you want to ask is
My first research is
Judging from the third party
Is there any connection?
Yes yes yes
The part of the third party
That's right
That research
It's just one wave
That's what I just said
My one
Uh, participation
Research
Research time is only one week
That is to say
He
He has only one wave
His settings are only one wave
That
Uh, I think
If you really want to do this
Multi-layer words
Then you have different waves
Then come different
Time to test
Then do this network
They
The members of each wave may be different
But I actually don't know
Say cross-group
This one
How do i change
In fact, I just
This first study
He actually only has one wave
So he was originally a
Just
Under that setting
He is a complete architecture
But I didn't think about cross-group
Comparison
Is the problem of cross-time point comparison
But
Um
You said you
How will it be done in the relevant research?
Or do you have any suggestions or questions?
Actually, I'm not sure
Because I just
I thought you were talking about the second one
Because the second one
I just talked about the second study
Only
Only cross
Comparison
But the first study did not
The first study is
I find a time
A week
Then make this network
What I want to compare is
The third party's subjective recognition
With our own
Objective report
What's the difference
Um
Yes, so I didn't think about it
Do the first study
Cross-group
Maybe it can be
But
If that's the case
These people
He will be
There are in and out
Then
Cross-group
How do i cross
Cross-time
How do I divide
Will also be a question
Because what I just said
Divide
Divide at the same time
OK
Understand
Thank you
No no
That
Let me ask a few questions
Because there is
Just
We are now
To the second study
Right
Natural conversion
So there were some friends just now
There are some questions about the second study
Then I
Uh
I'm here now
I'm probably summary now
Then ask
Then if I ask
What do you think
I'm the one who asked the question
I think I expressed it wrong
Then you can turn on the microphone
It doesn't matter
Um
It's about the second study
Ah
This Liu
Asked to say
I'll just read it
The second case
What is it
Analyze method
Analyze intervention
What about the effect
This is the first one
Then
A little bit related to this question
Is this one
There should be a surname
Ning
Ning said
Is there
Control
This control group
Or
The so-called contrast group
Because what you are analyzing
Is the effect of the experimental group
You can
You can say that
Then this is
I think it's the first group
problem
Ah
The second question is
Zhang
Is
There will be a lot of groups
Will there be a lot of groups
No no no no
In fact, only
Only the second group
The second group
There is one more
It's my own question
But that
If you don't have time, forget it
Then there is another one
Zhang Yong
He asked
Because your state
Your notes
The state is 1010
He said
Is there a mix state
Then I'm not sure
What does he mean
Then if
When you answer later
Or he
Uh
He wants to clarify
You can also say it like this
Okay, that's it
it is good
Ah
Thank you for your feedback
Then I want to talk first
Is
I think it's better
Ah
Good talk
Is 0
Like the last question
Ah
Yan Yong asked this
Mix state question
Because
The simplest thing we do
One thing
Is binary
Always better than multi-state
Do a lot
So
We only test
Uh
Binary
Then
Ah
Let me pour this
Is
This is very similar to the first question
How do we measure
Say
Does this intervention measure work
So
Let's look at the changes in bad behavior
Bad behavior is
Maybe it's
I asked 39 questions later
Is
Of the 39 questions
Some of them
If he answers
Good
Like
Uh
Do you have the idea of ​​suicide
Do you often think of the idea of ​​suicide
If he says yes
We think it's a bad behavior
It's like smoking
Is a bad behavior
That
The way we record this
Use 01 to record
Of course you can be more complicated
You can even make it
Is a continuous extent
But for us
Is 01
Is
The first step to do
If we don't do 01
It will be more difficult later
So
We use 01
This kind of binary
Binary classification
To divide this matter
That
The way to measure is
I just said
We have 39 questions later
Ah
Sorry
There are 39 questions here
That
Every question
Ah
You can put
Uh
There is bad behavior called 1
Then there is good behavior called 0
Then we look at this
At this point in time
How many changes in 01
You were originally 1
Later maintained as 1
It means that
This person may not have improved
It's all bad behavior
At the time of 0
At the first time
Still bad behavior
That
If it changes from 1 to 0
We think there is an improvement
Under this question
He has improved
He had bad behavior
Then there was no bad behavior
Then we also see
Suppose a person
He participated in this intervention
Then his neighbor
Is there any way for him to change from 1 to 0
There was originally bad behavior
Later it became no bad behavior
We want to see the effect of his spread
So we look at this unit
Both
Two of this
Uh diet
That is
We
Of course, you can continue to look at it
That is to say
Three layers of diet
Triplet or triad
Ah
Or four layers
But we just care
We are most concerned about
Can he spread to his direct neighbor
So we all look at each one
He is this kind of two pairs of this
Uh
Connection
Okay
Then
This question is the control group's question
Actually, uh, we didn't do that
This is
This is of course a
It should be a pretty big problem
This reviewer is also asking
Then we are running directly
He is
Two networks
Then the two networks
We do the same thing
So uh
In fact, we
There doesn't seem to be a good way to explain it
But if
Of course I believe
If it's a good study
He should be
Bring
Uh, there are a lot of control variables
It's just that I might
Uh, two
Different villages do the same thing
One is the experiment group
One is the contrast group
but
Uh, our model is more like
It's a return model
It's us
My model is bootstrap
It's a re-draft
And then look at him
How much of this deviation from the re-draft
If the deviation is very high
We think this
Uh, the phenomenon is
Ah, it's obvious
Or it's obvious
That
It's just that I have this
Under the experimental framework
He just didn't do it
That's when I got the data
I got the data first
To start modeling
I got the information
Uh, both villages do the same thing
Then I report this
One of the villages is
His results are better
Then I directly take this village
The result of the report
But when we designed it
It's just that there's no control
Then we use the model
It's not a return model
We can put some variables
Put it in to control
Just the whole
The whole structure is not the same
I hope
If of course agree
If there is more control
Maybe it's better
But I'm not doing it
Professional in this area
It's just that we have this model
No
I'm sorry
That's about it
Okay
So do you have any questions for
Is there any question?
For the first study
Second study
Or even a front one
For your academic history
Such a question
Hello Wei
I would like to ask again
Is the second experiment
What is the analysis method you use
This is a more detailed process
Ok
Um
We are first
Uh
Then I might have to start from
I'm thinking about where to start
What we care about is
A intervention
Its effect
Is there any way to extend it to this social network
Friends in the middle
Is that you give a person this intervention
It's this intervention
Is there any way to spread to a friend
So we measure
Is this intervention
In different directions
Is that we have different directions
That's what I just said
The 39 questions
Is to commit suicide
Suicide prevention-related 39 questions
That every question
We can say
It has good results
With no good results
It's like smoking
Smoking may be bad
Smoking may be good
That has this information
This information is
Uh, who participated
We have these people's web map
These people are
Uh, we're sure this web map is true
Then we know that there are some people
Participate in our preventive research
These intervention measures
Then we also know
These people are at two points in time
His state in 39 questions
Maybe 1 is a bad behavior
Then 0 is no bad behavior
So I follow this, uh, information
I'm going to build a mathematical model
The mathematical model is what we just talked about
There are six aspects of this, uh, the amount of calculation
The first two aspects are in this diet
The relationship between x and y
Or the relationship between u and v
X or u
Did he participate in this preventive behavior
This is the first two
What about the last four
At t equals 0
This, uh, x and y
Do they have this bad behavior
The last two are t equals 1
At this time
Do u and v have this bad behavior
So we're going to do these measurements
It's just that we're going to look at this
I just talked about this 011101
He participated in x, y did not participate in x
Bad behavior
At t equals 0
X has no bad behavior
Y has bad behavior
At t equals 1
Let's see
Then compare with random
Random how to compare
Random is that we put these things
After calculating this value
And then we look at it as a, uh, here's a
It's a binomial distribution
It's every experiment
Its, uh, the probability of production may be different
Then we can create it
It's in every grid
What is its expected value
What is the expected value
But we have the actual observed value here
Because we are at t equals 0
When t equals 1
There are different observable values
They took this value
It's called M2, the real value
Compare with a thousand random repeated experiments
See if it's more obvious or less obvious
If it's too obvious
We say, okay, this aspect
It has a positive result
If it's not obvious
We say, okay, no, it doesn't have a negative effect
It doesn't, it has an obvious negative result
So the final way to present it is
39 questions
There are eight aspects of our measurement
Some of them are good
You see the red one
The bigger it is, the more obvious it is
Some of them are negative
So that's about the whole process
I don't know
I think there's no problem with the statistics
You explained it very clearly
But I want to know
By the time of this page
How to put these different factors
Make a
It's clear in terms of understanding
Network or something
It's a kind of narrative
A description
Yes, that's good
If that's the case
We can look at it based on one question
Then we'll see
I'll just say it here
Suppose it's the 24th question
We'll see
I don't know if you can see my cursor
I'll look at the 24th question
Q24
The first one is
Diffusion of Prevention
It's a big blue triangle
It's negative
That is to say
If this person participates
His M1 is a significant negative
What is M1
M1 is what I just said
There are eight indicators here
The M1 indicator
We'll look at the definition of the M1 indicator
The definition of the M1 indicator is
You participate in this intervention
Will it cause
The change in your direct state
Is from good to bad
From bad to good
This is from 1 to 0
That's under this degree
This is blue
So this is a significant negative
That is to say
He himself
He can't have this
From 1 to 0
The second problem is red
The second face is red
M2 is red
The third and fourth are not significant
The fifth is red
The others are
Sorry
24 is the fifth significant
The sixth is the small negative
Then the seventh and eighth are not
The conclusion of the statistical significance
So we are all based on
Let's understand the questions one by one
Let's look at the eight indicators we just talked about
The eight indicators are different
Then I am in the article
We have defined these eight indicators
What are you measuring
So the final interpretation is that you see
There are 39 questions
We measured 39 questions
Within two waves
Is there any significant improvement
Or obvious retreat
So I don't know if that's the case
I want to ask
Because you have 39 indicators
Have you considered doing
For example, factor analysis
Or a multi-scale analysis
Let the connectivity between the 39
A clearer network context
Actually, I think it's good
I think we should do it
Because 39
We didn't do it
but
I think it's good
Because of this 39 question
There must be a lot
There are many repeated
There are many repeated parts
That is
But we
We didn't do it on this issue
We put this question
These 39 are seen as independent 39
In fact, the first question will not affect
To the second question
Will not affect the third question
You can think of it as 39
Indicators run together
But I agree
I totally agree
Say you can do factor analysis
Or decrease
These are all possible
But we haven't done that yet
OK, thank you
Thank you
Thank you all
Because of time
We want to say
This is the last question
Then I will represent everyone
Give this warm applause
Very, very exciting
Thank you all
Thank you
OK, OK
Before the end
This is again
Business time again
We are still collecting
More of this
The winner of the second half of the year
So if you feel
Your own research
Or
Research
This topic can also be
I want to share with you
Then let everyone know
Please do this
Don't hesitate to share with us
Then sign up to become a winner
That's it
Thank you all
Thank you
Then I will stop this video now