Today, I am very honored to invite Dr. Yu Song-Huan, our speaker, to give us an online presentation.
Dr. Yu Song-Huan's school and research unit is the Max Planck Institute of Biochemistry.
His main research area is focused on bioinformatics.
Today, he is going to talk about the topic of
Energizing the Three-Arm Knife for RNA-Seq-Based Entotation of Bacterial Archaeogenomics.
Now, Dr. Yu Song-Huan, please introduce the topic to us.
Thank you for the introduction.
Basically, what I am going to talk about today is a tool for analyzing biological information.
This tool is mainly used in the analysis of large data, which is often used and very important.
It is mainly used in RNA sequencing.
Later, I will introduce the basic background.
We are focused on the providence of gene assistance for bacteria and fungi.
I believe that not all the audience comes from biology.
So, I will briefly introduce the background.
I believe that quite a few speakers have talked about the background.
If I am not clear enough, you can also go back and look at the part of the speakers.
They are all very good.
The whole organism needs to undergo a process of normal metabolism growth.
That is, all their genes need to function normally.
We all know that genetic material is actually stored in DNA, which is the gene we are talking about.
DNA is a structure of double-bone spiral.
You can see that there are two bones here.
When the DNA is copied, it will be like a zipper.
These two bones will be released.
Then one of them will be used as a template.
According to this template, we will have DNA polymerase.
It will read the genetic code above and then copy another bone to form a new DNA.
However, in order for the DNA to function properly,
in most cases, it still needs to reach the protein level.
There is a middle product called RNA in the middle.
From DNA to RNA, we call it transcription.
It's very simple.
DNA will decompose into a single bone.
RNA polymerase will be combined with the single-bone DNA.
It will read their genetic code and produce another single-bone structure.
We call it RNA.
RNA can interact with the ribosome.
This process is called translation.
These RNAs will be compared with the correct amino acid.
Then it will be combined into a functional protein.
This is the case in most cases.
A very important topic in recent years is that
biologists use big data to analyze some of the phenomena of biologics.
Or to understand the situation of biological manipulation.
We can also roughly divide it into these three levels.
DNA level, RNA level, and protein level.
These big data studies are called biologics.
In English, it's omics.
DNA can form genomics.
RNA has transcriptomics.
Protein has proteomics.
Basically, it's like this.
This is omics data.
They all have different levels of omics data.
We can study different projects at different levels.
Or different studies.
For example, if we want to know the situation of the sample we get.
Maybe we need to go to DNA level.
Let's see if there is any change in the genome.
If we want to see if some gene mutation
will cause the sample we want to study
to have a morphological change.
Then we might have to do proteomics.
Different omics data have different uses.
Different research directions.
Speaking of omics data, we need to talk about
several important technological developments in recent years.
This led to the emergence of omics data.
At the beginning, around the 1970s,
there was the first generation of sequencing.
It's mainly focused on DNA.
Simply put, because when DNA is copied,
it needs to use nucleic acids.
Four different nucleic acids.
Simply put, C, G, A, T.
These four different letters represent four different nucleic acids.
When copying these nucleic acids,
it should be said that in this DNA,
the four nucleic acids have different sequences,
which leads to a difference in genetic code.
Then different products will be produced.
Sanger is a scientist.
He used different lights to mark these four different nucleic acids.
So you can imagine that when this DNA is to be copied,
this single cell will receive these fluorescent nucleic acids.
After these fluorescent lights are emitted,
we can use this fluorescent light.
By detecting this fluorescent light, we can know
what the sequence of this gene looks like.
What is its genetic code?
Simply put, it's like this.
This is the first generation of sequencing.
The problem now is that the first generation of sequencing,
of course, is also used a lot.
Even now it is still in use.
But it has a few shortcomings.
The first one is that it can't be automated.
Because when we want to do this sequence,
we need to amplify our sample first.
Then we can do the sequence.
In the first generation,
it can't be automated.
The second one is that its genes need ...
There is no way to do the overall gene.
I can't take all the DNA out of a cell
and do the sequencing directly.
There is no way.
So we need to have an assumption first.
We know that this gene may ask
what we want.
So we do the sequence.
The third one is that
in terms of gene sequence,
our target gene usually has a certain length.
So when we do the sequence,
there is a high probability of error.
We can imagine that
if we have a shorter sequence,
there is less chance of error.
But if our target gene is longer,
there is a greater chance of error.
So if there are people doing experiments,
we know that
if we do the sequence again,
sometimes at the end,
there is a lot of quality drop.
The reason is the accumulation of error.
So there are these problems.
Although there are these problems,
people still use it quite often.
So in the early 2000s,
there was another one.
We call it Next Generation Sequencing.
It is to solve the shortcomings of the first generation sequence.
Next Generation Sequencing can be done at different levels.
For example, it can do DNA sequencing,
and it can do RNA sequencing.
Then it can automatically copy a large number of samples that we are interested in.
It's not just to get a specific gene,
but we can get all the genes.
There is no problem with sequencing.
So it solves this problem.
How does it do it?
It's very simple.
DNA and RNA are actually similar.
Simply put,
we take a cell,
and then we lysate the outside.
Then we extract the genetic material we want,
whether it's DNA or RNA.
Then we break it into pieces,
which is a relatively small piece,
usually 200 to 300 nucleic acid lengths.
Then we will connect the two ends with the adapter.
This adapter can be glued to the flow cell,
which is on this piece.
It can stick a lot of DNA.
After that,
after it is glued,
and then we go to the primer,
it can be easy to copy.
You can see that there is a lot of DNA here.
Then we use the machine to read.
We can know a lot of different DNA fragments at once.
Suddenly we may have millions,
even tens of millions of DNA fragments,
which can be sequenced by us.
These things are good tools for us to do analysis.
Maybe it's still not clear here.
What is it for?
I simply use a very simple example,
let everyone understand the use of this technology,
or its strength.
Simply put,
if we have two people today,
one is normal,
which is generally not sick,
nor have any bad habits.
The second is a person who has a smoking habit.
Then we go to take their genome cells,
then we go to take the genome,
then we go to do the sequencing.
The data we get may look like this.
These two are actually histograms.
You can imagine the height,
in fact, how many DNA fragments,
we call DNA reads,
it accumulates on it.
So the higher,
it means that the more DNA accumulates here.
It means that its performance is higher.
Just here there is a gene A,
in the case of normal people,
it does not have a very high level of performance.
But on people who have smoking,
it has a very high level of performance.
It is said that smoking will affect this gene,
will make this gene alive,
or make it perform more.
It may cause some diseases,
it may cause cancer, etc.
Then you compare gene B,
there is no such situation.
It is said that gene B is not the key gene.
Then we do not use
next-generation sequencing technology,
we may need to determine first
that gene A is the gene we want to study,
then we do the sequencing.
But in next-generation sequencing is different.
We can have no hypothesis.
We can do it in a data-driven way,
that is, we do the sequencing first.
We know these two people,
they must have something different,
but we do not know what gene,
it does not matter, we do the sequencing,
and then we do the comparison.
From this direction of comparison,
we can find a lot of candidates,
and then we do downstream analysis.
That is, we use next-generation sequencing,
we can start from hypothesis-driven,
sorry, I should say,
assumption or hypothesis-driven study,
into a data-driven study.
So that is,
we can use next-generation sequencing,
this way of big data,
to enhance or help us do biological research.
But in fact,
there is still a problem with this sequencing.
For example, we got today,
we finished the experiment,
we got our data,
and then we go to read.
We found that there are indeed two blocks,
it has a high level of performance.
Now the question is,
we do not know what these two blocks are.
If we do not know what protein it is,
or do not know what gene it is,
we can not do downstream analysis.
So, is it possible,
we directly use these sequencing,
what I do,
what I do now,
this tool is focused on RNA.
Can we directly use RNA sequencing data,
we automatically find out,
we want the genomic features.
Where is the gene?
What is this gene?
Where is the protein?
What is this protein?
Is there a way to do this kind of thing?
If so,
we can do downstream analysis.
The advantage is,
in fact,
how to say,
but now,
of course,
there are a lot of public databases,
have stored the information of these annotations.
In fact,
we can easily read it to our,
with our RNA sequencing to compare.
For example,
this CDS,
that is,
the meaning of coding sequence,
the meaning of protein.
There is a protein here.
Then we know,
this segment,
it is actually the protein performance.
OK, good.
But now the question is,
RNA sequence,
in fact,
contains or contains more information.
Some useful information,
in fact,
not necessarily stored in these databases.
The second is,
usually stored in these databases,
are the wild type,
sequencing,
or wild type,
wild type annotations are more.
But you may be in this experiment,
your condition is different.
We did some of the mutation,
we did some of the different training,
resulting in our data may be different.
These annotations may not necessarily be used.
So,
for example,
we are in this data,
can not see more hidden information.
For example,
here is a starting value,
transcript starting sign,
abbreviated TSS.
On both sides of the two sides,
there are 5' UTR and 3' UTR,
that is,
will not be transferred out of the region.
Look here,
there is actually a section of the transfer block,
but only here is the protein,
that is,
this section and this section,
will not be transferred into protein.
But recently,
a lot of research has been found,
in fact,
these two blocks,
it may be some,
uh,
controlled protein,
where they will interact,
it will affect the later protein transfer.
This is a very important block,
but most databases
will not provide this information.
There is another one here,
very high expression of the block,
that may be a non-coding RNA,
we will introduce this thing in detail later.
In terms of cells,
we call it small non-coding RNA or SRA.
So,
is there any way we can
integrate these
multiple genomic features,
and then we will produce a
high-quality annotation
to help everyone,
so that users can use it?
And is it possible to customize,
that is,
what is my RNA sequence,
based on my sequence data
to do annotation?
Is it possible
that we can not only know these genes,
we can also know its function?
These questions are our motivation
to design this tool.
In fact, there are many,
in fact, there are many tools
that can do these,
uh,
do annotation.
But they all have some,
uh,
shortcomings.
Most of the tools,
they are all based on
genome sequence.
What does it mean?
That is, they only refer to
this,
there are some,
uh,
for example,
we do bacteria,
some bacteria,
it already knows
what the gene code looks like.
So it only based on this gene code,
and then do the analysis.
It will not look at
how many reads to,
to, uh,
compare to the position we want,
or the gene we want,
these information,
it will not consider.
So it leads to,
this prediction,
uh,
things are not necessarily
in line with our needs,
and the accuracy rate is usually
not so high.
The second,
they also lack a systematic comparison.
For example,
we use a tool,
we go,
uh,
to predict,
a part of the starting point,
and then we use another tool,
we go to predict,
this,
the part of the terminus.
As a result,
we find that these two
predict the result
is contradictory.
Often there is such a thing
to happen.
That is to say,
they will not systematically
to compare.
Okay.
So this is,
uh,
we want to do this,
the reason for the analgesic,
uh,
it is the first tool,
we are using RNA sequencing,
the data,
to do the genome notation.
That is especially for bacteria,
and archaea research.
Now introduce the analgesic,
this tool,
uh,
its several features,
the first is that we can
analyze different protocols,
RNA sequencing data.
RNA sequencing,
it has a lot of different protocols,
in order to do different purposes.
Uh,
we can,
we integrate
many different
RNA sequencing protocols.
The second,
we compare a lot of existing,
uh,
biological information tool.
Then,
we do the combination,
even,
we do,
the optimization of variables.
Then,
we even,
if some of the,
uh,
methods are not too good,
we do improve.
If the features we want,
it does not have,
the existing tool can predict,
then we will create a new one.
This is a modular tool,
that is to say,
it is very flexible.
The user can,
for their own needs,
and then build,
build the tool you want,
and then do the analysis.
Then,
the interface is consistent.
Finally,
we will also provide some statistics,
and visualization,
so that everyone can see,
to analyze,
your,
uh,
generated notation,
some accuracy,
and information.
So,
the overall purpose is,
we hope to be able to produce a,
systematized,
and high-quality notation,
and then be able to include,
different genomic features,
and then let the user can,
overall,
to see,
to analyze their data.
Simply put,
for example,
Lego,
piece by piece,
Lego piece,
that is,
RNA sequencing reads.
Then,
of course,
we can add other information,
but it is not necessary.
After that,
we can assemble,
into a variety of different models.
These models,
can be tailored to the user's needs,
you can assemble,
the model you want,
and then do your prediction.
In the end,
it will give you a,
high-quality notation.
At present,
Jessica has been able to predict,
more than 20 different features,
the accuracy rate,
is about 80% or more.
Today,
because it is impossible to introduce so much,
we will focus on a few,
core features,
to introduce to everyone.
These features,
these core features,
in fact,
we often use,
to predict other things,
a core.
Before introducing,
Jessica,
introduced two protocols,
two RNA sequencing protocols.
These two sequencing,
to do annotation,
is very helpful.
Of course,
if the audience of biologists,
if you want to directly use,
traditional RNA sequencing,
to do analysis,
there is no problem at all.
It's just that we think,
these two protocols,
can help to do annotation.
The first one is,
Differential RNA Sequencing,
called D-RNA-Seq.
In fact,
the number of applications is also very wide.
Simply put,
RNA reads,
it can be divided into two different types.
One is called Primary Transcript,
that is,
Triphosphate Binds,
at the front.
The second is called Processing RNA,
that is,
it does not have Triphosphate Binding.
What is Primary Transcript?
If you look at this picture,
this red line,
is actually reads.
That is,
it is in this,
will shift the starting value,
part.
If it is included in the starting value,
it will have this Triphosphate,
here.
If not,
like these,
these five different,
these five reads,
it is the middle part.
OK.
Then we add an element,
called Tags.
It will degrade the Processing RNA.
So,
with no Tag Tree Library,
its Primary Transcript,
and Processing RNA,
the ratio will not change.
But in Tag Tree Library,
the whole ratio,
Primary Transcript,
the ratio will be,
will be Enriched,
will be improved.
So when we do RNA Sequencing,
we compare these two libraries,
we will find that,
at the starting point,
this Tag Tree Library,
will be significantly,
higher than the Non-Tag Tree Library.
This will allow us,
to quickly determine,
where is the starting point,
the starting point of the transition.
If we know the starting point of the transition,
it can help us to determine,
there will be,
there may be some genes,
there may be some UTRs,
some very important information.
OK.
And this Resolution is very high,
can go to Single Neutral Type.
The second Protocol is,
RNA Sequencing with Transcript Fragmentation.
General RNA Molecule,
is about what I just said,
about 200 to 300 Nucleotides.
If we do directly,
sequencing,
this situation will often occur,
that is, we will lose,
3'N,
that is, the end of the information.
What is the reason?
Because our reads,
as I just said,
the longer the length,
the higher the probability of error,
or the higher the accumulation rate.
In order to,
sometimes the error,
the error ratio reaches a certain level,
we are very difficult to use these,
to help these reads to detect,
it is in,
which position of the genome.
Because,
this score,
the score of the mapping is not high.
So, when we are doing the mapping,
we will do a Quality Trimming,
is to put these,
error rate,
or when doing sequencing,
the quality is relatively poor,
we cut it off,
remove it,
and then only use the remaining part,
to do the sequencing.
Because it was cut off,
so 3'N information,
will be lost.
If we do a,
Fragmentation,
to make this RNA reads shorter,
usually we will set to 80 to 100.
At this time,
it will make this,
the number of neutrophils that have been sacrificed,
can be reduced.
That will make us able to,
detect the whole gene transcription location,
from the beginning to the end,
maybe we can detect it.
This can help us to see,
which are the real areas,
this transition,
where is the transition area.
OK, those are the two protocols.
OK,
to enter this,
our core feature,
our most important feature,
called Transcript Boundary Detection.
Because if we do not know,
where is the boundary,
we certainly have no way,
to easily judge,
the location of this gene,
or its length.
So the boundary is very important.
This is the starting point,
TSS,
as we just said,
if we have the RNA-seq,
we can easily judge,
this place.
Then,
this is more common,
we often use,
biological data analysis tool,
there are three,
called TSS Predictor,
TSS-SAR,
TSS-SAR.
Then we have,
after comparison,
found that TSS Predictor,
is the best,
the highest accuracy tool.
But the problem is,
it has a lot of parameters,
and its parameters are very sensitive.
If we change a little bit,
the whole result,
will be very different.
So we have to do,
optimization.
Then,
I will introduce this part,
below later.
Terminator,
is the terminal part,
there is a very common tool,
called TrenternHP.
This tool,
but it has a shortcoming,
that is,
it only uses,
genome sequence,
to do,
reference sequence,
to do predictions.
So the accuracy is not too high,
so we also made some improvements.
Then,
if,
our,
sample,
in,
database,
has stored,
the information of the protein,
we can directly read.
If not,
we can use,
RET,
this tool,
it can,
this,
use,
clean source,
and,
annotation,
sample,
or,
how to say,
species.
Then,
we transfer it,
to our target,
species.
Then,
we have,
this,
just mentioned,
fragmentation,
RNA sequence,
we can also easily,
read,
where is transcript.
Then,
finally,
we compare,
we have starting value,
we have protein value,
we have transcript,
we have terminator,
naturally,
then this is,
simply to see,
how we can achieve,
Boundary.
Then,
let's take a closer look at,
these,
feature prediction.
The first one is,
TSS.
I just said,
TSS,
is,
tool,
is TSS predictor.
Then,
in order to do,
parameter optimization,
we use,
a machine learning based,
optimization method,
called,
Genetic Algorithm.
Genetic Algorithm,
this is morphology,
I will introduce later.
Simply put,
Genetic Algorithm,
uses,
two different,
changes,
to achieve,
the purpose of optimization.
Simply put,
for example,
we have,
today,
this black line,
represents,
all the results,
that is,
all of our,
parameter,
array combination,
all the results,
are just,
make up this line,
every point,
it is a,
parameter result.
Then,
the lower part,
means the worse,
the performance is worse,
the higher the performance,
the better.
Then,
we will,
randomly choose,
a point,
then,
we may,
add one,
then we find,
oh,
two results,
better than one,
we keep two,
then we add one,
find three,
better than two,
so we keep three,
this traditional,
algorithmic method,
keep doing,
will do this point,
right?
Then we add one,
we will find,
hey,
the result,
seems not as good as before,
we will leave the previous,
then we will keep doing,
will find,
not as good as this,
this is the best,
optimized point,
but we,
there is another point,
actually better than it,
then we,
so it can not,
really find,
optimization,
what is the optimized part,
how,
that,
genetic algorithm,
what is the concept,
that is,
we also,
randomly take a point,
but we have a,
huge change,
that huge change,
will randomly,
run,
assign parameter,
so you do not know,
run to where,
may run to this point,
then we find,
hey,
better than this,
then,
next,
we adjust a macro,
add 1,
we find,
3,
better than 2,
we take 3,
then add 1,
add 1,
naturally,
we will slowly run here,
so simply,
that is,
through this global change,
we can help us find,
global optimization,
that,
macro adjustment,
help us find,
local optimization,
so that,
after we combine the two,
we can find,
the best,
optimization method,
that because,
TSS predictor,
too much,
so,
we,
transform a little bit,
this,
genetic algorithm,
that is,
we have one more step,
we have a global change,
that is,
we randomly assign,
all parameters,
that,
we do evaluation,
then,
we only take a few parameters,
to change,
the same,
randomly assign,
a few,
not all,
that,
will be large change,
then,
we do evaluation,
we do macro,
then do evaluation,
so,
we will get,
our optimized parameters,
OK,
that,
this is our result,
we use,
in three different,
bacteria,
and so on,
we will find,
that,
after optimization,
the sensitivity,
are largely,
have increased,
especially,
this,
we have increased,
about 30% sensitivity,
that,
in the specificity part,
it is difficult to see,
what changes,
the main reason,
is because,
data sets,
this,
bacteria,
may have 100,
nucleic acid,
but its starting value,
may be only 1000,
that is to say,
there are more than 900,000,
nucleotide,
it is actually,
not the starting value,
so it is 900,000,
than 1000,
this is very,
unbalanced,
will lead to,
its specificity,
has always been very high,
because you,
as long as you,
always say,
it is not the starting value,
it is actually,
prediction accuracy,
is also very high,
so,
this is the problem,
but,
the number of,
golden grape bacteria,
here,
has dropped,
about 2000,
we can,
remove 2000,
nucleotide,
ok,
this is,
the starting value part,
let's look at,
this transcript,
is the part of the transition block,
because,
we have sequencing data,
so,
we can easily,
see,
its,
gene performance,
so,
we can set,
a cut-off,
as long as,
higher than this cut-off,
we will determine,
it has performance,
so,
the reason for the cut-off,
is actually,
some mapping,
it is noise,
it is random mapping,
so,
we do not need to deduct these parts,
we set a cut-off for it,
then,
in addition,
we also set a tolerance,
that is,
if this performance,
has a,
temporary,
short-term decline,
we can tolerate,
then,
we can connect,
a few,
transcripts,
out,
then,
we can compare,
with our genes,
because usually,
a gene,
so,
we can use,
this gene,
information,
to help us,
to connect,
this is,
we do,
this,
transcript,
block,
this,
prediction,
way,
then,
finally,
talk about,
this,
terminal,
then,
actually,
terminal,
there is,
a common tool,
called,
TrenturnHP,
but,
we found,
when we use,
very intuitively,
to,
to judge,
if this is,
a terminal,
point,
then,
its performance,
should be,
significantly,
down,
or end,
is no longer,
right,
so,
we went to see,
this highest point,
and the lowest point,
it should have,
a decreasing,
if there is,
we say,
this is the correct,
terminators,
but,
the problem is,
some,
TrenturnHP,
it predicts,
this terminator,
or,
it is false,
it is in this,
uh,
condition,
in this sample,
it has no effect,
or,
there is no performance,
this,
basically,
this CDS,
has no performance,
then,
this terminator,
naturally,
has no function,
so,
by this way,
we can increase,
our specificity,
then,
we can remove,
some of the,
but,
how do we increase,
sensitivity,
uh,
for example,
if today,
we have two proteins,
uh,
it,
the direction is relative,
then,
naturally,
there should be,
a terminal,
otherwise,
it will be like this,
turn,
there's hairpin loop,
we're talking,
about hairpin,
so,
it has two-level structure,
very stable,
so,
we're going to search,
this part,
this position,
this,
the middle of two proteins,
do we have,
this two-level structure,
if yes,
then,
uh,
this,
performance,
this RNA,
and sequencing the,
this performance,
and there are these,
deterioration pattern,
we will judgment,
it is a terminator,
then,
thus,
the sensitivity,
so,
the whole terminator,
prediction accuracy,
can be mentioned,
about 80% or so,
good,
then,
this is our,
a real example,
this is,
uh,
a golden grape ball,
an example,
you can see,
the red,
this histogram,
it is,
we're talking about,
fragmentation RNA-seq,
you can see,
it covers,
the whole transcript,
can cover,
this block,
then,
general RNA sequencing,
this is differential RNA sequencing,
you can see,
this information,
good,
then,
we just talked about,
this dRNA-seq,
through this text tree,
and non-text tree comparison,
we can know,
TSS,
uh,
where is the starting point,
you can see,
obviously,
there is a text tree library,
higher than non-text tree library,
so,
this is a TSS,
here,
then,
we use,
terminator prediction,
we find TSS,
terminator is here,
then,
CDS,
protein is here,
then,
naturally,
with this feature,
we can,
extend,
to predict more things,
for example,
we can predict,
where is the transition,
where is the operon,
you can see,
for example,
this example,
there is a transcript,
there is a whole transition block,
then,
there are two proteins in this block,
meaning,
these two proteins,
they are together,
transferred and transferred,
so,
these two proteins,
it is possible,
they are related in public use,
then,
we can also find promoter,
promoter,
it will accelerate,
or promote,
this,
we do the transition,
process,
so,
usually,
it is in TSS,
which is the front of the starting point,
about 35 to 50,
this nucleic acid,
this position,
so,
when we,
we already have TSS information,
naturally,
we can extract,
extract the front,
or extract the front,
these sequences,
then,
we do,
this,
this promoter,
analysis,
then,
we can find,
oh,
indeed,
it has a very specific,
sequence,
code,
TA,
TAAT,
this,
in bacteria,
we call it pre-know box,
it is a promoter,
ok,
good,
now,
we have,
this,
transcript boundary,
then,
sometimes,
it is very interesting,
that is,
what we just said at the beginning,
sometimes,
we will find,
it has a very high expression block,
but,
it is not a protein,
so,
this is a very common,
a topic,
called non-coding RNA,
no matter in which field,
you do nucleation,
you do,
cell,
bacteria,
will,
will be involved,
will want to do this,
what is non-coding RNA,
that is,
we just said,
traditional,
in fact,
it should be DNA,
into RNA,
RNA into protein,
but,
there is,
there is a special case,
that is,
DNA into,
into RNA,
it will produce,
a very interesting,
secondary structure,
that is,
it can interact,
it can interact with,
with this RNA,
it can control,
a lot of different things,
you can see,
in,
in this bacteria,
in the research of,
Sermal RNA,
from 2000 to,
2000,
2016,
this publication,
the number,
is an increase in the number,
say,
it is a very important,
topic,
so,
we use,
analgesic,
you can also read,
non-coding RNA,
how to do it,
because,
non-coding RNA,
in it,
there is a type,
this type,
we can use an example later,
very simple,
let everyone see,
that simply speaking,
that is,
intergenic,
the,
the position,
that is,
it is like an island,
not with any protein,
there is a connection,
that this,
if this part,
we can,
directly judge,
it is very likely to be Sermal RNA,
of course,
we will look at its length,
Sermal RNA length,
usually,
within 300 to 500 nucleotides,
so,
if it does not have any,
with protein,
any contact,
high,
high expression,
and then there is the starting value,
the length,
again,
less than 300 to 500,
then we can directly judge,
it is very likely to be,
Sermal RNA,
non-coding RNA,
if its distance is too long,
we will go to see,
is there a part of the part,
a,
a point,
is that it has this,
obvious,
large magnitude,
expression of the decline,
if there is,
it is very likely,
this paragraph,
is that we did not predict,
the Terminator,
so,
here may be,
Sermal RNA,
or is there,
is there a possibility,
it is a process inside,
that is,
process inside,
it has enzyme,
it will cut the gene,
let it,
this paragraph,
that is,
take it to do,
do prediction,
that is,
it will cut this paragraph,
and then this paragraph,
becomes a functional Sermal RNA,
if this situation,
we also think,
it is possible,
that another location,
is in UTR-derived,
that is,
it will,
it will be with protein,
together,
transition,
sorry,
but it will not transition,
into the protein area,
that is,
at the end of the part,
if it has TSS,
that is,
already to the end,
obviously to the end,
but it has a start value,
or it has a process inside,
will cut it,
that it is very likely,
in fact,
it is Sermal RNA,
at the end,
that is,
if it has a start value,
that end,
in,
to reach,
protein time,
it has a process inside,
here,
or it has an expression,
a significant decline,
we also think,
it may be Sermal RNA,
the other is,
Interstitial,
that is,
it is two proteins,
transition,
as mentioned earlier,
it is a transition together,
two proteins,
and then in the middle,
this block,
with 5'-LUT is very similar,
if it has a start value,
because there is a process inside associate,
or its end,
it has a significant decline,
that it may also be Sermal RNA,
good,
let's take a look,
this,
our algorithm,
will not work,
so we apply it,
in several,
uh,
strands,
several proteins,
first of all,
this is a,
Intergenic Sermal RNA,
you can pay attention to see,
in this,
uh,
transcript is very obvious,
high expression,
then there is TSS,
that is,
start value here,
then we go to take this sequence,
we go to the data base to compare,
it is a known Sermal RNA,
that we can not only find the known,
we can find some unknown,
some novel,
for example,
here,
it is the same expression,
that is,
there is TSS here,
it has not been reported,
it is Sermal RNA,
but it is obvious,
if it has expression,
there must be something there,
so it is very likely,
it is not found,
Sermal RNA,
that is,
in 5'UTR,
you can see,
about the front part,
it is a transition,
here,
protein here,
that front un-transition block,
there is a very extreme,
high expression,
block,
then we go to cut it to see,
then here,
there is a very fast decline,
we go to cut it to see,
found that it is,
a known Sermal RNA,
that is,
3'N,
has reached the end,
there is a very high expression,
then we go to see,
it is also a known Sermal RNA,
that is,
inter-CDS,
these two CDS,
it is a transition,
you can see,
in the middle part,
there is a sudden high expression,
there is also a TSS,
then we go to see,
it is also a known Sermal RNA,
that is,
antisense,
I just did not talk about antisense,
basically,
it is in a direction,
there is protein,
for example,
it is in this direction,
from right to left,
this direction of the transition,
it is going down,
it means it is in this direction,
then it is a protein,
but in its relative direction,
from left to right,
it also has a block is expressed,
they are overlapping,
then we go to see,
found that here,
in fact,
it is also a Sermal RNA,
then we call it antisense,
Sermal RNA,
that is,
it is different from the protein in the direction,
overlap each other,
OK,
then,
since we have seen these cases,
we want to know,
what is the accuracy rate?
So,
we went to compare four different bacteria,
they all already have a known Sermal RNA list,
then we go to predict,
we found that our detection rate,
probably up to 80%,
according to different species,
different percentages,
but 80% to 90%,
we can detect all of them,
known Sermal RNA,
that is,
there is no problem,
that unknown,
we will not have a lot of mutations?
So,
we have a cooperation with NIH,
then they use our tool to analyze,
Bordetella pertussis,
is also a bacteria,
then he found 15,
they think it is possible,
Sermal RNA candidate,
some of which,
they think it is possible,
but,
Energetic did not predict,
if you see the ID,
Energetic ID,
we have predicted,
that is not,
we do not think it,
Energetic,
do not think it is,
that result,
that is,
there are about 10,
is the correct prediction,
that is,
really is Sermal RNA,
or really is not Sermal RNA,
so,
there is about 70% accuracy,
that we simply introduce a case,
we think,
we all think very interesting case,
that this is,
two proteins here,
in the middle,
there is a very high expression of Sermal RNA,
we predict it is Sermal RNA,
OK,
its length is about 67 nucleotides,
is 67 nucleotide length,
then,
we know that this is very interesting,
Maxine fat burning,
it is known to suppress,
the expression of the cause of the disease,
so,
if we do not add Maxine fat burning,
you will find that this Sermal RNA exists,
67,
there is a very strong signal,
that is,
this Sermal RNA really exists,
it really will function,
but,
if we add Maxine fat burning,
because the cause of the disease was reduced,
you will find that the expression of this Sermal RNA is also reduced,
it is said that this Sermal RNA,
it is related to the disease,
OK,
then,
the study has found that,
BVG-AS,
it is two,
called two-component system,
they will interact,
then,
how to say,
will promote the expression of the cause of the disease,
when we,
if we go to mutate,
this BVG-AS,
you will find that,
no matter if you add Maxine fat burning,
this,
Sermal RNA,
its expression is reduced,
that is to say,
this Sermal RNA,
it will also be,
this,
BVG-AS,
two-component system,
control,
in addition,
there is a thing called,
HFQ,
it is a global,
Sermal RNA binding chaperone,
that is,
it will be with many,
different Sermal RNA,
do the interaction,
that,
the purpose is to help these Sermal RNA,
to,
find,
its target,
above,
so,
when this HFQ,
is mutated,
you will find,
Sermal RNA,
reduced more,
so,
here,
it is very simple,
to launch a,
hypothesis,
that is,
this Sermal RNA,
it is related to the cause of the disease,
it will do the interaction with HFQ,
to find its target,
to,
target gene,
that,
it will also be,
BVG-AS,
control,
so,
from here,
we can see that,
in fact,
analgesic,
we have predicted,
novel Sermal RNA,
with a certain accuracy rate,
good,
in addition to Sermal RNA,
we can also,
as we just said,
predict 20,
20 different genomic features,
so,
we will compare,
each different,
feature,
their database,
that,
most of the database,
it has Ecoline,
large-sensitivity data,
so,
we use large-sensitivity to do,
that,
we have differential RNA sequencing,
or,
we only use traditional RNA-seq,
that,
most of the accuracy rate,
can reach about 80%,
the prediction accuracy rate,
but,
there are two,
very special,
one is called TSS,
which is the starting value,
one is Promoter,
one is only 6%,
one is 39%,
but, of course,
we can also understand,
because Promoter and TSS,
are related,
Promoter is usually,
on the top of TSS,
35 to 50,
nucleotide length,
so,
TSS is not good,
Promoter,
of course,
will not be good,
so,
why not,
we will see,
that,
this is,
in Public Database,
RegulonDB,
three,
RNA sequencing data,
they,
then,
you will find,
they have,
very large,
sequence,
only 43,
starting value,
they are,
can be found,
that,
there are many,
most of them,
they are self-evident,
there is no overlap,
then,
we suspect,
this data,
there should be a problem,
because,
they are all Ecoline,
how can the difference be so big,
so,
we want to say,
then,
we put,
all,
these three,
Database,
plus,
these data,
these TSS data,
we all go forward,
to find Promoter,
see if we can find Promoter,
the result,
is like this,
these three,
Database,
Dataset,
they have no way,
to find,
the existence of Promoter,
but,
in Energetic,
80% of TSS,
can find,
with this Promoter,
Association,
so,
we can know,
these three,
Public,
Public Dataset,
actually,
there is a problem,
then,
Energetic,
it is actually,
accuracy,
in providing,
Annotation,
it is a,
high-quality,
Annotation,
OK,
then,
I want,
to introduce here,
then,
other Features,
if you are interested,
we can discuss,
no problem,
then,
finally,
I want to,
give you a little,
report,
advertising,
welcome everyone to use,
basically,
it is like this,
this,
our,
Energetic,
has been,
integrated,
to NIH,
biological information,
list,
inside,
so,
NIH,
can also be very free,
they are also very,
often use our tool,
then,
the second is,
LabOne,
it is a,
organization,
it will collect,
various,
different,
biological information,
software,
they are,
when they collect,
software,
they will do,
voting,
will let this,
they can vote,
they feel better,
then,
we were,
recorded that week,
voting,
we are,
top three,
position,
then,
the other Energetic,
was also reported,
by RNA-seq blog,
then,
when we have preprinted,
we will be reported,
to RNA-seq blog,
that blog,
is also a lot of people,
in addition,
we are now,
this Energetic,
has been applied to,
very,
different,
bacteria,
so,
a lot of,
published,
paper,
then,
some,
tools,
also started to use,
our tools,
as a,
standard,
because we are,
the first tool,
to use RNA-seq,
to do,
non-coding RNA,
prediction,
so,
they also started,
to integrate,
these Energetic,
tools,
or compare,
our tools,
then,
recently,
a lot of,
papers,
have been published,
so,
I will,
I will also,
reply,
if I have a bug,
welcome to tell me,
then I can also,
correct,
so,
this is,
our GitHub,
basically,
Energetic,
is stored here,
it is an open source,
everyone can,
use at will,
you want to modify,
or how,
there is no problem,
if there is any problem,
this issue,
you can also open,
then I can also,
go to see,
to upgrade,
OK,
good,
finally,
Energetic,
is the first,
modular,
and systematic,
RNA-seq-based tool,
to do,
genome annotations,
mainly for,
bacteria and archaea,
then we compare,
a lot of different tools,
then we integrate,
the best one,
then,
we also create,
then improve,
these methods,
we not only integrate,
we also improve,
then we can,
systematically,
to compare,
to detect,
many different,
genomic features,
then we also,
optimize,
necessary to optimize,
these parameters,
so,
users can freely,
to use,
to do,
you want to do,
feature detection,
then we provide,
statistics,
and visualization,
for your reference,
OK,
finally,
is to give you a,
high-quality annotations,
then,
in the future,
we hope to continue,
is,
to use deep learning,
to improve,
our predictions,
deep learning,
it is a,
up-to-date,
machine learning method,
then the other is,
we also hope,
to integrate more,
RNA-seq protocol data,
to help us,
improve,
our prediction accuracy,
we also hope,
to extend,
our function,
to,
virus,
and,
biological research,
above,
that,
finally,
thank you,
my,
this is my,
subject,
although,
I have left,
for a while,
but,
this,
we have been updating,
that,
this is my,
boss,
then his,
people below,
help me,
experiment data,
that,
this is our,
bioinformatics team,
that,
NIH,
help us,
experiment,
cooperation subject,
that,
this is my boss now,
although,
I have jumped to,
proteomics,
and,
multiomics,
single cell,
less touch,
RNA-seq,
this,
bacteria,
RNA-seq part,
but,
he still,
give us a lot of freedom,
can go,
maintain,
my tool,
probably,
that,
if there are any questions,
I am very,
welcome,
then,
we can discuss together,
thank you.
OK,
thank you,
Songpan,
help us do such a wonderful speech,
OK,
now,
audience,
is there anyone who has any questions,
you can turn on your microphone,
then,
ask questions,
OK,
if not,
I will,
have,
OK,
hello,
I am,
British,
Bristol University,
first time,
to attend,
this conference,
thank you,
have you heard,
yes,
thank you,
one question,
you mentioned,
that,
there is a,
TSS optimization,
that is,
parameter adjustment,
that,
myself,
recently,
was taught by the boss,
to analyze,
proteomics,
that adjustment,
refers to,
comparing,
the RNA sequencing,
with
the Z-score,
how do you,
how do you say,
that part is,
relatively,
not so,
complicated,
because,
we are,
our,
the WebLab,
members,
they are,
seriously,
to really
use the meat of the body,
to compare,
this,
RNA sequencing of data,
so they are very certain,
to find out the meat,
after the comparison,
set,
so these sets,
is our Golden Standard,
so I'm going to compare,
this set,
and then calculate,
sensitivity,
and specificity,
right,
so,
I did not use,
P-value,
this thing,
right,
but,
if you are doing,
proteomics,
then,
it is possible,
you need to compare,
P-value,
but,
how to do this in detail,
we may,
need to know,
ah,
the purpose of your research,
and,
optimization,
or,
you can do this,
so,
you need to know,
how to do this,
to determine,
this,
right,
thank you.
Okay,
so I have a question,
which is,
thank you for providing,
this,
and this.
So,
the question I want to ask you is,
about your research,
I did,
some solar star system complexes,
what are the general characteristics of this solar star system,
and how do you determine
the individual characteristics,
for example,
we have different,
uh,
patients,
their,
for example,
we want to know,
does it change the pathology of the pathology,
that this thing,
for,
for annotation,
the requirements are relatively low,
so they will usually,
usually go to see the pathology of the change,
to do statistics analysis,
right,
but he,
this method,
he can study some of these pathologies,
that is,
the performance of RNN,
uh,
polygons,
or,
does he have any RNA performance?
Can you use this tool?
There may be no way,
because if you want to do,
look at the performance of RNA,
in fact,
we do,
simply do mapping,
we can get this,
uh,
that is,
we generally talk about this,
we just said,
at the beginning of this histogram part,
that is,
you can get,
you can get this thing,
that,
usually we do,
will not do,
there is a need to see,
non-coding RNA,
UTRR,
and so on,
less,
but of course,
if they,
someone wants to use,
there is no problem,
it can also be done,
it can also be analyzed,
absolutely no problem,
can be used,
just that I am,
I am just less,
almost did not see anyone,
will do,
to do,
want to go to see,
non-coding RNA,
or go to see,
this UTRR,
or look at the binding type,
and so on,
less,
usually go,
directly to see,
UTRR,
will be more,
understand,
good,
thank you,
that,
there are people,
any questions?
OK,
if not,
then we thank,
Songwan today,
to give us this speech,
that we look forward to next time,
if you still have a chance,
can come again,
Taiwan,
update the latest research,
thank you,