Hello everyone, I am the host of today's presentation. My name is Lu Haoran. I am currently studying for my doctorate degree at the University of Connecticut in the United States.
I am also a staff member of Project Terra.
Project Terra provides online presentations to young Taiwanese scholars from all over the world.
Today's speaker is Mark Du Youlin.
I would like to start by reminding Mark that what we are about to see is not his video.
Therefore, I would like to ask him to share his screen.
Mark's past experience is in social science and education. His major is artificial intelligence, which includes personality, creativity, and consumer behavior.
After his research on cognitive science, his current research is related to natural language.
He is now a research assistant at the Center for Cognitive Neuroscience at the University of Connecticut.
He also has a personal website.
You are welcome to visit Project Terra's website for more information.
Today's topic is Applied NLP to Understand Creativity.
Take Twitter and Kickstarter for example.
It focuses on the knowledge of reverse engineering and applied psychology.
I believe everyone is very interested in today's presentation.
Thank you for attending today's presentation.
Before Mark's presentation, I would like to ask everyone to leave a comment in the chat area.
I will pass this question to Mark.
Please reply.
Now I will give the floor to Mark.
Hello, everyone.
Thank you for attending today's online presentation.
Today's topic is about public knowledge.
My name is Du Youlin.
My English name is Mark.
I will jump to my self-introduction page first.
My name is Mark.
At first, I studied social science at the University of Connecticut.
Then I transferred to the adult education department at the University of Connecticut.
Then I stayed at the University of Connecticut.
I was a research assistant at CS.
Now I am a research assistant at the Center for Neuroscience Research at the University of Connecticut.
When I was in college, there was a professor who specializes in human resources management.
He was interested in creativity.
So I learned from him.
When I graduated from college, I worked on an AI project.
So I am also quite interested in computer science.
I will combine these two topics today.
If you are interested in psychology, computer science, computer science, or data science,
you are welcome to communicate with me.
Data science has three parts.
If you have seen the literature diagram,
The top left corner is computer science.
The top right corner is data science.
The bottom is domain knowledge.
It depends on which major you are majoring in.
This field is really fascinating.
I will share it now.
There are four parts to my outline today.
The second part is self-introduction.
The second part is about public knowledge.
In general, people think that creativity is good.
In theory, the public knowledge website is very popular.
If you are very creative, I will share my research results.
The third part is about behavioral economics.
It's called reversal bias.
In a certain situation, we will choose A.
In a certain situation, we will choose B.
Why do we have such a reversal bias?
I will explain more later.
The last part is the conclusion.
Let's review today's topic.
Creative Fundraising.
How to write a creative fundraising?
How to raise the most money?
The tool I use is the latent language analysis in natural language processing.
I use KS as an example.
Let me briefly explain the definition of creativity.
There are two definitions of creativity.
The first one is the most familiar to us.
It's novelty.
It's the level of imagination.
The second one is more interesting.
The second one is useful.
It's not just imagination.
Your imagination can be used.
That's the so-called creativity.
There is a theory that creativity is economic theory.
If you can achieve great success in the economy,
we will think you are a useful ability.
That's all for today.
Sorry.
At the beginning of the first day,
I want to invite you to do a small activity.
This activity is a question.
The three pictures on the screen are the three products on Kickstarter.
The leftmost one is a ten-second toothbrush.
When you open your mouth,
the machine will clean your teeth in ten seconds.
This is the leftmost one.
The middle one is the 8K VR glasses.
The rightmost one is the first smart watch in the world.
These three are on Kickstarter.
I want you to guess which one is more creative.
In terms of natural language processing,
which one is more creative?
Which one gets the most money?
If you use consumer questionnaire,
which one is more likely to be chosen by consumers?
At this time, I want to cut it back.
Everyone guessed it.
One person said he thought it was VR.
The other three said it was a toothbrush.
Four people said it was a toothbrush.
More and more people chose the toothbrush.
This is quite interesting.
I also want to brush my teeth clean in ten seconds.
Let's wait another 20 seconds.
Okay.
I want to tell you that the screen has turned white again.
Let me check the comments.
Okay.
Let me take a look.
Two people said it was VR.
The other three said it was 567.
About seven people said it was a toothbrush.
Okay.
Let me switch back.
Let me announce the answer.
Sorry, my mouse...
I can't see my mouse.
Oh, there it is.
Okay.
Announce the answer.
The mouse on the far left has the lowest amount of money.
The mouse on the far right has the highest amount of money.
However, if it is processed by a natural source and a questionnaire,
it will be the opposite.
As everyone voted,
everyone prefers a ten-second toothbrush.
If it is processed by a natural source,
the ten-second toothbrush is the most creative.
Okay.
You may think,
how can it be like this?
It looks like a great product.
How can it have such a low amount of money?
Next, I will introduce it.
Okay.
This product is recognized as one of the most creative products in history.
It is our iPhone.
Before Apple launched the iPhone,
it failed about 12 times.
Except for iPod, Macintosh, and Apple II.
It failed about 12 times.
Among these 12 times,
there are 9 products.
I listed them here.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9.
These 9 products have something in common.
They all have something in common.
In fact, there is something in common
on the iPhone.
But the iPhone didn't fail.
And this feature
became the selling point of the iPhone.
It became the selling point of the iPhone.
Let's review it.
There are Newton, Lisa,
Apple TV, and palm-shaped computer.
There are many reasons for the failure of these products.
But they have one thing in common.
The iPhone has it, too.
It's too expensive.
Frankly speaking,
I personally think
the design of the iPhone is really amazing.
But in terms of business strategy,
especially in terms of pricing,
it is a completely wrong strategy.
Because it failed 9 times in a row.
This is definitely not a coincidence.
This is definitely the consumer's preference.
So we can see that
if a creative product
is priced too high,
the probability of failure is very high.
Even a genius like Dr. Jia
can't save this thing.
Next,
before I solve this problem,
let me introduce the natural resource processing tool I use.
This tool is called
latent semantic analysis.
It's a very interesting field in AI.
It's called latent semantic analysis.
This language analysis
assumes that
the similar text
between text and text
is less creative.
If these two words
are far apart on the language network,
if the probability of it appearing in the same article
is relatively low,
then we assume that it is more creative.
Because you think of something
that others may not think of.
People rarely connect
10 seconds with machines and tools.
So of course,
it is more creative.
Latent semantic analysis,
in addition to being used in this creative field,
it can help you sort your articles.
You can throw about five sentences.
After five sentences,
it may divide you into two concepts.
In these two concepts,
there will be a lot of words below.
You can see that
the meaning of the A group of words is closer.
The meaning of the B group of words is closer.
The result may be different from what you think.
So if you are interested in LSA,
you can search on the Internet
and try it.
This is LSA.
This picture is a bit out of place.
To put it simply,
this is a screenshot of a paper.
This paper was written by
a professor at UNC,
Kurt Gray.
He led a paper.
He measured creativity with words.
The green one below is Low Creativity.
He asked the audience
to write words
with their own ideas.
They kept writing and writing.
They tried to write something creative.
For example,
this group below
is called Grape, Strawberry, Fruit.
These are all fruits.
This is very close.
In terms of definition,
we can say that it is less creative.
For the above,
Grease, Slick, Sick, Nelsia, Ocean, Glass,
it seems that
they appear in the same article.
We define that
this person
is more creative
and more imaginative.
After introducing
the method of measuring creativity,
let's go back to the previous question.
Why do we like creativity
when we do
paper research,
but we don't like it when we actually buy it?
As you just saw,
if you do paper research,
when you actually
talk about it,
you will choose
creative products.
Computers can also measure this.
But if you put it
on the website
or sell it
directly on the market,
sometimes
these very novel products
are not sold well.
Why is this?
Because
we are actually
very
risk-averse.
When a product is
different from others,
consumers
like your creativity.
But on the other hand,
you have to think that
your product is very creative,
but because it is new,
we have never seen you before.
We will have uncertainty.
Uncertainty will produce
another thing called risk.
Let's take
Kickstarter as an example.
Kickstarter is a fundraising website.
Before your fundraising amount
reaches the target,
it will not be sold.
Your money may be invested
and it may be reimbursed.
Because the investment failed,
it can't be sold.
At this time, consumers will measure
the risk.
If I buy your product,
aka invest in your product,
will it evaporate
or not be sold?
So when your product is
very novel,
on the other hand,
people will be a little scared
and dare not buy it.
When I asked my friends before,
I got a similar result.
My friends also chose this way.
Their reason is that
they really want to buy it,
but it is too expensive.
This is what people think.
This is very strange.
So,
do we like
creative products
or hate creative products?
This is very strange.
It means that
our attitude has changed.
We like it and we hate it.
I want to cut this thing
from the level of
behavior economics.
In behavior economics,
there is a thing called
conversion preference.
These two economists
did research in 1973.
When we
choose a product,
if its price
is fluctuating,
we will put the
high and low rankings
of this price
to make a conversion.
A is better than B,
but after the price adjustment,
B is suddenly better than A.
This is very contradictory
to traditional economics.
No matter what,
A is good.
No matter how the price changes,
I will definitely choose it.
This is the development
of behavior economics.
This is a small experiment.
Which plan do you
prefer?
We are now
investing in a plan
to save African children.
We spend $1,000 to save
100 children's lives.
We feed them.
This is the first plan.
Or we use
$2,000
to save
African children's lives.
This is very
intuitive.
The proportion is not equal.
$2,000 can save
300 lives.
The return on investment is higher than the previous plan.
There is no doubt.
Moreover,
life is priceless.
You can't use money to measure life.
It is reasonable to
choose A.
However,
if
today
I cover
A plan
to save 100 lives,
B plan to save 300 lives,
A plan is $1,000,
but
I cover
B plan $2,000,
I ask you
if you save 300 lives,
how much money
do you think the government
should spend to
save these lives?
However,
usually
the beneficiary will answer
the price lower than $2,000.
For example,
$1,500, $1,400, $1,300
will not
jump to $3,000.
They will
use your $1,000
to save 100 lives.
This is
Daniel Kahneman
and Tversky's
anchoring bias.
When you are given a set amount of money,
you will make some mistakes later.
You will not
multiply
100 to 300,
1,000 to 3,000.
We will save a little
$1,500, $1,600 will not
jump to $2,000.
This is the anchoring bias
in behavioral psychology.
Let's go back to
the product
of creativity.
Psychologists
do a series
of experiments
on creativity
and risk.
There are two groups of beneficiaries.
The first group
is the control group.
It presents a product
that is not creative like the iPhone.
The beneficiary uses
an attitude test
to connect
the creative product
with positive words,
such as happiness and warmth.
The positive words are connected.
The negative words
such as disgust and ugliness
are separated.
The other group
does the same experiment.
The beneficiary gets a creative product
and assigns
positive words to the creative product.
The negative words are
far away from the product.
Creativity
is very social.
In theory,
if you don't talk about it,
everyone will think
that you like creative products.
The more, the better.
Whether it's business or other aspects,
as long as this person is creative,
everyone thinks it's great.
The attitude test is implicit.
It doesn't affect
your social expectations.
If you have a different view
from the society,
it can be tested.
This is the so-called
inner attitude test.
Let's talk about
the experiment group.
What is the behavior
of the other group?
There is a balloon
next to the iPhone.
The experimenter
will accidentally
poke the balloon.
The balloon will explode.
When the balloon explodes,
the beneficiary will hear the sound.
The beneficiary will be surprised.
The sound is enough
to scare the beneficiary.
After the beneficiary is scared,
there is a little cash in the balloon.
It means
the money is yours.
In other words,
you don't know how the balloon will explode.
The sound will scare you.
You will feel disgusted.
After this uncertainty,
there will be some cash.
It simulates
the creative
and high-risk creativity.
They asked the beneficiary
to do an inner attitude test.
As a result,
the experimenter
found that
the group without balloons
have a good relationship
with the beneficiary.
But the group above
had a different experience.
The group above
has an inner attitude.
They are not
so close to the beneficiary.
Their relationship
with the beneficiary
will be easier.
The beneficiary will feel disliked
and sick.
Faced with
the high risk
of scaring people,
our attitude
towards entrepreneurship
will change.
So,
our attitude towards entrepreneurship will change.
How do we explain this?
This is
based on
the reversal bias of
the group above.
Let's say
you want to choose a handsome guy
to be your partner.
I will present
three options.
The first one is Tom Cruise.
The second one is Joe Kerman.
The third one is Elon Musk.
Tom Cruise is more handsome
than Joe Kerman.
Joe Kerman can sing
and he is also handsome.
He also acted in a movie.
Elon Musk is also
one of the candidates.
However,
if you compare Elon Musk
with Tom Cruise,
Tom Cruise is not
as handsome as Elon Musk.
Some people
may think
Elon Musk is
an entrepreneur
and he is smart.
He is smarter than Tom Cruise.
So,
people will choose Elon Musk
over Tom Cruise.
So,
A is greater than B,
B is greater than C,
but C is greater than A.
This is a magical inequality.
This is
the experiment
of Daniel Kahneman,
his partner,
who did
a classic
economic experiment.
You may think
how to calculate
the weight of power.
Is smart more important
or handsome?
Or is it as important
as Joe Kerman's dancing?
Which one is more important?
It is strange.
We have to use a mathematical formula
or it is illogical.
This is
what I learned
from YouTube.
It is
a course
by Amos Tversky
in 1981.
It is called
Measuring Inequality.
It was
uploaded to YouTube
in October 2019.
It is called
Measuring Inequality.
He wrote
this proof.
It is
9, 13, 19 points.
Let's interpret it
as a product's quality
or creativity.
9 points of creativity, 13 points of creativity, 19 points of creativity.
Of course,
19 points of creativity is higher than 9 points of creativity.
It is unquestionable.
What about the left?
The left is the price of the product.
No one
wants to buy things with 30 dollars.
Try to use 10 dollars.
So,
our preference is
from left to right,
from top to bottom.
Then,
we multiply
these six numbers
by 9.
We use
the product's
quality score
to multiply
the product's price.
Let's say
13 times 30 is
390.
Let's take 390
as a general attitude.
Overall,
how much does he like this product?
For
normal logic,
let's look at the orange arrow.
The orange arrow is normal logic.
It is
from top to bottom.
The lower right corner
is
the lower
the score.
We can use
lower cost
to buy this product.
This is normal logic.
However,
under certain conditions,
you can see the middle
line.
There is a god logic.
It will
show 270
to 260.
We call it
risk.
In this case,
we don't care about the risk.
We don't care.
270 is high risk.
If
there is a god logic,
how does it work?
On the left,
we multiply
by
10.
We multiply
by 10.
On the right,
the growth rate
is not that high.
On the left,
30 and 10
are 3 times higher.
9 and 19
are not 3 times higher.
Let's assume
we don't care about
creativity.
We don't multiply.
The price is double.
The number of creativity
is not
the growth rate.
In this case,
the matrix
will be
multiplied by
the god logic.
Under certain conditions,
we are afraid of
the risk.
Under certain conditions,
we don't care about the risk.
It is
hard to understand.
So,
I think it is better
to use crisis analysis.
In general,
we have the same
statistical chart.
We have the same
preference for a thing.
So,
we draw a straight line.
However,
our preference for creativity
is not a straight line
but a curve.
At first,
we like creativity.
However,
as the price goes up,
we only go from 9 to 19
instead of 27.
So,
our creativity
is not a straight line
but a curve
on the chart.
So,
it is close to the concept of crisis.
As you know,
behavioral economics
shows the preference
for a thing
in the way of crisis analysis.
Traditional economics
is a curve.
It is a straight line.
It is very intuitive.
However, human beings are irrational.
When the price
goes up to a certain level,
the preference
for a thing
becomes smaller and smaller.
This is the difference
between traditional economics
and behavioral economics.
In fact,
it lacks professional knowledge.
I asked a senior
how to explain
the curve
to a manager.
He said
it lacks domain expertise.
You need professional knowledge.
You can't explain it
to your manager
with your professional knowledge.
This is the concept of curve.
To sum up,
if your idea
is very novel,
you should
lower
your price.
Don't raise
People will be afraid.
They will think
your idea is good
but
on the other hand,
if your idea
is very low,
you should
use your imagination.
For example,
when a YouTuber
uploads a video,
the cost is low.
So,
if you want to be a successful YouTuber,
you need to
use your imagination
to make your video popular.
For example,
if your video
has 10 views,
but none of them likes you,
the 10th video
happens to
hit a certain person,
the person
likes your video
and your subscription
goes up.
This is the strategy.
If you don't join the membership,
I will click your video
to watch.
On the other hand,
if you are a high-cost YouTuber
who is conservative,
you want to satisfy
all your subscribers,
the success rate will be low.
In general,
people don't want to watch
funny and boring videos.
These are the references.
The first one
is a paper
about
measuring creativity.
The second one
is
a book
about creativity.
There is a Chinese version
of the balloon experiment.
You can check it out.
It's very interesting.
The third one
is Originals.
It's written by
Alan Grant.
The Chinese translation is
版判.
It's very interesting.
It describes
the risks
of creativity.
It describes
how creative people
are.
Alan Grant is
an excellent psychologist.
The next one is
Justin Byrne.
He specializes in
predicting creativity.
He predicts
whether creativity
will be successful in the future.
It's very difficult.
But he did it.
He is really strong.
The next one
is
a paper
on behavioral economics.
It was first published
in 1973.
It's called
Experimental Psychology.
The last one
is
Daniel Kahneman's
partner,
Amos Tversky and
Richard Seiler.
It's about
anomalous preference reversal.
why our preferences
are so amazing.
A is greater than B,
and B is greater than A.
It's amazing.
There are many
details in the paper.
If you're interested,
you can
look it up.
That's
all for
my presentation.
Any questions?
If you have questions,
you can ask them directly.
Yes.
I have a question.
You just
drew a picture.
You said creativity
is not limited
to people.
It's increasing
and becoming more and more attractive.
For example,
is there any experimental
approach
or someone trying to
analytically model it?
For example,
is there any way to
quantify
creativity
and make it a axis?
Another axis is
I can somehow quantify
attractiveness.
Then I can
quantify
the green line.
I think
this model is OK.
But I'm doing
document analysis and
data science analysis.
So I haven't done it
in the lab.
I'll figure it out
in the future.
OK. Thank you.
Any questions?
If you have
other questions,
you can unmute
yourself.
Then you can ask.
If you have questions,
you can unmute yourself.
Hello?
Can you hear me?
I'm Anping.
I have a question.
Your speech
was very interesting.
I didn't hear
what you said
about data science
in the beginning.
How does data science
contribute to creativity?
But I heard
data science
contributes to
future direction,
possibility,
traditional experiments,
behavioral economics,
and experimental psychology.
Can you tell us
more about
data science
playing a special role
or future role?
And you seem to have the result.
You said you have data to predict.
Is it something like that?
Thank you.
At that time,
I was purely
analyzing
the website
provided in the paper.
The result of the analysis
is the total amount
of data
on Kickstarter
and the paper.
It's called Forward Flow.
It's related to
negative.
So,
I think data science
and psychology
are interlinked.
You will see
something different
from your common sense
or domain knowledge.
At this time,
you have to think
whether
there is something wrong
with this program
and whether
common sense is biased
or domain knowledge needs to be modified.
You need to have
a little intuition
and professionalism.
If you find that
this is against
common sense,
but it has
the academic theory
of creativity to explain it.
However,
there is a theory to explain it,
but it's still
in the academic theory.
So,
this is a space for development.
You can
use
this kind of
computer program
to run some data.
You can copy and paste at the beginning.
If you find that
it's against common sense
and domain knowledge,
you can think about
whether this is
a good question
for future research.
Can I ask another question?
You mentioned
data science
and the difference
between it and domain knowledge.
I'm not sure
if you know
what data science is.
I don't even know what it is.
Can you explain
what kind of
way data science
looks at these issues?
I don't know what it is.
Thank you.
This question
is a bit difficult.
Let me use another PowerPoint
to explain.
This is another research I did.
I went to
Cambridge Analytica.
If you know
how to steal
data from Facebook,
you should know
what Cambridge Analytica does.
A group of data scientists
steal text from Facebook
to predict your personality traits.
Their research
is in conflict with
domain knowledge.
How do we
explain this phenomenon?
Data science
is the third
block,
and it's the most important.
LSA,
Latent Semantic Analysis,
doesn't use
Bayes' Theorem to calculate.
It calculates
the relationship between
words and words,
not cause and effect.
Cambridge Analytica
does use cause and effect.
Here,
they use LSA
plus probability.
D stands for text.
Z stands for topic.
W stands for word.
This word
has a chance
to appear
in this document.
This is
the probability.
If I appear
in this topic,
what is the probability
that I appear in this word?
If I appear in this document,
what is the probability
that I appear in this topic?
They use Bayes' Theorem
to calculate.
Here,
we can explain
these two things
in the same way,
but the difference
in the algorithm
causes the difference
in the data structure.
Let's use
LSA's Theorem.
Let's look at
a set of data.
We can see
this large piece of data
as Cambridge Analytica.
We can see
this large piece of data
as Cambridge Analytica.
If you divide it
into popular singers,
the popular singer
is related.
However,
the popular singer
is only a small piece
in all creative people.
If you add
a conditional probability,
you can cut
this small piece
of data.
I tried to
explain in math.
I tried to explain in math.
This is the mathematical proof
of the Tversky hypothesis.
This is the Mathematical proof of the Tversky hypothesis.
I used this mathematical proof
to explain
the question of
computer science
and
the knowledge of creativity
.