OK, thank you very much for being able to participate in the weekly speech of Taira today, and of course, thank you very much to our speaker today, Shen Mingxue, for sharing with us what she is going to talk about today.
Before we start, let me quickly introduce Ms. Mingxue. Mingxue is a master's degree in aerospace engineering at Tsinghua University.
Next, we will continue to read about the details of space science related to the CU Boulder.
But I think the most interesting thing is that when I look at her introduction, it looks like a Star Trek fan.
This is the technology required for space exploration, as well as the research that needs to be solved, which is very exciting.
Without further ado, let's give the time to Mingxue, and then let me warmly welcome today's speaker, Shen Mingxue.
Shen Mingxue is a master's degree in aerospace engineering at Tsinghua University.
She has a master's degree in aerospace engineering at Tsinghua University.
Today, I would like to introduce the measurement and exploration of cosmic dust.
If you can see my mouse on the right, we are using a lot of spacecraft.
What I do is related to space. When I was in college, I watched a lot of movies, so I wanted to know something about Star Trek.
There is a space engine in Star Trek, so I went to the teacher to ask him what kind of space engine could be used in space.
Later, I found that it was not practical, and when I was in the master's class, I was not good at it. There is an impulse drive on Star Trek, which is the so-called electric power engine.
So I went to the master's thesis and did an impulse drive. After doing it, I found that there were not many people using it in the world.
At that time, the propulsion in space was still a rocket or a coolant. My so-called rocket is only the chemical propulsion and combustion. This part is related to its propulsion or other things.
Another part is that you need to pay attention to the space environment where you are in the space when you are in space.
The space environment we are in today is very different from the one we are protected by the entire atmosphere. I went to do some research on the electric power layer later.
Now when I come here, we start to do star science and do some aspects related to cosmic dust. I have done some data analysis of Cassini.
What I have been doing recently is the Parker Solar Propeller and the Solar Orbiter. The one above is NASA, and the one below is a project mainly cooperated by ESA and NASA.
Both are orbiting within a solar unit within 1 AU near the sun. Why is it special? I want to mention this distance.
When we talk about cosmic dust later, the space environment is close to the distance of the sun, the position of the solar unit on the earth, and even the outer solar system.
The space environment is different. This will lead to the charging effect of our probe or spacecraft, that is, the charging effect on it or the position it is in is different.
It will have a different interaction with the surrounding background environment, which may lead to different things happening on both sides of cosmic dust.
The first thing we need to talk about is dust. When we go to the beach, there is also sand, or when you wipe the floor, there will be some dust. These are indeed called dust in Chinese.
But scientifically speaking, these dusts still have to start with the Big Bang, which is the large-scale theory we are talking about. After all, it is the source of all matter.
So the Big Bang is the beginning, and then it starts to gather or form some hydrogen or hydrogen, and then it slowly starts to have more and more ions, and then it finally forms more atoms and molecules.
In the end, it forms our galaxy or the entire universe. In the middle of this process, cosmic dust is often a very important role.
You often see some photos in astronomy about the nebula. The nebula is simply a cluster of clouds, which contains a lot of gas or dust.
When they gather together, they become such a nebula. But because there is density inside, so when they get denser and denser, another singular noun is dense molecular cloud.
It is also a part of the nebula, but it slowly, because at the beginning of the universe, we said there was a strange point, and it was very hot.
After it began to slowly expand, its temperature began to drop. After a long time, when its temperature became slightly less than high, and then slightly denser and denser, it began to form molecules.
In the process of these formations, it slowly began to evolve and form. When those heavier and heavier substances are formed, they slowly gather.
Because of some gravity, it will begin to form some possible stars that are going to form a star.
Next, another form will appear, which is the stellar nebula. It is really going to form our star. It will encounter some gravitational collapse and gather it up.
Then, its core will begin to heat up more and more until it begins to form a fusion state.
In the process of these, all of their molecules, atoms, and gatherings will begin to encounter some fine, iron, aluminum processes, plus some high-energy UV or other high-energy ions colliding.
It will produce some basic examples of cosmic dust. At present, it is still in a theoretical state, which means that its theory is not yet complete, and we do not yet know how they are produced.
After all, if we can be clear about this, we may be able to start thinking about how organic matter is produced, or how our life originates.
In the end, this whole situation will begin to form an original nebula. The center of the original nebula is a star, and then it will start to rotate around the orbit.
After the orbit, they will begin to gather into 10 stones, larger asteroids, and even form the eight stars we are in.
In these cases, it forms a so-called stable orbit, which means that when you have a star-shaped orbit like the Earth, we will roughly clear out the dust of these places around the distance of our astronomical unit, either gathered or sucked into the atmosphere.
If there is no gathering, there will be a small nebula between the Earth and Mars that we are familiar with.
After billions of years, when the sun is no longer the current yellow, it slowly becomes a red giant and slowly reaches the end of its life.
As soon as it explodes, it swallows all of our stars, and then it spits out those substances. It eventually becomes a small stone, becomes dust, and returns to the origin.
That is, in the end, this so-called planetary nebula is directly blown up, and then it becomes a very beautiful, clouded image.
That's why we usually say dust to dust. The reason we say dust to dust is because some of the cosmic dust that was created at the beginning, some small substances, and then slowly gather together to form bigger things, until they can become a solar system, a star system.
In the process, there will be some satellites, some small stars, and then interplanetary dust. In the end, after the whole explosion is blown up, it will all come back again.
In other words, all of us here are a part of the star system, and we are all their main components.
Okay, let's jump back. In the solar system, we have a lot of cosmic dust. In the upper left corner, this is our Cassini, which was on its way to Saturn.
It encountered a satellite in the middle called Enceladus. The interesting thing is that it will spray this kind of water ice dust in its south pole. We call it dust, or we call it a small particle, a small crystal.
Scientists are very interested in whether there will be any life on the surface of the ice. The other one is that it can produce Saturn's E-ring, E-ring, the little crystals that we can see, which are made up of these dust.
Or in the upper right corner, our moon also has a lot of dust, and then it will have some dust because of some magnetic field fluctuations and some external solar wind blowing.
That is, before the astronauts went up there to step on a footprint and stepped on that footprint, that was the dust.
There are also some very interesting examples, such as the Saturn satellite Io in the lower left corner. The volcano will erupt, and after it erupts, the particles that erupt into dust will start to go into the solar system after the gravity of Saturn's star group is finished.
So there will be a part of the group coming from there near our Earth. Or we used to have people, uh, Rosetta, right, uh, European probe, they went to this, uh, 67P to learn about these dust streams.
Or the Japanese who just came back, they just picked up some dust from the little stars of the Dragon Palace. Or the next new flagship plan is to go to another satellite in Jupiter, Europa, to measure some of the cosmic dust.
Okay, so is there anything closer? First of all, the cosmic dust is probably going to look like this, and it's probably within a few microns. Of course, if it's a little bigger, it's probably up to 100 to 1000 microns.
There is also a kind of classification, the so-called nanodust. The main thing is that if you are on our Earth, uh, I remember it was early in the morning to the east, uh, west to the east, to the west.
When you look to the west, you will see something like yellow light, and yellow light is interplanetary dust, which is the so-called dust in the solar system, which is constantly fixed by the gravity of the sun, and it has its own orbit.
It will scatter some of the sunlight, and what we see is the yellow light, and what we just saw is the bright E ring, which is what we just said, Enceladus, which is caused by the dust of those ice crystals blown out by the South Pole.
No, or when our comet usually passes by, we will see the dust tail, the dust tail, so the dust tail is the dust tail, which is our dust.
Well, since we have a lot of dust in our solar system, how do we measure it? There are a lot of measurements on the right side, including you can see the light, you can see the thermal emission, or someone can use the radar, even like Arecibo, Arecibo Astronomical Observatory, they can measure some, uh, some things about the comet.
Well, the main thing we do in space, if we use a satellite or a spacecraft to measure, it is the so-called impact ionization, which is the impact ionization, which is the impact ionization, which is the impact ionization, which is the impact ionization.
Well, what about this thing? The impact ionization mechanism is directly related to the volume or weight of your dust.
So what is the mechanism of the impact ionization? If we have a high-speed L, which is generally considered high-speed, which is at least greater than 1 km per second, if our dust hits any surface,
then the first thing that comes out may be some neutral particles or ions or electrons, because we have tied it up, uh, to become impact ionization, which is ionization.
So there will be ions and electrons, and of course some solid pieces will be sprayed out, which is from those, from that spacecraft or anything else.
Then its formula, here you will mainly see that it is related to the weight of your cosmic dust and the speed of its impact, and the speed of this impact is even more powerful.
Okay, so why do we say this is important? The first one is that we can use this mechanism to understand the weight of your impact, and the weight will usually be directly or indirectly related to its volume.
The other one we can know its speed, so when we know its weight and speed, if we can use other methods to know the location or source of its impact, we can roughly simulate its orbit, its position, its size in the entire solar system.
If we go back, we can understand where it may come from, from Jupiter, from Saturn, or where it comes from. If we go back, we may understand, uh, or even know, uh, how long these dusts have lived in the solar system.
Can it tell us some information about life that happened a long time ago or something? What about the electromagnetic cloud generated by the impact plasma cloud? Some related formulas may be related to some temperature, some speed, and some other things.
So how can we measure it? Generally speaking, it is not measured by the antenna we are talking about. It is actually measured by some of these so-called, uh, a lot of electrical networks.
Then we can get some scale maps, and from the scale map, we can know that, uh, the ice or dust that hit it contains some, uh, gas, carbon, CH-related, or some silver, iron, uh, uh, gold, or something else.
Then these can help us understand that the components on it and even whether there are some organic matter. The one in the upper left corner is the Cassini project.
Well, the instrument it carries is something similar in the middle. There is another very interesting thing that, uh, they used to install some so-called PVDF, which is a very thin film.
That thin film is when there is ice or dust hitting it, it will also produce a similar electrical signal. This is just the difference between different instruments, but it is actually the same, uh, mechanism to measure.
Okay, so let's go back to how we use the antenna to measure. How does the antenna do the measurement? It must have a collision at the beginning to measure something.
After the collision, it is 5 to 10 or 12 kilometers per second because of the high speed. This is relative to the speed of our probe, which means that when the probe flies 100 kilometers per second, like Parker Solar Probe, it actually flies faster.
After the collision, it produces the electric field cloud of Impact Plasma Cloud. It will start to expand because it is going to leave. At this time, we will have the effect of charging on the probe or on our antenna.
In the end, it will be our background, because we are actually in the state of electric field in space. The electric field in our space mainly comes from some of the electrons, light, or other direct things brought by the solar wind.
Let's talk about the space environment a little later. So we mainly find that if a main instrument, like the one just now, is very expensive, several kilograms, 7, 8 kilograms, or even more than 10 kilograms, it can only be measured in such a small place.
But what about our antenna instrument? Our antenna instrument has a form called monopole. The difference in its measurement location is on the antenna and our probe. That is to say, anything can hit the antenna.
It can also hit any part of the body of the entire probe. In other words, the entire probe is the surface area that we can measure. Compared to this small, special one, we will tell people that, of course, what we can measure is definitely not as complicated as the design just now.
It may be more complicated to measure, and it may even be flat. But we can tell them more supplementary information and some basic features of Impact Plasma Cloud. So we will say that it is very sensitive because it has a very large measuring surface area.
When we do research, the predecessor must have done something. What the predecessors have done is probably to say that they found that they provided some theory that after the impact, they felt that all signals were only related to the antenna.
They did not consider the fact that they hit the probe, and they said that they felt that because the antenna was measuring something, it was just a probe, so it was only related to the antenna. The second person said that after the object hit it, I think it may be related to the antenna, but mainly because it hit the body, so its formula is only related to the spacecraft itself.
The third person said that I think what you said before is wrong. Since our formula is called the difference between the signal on the antenna and the signal on the probe, the two may be able to measure something.
So he used a correct idea to do it, but he did not know how to understand how this signal was, so he assumed some mathematical formulas and then did fitting, and then he found that the fitting was not very good, so he kept introducing new variables, and then after the introduction, he gave some experimental parameters, and finally found that it was OK.
So we will sum up the above, we will find that in fact, we may not know how the signal is produced, but we know that there is a signal, and there is no good qualitative model at present, which is what we want to do.
Fortunately, what the people in front of them do is to analyze two things in space. At Colorado University, we can not only do those analyzes, but we also have a so-called accelerator, we can simulate the impact of dust.
What kind of device is this? It is a peletron, which you can imagine as a static accelerator, which is what I call an electron cannon.
It will pass through some of our middle Particle Selection Units, which is the speed at which we can control the impact above. We can set our model to the lower left corner, which is a space probe model.
We can set its floating position on the body, which is about how much. We can know that different antenna configurations are actually different, and the impact position will be related later.
There is another one, because after we collide, we produce electrons and ions. If some of the students of the Institute of Engineering or the Institute of Physics know that electrons and ions, it will start to work with the battery factory, and it may rotate.
In this case, if we encounter a magnetic field, or some external magnetic field, the impact plasma that actually erupts will have a different shape.
Another one is that we find that the dust particles of different materials may have different reactions after they collide. This has a lot to do with the atomic mass contained in it, or some of its other substances on the surface of the probe surface.
Later, we will talk about this thing, which is more mathematical or physical. We will talk about Induced Charging and Direct Charging. In other words, if you imagine this yellow ball as a charge, you put a dot outside.
Finally, after we go through the so-called image charge method, we will sum it up. In other words, on this whole ball, in fact, this ball is the subsequent probe. What you measure will include the entire charge on this ball, your probe.
In addition, when the external charge is further away, it will have a 1 over r decay, which is a lot of electric field, or electric position, or something else.
When you are close to your parents, you have a greater limit, and when you are far away, the limit you are subject to is relatively small, and the impact you are subject to is relatively small. So what's on top of this is fixed, but what's far away from the dot will be reduced with the distance.
So what about our antenna signal? You will find that this is very similar to the thing I just drew, the Cassini number.
After we hit it, didn't we just say that there was a cloud, and then it went out? At this time, in general, the electrons will expand faster, and then the ions will expand slower.
In this case, it will produce a signal similar to the one in the lower left corner. The main source of this situation is because your spacecraft may be positive or negative.
If your probe is positive, you will absorb some negative electrons on the surface with positive electricity, and you may be negative.
Then all the ions will leave, and then these leave, which is what we just talked about. In the process of leaving, it will produce different positions on your probe correspondingly.
In general, you can imagine a situation, and then the electrons start to go out, so the electrons go out correspondingly to the ions that remain on your probe, so you are positive.
But in this case, because we are on both sides, we usually cut off the antenna signal and the probe signal. In this case, we generally think that when the antenna is far away, we simplify it as the oscillation of the position of the probe alone.
So we just said that the electrons ran away first, and the rest of the main positive on the probe, because of the negative number just mentioned, so it gets a feature of downward.
Then your ions are gone, and your probe is not so positive, so it is relatively negative. Negative plus a negative number, it becomes a positive, and then it comes down.
So in general, as long as you see a similar signal, in general, any beam probe in space, the signal of general dust is all like this.
This is a very complicated formula, mainly to tell us that when you have something hit your probe at the beginning, the thing that hits it will produce a charge because of the oil or electricity.
It is directly related to the quality and speed of the dust that hits it.
Next, because of the position of the probe, it may be positive or negative.
In contrast, your ions or electrons will be divided into those who have enough energy to escape, or those who are trapped on the surface.
Then we can get these different quantities and tell them that they are collected and stuck on it, or they can escape.
The charging equation will finally tell us which ones are on top, which ones are gone, and it is related to 1 over r decay.
There is also the so-called discharging, which is a very fun thing.
Discharging comes from the solar wind in the space environment, for example, when light hits, it produces a light-emitting effect and kicks out an electron.
Then your spacecraft will become positive, or the electron hits and is absorbed, and your spacecraft becomes negative.
So we will have a floating potential floating position in space, which is the meaning of this so-called discharging.
Finally, according to q is equal to cv conversion equation, we can get the floating picture of the position just now.
What we just talked about is the equation we came up with, and we found that the equation is the so-called red thing and the green experiment thing.
The so-called discharging feels pretty good, and it can provide us with some numbers or some information.
It tells us that after these impacts are collected, what are some of the characteristics of the electricity generation temperature, electron temperature and ion temperature?
Or after it produces the electron, how can it leave its speed or its background?
Because when we were experimenting, we knew the so-called position floating and we knew the speed of impact and mass.
So we can understand the following things, but on the other hand, in space, we actually don't know much about the above information.
So we are mainly from the following things, after you have finished, we can guess the position of the floating above.
Then according to our orbital mechanics calculation, we can guess that the speed of impact is about how much.
Then from the following data to rebut tell us that how much is the value of our dust?
So it is the so-called, we are generally talking about the measurement of the antenna instrument, it is similar to the supplementation or the measurement of a specific dedicated measurement.
Then we will think that we want to make a standard model, then you will find that this kind of thing looks like Sputnik, or it is very similar to the Pike solar propeller.
Because we want to know if it is hit in any place, its signal is the same, but we find that it is not the case.
So this is a top view, you will find that after the impact, if it corresponds to 45 degrees away from any antenna, you will find that it actually looks very similar.
That is, its signal may be almost the same, which is mainly what we said before, most of the reaction is on the probe, so it is caused by the probe charging.
But when we look to the right, we will find that if your impact is very close to a certain antenna, it will have a very special peak.
Then we think this is related to induced charging, because we have added this conductor antenna here, so we think it will affect this.
Then we think this is a very important reason, because the first thing you have to do is to make a box.
If this kind of thing just affects your box, in fact, the number of boxes here is not the real thing, it may actually be some fake things.
So we have to understand the location of the impact first, and then we can restore the real box process to get the real data hidden in it.
So the paper we are writing now is to tell you that we think we can simulate this situation.
That is to say, if you simplify what you just saw into a probe and an antenna, you will find that some of the boxes will be collected after the impact, and some will leave, as we just said.
Because they are not particles at all, they are electrons, so they are charged.
The charge will produce an electric field line, for example, at the beginning, when it is very close to the probe, it is all connected, slowly approaching the antenna.
It is actually closer to the antenna, which means it affects the antenna more, and then it slowly ends when it reaches infinity.
So when we simulate some of our problems, we can simulate some of this shape and tell people that, hey, actually, look, if this is an x-axis, it is a distance, and the y-axis is your location.
You will find that compared to this round probe, in fact, as long as your charge is away from it, it is a 1 over r decay.
That is, the further away you are from it, the less you feel its impact.
But the antenna is very strange, it comes out of this peak in the middle.
That's because at the beginning, the main thing that affects the charge particles is your probe.
But in the middle, your antenna is here, and it is more affected.
So you are in these two, because we measured the antenna, subtracted the spacecraft probe, you will get this particularly high peak in the middle.
That is to tell us that this is the reason, this is why we can get this peak.
So when we can simulate this situation, after the calculation of static electricity, we can go back and get those simulations.
So when we get those collision locations, we can start playing with all the probes in space.
For example, Cassini, or Stereo, this is for measuring the sun.
Or it's already far away from our ball shock, not ball shock, terminal shock.
It's already close to leaving our solar circle, the Voyager.
Or recently near the sun, the Parker Solar Probe, or the solar orbiter.
There was Wind and MMS earlier.
Then you will find that there seems to be something different.
If you cut it off here, we find that the reason why we are doing experiments is that these antennas are stuck on the side.
It's stuck with three of these antennas.
The signal it measures will be different.
That's a lot of trouble because it has something to do with some of the configurations on our circuit.
It's related to the C conductor between Q and CV.
That's what we're doing right now.
So you can imagine that when we have this method or technique,
We can measure from the inner solar system near the sun to 1AU, the so-called Stereo or Wind orbit around the Earth, or even MMS within the Earth's magnetic field.
Then all the way along, including Europa Clipper in Jupiter, Cassini in Saturn, or Voyager has left our solar circle all the way.
So after we have this method, we can analyze all the way from the inner solar system to the outer star Gaia, all the way to the outer solar system.
The distribution of our cosmic dust, or their orbit, or their source.
So to sum up, we're all sources of cosmic dust.
Of course, we know that we've heard of some space stuff, but we don't want to measure those ashes in outer space in the future.
But basically, these things are all dust.
The second thing is that the simulation we're doing right now and the model functions we're providing.
We found that it's actually a good way to analyze a signal of cosmic dust hitting your probe or antenna.
So with these things we provide, we can understand some of the hidden impact plasmas in the middle.
The inner characteristics of the impact probe to understand some of the temperature inside, its speed, its distribution.
And then after the application, we can get some impact locations.
And after we get these impact locations, we can find out where these dust comes from.
And then we can understand the characteristics of the location of that planet or the original dust, or its space environment.
And even some of the things that are measured on top may be organic.
So can they tell us some information about where our origin comes from?
Are we the only species in the universe?
So that's what we're doing right now.
Okay, I guess 40 minutes.
So, let's start the Q&A.
Is my microphone on? Okay, it's on.
The timing is just right.
Before we start the Q&A, let me give a warm round of applause to thank Mingxue for sharing with us today.
I personally think that the first part of the presentation was very precise.
The other part was very rich in content.
I tried my best to speak in Chinese.
All kinds of demonstrations and illustrations were very impressive.
Very clear.
Very good at explaining.
Do you have any questions?
If you have any questions at this time, you can turn on the microphone and speak.
Before you speak, please tell us your name and affiliation so that we can get to know you better.
Hello, I'm Chengxin Da.
Can you hear me?
Hi, I'm Mingxue.
I'm a postdoc at UPenn Chemistry.
My name is Chengxin Da.
I have one last question.
You mentioned that you can analyze impact of a project.
Can you tell us where it comes from?
Yes.
That's a bit too...
That's a bit too far.
From the analysis of its composition,
I know you can know its mass and see if there's anything organic in it.
But how do you know where it comes from?
Okay, good.
First of all,
you can start by imagining if...
Let's say we launch a space shuttle from the Earth.
If you fly to the moon,
because first of all, any probe in any place,
we can basically calculate its orbit and speed.
After you know the orbit and speed,
if we can know the impact location,
we can probably know its origin and speed.
Right?
The first one is the origin and speed.
After the origin and speed,
we have a method to calculate the speed of escape.
So you can know the speed of escape.
You can know who might tie it up.
For example, is it tied up by the Earth?
Is it tied up by the Moon?
Or is it tied up by the Sun?
I think you can know...
For example,
your probe is between the Earth and the Moon,
so you can know where it comes from.
For example, if I fly to the Earth and the Moon,
I measure 8 km per second.
8 km per second is probably the escape speed of the Earth.
But it can't escape 30 km per second from the Sun.
At this time, we would say
it should be in the middle.
If you measure 5 km per second when you return to the Moon,
it won't be outside,
but the speed on the surface of the Earth.
It's about 2 km to 5 km.
So we can guess from here.
There's another one, like the Parker Solar Probe.
I can't show it,
but I can tell you that
when we measure,
we know that the closer we get to the Sun,
there will be a block,
that is, your impact will be higher and higher.
But when they...
In addition to the impact,
they found another unknown peak.
It's still being studied at the moment,
but they think that
in the measurement or non-passing process,
just at that time,
there was a comet passing by.
So they think it's related to the comet.
Yeah.
The comet is a dirty snowball.
There's water in it, and there's organic matter in it.
So we're always happy to say
that as long as the measurement is related to the comet,
will there be life in the universe?
So if we're talking about chemistry,
the latest thing we're going to do
is the Europa Clipper.
It's going to go to Jupiter.
If it used to be Cassini,
I'll zoom in for you.
if it used to be Cassini,
oh, this is not zoom,
I can't draw this.
Wait a minute.
If it used to be Cassini,
its resolution would look like this.
OK.
Its resolution is really bad.
You probably know what it looks like.
But you don't know what's in the middle.
For example,
its isomers can't be seen.
Yeah.
But the latest one,
its resolution can be higher.
So we want to look at the middle,
especially some of the carbon dioxide compounds
to understand
if there's any life in it.
OK.
Does that answer your question?
Yes.
Very interesting.
OK.
Does anyone else have a question?
Or you can go ahead and ask.
Hello, I have a question.
OK.
Hi, I'm Zheng Yunting.
I'm a Ph.D. student at Caltech.
I do astronomy,
as well as cosmology.
I think your talk is quite interesting.
You see,
these things are
foreground for us.
We don't want them.
I have two questions.
The first one is
I want to know
how much
the rate of
cosmic dust
is in
Cassini.
Is it like
tens of thousands per second
or a few seconds per second?
We can say a few tens of minutes.
Sorry?
We usually say
a few tens of minutes.
A few tens of minutes?
Yeah.
If you want to get close to the sun,
at the nearest point,
at 340 solar radii,
that's 20 minutes per second.
As far as I know,
the New Horizons
is
I don't know if there's one per week.
That's the current rate.
But if you're talking about
Cassini
in Enceladus,
where it flies through the ice,
it's saturated.
It's like
a hundred or a thousand per minute.
So,
it's like
a hundred or a thousand per minute.
In this kind of place,
it's hard to measure
because the whole instrument is overloaded.
OK.
What if it's
outside of Mars?
What's that called?
The small star belt?
The small star belt is usually
If this is a small
Oh, the small star belt rate.
I'm not sure about this.
But
if you can get close to
these sources,
it should be pretty high.
But other than that,
if it's in a general empty space,
it's a few dozen minutes.
OK, OK.
Got it.
And my other question is
if you have
If your detector
is hit by Cosmic Ray,
will it affect it?
OK.
Good question.
If it's an antenna device,
it won't.
But if it's this kind of PVDF,
it will.
Because this kind of thing
for high-capacity ions
or even for temperature control,
it's going to give you a wrong signal.
But for a PVDF detector,
it will.
In this case,
if it's what we just talked about,
these two on the left,
this kind of dedicated dust analyzer,
UV will also be affected.
So it can't measure directly in front of UV.
It's usually sublim.
It's about 30 degrees to 45 degrees.
You can start measuring
to all the back sides can be measured.
But you can't go to the sun.
There's a problem with the sun.
Because it's got MCP
Yeah, that's a good question.
As for the antenna measurement we just talked about,
because this kind of thing
is something that can be hit.
There's no difference in UV.
OK, OK.
What if you look at the stars
and then reflect the light of the sun?
Will the UV be too strong?
Stars reflect UV?
Generally, it won't.
Because in general,
albedo,
what we usually hear is no.
It's not that exaggerated.
OK, OK.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
OK, thank you.
You're welcome.
I know you guys,
there's a picture that looks like
something like that,
that size,
and then it goes down like this.
And then the lower part is the bigger star
or that kind of star.
And then in the middle is a small star.
And then the upper left corner is dust.
Is this albedo?
No, no, no.
In astronomy, when you measure,
you usually measure the bigger the better.
We measure where we don't want
the smaller the better.
Oh.
Yeah.
Because our experiment,
Zodiacal Light
is our biggest experiment.
Because we measure
near-infrared wavelengths.
And our main wavelengths
are actually
the reflections
of small stars nearby.
Yeah.
Got it.
OK.
Can I ask a question?
Sure, go ahead.
I don't know if this question
sounds unprofessional.
But when you were drawing
the rotation angle,
what did you say?
If the two antennae are in the middle
at 45 degrees,
it will look like this.
But if you put it on the antenna
from time to time,
it will look like this, right?
Yes.
OK.
That's the picture, right?
I was thinking
about the frequency problem.
It doesn't sound good
for two weeks.
But if today
it's a stable beam,
it's not one thing,
it's a beam,
and we assume it's a stable frequency.
At this time,
because we know
the rotation of the detector,
because the rotation
is on our machine,
we can record it.
Of course, there is an assumption
that the direction of the beam
is fixed.
In this case,
for example,
the first one looks like this on the left,
and the second one
has a different angle,
and it looks more and more
like the picture on the right.
When it hits the antenna,
it becomes the picture on the right,
and when it leaves the antenna,
it becomes the picture on the left.
There is an oscillation
that can be solved.
In other words,
it can be solved
what kind of frequency
it is now.
The first thing to know
is the frequency.
But the frequency knows
because it knows the frequency
every time it pauses.
So you can take this parameter
and use it.
But this is something
that needs a stable flow.
Can you do this?
I think I deleted something
and missed to tell you.
When we were doing the experiment,
we measured where the collision was.
There are 10 degrees, 30 degrees,
45 degrees, 60 degrees,
and then we went around like this.
So we measured a lot of things.
Of course,
for example, this is 10 degrees,
and 30 degrees may be in the middle.
Yes, yes, yes.
Yes.
What you just said is right.
When we do measurements,
generally speaking,
the main probe in space
is actually not fixed.
It's best to let it choose.
There is a frequency to choose.
Our attitude control system
will know its angle of rotation.
If you say today,
for example,
let's say we encounter
an Enceladus.
This is the one that keeps spraying ice.
It has a fixed
time rate.
OK,
what you want to talk about is this, right?
Yes, yes, yes.
You really know how to explain things.
After going around like this,
you will find that
if the original signal
is red,
you will see the blue signal
going up and down.
This is what you want to talk about, right?
Yes, yes, yes.
Yes, yes.
In this case,
we generally believe
our attitude control system.
In this case, it's really interesting.
We must believe
our attitude control system is correct.
So if our attitude control system is correct,
we can know that
suppose I want to change a color today.
Then I set it as the
pointing direction.
I might have known at the beginning
that my pointing is like this.
I think my first antenna points there.
The second antenna points there.
You will rotate like this, right?
Yes.
In this case,
we can solve the location of the collision.
But I have to say
there is a drawback in this case.
The first drawback is
our probe
will never be as beautiful
as this sphere.
This is the first one.
The second one,
even if this sphere
I draw a big probe now.
The middle one is called
your antenna.
I will face it directly at the top.
There is a drawback in this case.
You know its angle.
It's the distance
between you and it.
But the distance is
similar to the distance of a copper core.
Right?
You don't know
the distance.
If the distance is so close
and it's a perfectly fixed sphere,
the signal here
and here
look like this.
The distance is there.
You don't know if it's here
or here or there.
So we need to
develop a new model
or think about how to explain it.
It needs to be improved.
OK.
I just thought of another one.
Can't we just
hit the earth
and build the model first?
That's right.
So now we have a model
like the Pyke Solar Probe.
Cassini made a model.
This is a 20 to 1 model.
It's exactly the same.
So we later said
we have this model.
We have this physical model.
This doesn't seem right.
I mean
there is a formula for the physical model.
After we have this,
we take a physical model
which is also called physical model in English.
Laboratory model
to do this kind of simulation
of hitting the earth.
Then put the two together.
We just want to tell people
who wants to launch a thing with an antenna.
We can make a model
and then do this kind of simulation.
After knowing all the parameters,
when you get to the sky,
you are facing these databases
to correspond.
Then it's accurate.
Yes.
Got it.
Good question.
Any other questions?
You can ask anything.
If you don't want to ask about the universe dust,
you can ask about the electromagnetic dust.
Or you can ask about the particle promoter.
Since you mentioned it,
let me ask.
Why did you decide to
make an antenna?
Because the particle promoter
is a bit far away.
But it doesn't seem impossible.
It can't be done.
First,
in the US,
you can't make a promoter.
Second,
everyone knows
who gives you money,
just do it.
You said you can't make a promoter in the US?
What do you mean by that?
I don't know.
What does it mean?
As long as you come across
defense or military industry,
you can't do it.
Even if you are a foreigner in Taiwan,
You can't do it as a foreigner.
Let's be official and scientific.
After I made the particle engine,
the particle engine
is related to the space environment.
In the space environment,
in addition to electromagnetic waves,
matter will collide.
So we need to make some cosmic things.
You can also understand the origin of your life,
right?
That makes sense.
Do you have any questions?
Let me see.
We are waiting
for one minute.
If you don't have any questions,
I'll end the recording.
Someone wants to ask a question
but doesn't want to be recorded.
You can ask after we're done.
I mean we'll end the recording
after one minute.
No problem.
Okay.
One minute is up.
On behalf of everyone,
let's give Mingxue
a big round of applause
before we end the recording.