Recording has started.
All right.
In 2011 and 2015, he received his master's and Ph.D. degrees from the Narrow Engineering and Microsystems Institute of Tsinghua University.
He also served as a postdoc researcher at the University of Illinois's Urban Champion.
He is currently working as an assistant professor in the Department of Power and Mechanical Engineering at Tsinghua University.
Today, Prof. Ming-Huang will be giving a presentation on RF Microdevices Based on the ThinFILM Lithium NeoBit.
Prof. Ming-Huang, please give us a warm welcome and applause.
Thank you for your introduction. I am Prof. Ming-Huang Li.
I am currently working as an assistant professor in the Department of Power and Mechanical Engineering at Tsinghua University.
My background is the same as what I just introduced.
I received my master's degree in mechanical engineering from Tsinghua University.
After that, I completed my Ph.D. degree from Tsinghua University.
After completing my Ph.D. degree, I briefly served as a postdoc for a year in Taiwan.
I then looked for opportunities to work as a postdoc in the United States.
Later, I was able to successfully work as a postdoc in the ECE Department of UIUC.
My main research topics are divided into two directions.
The first one is a funding project for me.
It is a DAPA Amoeba project.
The goal is to develop a low-frequency mechanical rectifier that can be used in the military.
At the same time, we have another project under execution.
This is the topic I am going to talk about.
My research interests are these.
Whether it is a static power supply or a power supply,
As long as it is a microcomputing component or a supercomputer component,
They are all in my area of interest.
If you have any questions, please feel free to interrupt.
Thank you.
This is my outline today.
First, I will start with our motivation.
The motivation is divided into two parts.
The first part is why we want to apply the sound wave component to the RF system.
It has a very long history.
But maybe everyone doesn't know why.
So I will start from this point.
Next, I will explain why lithium niobate is now considered to have a chance to become a star of the day.
I will introduce a few classic components in the current field.
Then I will explain their characteristics one by one.
Finally, there are two simple case studies.
The latter two parts are what I am doing.
The first one is about the adjustment of the temperature coefficient.
And its theoretical calculation and simulation.
The second part is what I started to do after I returned to Taiwan.
Due to these small components,
Usually, you have to make it with a seamless device.
If the device is not so useful,
In fact, the performance of the components will not be so ideal.
So after returning to Taiwan, we hope to reduce the loading in the process as much as possible.
So we developed all the thin-shaped lithium niobate components.
After returning to Taiwan, we hope to use the same concept.
We use surface-to-surface components to make.
We have also achieved some results recently.
The first part is my motivation.
Just like all human life requirements,
We hope to obtain information quickly and conveniently.
This is why the communication system has been improving.
From 2G and 3G decades ago to 4G and 5G in recent years,
We all hope that the communication system can meet all our needs.
It also includes high-speed transmission, low latency, and high reliability.
Based on this requirement, 5G communication is divided into three categories.
The first is high-speed, the so-called ENBB part.
It mainly uses high frequency bandwidth.
Because when the center frequency is higher,
The same ratio of bandwidth allows you to accommodate more communication channels.
This can improve the transmission speed of your data.
On the other hand, we also hope to have a low latency network.
Low latency network is used for safety or special applications.
For example, the network of a self-driving car.
If the network is interrupted in the process of self-driving,
It may not be able to receive important information.
This will create some doubts about the safety of passengers.
Therefore, this low latency and uninterrupted network is also an important part of 5G.
In addition, in smart homes or smart cities,
In the future, we will hope to build an Internet of Things system.
Therefore, we also hope to have some low-power transmission
To meet the applications of these sensor nodes.
Since 5G divides our needs into three categories,
It is impossible for them to operate on the same frequency band.
Because the frequency band is limited,
The number of channels or users that can be accommodated within the frequency band is also limited.
So it is obvious that if we want to meet these three needs at the same time,
It must be distributed in different frequencies on the distribution of frequency bands.
So we can see at the bottom of this picture,
In fact, 5G is divided into three parts.
Low-band is less than 1GHz,
Mid-band is between 1GHz and 6GHz,
High-band is between 6GHz and 100GHz.
Generally, Low-band and Mid-band are divided into FR1,
And MW is divided into FR2.
Is there any difference between 5G frequency band, 4G and 3G?
In fact, there is a big difference.
The main difference is that 5G hopes to
Use the limited frequency left by the communication system.
And hope to give them a new mission.
So in addition to the existing 3G and 4G infrastructure in the 5G communication system,
It also needs to insert these new frequencies in addition.
The biggest challenge of these new frequencies is that
It is very different from the traditional 4G network or 3G communication.
The frequency range of some bands is very large.
For example, we have the so-called band N77 and band N79.
These two frequencies may account for more than 10% of the frequency range.
In terms of N77, it accounts for 24%.
For higher frequency bands, such as band 258,
Its frequency range is about 10%.
The size of the frequency range has a great impact on hardware design.
Because at present, most of the radio waves used in the current communication system,
Especially in mobile phones, are radio waves.
The frequency range of these radio waves is limited.
The frequency range of these radio waves is usually controlled by the characteristics of its voltage material.
So for the current frequency range of 10% to 20%,
It is very difficult to achieve with the current technology.
So this is a new challenge from the system to the hardware design.
We also believe that we can get some new opportunities in this new challenge.
This graph shows the communication system architecture used by 3G, 4G, EET, and 5G carriers.
Compared with the traditional 3G and 4G,
It is obvious that 5G wants to have more applications,
So it has more usable frequency bands.
In order to properly process these signals, we need more filters.
The filter is used to process a specific frequency band signal.
For example, if the center frequency band of my filter is 1GHz,
And the frequency band is 400MHz,
So I will probably go from 980MHz to 1020MHz.
The frequency in the middle is allowed to pass.
I will try to suppress the signal beyond this frequency band.
So I can use these filters alone to select the communication frequency band I want,
And erase other signals.
In this way, it will be more convenient for me to process the following signals,
And the error rate will be lower.
Since the frequency band keeps increasing,
As we described earlier,
When the frequency band increases, we need more filters.
These filters also hope to have large frequency bands.
Therefore, the characteristics of the filter and its size need to be precisely controlled.
Especially if we want the phone to be able to use 5G communication properly,
So many filters have to be stuffed into the phone.
Therefore, the size of the filter is very strict.
This brings us to the first topic today.
Why do we want to apply the frequency band software to 5G communication?
Especially 5G communication with strict size restrictions.
The reason is that the frequency band is lower than the battery band.
Therefore, the size of the frequency band will be smaller than the battery band.
In the above picture,
We can compare the EM duplexer in the form of a battery band,
And the duplexer produced by the frequency band software.
The size of the duplexer is 10 times smaller than the battery band.
Therefore, we can expect a frequency band to be 100 times smaller than the EM duplexer.
In the same space, we can put more frequency band filters to meet our communication needs.
The frequency band is a mechanical resonance component.
In general, the quality of mechanical resonance will be higher than that of the EM duplexer.
Therefore, it usually has the characteristics of low insertion loss.
The most important thing is that the EM duplexer still needs to go through the steps required by the general semiconductor manufacturing process.
For example, exposure, salinity, time, etc.
These technologies are very mature in the industrial world.
Therefore, the EM duplexer can also be mass-produced and maintain a very stable salinity.
Sorry, I have a question.
Please go ahead.
It's a bit of an outlandish question.
Because what I'm doing is resonator, but what I'm doing is superconductor.
So, I don't understand.
What is the reason for the fundamental physics?
The quality factor of the resonator will be higher and the loss factor will be lower.
Because it feels like it uses a lot of energy to vibrate something.
It has the effect of EM in a space.
I can't understand intuitively why its quality is better.
In my opinion, this wave can be limited to a certain range.
Because mechanical vibration can be understood as
For example, I take a beam and let it vibrate.
Its boundary is very clear.
Because my beam is a beam with a fixed length and height.
So when it vibrates, it's like it's in this object.
It produces a beam.
But if it's EM, I'm not sure if it has such a good boundary to limit its EM.
It's the distribution of electromagnetic waves in space that produces a beam.
But I do know that there are some high-quality EM resonators.
It's like some dielectric resonators.
It should be a transmission line mode.
Its Q can reach several hundred.
But in terms of deep wave components,
At present, commercial components,
We call it an amplifier component of a deep wave filter.
Its Q can reach about 4000 to 5000.
So I think it still has a difference of one or two quantities.
Oh, I see. Okay, thank you.
Okay, I'll go on.
At present, 4G LTE has a lot of communication frequency.
Usually, there are about 3 to 4 wireless modules in a mobile phone.
To meet the needs of different frequencies.
For example, Wi-Fi has 2.4G and 5G.
These two may be a module.
The traditional GSM communication and CDMA communication may be another module.
In such a module, it will contain a lot of active and passive components.
For example, in terms of this package,
It contains 4 PA, which is the so-called power amplifier.
To generate enough energy for long-distance transmission.
It has 18 filters and 5 switch modules.
There is also a collective circuit for communication.
There is also a chip for impedance matching.
So in such a module, it actually contains 18 filters.
So we can imagine that if there are three such modules in our mobile phone.
It has more than 50 filters.
In the future, we hope that 5G can accommodate more bands.
So we can expect that the number of filters will continue to increase.
At the same size, we hope that these filters can be small and high-performance.
So this is also the main challenge of the current filter design.
The second part is to explain why we think that Li-Lian NIOBE is a material with a good prospect.
Before the introduction of this LN, we can briefly review the three common transmitters.
The first one on the left is the traditional transceiver.
Its material is usually Li-Lian NIOBE or Li-Lian TENTALATE.
These two materials are all man-made crystals.
So they generally do not appear in the normal environment.
Because they are man-made crystals.
Because the traditional transceiver uses a thicker base.
So when we use a very small indexing electrode to stimulate the sound wave on the surface.
It usually forms a surface wave.
There are many forms of surface waves.
But the most common ones are usually Rayleigh waves or Leaky waves.
The Leaky wave has the opportunity to get a relatively large magnetic resonance.
But its loss will also be relatively large.
In terms of Rayleigh waves, its typical magnetic resonance factor is about 7%.
In our field, we are used to using KT² or KEffective² symbols to represent magnetic resonance.
Its Q is about 1000.
The second one is also the most popular model of transceiver at present.
We call it FBAR.
It is a transceiver with a film buck acoustic wave resonator.
After a long search and research,
we finally determined that aluminum nitride is the most suitable commercial application for FBAR.
Because other materials have more or less other problems.
Its general magnetic resonance factor can give you about 6.5%.
Its Q is about 3000 in 2GHz.
But there are already some companies, such as Brokon, which is the predecessor of Avago.
In terms of Brokon, their Q should be able to do more than 45,000.
In order to strengthen its magnetic resonance feature,
some researches will use KONG element to dope it into aluminum nitride.
Generally, it is used to improve the transceiver.
When aluminum nitride is sputtered, KONG element is used to dope it into aluminum nitride.
The higher the content of KONG element, the higher its magnetic resonance factor will be.
However, due to the increase in the defect of KONG element,
KONG element's magnetic resonance factor will decrease as time goes by.
The third type is the so-called LAMP wave.
It is usually made from aluminum nitride.
It is a fairly good material now.
Its coupling is about 6.5%.
Because its thickness becomes very thin,
it is usually less than one wavelength.
You can see that its electrode configuration is very similar to that of SOHL.
However, what it triggers is not a surface wave, but a body wave.
The body wave will be described by another set of equations.
So it will have completely different characteristics from SOHL.
Since the coupling of aluminum nitride itself is not particularly strong,
and its coupling will change according to the direction of the electrode and the form of the wave,
its coupling will generally be between 1% and 4.5%.
The Q value is about 2000.
By combining the above three different components,
we can see that we are very concerned about its two characteristics.
The first is its magnetic resonance.
The second is the quality factor.
The definition of magnetic resonance is probably the ratio of mechanical energy to total energy.
Because we want to know how much energy is transferred from electricity to the mechanical field
when we give some energy to the electrode on the surface.
So we generally use KT square as a very important indicator.
The second indicator is the so-called quality factor.
Q has a lot of definitions,
but the most widely known one is the ratio of the energy stored in our system
and the energy lost by each cycle of movement.
So the higher the Q, the lower the energy loss.
When the energy loss is lower, I have a chance to make a green wave that has a lower energy loss.
Because KT square and Q are very important,
we will define our performance indicator,
which is to multiply Q by KT square.
So we can use F bar as an example.
Its performance indicator is probably between 100 and 200.
This graph shows...
Sorry, I have a question.
Can I go back to the last page?
You said that your excitation is at 2 GHz,
but my question is that,
for example, the受 is the surface wave,
or the lamp wave on the right is the body wave.
Is the excitation mode 2 GHz or not?
My question is, what is its phonon frequency?
It's 2 GHz.
Oh, so that's only a few million EVs.
Let me check the Planck constant.
It should be.
Okay, I see. Thank you.
In fact, according to the characteristics of IDT,
it has a periodicity.
So its complete cycle will be a wavelength.
So we will also use the size of these wavelengths
and the relationship of IDT cycle to design a mode that suits them.
That's how it works in practice.
Okay, so I just checked.
I'm more used to the unit of energy.
Anyway, it's multiplied by h.
So what I mean is,
I'm curious about one thing,
that is, if 2 GHz is multiplied by Planck constant,
it's less than 10 mEV.
That is to say,
if I give this device at least 10 mEV,
it will have a signal.
It will trigger a quantum, right?
A quantum.
I'm not so sure about the definition of physics.
Oh, okay.
But basically, its mode is 2 GHz mode.
That's for sure.
Okay, I see. Okay, thank you.
This graph shows
the motion of these three different components.
Generally speaking,
the Resonator of the Soul
is made on the surface of the crystal,
so there is no boundary around it.
So we will artificially add
the so-called Acoustic Reflector.
It is made in the form of the so-called Block Reflector.
That is, my grating,
its cycle,
is about a quarter of the wavelength.
This method of stacking
to enhance its ripple on the boundary reflection.
On the right,
you can see the motion of its surface wavelength.
Its motion mode
has a ripple on the surface.
Then in the depth of the crystal,
about a few lambda below,
it is a non-moving state.
So its ripple exists on the surface of the system.
What is different from the surface wavelength
is that the two graphs below,
which are FFAR and LandWave,
they are vibrating the whole structure.
FFAR is a longitudinal mode
in the center of the crystal.
So its upper and lower surfaces
will move in different directions.
Then the center of this material
is the node of the movement,
so its stress will be the greatest.
On the right,
it is the so-called LandWave motion mode.
Although LandWave
also uses the IDT electrode as the trigger,
its upper and lower surfaces are free surfaces,
so it generally has two different motion modes.
The first is the so-called symmetrical motion,
that is, the upper and lower surfaces
move in different directions.
So its center plane
is a mirror mode.
The second is the so-called asymmetric motion,
that is, the upper and lower surfaces
move in the same direction.
So it is more like a high-speed fractal mode.
After understanding the basic components
and their motion and some of its characteristics,
we can talk about
how to make a deep wave filter.
In fact, when we generally analyze,
we will only look at its physical behavior
at the level of a device,
that is, at the level of a single rectifier.
But when it comes to designing a filter,
we generally use
the so-called ladder filter circuit.
With such a circuit,
we can treat each rectifier
as an independent component,
so we use a simplified model to describe it.
In terms of a rectifier system,
it can be seen as a combination of
quality, resistance, and strength.
On the circuit,
we can find that
it has the same motion
as the connected
resistor, capacitor, and inductor.
It has the same mathematical form.
So we also tend to use
such a set of equivalent circuits
to describe it.
Because of this,
we can directly use
the circuit design tools
to design and simulate.
It will be more convenient.
With such a set of equivalent circuits,
it also has a C0
parallel to the main
motional branch.
The meaning of this C0
is that it is a static capacitor
produced between the
rectifier capacitor
or the electrode
.
Such a model
is usually called
Modified Butterworth-Van Dyck model
or MVVD model.
Such a set of models
can be seen on the circuit
as a
rectifier and
a anti-rectifier model.
Its rectifier frequency
is mainly connected
by the connected
RLC.
The parallel rectification
is determined by the
ratio of Cm and C0.
After obtaining
a single rectifier
motion form,
we can start
designing the filter.
In the case of
Ladder Filter,
it has a series resonator
and a parallel resonator.
In general,
the wavelength of the parallel resonator
is slightly different from
that of the series resonator.
We want to
match the
anti-rectifier frequency
of the parallel resonator
with the series resonator.
Through such a circuit,
we can use
two parallel resonators
with different frequencies
to form the
passband of the filter.
The passband can be controlled.
As long as
we carefully select
the separation
of the resonator,
the parallel resonator
and the anti-rectifier,
we can achieve the effect of
controlling the wavelength.
In theory,
there seems to be a way to
make it.
However,
by observing such a circuit,
we can find that
the K effective square
is limited by a factor.
After some
deductions,
we can find that
the K effective square
is related to
Fp and Fs.
Another potential factor
is that it is related to
the opamp factor.
On the other hand,
the opamp factor
determines the size of
the K effective square
and affects the separation
between Fp and Fs.
In order to meet the requirements
of 5G communication,
such as 10% and 20%
frequency,
we must find
the K effective square
as the basis of
the design of the resonator.
Therefore,
let's look at
the material
lithium niobate.
It is a material
with a long history.
It was probably
synthesized
30 or 40 years ago,
and it has a very
unique feature of
a three-dimensional
crystal structure.
Therefore,
it has different
opamp characteristics
in different wave directions.
It has also been widely used
in the design of
this kind of
surface wave components.
For general
surface wave components,
its pixel speed is
about 4000mps.
Its effective coupling
is about 17%,
and its Q is about 1000.
However,
we have always thought
that we did not fully
apply the characteristics of
this material,
because its K effective square
is actually much lower
than the theoretical prediction value
of this material.
Therefore,
about 20 years ago,
there was a famous paper
that mainly analyzed
the coupling of
lithium niobate crystal
in three different directions.
Since lithium niobate
is a three-dimensional crystal,
it has different characteristics
for its X-cut,
Y-cut and Z-cut.
The so-called X-cut
refers to
the X-axis of the material
as the Y-axis of the crystal,
and the wave transmission
will be on the YZ plane.
Similarly,
the Y-cut and Z-cut
respectively represent
the wave transmission
on the ZX and XY planes.
This article
mainly discusses
the thickness
of the three different
cuts and
the thickness of the different
waves.
It can be seen that
whether it is X-cut or
Y-cut,
in terms of these three cuts,
we target
two modes respectively.
The first is the so-called SH0,
which is the level-cut mode.
It can be seen that
there is almost no up-and-down movement
on the surface,
and its movement occurs
in the shear inside the plane.
The second mode
is the so-called S0 mode,
which is similar to SH0.
There is no up-and-down movement
on the surface,
but its wave transmission
is in the shear inside the plane.
Based on the analysis
of these two modes,
it can be found that
when you select the thickness
of the film properly,
the K-square,
that is,
the thickness of the film,
has a chance to reach 30%
or more than 40%.
From this theory,
it can be found that
when we
thin the film
from the thick wafer
to a very thin film,
it actually has a chance
to get a very large
film thickness,
which can meet
our demand for
high-frequency green wafers.
As for this technology,
why did it start to develop
around 2010,
mainly because
lithium nitrate
itself is a material
that is not easy to process,
and it has a very good
resistance to
all kinds of acids and alkynes.
This threshold
was broken about 10 years ago,
which is mainly the progress
of smart card technology,
which allows us
to do research
at a relatively
cheap price
to obtain such a crystal.
The method of smart card
is like this.
We mainly prepare two wafers.
One is the pressure crystal
we need,
and the other is the
board we carry
the pressure film.
So at the beginning,
we put a very thin layer
of electrolyte
on the pressure crystal,
and then,
in addition to being used
for bonding,
it can also be used
to resist
the depth of lithium nitrate
and can be used
for bonding.
So when we do smart card,
we use the
lithium nitrate arrangement method
to inject a thin layer of
lithium nitrate
into a certain depth
on the surface of the crystal,
and then,
after a simple surface
cleaning and bonding,
use a heat treatment method
to produce a stronger
heat resistance
and then crack
on that layer,
separating the two layers of crystal.
So finally,
after the bonded crystal
is exposed to the surface,
the surface is very smooth
and the pressure material
is very thin.
This material is very suitable
for some subsequent processing
to get the lithium nitrate
we need.
Okay,
do you have any questions?
If not,
I will continue to the next part.
Before we
design the components,
we will briefly
discuss these
thin boards
and their transmission behavior.
Generally speaking,
there are two main modes
for thin boards.
The first mode
is called Rayleigh-Lamb Wave.
The second mode
is called Shear Horizontal Wave.
These two modes
are completely different.
However,
both Rayleigh-Lamb
and Shear Horizontal Wave
have the same feature
that they
have the so-called
Shear Horizontal Wave.
The Shear Horizontal Wave
can be simply understood as
the wavelength of the wave
for a certain mode.
Its wavelength
will actually
depend on
the thickness of the thin board.
For this S0-Lamb Wave,
when my board
is very, very thin,
its wavelength
may be close to 10,000 ms.
However,
when I slowly
thicken my thin board,
it will actually
transform from Rayleigh-Lamb Wave
to Rayleigh-Wave.
Therefore,
their final frequency
will be close to the thin frequency.
Therefore,
it can be clearly seen that
in these different waves,
in addition to
the different waves,
the frequency will also
be affected by the thickness.
Therefore, their frequency
is very important.
Since the frequency
has frequency,
other features
and features
will also have frequency.
For example,
the Shear Horizontal Wave
is also a parameter
with frequency.
Next,
we will use
the so-called
30° Rotated Y-Cut
Lithium Niobate
as an example.
This is a simulated
result.
Let's assume
that the surface of
the Y-X Lithium Niobate
is coated with
periodic IDT electrodes.
Through these electrodes,
we can trigger
a frequency
called
a0s0
and a1s1.
In addition to
LandWave,
there are other
so-called
Shear Horizontal Wave,
Shear Horizontal Wave.
When the thickness of the electrode
is increased to a wavelength,
almost all the
frequencies of the wave
will decrease.
Except for a special wave
called
a0s0 Shear Horizontal Wave,
which is almost a parameter,
other frequencies
will be significantly affected.
In addition to the frequency,
the periodic IDT
is also a parameter
that is very sensitive.
So we can see that
these different modes
have a very big difference
in the thickness
of the electrodes
under different thicknesses.
In this picture,
with such a special section
and a specific
wave direction,
we can find that
it actually has a lot of potential
because its periodic IDT
can be greater than 40%.
Therefore,
such a material
with such a
Shear Horizontal Wave
will obviously be
quite suitable for
wide-frequency wave design.
I have a question.
This picture
is normalized by lambda,
but if it is actually
a few gigahertz,
is it one centimeter?
Is it millimeter scale?
It should be
in micrometer scale.
Micrometer scale?
Yes.
Because it is related to
the frequency,
the frequency of each mode
is actually quite different.
So for SH,
it is about
4,000 to 5,000 meters per second.
So if it is operated
at 1 gigahertz,
its thickness should be
less than 1 micron,
in order to achieve
such a high coupling.
I see.
Thank you.
I have a question here.
Sorry.
Does KT
square
equal 100%
have any special meaning?
Does it mean that their energy can be exchanged?
So far,
I have not seen 100%.
But I think
in theory,
in terms of definition,
it is true.
100% means that
if you add
1 mW RF,
it will produce
1 mW phonon.
I don't know
if it can be directly
seen as phonon.
We generally
see it as
an energy coin.
Because
its
K effective square
is equal to
Cm divided by C0.
Cm represents
motional capacitance.
It is actually related to
my mechanical strength.
C0 is my
capacitance,
and Cm is my
actual capacitance.
There are two kinds of energy.
The first one is
1 mole
divided by
CmV square.
It is a
mechanical domain energy.
The second one is
1 mole divided by
C0V square.
It is an
electrical domain energy.
It is 1 mole
divided by
CmV square.
It is a
mechanical domain energy.
If we imagine it as
a wave source,
we can also use
the MCK system
to represent
the energy produced
by its spring energy
and my
actual transducer capacitance.
Can I use
your explanation?
Yes.
According to
their high coupling
characteristics,
these articles
were published
in 2015.
They are new
results.
According to
their materials,
they started
to look for
new components.
The first article
is a
level-cut module.
It
uses
two
pairs of capacitors.
It is similar to
the form of a fingerprint capacitor,
but it has only one pair.
It is a
level-cut module.
It uses
two pairs of
capacitors
to generate
SH0
by
coupling
the
current
and the
wave direction.
According to
their
research,
SH0
generates
by coupling
the current
and the wave direction.
SH0
generates
by coupling
the current
and the wave direction.
We can also see that
when we set the frequency
to a relatively low range,
because some special applications
do not require such a high frequency,
for example, 50 MHz is enough,
its Q can reach 5000,
and
the coupling is also about 30%.
The overall
performance indicator,
which is KT square times Q,
is about 1500.
At present,
the highest
coupling we have
is about this level.
Of course,
we also find that
the Q value of the material
is quite related
to the thickness of
the thin film of
LN.
Because the
high-performance,
high-Q, high-coupling,
and low-frequency capacitors
have a thickness of
about 2 microns,
but the example on the right
is a study of
EPFL.
What they use is very thin,
only 400 nm
of LN.
So,
it can be seen that
even if it can reach a very high frequency,
its Q
will drop from 5000
to 700.
It can also reach
a very similar
electro-mechanical coupling
under the same
H over LN,
that is,
under the thickness of
normalization,
which is about 30%.
The third case is...
Sorry,
I have a little problem
with the previous statement.
My intuition is that
the effect of
LN is very large.
Is this right?
Or is there another reason?
This is our current guess.
Because we actually
used some AFN methods
to measure
some extremely thin
LN thin films.
The roughness of those surfaces
is less than 1 nm.
So we are not sure
why the Q
or other performance
will go up
as long as the film
is thin.
And when it is thin,
the result will be worse.
Is there any reason
not to make it very thick?
Is it going to take a long time?
Is it expensive?
Mainly based on
the previous picture.
If my thickness is too thick,
I can't enjoy
Oh, I got it.
Thank you.
The third example
is the so-called
A1 mode resonator.
This A1 mode
is a high-level LN wave.
It looks like
it connects
many thickness-shear
waves together.
So we can see
its movement
is horizontal
instead of vertical.
The advantage of
such a resonator
is that
its feature size
is mainly controlled by
its thickness.
Because its thickness
direction becomes
its real 1 in 2 wavelength.
So a very thin resonator
can achieve
a very high frequency
of coupling.
So in this design,
its Q is about
300-400.
And its
operating frequency
is about 3.2 GHz.
The coupling is about 40%.
So by combining
the above demonstrations,
we can get
that S0, SH0
and A1 modes
are very potent
and can be applied
in high-level and high-coupling situations.
However,
there are
some relative
shortcomings.
For example,
due to the thinner membrane structure,
it becomes unusually fragile.
There may be
some problems
with the coupling.
Secondly,
lithium niobate
is a material
with a very low thermal conduction rate.
Its thermal conduction rate
is only twice that of silicon oxide,
which is about 1% or 2% of
metal.
So it does not conduct heat very well.
So when communicating
at high power,
it can easily
have some negative effects.
Thirdly,
its temperature factor
is quite high.
So when the temperature
changes in the environment,
when using mobile phones
in the suburbs
and in the northern and southern regions,
the frequency will change
with the temperature.
In this case,
it is difficult to convince everyone
that it can do a good
and stable communication.
So this is mainly
a few problems with this material.
However,
although it has some problems,
some companies
and some research institutions
have also tried to use
such components to make
some durable and high-frequency
lithium niobate.
The N79 filter above
satisfies the N79 band
mentioned earlier.
The frequency is about 10% of the strict conditions.
The center frequency is about 5GHz.
It uses
the so-called A1 mode
rectifier.
Below is what I did
with my colleagues at UIUC.
It uses a higher mode
to make
a 10GHz filter.
Of course, it is a demo,
so you can see that
its passband is not as beautiful
as the company's design.
Next,
I will quickly talk about
two case studies.
The first one
is our goal
to reduce
the dependence of
this rectifier
on temperature.
Due to this temperature factor,
it is mainly related to
the material.
In terms of Ln,
its temperature
factor is
about 70 to 90 ppm
per degree C.
According to different
cutting surfaces,
in order to
improve this performance
to be enough
for the filter
or rectifier to be used,
we would like to
reduce its TCF
from 60 to 70 ppm
to 20 ppm or less.
In order to convince
others that
it is a candidate
for the future
wireless communication hardware.
Therefore,
we do a simplified analysis
of its TCF source.
TCF actually
refers to
the frequency,
the normalized frequency
of temperature.
Therefore,
in terms of mathematical form,
it is partial f, partial t
divided by its TCF frequency.
After calculation,
we can divide it into
three elements.
Since the frequency
is related to
the frequency of my wave
and the wave
is related to the
speed of my material
and its density,
the first element is
the frequency of my wave
with the change of temperature.
The second element is
the frequency of my material
with the change of temperature.
The third element is
the frequency of my material
with the change of temperature.
In addition to these three elements,
there is another element
that is related to
the characteristics of
the pressure current.
Therefore,
we need to understand
the characteristics of
its material first.
Traditionally,
the method of temperature compensation
has been
in modern technology
for a long time.
There is no better way
than this,
which is to select
a material with
a perfect ratio.
For example,
the temperature factor of lithium niobate
is about negative 70 ppm per kelvin.
However, silicon oxide,
a very common material,
has a positive temperature factor
of about 90 ppm per kelvin.
Therefore,
if we can
perfectly
mix these two materials
with a perfect ratio,
for example,
silicon oxide,
we can theoretically
reduce Tcf to zero.
However,
in the process of
such a production,
we will find
that if we ignore
the wave
and its electric field
distribution
and its
motion distribution,
it is actually
unpredictable.
Secondly,
when the film becomes very thin,
the metal electrode
on the top
will also have a certain degree of impact.
In particular,
the Tcf of the metal electrode
is generally quite large.
Therefore,
when we want to
target some thin components
with high electromagnetic cohesiveness,
we must not ignore
the Tcf of the metal electrode.
As early as 1985,
Professor Kenya Hashimoto
discussed
some deep-wave
temperature coefficients of delay
on different surfaces.
For example,
a special op-amp material
has a free surface
with a metal electrode on the surface,
but there is no power.
It is an open-strip.
The metal electrode on the surface
is short-circuited
and becomes short-strip,
or the whole surface is covered
with metal and grounded.
Every situation
will show that
their Tcf is different.
In particular,
in the two cases,
open-strip and short-strip,
the mechanical structure
of these two cases
has not changed.
The difference is
whether the Tcf of the metal electrode
is grounded or not.
It will also have a great impact
on the Tcf of the metal electrode.
In conclusion,
when we deal with
a material with
high Tcf,
we cannot ignore
the Tcf of the metal electrode.
To solve this problem,
we use
the so-called
multi-section model.
Since
our goal is
relatively simple,
it is a deep wave
that only circulates in one dimensional space.
Therefore,
we do not need to develop
too complicated 3D analysis.
We hope to
transform
such a complex structure
with Tcf and metal
into a
multi-section model
with Tcf
and Tcf
in different areas
with different Tcf
and Tcf
in different areas
with different Tcf
and Tcf
We also found that
in the case of
하대기
different areas
require different models.
For example,
we divide the graph into three zones.
The first zone
is the free surface
and the surface is open circuit.
That is, the surface has no electric field.
The second zone
is the metal electrode
on the surface
and it gives a fixed voltage.
It may be
a small signal
that is dc ground.
Its condition will become
a metallized surface
and a short circuit
boundary condition.
The third zone is more complicated
because it is between two electrodes
and it will
have a horizontal electric field
between the two electrodes.
So we guess
when the metallization ratio
is very high,
we should think
that the surface
has no electric field
and it is a free surface
with a short circuit boundary.
When the metal
is very small
and the two electrodes are
very far away,
maybe we should use
the open circuit boundary
to describe it.
Based on this idea,
we also use
the method of
finite element
to simulate
a thin film of
lithium niobate
to observe the temperature change
and we can see
that its result
is quite similar
to what we just guessed.
When the wavelength
is very long,
it should be said
that it will
use the gap
as a boundary
of 2λ.
When the wavelength
is less than 2λ,
we generally
regard it as a short circuit
and if it is larger,
we regard it as
an open circuit boundary.
Based on this hypothesis,
we can simulate
the temperature coefficient
under three different cases
and then
combine it
with the mathematical formula
we just introduced.
Theoretically,
we can predict
the temperature coefficient
of the uniformly distributed
resistors.
In order to
do the experimental verification,
we made
two different resistors.
The first one
has a mechanical electrode
and a capacitor.
It can stimulate
the magnetic field of the resistors.
The second one
has a capacitor and a capacitor
to stimulate the magnetic field
of the capacitors.
I have an idea.
Sorry.
Will it be published?
Well,
you give it
a DC bias,
VIN,
and GND.
Then you use the
SIO2 to
hold the material
you want.
If you give it
a DC current,
it will push
each other away.
If you give it
a DC current,
it will push
each other away.
If you give it
a DC current,
it will push
each other away.
Then you can use
the electrodes to
hold the substrate.
You can use
the DC current
to resist
the temperature coefficient.
Is it feasible?
Let me think about it.
The DC current
is from the VIN, right?
Yes.
I didn't say that.
I made a mistake.
The two pictures
are the experimental
components.
The picture on the left
has three electrodes.
Because it has
a capacitive electrode,
it is suitable to
stimulate the osmosis.
The picture on the right
has two electrodes,
but it is arranged
as an array.
The array
doesn't affect
the temperature coefficient.
We use the array
to connect
all the electrodes
to enhance the output signal
for easy observation.
Then we can
process the components.
First of all,
we take a lithium-niobate wafer
and
use a low-temperature
layer of
oxidized gas
on the surface.
We use the exposure
to define the
assembly shape of the components.
Then we use
a dry-etching method
to remove
lithium-niobate and
silicon oxide at the same time.
The dry-etching
mainly uses
some gas from the filter,
which has a stronger
activity relationship
to successfully remove
these two materials.
After the assembly
of the components is completed,
another exposure
is used
to apply
the metal electrode
using the lift-off method.
Finally, we use the
XF2 gas
to remove
the silicon oxide
at the bottom
to make the components.
As you can see,
there are two cuts
around the components.
These two lines
not only define
the area around the components
with darker brown color,
but also the area
where the silicon oxide
is removed.
In the experiment,
we measured
two different
electrode components.
First of all,
two electrode devices
will trigger
1,3,5,7,9 and so on.
Due to the high-strength
silicon oxide,
it also produces
a lot of free smoke,
so we don't
specifically discuss
those electrodes.
We only discuss
the first three
electrodes of each design.
For this device,
its Q is 450,
KT2 is 5.5
for free smoke,
and TCF can also
be used.
Its displacement
and shear stress
are different,
but its electrode
won't change with the mode.
So,
these different modes
also have different
temperature factors.
We can also observe
similar phenomena
from these three electrode devices.
We trigger the so-called
Q, which is around
1,000 or 3,000,
KT2 is around 12%
for free smoke,
and its three
temperature factors are also different.
According to the previous theory,
we can calculate
its
theoretical temperature factor
and compare it with the experiment.
What we can see
is that
the simulation of model
and finite element are quite similar.
Their error is less than 1%,
but compared with the measurement,
the error is around
3%.
Although
the expected result
is slightly worse than
the expected result,
I think
its accuracy
can be used
to design more detailed components.
Or,
we don't need to rely on
finite element before
actually making the components.
We can directly calculate
the value of our temperature factor
to assist designers
in the design of
compressors and filters.
This is the conclusion.
We use some methods
to calculate its temperature factor,
and
its error is quite small
compared with the previous theory.
The second case is
the research I did
after I came back to Taiwan.
The main reason is that
we encountered
a big problem
in the production of components.
It was found in the
Lillian Nile Basin Fin Action.
The RF power required
for this action
is quite large,
about 800-900W.
Generally speaking,
there is not much RF power
in the Lillian Nile Basin Fin Action,
because the RF power
is quite old.
So,
before we start
the research on
RF components,
we need to
pull back our research
to see the effect.
At the same time,
we hope to solve
the problem of
thermal conductivity.
The thermal conductivity problem
of LN-SINFIN device
mainly comes from two reasons.
The first one is
the high temperature factor,
and the second one is
the poor thermal conductivity.
So, when you drive
with high power,
you will find that
the frequency starts to decrease
near the rectifier.
So, when the temperature
changes,
the frequency starts to change.
Therefore,
if there is no good thermal conductivity,
the frequency will
decrease
as you drive
with higher power.
So, there will be
a non-thermal phenomenon.
If there is a non-thermal phenomenon
in the rectifier,
it means that
there will be a non-thermal phenomenon
in the rectifier itself,
which may cause
a distortion
when the signal is transmitted,
or even increase
the error rate
of the code, etc.
So, in order to
solve this problem,
there is a group of
ideas that
we can come back
and use the concept of SOHL
to bind the LN synth
to a substrate
with a block reflector.
We can use
these reflectors
to virtually
create a floating resonator
that can
reproduce the
sound wave reflection
characteristics.
In fact, it is directly
bound to the board.
If it is directly
bound to the board,
it can actually
enhance the efficiency of
heat transfer,
so that it can theoretically
solve the problem of
temperature non-thermal.
In fact, this idea
already had a series of
patents in 2004 and 2009,
but it has not been
developed well.
Mainly because
there was not enough technology
to produce LN synths.
However, it has become possible
in recent years,
so this also forms
a new research direction.
In particular,
there are two professors
from the University of
Tokyo, Japan,
Michio Katota and
Shuji Tanaka.
They use
the structure of
LN synths.
They successfully demonstrated
that even if it is a
SO type resonator,
my coupling can also be
greater than 40% and
operate at high frequency.
It is like the
newly introduced
release synth
resonator.
I don't release it,
but I bound it to
the sound wave reflection layer
with a very strong boundary.
It can be seen as a
release component.
The same design concept
was also adopted by the company.
Murata called it
IHP-SOL,
Incredible High Performance-SOL.
Through some
designs,
its coupling
can be maintained at
about 9%.
Mainly, the company uses
a relatively low coupling,
but its Q can be greater than 3000.
Murata's idea is
that they don't want to
use so many layers of reflectors.
For example, it needs
two materials,
silicon oxide and
aluminum nitrate,
to stack five or six layers
to make this reflector.
From the perspective of the company,
this design method is not economical,
so they hope to use
a single silicon oxide layer
as the simplest
reflector.
In fact,
they have observed
a pretty good effect,
because it raises the Q
to more than 3000.
Based on this idea,
at least
at this stage
of my investment,
no one has discussed
Synthene Lithium Niobate
on silicon oxide
on silicon.
So,
we raise the Q
to this level.
The wafers we use
are silicon
500μm,
silicon oxide 2μm,
and the transfer Ln
is 0.7μm.
We hope
to use the so-called
shear horizontal sole.
Its wave motion
is like the picture on the right.
It is a cut wave on the surface,
so its motion
will decrease rapidly
in the substrate.
So, we think it has a chance
to become a high-Q,
high-coupling model.
By inserting a layer of
oxide between
Synthene Ln and silicon substrate,
it should be able to effectively
reduce the leakage
to the substrate.
For this structure,
we study
its propagation direction.
We use the Final Element
to simulate
its wave distribution
at different thickness
of lithium niobate
when it is
propagated on the
two-dimensional plane.
By
setting the surface
of the crystal
as open
or short-circuit condition,
based on the
so-called
outerless approach,
we can calculate
the size of
its base
lithium niobate.
So,
we can see that
the SH sole
has a very large
difference in coupling.
In order to get the highest coupling,
the propagation direction
will be selected
at the angle of
10 degrees
backward on the y-axis.
By combining
the simulation results
at different thicknesses
of lithium niobate,
we can also find that
its lithium niobate
is also a
design parameter that
we can control.
After understanding the
propagation direction,
we start to study
its dispersion behavior.
It can be seen that
when there is no electric shock
on the surface,
such as the previous situation,
when the thickness of lithium niobate
is greater than 0.15,
the coupling will
decrease.
This situation is
quite similar to
the plate wave of SH0.
That is to say,
the dotted line above
and the purple dotted line
below
have a similar
coupling reduction mode.
However,
we also find that
when we apply some electric shock
on the surface,
especially the heavier metal,
the higher the rate of increase.
Similarly,
through simulation observations,
we find that
when the metal on the surface
is heavier,
it can actually help
the horizontal wave
to concentrate
the strain energy
on the surface.
Since most of the strain energy
is concentrated in the opaque layer,
it has a chance
to get a higher coupling.
That is to say,
when the thickness
of the metal electrode
is limited,
we should use
the heavier metal
to design
to get a higher coupling.
For example,
this is a comparison
between gold and aluminum.
It can be seen that
when the thickness of gold
is 0.025 lambda,
it can actually
increase the coupling to 40%.
However,
aluminum, which is a lighter material,
needs a thicker electrode
to achieve a similar effect.
The last part
is to discuss
the impact of different modes.
Since
we want to use SH
as a target,
we compare SH
and Longitudinal Leaky Soul
to see
what is the difference
between the two modes.
Through analysis,
it can be found that
SH Soul is more likely
to be affected
by the two-layer structure
of lithium niobate and silicon arsenide.
However, Leaky Soul
has a larger position
than SH Soul,
which means that
its wave is more likely
to be lost by substrate transmission.
Therefore,
it can be seen that
the impedance ratio
of Leaky Soul
is about 20-30 dB higher
than that of SH Soul.
Therefore,
it is not a good choice.
Finally,
in order to verify
the effect of SH Soul,
we use the
OnePort single-layer
SH Soul resonator
with traditional IDT electrode
and grating reflector.
However,
unlike the traditional one,
we use a
Synthene-Lithium Niobate
on silicon arsenide
on silicon
as a reference point.
This is the
one-port single-layer
SH Soul resonator.
In addition,
SH Soul has a
smaller position
than SH Soul,
which means
that
its wave
leakage is
relatively small.
Therefore,
its wave
leakage is
relatively small.
The picture in the lower right corner
is the actual
picture of the component.
In this picture,
its wave length is 8 microns.
Finally,
this is the result of the experiment.
We selected
3 different components,
Lambda,
8, 6, and 4 microns
to compare.
It can be seen that
the difference in Q
is relatively large.
Here we use
the definition of body Q,
which is to use its group delay
and its S11
to calculate its Q value.
Its definition of Q is
similar to the traditional one,
but through a new formula,
which is the formula of body Q,
it can equalize
every Q value
on this resonance scale,
and it can be seen that
the highest Q value
of the resonator
we designed
is about 960,
and the carbon
is about 25.5%.
Therefore,
FOM is about 245.
Compared with the traditional
F-bar resonator,
its performance indicator
is between 100 and 200.
Therefore,
more than 200
indicates that
the component we designed
has a certain performance.
At least,
it may outperform
some low-performance
F-bar components.
We also
measured
the power handling
of this resonator.
It can be seen
that
compared with
the previously released
SYNFIN
lithium-ion battery components,
this SO-TYPE
resonator
does not have
any significant
fluctuation
after 10 dBm RF power.
Therefore,
it can be further verified
that when I use
SO-TYPE components,
it can dissipate heat
through the base plate,
which can greatly improve
the power handling problem.
At the same time,
we also used the combination
of different thicknesses
of L-N and C-NR
to get a higher
capacitance coefficient
of more than 36%,
but its Q is reduced
to about 250.
This is a prediction
from the metal we used.
Due to the
absorption of
the acoustic of the metal,
it is actually much
stronger than aluminum.
In other words,
the loss of the metal
is much greater than that
of aluminum,
which is about 4-5 times higher.
Therefore, we estimate
that the Q of the components
is the effect of the metal electrode.
However, this still needs further verification.
Through such a high-coupling
resonator,
its coupling is about 38%-35%,
we can use
such a resonator
to synthesize the filter.
We used five
resonators to synthesize
the filter,
and in the software,
we made it
sound
and input
and output matching.
We can find that
we can potentially
increase the frequency to 29%,
and the insertion loss is less than
the standard 3dB.
This also verifies that
the higher the coupling of
my resonator,
we will have the opportunity to
make a wider filter to meet
the growing needs of
5G communication.
So this is my
second part of the conclusion.
We used
Synthene Lithium Niobate
on Substrate to
make the SOHL components.
We can increase the coupling
to more than 20% or 30%,
and the Q can be nearly 1000.
And we also
verified that
using these high-coupling devices,
we have the opportunity to get
a very large filter
and the insertion loss
can also meet the needs of
communication.
The loss will be less than 3dB.
In the future,
we hope to
improve our
manufacturing capacity
and make the frequency
higher.
In addition to
our manufacturing capacity,
we will also need
to find
more interesting models
to support our research.
Finally,
of course,
there is a projection.
Lithium Niobate
is a very strong
supply material.
It also has a very interesting
optical feature,
but I don't understand this part.
Now there are also several more
well-known groups
to invest and research
acoustic optical devices.
For example, Stanford
and Harvard have
some teams
to discuss this.
Finally, I would like to
thank my founding
research, my students,
and my ex-bosses.
My report ends here.
Thank you.
OK, thank you Ming-Huang for
bringing us such a wonderful speech.
Let me see
if anyone has any questions.
If you do,
please turn on your microphone
or leave your question
in the chat dialog.
I can help you ask Ming-Huang.
I want to ask
a question.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
Hello, my name is Shreff.
I am a PhD student
at Taitung University.
I have read
several of your papers.
Previously,
Rob Candler
from UCLA
came to visit.
I worked with him
at that time.
However,
I was doing
fieldwork.
The papers you wrote
were about piezoelectric radiation.
Now,
I am also working on this.
I am glad
to hear
your speech today.
It is rare
to find such advanced research in China.
For example,
there should be
no manufacturers
in Taiwan.
Yes.
I don't know
if there are any
in Taiwan,
but there should be none.
I have read
your papers.
For example,
piezoelectric radiation
is done by UCLA
and Northeastern.
Piezoelectric radiation
is done by piezoelectric
and magnetic materials.
It is a big topic.
I want to know
the difference between
piezoelectric radiation
and magnetic materials.
I think
there are many
deep
physical phenomena
to discuss.
When we were
implementing the AMIBA project,
our main competition
was a Stanford group.
Their papers were published
earlier than ours
in Nature Communication.
You can read it.
They used a stick-shaped lithium-ion battery.
It should be
8 or 10 cm long.
It was a
metal stick.
They used
some suspension
to float it in the air
and make it vibrate
to radiate electromagnetic waves.
There were
several difficulties
that they didn't overcome.
First,
the surface of the battery
was exposed
to electromagnetic radiation
near the electrode.
It means
the battery
lost a lot of energy.
Second,
its Q was too high.
I think it was
between 100,000 and 1 million.
It ran down very slowly.
It seemed
that such a system
was not suitable
for communication.
It took a long time
to go from 1 to 0.
So they could only
use frequency modulation.
Frequency modulation
may also be affected
by its high Q.
If you are interested,
I think you can read
their papers.
We decided to use
PZT later.
We found a PZT manufacturer
that could provide
high-quality buck PZT.
Its Q was over 1,000.
It was very rare.
We used PZT.
But PZT had its own problem.
Its dielectric constant was too high.
So it
had almost no so-called
field-to-field effect.
It went from the moment
it left Resonator
to its original state.
But I think
PZT was not suitable
for communication.
Especially for measuring.
We measured it for a month or two.
But we found
that it was wrong.
Actually,
I used
Urban Nitride.
But I asked
UCL to make it.
They measured
the resistance
of the resistor.
So we couldn't measure anything.
PZT is made of
resin material.
So it's not that easy.
Yes.
I saw
they made
some other
alloy materials.
Not PZT.
Yes.
In this field,
you know
they made
PZT.
They have a
very strong
material team in
Northeast University.
Otherwise,
they are not
specialized in materials.
So I think
it's not that easy.
Another question
about architecture.
I don't have the answer yet.
For example,
they call it
mechanical antenna.
Mechanical antenna.
You can find
some articles
about it.
For example,
about radiation efficiency
and size,
we talked about
due limit.
I read some articles
that say
mechanical antenna
but I
don't understand it.
I don't understand it.
Yes.
When I was in the US,
our boss
told us about it.
He thought it could
go beyond the limit.
He wanted us to write
a theoretical paper.
But later,
he wanted to meet
DAPA's schedule.
So we just ignored it.
It doesn't seem
to have any new results.
Yes.
I'm not sure
whether it can
go beyond the limit.
But I think
we can calculate it
from a theoretical point of view.
It might be a great
theoretical paper.
But we thought
we couldn't handle it.
The last question
is a small one.
I'm curious.
For example,
when you simulate
the design of
multi-modem
or two-sided,
if it's complicated,
how do you
analyze it?
Because you can't
just recognize it.
From simulation?
I'll start from
a so-called
periodic session.
I'll go back to the beginning.
For example,
with this IDT-type
resonator,
we mainly
trigger some modes
with a horizontal capacitor.
These modes are
non-linear.
So we usually
start with a
periodic structure.
The advantage of a periodic structure
is that it won't be affected
by the boundary.
Its modes are beautiful.
For example,
with this A1 resonator,
the upper part
contains an electrode
and its boundary simulation.
The lower part
contains an electrode.
So I don't have a boundary.
You can clearly recognize
that this is A1 mode.
With this simulation,
you can roughly
grasp the position of
resonance frequency
and the shape of
its mode.
Then you can do a complete simulation.
Then you can probably
find out from the comparison
of frequency.
Basically, they are the same.
Then you can easily
find the corresponding mode.
This is my own approach.
If you do a complete
device simulation,
you may not
think that
this is the mode you want to design.
When I was doing
research,
I would simulate
a Bach resonator.
Sometimes its mode
is quite complicated.
If I do a very simple simulation,
it will be difficult to identify
whether it is the mode I want to design.
If you use eigenfrequency,
it will be more complicated.
Because eigenfrequency lists
all possible mechanical modes.
So I would suggest that
when you confirm your electrode configuration,
you can do frequency sweeping.
This is the so-called frequency
response simulation.
Although many mechanical modes
exist,
they can't be triggered by your electrode.
They can't be received by your electrode.
So many modes will disappear.
Only a few
are enough
to be received
by these electrodes.
In this way,
you can reduce a large part of
the work.
Thank you for your answer.
I am also working on
this field now.
It is a difficult topic.
I hope to have more opportunities
to communicate in the future.
If there is a chance,
you can
write an email to me
or make an appointment
to discuss.
Thank you.
Due to time constraints,
today's speech ends here.
You can turn on your microphone.
Let's applaud
Professor Ming-Huang's
wonderful speech.
Professor Ming-Huang's background
is well known.
If you want to get his email,
you can easily
search on the Internet.
If you have any other questions,
you can write to
Professor Ming-Huang and ask him.
Let's applaud
Professor Ming-Huang's speech.
Thank you.