Hello everyone, welcome to today's Tarot Talk. I am the host today, Zhang Yanyong.
We are very honored to invite Dr. Zeng Sihao, a colleague at my school, to tell us about the topic of his research on the Internet today.
His research focuses on the parallel and variable traffic engineering of re-adjusting latency.
Let me introduce Dr. Sihao.
Dr. Sihao majored in Electrical Engineering at NTU.
He then went to Cornell to study ECE, Electrical Engineering.
He then came to Caltech to study Computer and Mathematical Science.
He then studied Engineering and Applied Science.
Let's give the floor to Dr. Sihao.
Thank you, Yanyong, for the introduction.
This topic is actually a bit long and difficult to understand.
However, when Yanyong invited me to give a talk, I thought that since it is a talk,
why not talk about a topic that is actually related to my research?
So I took the ICMP paper that I submitted last year.
Today I will try to make it as simple as possible.
Although this topic looks very difficult, you don't have to worry too much.
Its English title is Perseverance-Aware Traffic Engineering in Rate-Adaptive Networks with Reconfiguration Delay.
So I just translated the English title into Chinese.
As for what each term means, we will see later.
If you have any questions in the middle, please feel free to interrupt me at any time and ask me questions.
In addition, Caltech has a special system called Computing and Mathematical Science.
This system is actually under Engineering.
Although C stands for Engineering, the department seems to be under it.
It seems that the relationship between division and department is not quite the same,
but it is actually not very important.
So why do we want to study this topic?
My research topic is mainly about the Internet.
What is the Internet? The Internet is actually a bunch of things connected together.
Why do we want to connect a bunch of things together?
Basically, we want to communicate with each other.
We send some things, some information from one end of the Internet,
and we hope to get this information on the other end.
Or we want to send some goods, such as a logistics network.
For example, we want to transport fruits from Chiayi to Taipei.
This is also a network.
In fact, most of my research is on the Internet of information,
that is, the Internet of communication between some electronic products or electronic devices using electronic signals.
How are these networks usually transmitted?
That is to say, how is this information transmitted on the Internet?
Usually, for example, we will have our own personal equipment.
For example, today's lecture is the same.
We may use a computer or a tablet or a mobile phone.
We will connect to the Internet.
What does it mean to connect to the Internet?
In fact, we are sending a piece of information to a place called an exchanger, a router.
Sometimes this router also has a wireless exchanger,
such as AP, Access Point.
This is for wireless networks.
Sometimes you will also use a base station to receive these things.
After these terminals receive the message,
they will send it through an exchanger to a space.
Then we will be on the other side of the space.
Maybe someone else uses another device to get this information.
This is basically how the whole network works.
In this case,
because we use an exchanger to connect a lot of different devices,
we may put our information into an exchanger
and then go to another place to get something else.
In order to get a specific thing,
we have to establish a point-to-point connection with it.
This is actually quite important.
In the early days, the Internet was a bit like a telephone line.
At that time, there was a connection god.
When the two of us wanted to communicate,
there must be a line in the middle to communicate with us.
But today, the Internet is not necessary.
Today, the Internet actually sends a lot of different traffic
in various ways, using this kind of exchanger,
one by one to our target destination.
These terminals can be various things.
For example, you can be a so-called cloud terminal,
a server at the far end.
Or when we play games with others,
we may have a server.
We may also receive messages from others.
For example, the 5G network, which is very popular recently,
is actually talking about the communication at the wireless terminal.
Obviously, no matter how we get the information at the far end,
we have to go through these exchangers in the middle
or through the network in the middle
to help us pass the information from one end to the other.
So even if we have 5G now,
5G means that
5G is very fast from our wireless device to our base station.
But after it gets to the base station,
no matter what you do,
you still have to go through the network in the middle to help you.
So this network is the main focus of my network research.
This is called the broadband network.
Broadband network means that
there is a great distance between the two terminals.
Relatively speaking, if we are only in a local area,
this is called LAN,
which stands for Local Area Network.
Actually, I don't know how to say it in Chinese,
but it's a local network.
So what's the problem with broadband networks?
Because these broadband networks are connected to very far places,
we know that
when we use telecommunications to send things,
electricity is actually very easy to consume.
So how do we send them?
We have to use a very special kind of wire.
We definitely can't use the kind of wire that we usually use to plug breadboards.
We must use a very special kind of wire to send.
So how do we send these things?
We will send them from one terminal to the other.
There must be a very special wire in the middle.
This actually requires cost.
But this cost is sometimes justifiable.
It can be accepted.
If the service I want to provide can make me earn more money,
then of course I am willing to spend a lot of money
to build this kind of expensive link.
You can think of it as these lines in the middle
to connect to two very far places.
For example, many big companies do this.
For example, Microsoft or Google.
Because they usually provide some cloud services.
For example, you may sometimes use
Google Sheets, Google Gmail,
or Microsoft Hotmail,
like this kind of thing,
or all kinds of different services,
such as YouTube.
They just store the data all over the world.
They will let you get the data very quickly.
For example, they will build their own broadband network.
What are the benefits of this?
If you have this broadband network,
I can effectively adjust
how I want to use these lines.
If I can effectively use these lines,
I have a better chance of reducing my costs
and making more money.
Basically like this.
So now most companies
are investing a lot in building their own network.
Instead of purely using some more traditional Internet.
For example, we may sign a contract with AT&T
or we sign a contract with Taiwan Cable.
They actually provide the network,
but the network is not under the control of these companies.
Sometimes you can't adjust
how to use your connection in the middle.
So these big companies usually
will build their own network,
and then they will operate these networks themselves
to achieve higher performance.
We just mentioned that
the network is so far away.
These lines in the middle are actually quite special.
What kind of lines are these lines?
They are not ordinary blue lines.
Of course there are ordinary blue lines,
but the amount of blue lines that can be passed is limited.
And it's more expensive.
So most of the time we use
cheaper blue lines with higher economic value.
This is actually not a blue line.
This is a blue line that uses optical technology
to transmit signals through this light wire.
This light wire is actually cheaper.
And then there is a lot of information that can be transmitted by the light wire.
Because you use light.
Compared to electrical signals,
you have all kinds of different frequencies.
It can also be used.
And the speed of light is also quite fast.
It doesn't need to use electronic signals
to receive it first and then transmit it.
They just enhance the strength of light
and then continue to transmit.
So it actually has a lot of benefits.
That is to say,
most of these big companies
will use some light wires
to transmit signals far away,
and then turn it into electrical signals
at the end point.
Then we communicate with electrical signals.
These light wires are actually
better than ordinary blue lines.
That is to say, it has a higher economic value.
But how do you say on this broadband network,
no matter how cheap it is,
you have to pull a few hundred kilometers,
it will be expensive right away.
So no matter,
and you are in maintenance,
or in operation,
it's actually not cheap.
So these light wires on the broadband network
are actually a kind of expensive equipment.
Usually we don't want to say
that our light wires can't be used.
What does it mean not to be used?
That is to say, light wires are actually usable.
That is to say,
my signal can go through this light wire.
That is to say, after I go through this light wire,
I can get my signal.
Let's use a simple example here.
How do we send a signal
from one end to the other?
You can imagine that
we are on both ends of the light wire.
We can actually send it,
we can send it at its frequency.
If we think of a white paper,
we can draw a dot on the white paper.
Then we put this paper through the light wire.
The light wire will pass this paper to the other side.
Then I look at this paper.
Ah, what is your signal?
If the other person can interpret your signal,
that means your signal has been successfully passed.
So let's use this simple example to see.
Suppose I have a big white paper now.
I can send this white paper to the other side.
Then I can tell the other person
a similar code.
Say, if you see me
put a dot on the left, it's 0.
Put a dot on the right, it's 1.
In this case,
we can use this code to send information.
As long as you have 0 and 1,
you can generate a lot of different information
in this sequence.
The problem is,
this actually sounds pretty good.
Then we keep sending this.
For example, my left, right,
right, left, left, right, right.
Then we can quickly send out the signal.
Isn't that great?
But what is reality?
Reality is that all signals follow the message.
That is to say, everyone is sending something.
In the past, it was not so beautiful
in the middle of the opposite.
In the middle, there must be some
battery signal or light signal interference.
Let's take a simple example today.
Suppose we have a message.
It will draw this thing on the paper.
For example, I draw this dot.
Shake it left and right.
When we get to the other side,
we look like
For example, I received a signal of shake.
For example, like this.
It's a little bit off.
But it's still roughly on the left.
So in the middle of this case,
we can say that this is still zero.
I probably know it's zero.
Anyway, although there is a little bit of noise,
but it's roughly the signal on the left.
So I know it's zero from my code.
Then it is possible that noise
may also put your signal
a little bit in a different direction.
In this case,
you are probably also quite confident that
this signal is actually on the left.
So it's zero.
But if I give you a signal like this today,
Is it on the left or on the right?
It seems to be a little bit on the left
and a little bit on the right, right?
So it's not easy to judge.
If we draw a line,
that is to say,
we separate the original left and right
and draw the line out a little bit.
It's actually still on the left.
So I know this signal
is probably still zero.
But sometimes it's just not so lucky.
For example, this noise is actually very big.
It pushed my signal to the very right.
How do you know
it's zero or one at this time?
Then we might say
your original signal is one.
But in fact,
the original signal I sent was zero.
So in this situation,
my signal is actually
unable to successfully send to the opposite side.
That is to say,
in this case,
if the noise is very big,
I can't actually successfully
send the message I want to send
through the light to the opposite side.
So in this case,
we can say that
this light can't be used.
Because you can't successfully
send the signal to the opposite side.
Let's use an example to see
if this kind of situation
is actually very rare,
then it doesn't matter.
For example, I might have
a million times, ten million times,
a hundred million times,
I only happen to have
a very unfortunate
case of my signal being intercepted.
Then I just throw it away.
I might just ask the other side
to re-send it again or something.
There's probably no problem.
If we take these two,
for example,
I either send zero
or send one,
the signal that is disturbed by the noise
will be drawn out to take a look.
For example,
it might look like this.
That is to say,
if I send zero,
we use red to show
the situation when I send zero.
After sending zero,
it may be disturbed by the noise.
The signal I see
at the receiving end
may look like this,
scattered everywhere.
Similarly,
if I originally send one,
it is the green signal one
that I originally sent,
it may also be disturbed by the noise
and scatter like this.
But even in this situation,
although we can see
that some signals
may be misjudged,
but generally speaking,
most of the signals
are still distinguishable.
In this situation,
this light wire
can still be used
because most of the signals
are actually fine.
There is no problem in judgment.
But if today's situation
is like this,
in today's situation,
the noise
scatters my signal
to such an extent
that most of the red
and green signals
are actually mixed together.
In this case,
it is easy for me to make a misjudgment.
Even if I send one at the beginning,
I may have a big chance
to be judged as zero.
Even if I send zero,
I have a lot of chances
to be judged as one.
In this situation,
it is difficult for you
to say that
you can't use this light wire
because its noise
is far greater than
the signal energy of your signal.
In this situation,
we have to separate
these two
original zeros and ones.
If we separate them,
we have a chance
to be judged as one.
At that time,
you will consume
more energy.
Or,
in this situation,
you may reach
the level of energy
your machine can send
every time
you lower the width
of the white paper.
Then you may say
that this thing cannot be used.
So this is the signal
that will be affected
by the intensity
of the noise signal
to cause
whether this light wire
can be used
or not.
Of course,
sometimes it is
a more unfortunate situation.
But,
in fact,
sometimes we are
very lucky.
Because when we
operate the light wire,
we usually
separate these two signals
very widely.
This is the so-called
conservative operation.
In this situation,
there are not so many
noise signals.
Even if there are noise signals,
we will see that
these two groups
are actually
quite widely separated.
That is to say,
if I give you
zero at the beginning,
then I will
probably
have no problem
to easily
determine that
this is zero.
Similarly,
I can easily
know that
the group on the right
is probably one.
In this situation,
in fact,
we will now say
that this light wire
can be used.
It's really good.
But in fact,
at the same time,
we can find that
there are still a lot of blanks here.
In fact,
we can
make this white paper
more efficient.
What should we do?
We not only give zero,
but we can also
give some other...
We can also
subdivide this
white paper
into four equal parts.
Let's say
if I see
this dot on the far left,
then I actually
want to tell you that it's zero.
I want to
say one zero
on the far right.
Similarly,
we can see
these dots in the middle.
I just say zero one.
If this signal
is actually not
disturbed by noise,
then in fact,
we can still
successfully
receive these signals.
Because
these signals
are still
roughly in
their original positions.
Since they are
roughly in
their original positions,
we can still
easily judge that
if I see
a signal here today,
then I probably know
that there is no problem.
Its original signal
is actually
zero.
Its original signal
is zero.
Like this.
So,
at the same time,
how many signals
can we send
with a piece of white paper?
It's not just
related to
the size of this piece of white paper.
It's also related
to the noise
it receives.
So this is
the so-called
noise ratio,
SNR.
So,
the bigger my piece of white paper is,
the more
I can send
messages.
At the same time,
I can not only say
zero or one,
I can also say
zero zero,
zero one,
one zero one.
That means
the messages I can send
at the same time
are more.
The more,
that means
my frequency is higher.
What about SNR?
Of course,
at the same time,
if you have a lot of noise,
then you can
do less things.
Because although
your piece of white paper is big,
at the same time,
the amount of messages
you can receive
is not that much.
The messages you can successfully
see on the other side
are not that much.
Now,
if we consider
the transmission of
signals,
it's like this.
If we want to
send a signal
from the left
to the right
via a light
to the right,
we can think that
our signal
is a bit like
a piece of white paper.
Then we
decide
the code
between each other.
For example,
if I see on the left,
this is zero zero,
zero zero,
zero one,
one one,
one one zero,
like this,
this is called
modulation.
Modulation
means
adjusting
the relationship
between
your changes
and your
signal.
What is this
modulation?
If the other side
also knows
this modulation,
after you send
the signal,
the other side
can interpret
your signal.
It's a bit like
if I say
the leftmost point
is zero zero,
zero zero,
like this.
Then we can
send the signal
from one side
of the light
to the other side.
Of course,
it's not that good.
If there is no
modulation interference,
of course it's good.
In fact,
we can
put a lot of points,
but because of
the modulation,
like the example
we just saw,
because of the modulation,
so we actually
see the signal
at the receiving end
here,
the signal
is a bit
not the original position,
it may be a little bit
off,
but if it's not
off a lot,
we can still
successfully know
what the original
signal looks like.
If you see
the signal is probably
in this area,
then we know
it was originally
this point.
Then we can
check our meter
and say
this is zero zero.
After this,
we can actually
not need
these colors
to mark them,
right?
That is to say,
what is my
modulation?
How do I
divide this white paper
into several
different areas
and then I use
each point
to represent
a signal.
If I say
there is not
much noise
on the other side,
I can say
it's probably
in this area
and it corresponds
to this point.
This point
represents a signal.
So this is
what we
generally call
constellation,
that is,
if I see
this point,
what is
the signal?
Usually,
at the receiving end,
we will
make a judgment
based on
the message
to see
which signal
is more similar
to the original one.
Then we will
interpret the
original signal.
So we can
also see that
this noise
actually
depends on
the strength of
the noise
is related to
the frequency of
our signal.
Sometimes we
say
why we can
we buy a line today
and we say
its frequency is
10 GB
or we say
it is 100 GB.
In fact,
the frequency of
this line
is related to
noise.
The reason is
because
we generally
operate these lines
in a conservative way.
For example,
these lines
may have
expected
noise
in the natural world
which is
something like
this.
Then we will
give a very strong
signal
to separate it.
In this way,
we can
ensure that
always
restore
the
original
signal.
Then we say
this line
probably has
capacity.
In fact,
when we actually
send a signal,
we are not
only
a blank sheet.
We are not
only one-dimensional.
Sometimes we
use multiple dimensions
or in this case
we use two-dimensional
to show.
For example,
I have a
two-dimensional signal
and we will
also be
disturbed by
noise.
These signals
scatter
and we
can see that
the degree of
scattering is
not much.
So we can
still clearly
tell if
this signal
is in this area
and its
original signal
is here.
So it
can still
successfully
pull our
signal from
one side
to the other.
The advantage of
two-dimensional,
three-dimensional
or multiple dimensions
is that
we can
expand this
blank sheet
so we
can see that
the width of
this line
is actually
the ratio
of the signal
to its
noise.
The noise
ratio
has a
very strong
relationship.
Generally speaking,
most of
the time,
as we
just said,
although
this line
is 50
Gbps,
which is
50 x
square
bits,
we can
still
clearly
tell
if
this
noise
is
in
this area
and
its
original
signal
is here
and
its
noise
ratio
is here.
So
this
noise
ratio
is
about
this much.
So
we can
clearly
tell
if
this
noise
is
in
this
area
and
its
original
signal
is here
and
its
original
noise
ratio
is here
and
its
original
signal
is here
and
its
original
signal
is here.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code.
If I
modify
the
modulation,
I can
send more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same time.
So
this
effectively
improves
my frequency.
So
even though
we still
receive the
same
signal,
I can
still
modify
the
modulation
code.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
I can
modify
the
modulation
code
and
send
more
messages
to the
other side
at the
same
time.
So
if
we have
the
light source
now,
we can
modify
the
code
to
increase
the
frequency.
But
the
signal
can't
be
very
noisy.
So
this is
the
architecture
that
Microsoft
has
proposed.
Or
there
is a
drawback.
It's not a
It's a
trade-off.
Yes,
what we
just said
was
great.
If
we
can
use
different
constellation
maps
to
achieve
better
frequency.
But
the
problem is
that
you
need to
reconfigure
the
map
to
achieve
good
frequency.
If
you
have
a
new
map,
you
need to
reconfigure
it.
You
need to
reconfigure
it.
So
I
need to
reconfigure
it.
So
we
need to
reconfigure
the
map
to
achieve
good
frequency.
So
I
need to
reconfigure
it.
So
I
need to
reconfigure
it.
So
I
need to
reconfigure
it.
So
I
need to
reconfigure
it.
So
I
need to
reconfigure
it.
So
if we
suddenly
reconfigure
the
map,
map
will
suddenly
break.
The
broken
map
will
cause
the
traffic
disturbance
caused
by
the
network
sending
signals to
the
network.
So
the
traffic
will
be
disrupted
or
thrown away.
So
the
users
will
protest.
For
example,
if you
call
the
network
to
slow
down
or
break
the
network,
it
will
cause
the
network
to
slow
down
or
break
the
network.
So
the
traffic
will
be
disrupted
or
thrown away.
So
the
traffic
will
be
disrupted
or
broken.
So
the
traffic
will
be
disrupted
or
broken.
So
the
network
will
be
disrupted
or
broken.
The
traffic
will
be
broken or
broken.
The
traffic
will
be
disrupted
or
broken.
So
the
traffic
will
be
disrupted
or
broken
damaged
or
so.
So
the
traffic
will
be
disrupted
or
broken.
So
the
traffic
will
be
disrupted
or
damaged
so.
So
the
network
will
be
disrupted
or
broken
damaged
or
other
traffic
will
be
disrupted
or
broken
damaged
or
****
disrupted
or
trashed
controlled
traffic
by
walking
or
biking
traveling
by
running
or
traveling
express
The traffic may be slightly affected by the movement of the network,
but it is not directly affected by the movement of the network.
This is similar to
what the paper said
in the past.
If we want to
change the
traffic,
we should change the concept in stages.
This is the update of the multi-step.
So,
we can see the difference.
If we use the original proposal,
which is to cut it off directly,
and then restore it,
we may cause a huge
churn.
But if we have several steps now,
what should we do?
What should we do
in each step?
This is what we want to do.
In this paper,
what kind of update
do we want to do?
In fact,
I try not to interfere with
so much
network traffic
in each step.
This sounds quite intuitive.
If I can
get to my
final destination today,
and in each step,
I will not
let my
original network traffic
be cut off.
It may only lose a little,
but not too much.
For me,
the less loss,
the better.
If the best situation is that
I do not lose any traffic at all,
I can get to the end.
But because you have to adjust,
you have to
have some lines that cannot be used.
So, you will definitely lose a little,
but you do not lose too much.
This should be
a conceptually
better
adjustment plan.
The concept of
not losing too much
is called perseverance.
Perseverance
is the so-called
consistency.
That is,
this traffic,
originally,
for example,
if it is 1,
it can be conservative.
It can not
lose much.
Its loss
may be less than
how much.
We call it
perseverance level.
Of course,
we hope that
this perseverance level
is
the higher,
the better.
Perseverance
is originally
1.
How much
do I need
for the rest?
For example,
0.9,
0.8,
like this.
Like this.
So,
what is
our final
plan?
Our plan
becomes that
we want to
get to the end
as soon as possible,
but we do not want
to lose too much
traffic
in each step
in the middle.
It becomes that
we look for
the so-called
perseverance way,
which is
to consider
the consistency of
traffic engineering.
The consistency of
traffic engineering
means that
we want to
get to the end
as soon as possible,
but we do not want to
lose too much
traffic
in each step
in the middle.
This is
what we
proposed
in the middle
of this paper.
We want to
do this
new proposal.
We think
this is
actually better
than the
original
churn-based
proposal.
Why?
Because
in the churn-based
proposal,
you cut off
most of the
traffic,
so you will
get a
very serious
network interference.
This is
actually the
so-called
perseverance level
zero.
Between
the two
steps,
what can
I lose the most?
I can lose
all my traffic.
All traffic
can be cut off,
which is
perseverance level
zero.
However,
if we
keep a
higher
perseverance level,
for example,
0.5,
there are
two middle
steps in
the update
plan.
In each
plan,
I lose
at most
half of the
traffic.
For example,
if my
traffic was
from the
left to the
right,
all my
lines were
used up.
In the first
step,
I pulled
the traffic
from the
top line
down
and cut
them
off.
In this way,
I keep
at least
half of
my
traffic.
In the
entire
update process,
Can you
go back
to the
last page?
Yes,
it's in the
last page.
It's in the
There are
several pages
in the
last page.
This one?
Yes.
It's a bit
laggy.
Yes,
this page.
I don't know
if this is
practical.
For example,
you show
a step,
the first
version,
and then you
propose
unstep.
The next
thing I think of
is why
don't you
make it
infinite?
This
line becomes
a smooth
function.
A very
good question.
Your
limitation
is not
how big
a step
is,
right?
But what
does every step
mean?
Every step
needs at
least one
line,
right?
But the
network is
made up
of limited
lines,
so you
can't have
infinite steps
because you
need at
least one
line every
time.
So you
can only
have n
lines,
so you
can only
have
one
line every
time.
For
example,
if I
want to
make a
better
step,
but
it
gets
bigger
in the
middle,
I
don't
enjoy
anything.
I
lose
some
frequency.
So
we want
the process
to be
as short
as
possible.
We
can't do
that in
reality.
The
second
thing is
that even
if we
consider
an infinite
network,
we
don't want
to do
that because
we want
to get
to the
new
state as
soon as
possible
so that
we
can have
more
flexibility.
For
example,
we can
ask a
few
questions.
We
call this
a
re-adaptation
planning
problem.
How
do I
adjust
this
variable
network
plan?
How
many
steps
do I
need to
do?
The
first
question is
how
do I
solve this
problem?
Is
there
a way
to
solve it?
Unfortunately,
this is
a very
difficult
problem
called
NP-hard.
This
is a
very
difficult
problem
in
computer
science.
It's
basically
very difficult
to
solve
this
problem.
If
I
didn't
calculate it
accurately,
it's
basically
the same
as
the
NP-hard
problem.
The
problem
is
too
difficult.
It's
not only
difficult
to find
the best
plan,
it's
also
difficult
to
solve
the
problem.
This
is
a very
difficult
problem.
It's
very
difficult
to
solve
the
problem.
The
problem
is
too
difficult
to
solve.
It's
very
difficult
to
solve
the
problem.
It's
a
very
difficult
problem.
The
problem
is
not
so
difficult
that
it's
not
so
difficult
that
it's
not
so
difficult
that
it's
not
so
difficult
that
it's
not
so
difficult
that
it's
not
so
difficult
that
it's
not
so
difficult
that
pride
is
not
so
difficult
that
it's
not
so
difficult
that
it is
not
so
difficult
that
pride
is
not
so
difficult
that
it is
not
so
difficult
that
pride
it is
it
is
not
so
difficult
that
pride
it is
so
difficult
that
it is
so
difficult
that
pride
is
not
so
difficult
that
pride
is
not
so
difficult
that
So, did our proposal really cut off the traffic?
Did we really avoid this from happening?
And then,
we said that we have heuristics.
Is this heuristic easy to calculate?
Or is it actually difficult to calculate?
If it's also difficult to calculate,
we didn't mention one thing,
and then we have to calculate for a long time,
for example, for ten minutes,
we can only update our link.
If we update our link,
and then the traffic changes,
then we won't have enough time.
So, we hope that it can be calculated soon.
So, we did some experiments.
We first used
Microsoft's Microsoft Swan
and Google's Beeple
to do the experiment.
And then our
Skynet design heuristic,
we call it ALG.
And OPT,
we call it the best solution.
So, let's answer the first question.
After we add this
heuristic condition,
can we get
a better rating?
The conclusion is yes.
This row equal to one,
if we call this heuristic
as 1,
we can never
lose any rating.
That means we basically
don't update our links.
We can never
lose any network traffic.
The simplest way is
we don't move,
and we will never lose any traffic.
The original overall rating
is like this,
the column on the far left.
The column on the far right
is the solution
proposed by Microsoft.
If we lose in the middle,
how much can we get in the end?
We can see that
even if we add
this perseverance limitation,
we still,
whether it's the best solution
or our heuristic,
in the end,
they can be the same
as the solution
proposed by Microsoft.
Basically the same.
That is to say,
although we have perseverance limitation,
we are more smooth
than the original proposal
proposed by Microsoft.
But we can't get
the best rating
because of that.
In fact,
we can't get
the same rating
as Microsoft.
So,
this is the answer
to the first question.
The second question is
what kind of number
should we set
as our perseverance level?
That is,
what kind of loss
can we accept?
We can see
what the second picture
is about.
That is,
the process of update,
the process of overall rating increase.
If we start with
a 0.5 perseverance,
0.5 perseverance,
that is to say,
I can accept
that I only have 0.5 left.
Of course,
we give the system operator
a lot of space
to adjust these lines.
So we can reach
our final level very quickly.
Of course,
the less loss I am willing to accept,
that is to say,
the higher the perseverance limitation I require,
the less links
I can update every time.
Because if I cut off a lot of links,
I can't ensure
that the original
load flow
can still reach
the original 0.9 level.
That is to say,
it will be slower.
This requires more steps
to reach the final level.
So the higher the perseverance limitation,
of course,
the slower you will be.
Then we will ask,
if there is a perseverance limitation,
what is the relationship
with my
converge time?
Of course,
if you are willing to
accept more interference,
that is to say,
if you are willing to accept more disturbance,
the faster you will
get to your final state.
This is the same as the picture just now.
This is a more detailed picture.
That is to say,
we ran 1000 random cases,
and we found that
of course,
the higher the perseverance level,
the more time it takes to converge.
We can find that
most of the time,
your perseverance level
is between 0.5 and 0.7.
That is to say,
it will converge pretty fast.
It will converge pretty fast.
It won't converge
when it is set to a very high level.
So our best choice is this.
That is to say,
we can converge
in 3 to 5 steps.
At the same time,
we keep the original
flow rate between 0.5 and 0.7.
That's actually not bad.
At least 7 steps.
Compared to the original
that we threw away directly,
we still have 5 to 7 steps
to throw away.
We originally
argued that
this perseverance level
can make the whole process
smoother.
That is to say,
we won't throw away a lot of traffic.
Is that so?
Let's take a look at
the degree of vibration
in the update process.
The more vibration,
the more to the right.
The less vibration,
the more to the left.
Can you see
that we have introduced
these two methods
of perseverance limitation?
Its vibrations are very few.
It's not very few.
Its vibrations are smaller
than the original
Microsoft Red1 method.
That is to say,
our perseverance limitation
does help
the whole update process
to be smoother.
The last question
we want to answer is that
this is great.
We are very smooth.
But how long
does it take to get it?
If it takes a long time,
it will be lost.
Let's take a look at
the computation time.
The computation time
is how long
it takes
to find
a solution.
The time on our watch
is millisecond.
That is to say,
millisecond.
If we want to find the best solution,
it can't be calculated
in a very short time.
But in fact,
if your network is very small,
this thing can be solved by force.
You just force
to find all the possible solutions.
In fact,
it can be calculated quite quickly.
For example,
if you want to find the best solution,
it takes 67 milliseconds.
If you have a bigger network,
a bigger network,
it takes more seconds.
Until you have this,
for example,
this is a Google network.
Google network,
you have to spend
1.2 times 16 times
milliseconds to find one.
How much is that?
This is about
more than 1,000 seconds
to calculate
the process of updating once.
After you finish the calculation,
after 1,000 seconds,
you may have changed the message again.
Then you just
wasted your time.
In contrast,
our algorithm,
our heuristic,
only takes more than 300 milliseconds
to calculate.
That is to say,
in less than a second,
we can tell the entire network
how to adjust.
This efficiency is very high.
The speed of our calculation
is very fast.
And we can also
let this
be found in the previous
few experiments.
In fact, the algorithm we proposed
is not much different from the best solution.
Although we can't prove
that they are always close to each other,
because we just said
that this thing can't be
done on this mirror.
But in fact,
in terms of real things,
the solution we calculated
is not much different from the best solution.
And our algorithm
is very fast.
This is the benefit
of our new solution.
To sum up,
what is this paper
talking about?
This paper says
that instead of cutting
all the lines directly
and then update them,
and then we use
a higher frequency
to send new traffic,
we should consider
consistency.
That is, we need to make sure
that the network traffic
is not lost too much
in the process of traffic.
Considering this consistency,
it won't cause too much burden.
Because we have
a very good algorithm.
It can quickly
solve this problem.
It can quickly approach this problem.
It's not a solution,
but it can quickly
find a solution.
And this solution
is actually pretty good.
It's not much different
from the best solution.
from the performance
of cutting directly.
But it's very
smoother than
cutting directly.
Of course, we also admit that
in addition to consistency,
system operators
can also consider
more different aspects.
For example,
in the middle of the network,
in the middle of the update,
we hope that
these traffic
are not lost too much.
We may also hope that
they have some other
characteristics.
For example,
each traffic
cannot be less than
the absolute traffic.
For example,
I must be greater than 10Mbps,
I must be greater than 20Mbps.
It may not be a percentage,
but an absolute traffic.
We must maintain
how much traffic.
Otherwise,
I won't,
for example,
I won't feel a lot of delay
in the middle of playing video games.
How much traffic do I need at least?
For example, like this.
So this system operator
can actually adjust
their requirements
for the network.
And then,
let this network
operate more effectively,
more efficiently.
And they can,
in the end,
get a better balance.
That's all
for my speech today.
If you have any questions,
please feel free to ask.
Thank you for listening.
This topic,
this topic
is a little bit harder.
So,
if you have any questions,
please feel free to ask.
Let me welcome,
let me give a round of applause
on behalf of everyone.
Yeah.
Okay,
do you have any questions?
Do you have any questions?
Let me ask.
Yes.
For example,
if you are now
changing
their,
for example,
the two ends of the fiber.
For example,
the way they receive
modulation.
Yes.
So,
on the hardware,
will this thing need to be changed for a long time?
For example,
you were,
for example,
you said green light, red light, blue light.
Maybe it was only red and yellow.
Then you added
green light into it.
Yes.
Will it work
on the hardware?
This is a very good question.
Yes,
it works.
Then how long does it take?
At the time of RedOne,
in 2018,
it took
a few dozen to a few hundred milliseconds.
Every step,
Of course,
we can consider,
if you say
a few dozen to a few hundred milliseconds,
there is no difference, right?
But if you consider
these are broadband networks,
these broadband networks
carry a lot of traffic.
It may have a few terabytes of traffic
or a few thousand terabytes.
Multiplied by a few hundred milliseconds,
that is a very objective
traffic loss.
But,
how did it work before?
It used to be like
you said,
what if you want to add red light,
add blue light?
It is to turn off both sides first.
Because your laser needs to be adjusted again.
After you adjust the laser again,
you let it send out the laser again.
So,
turning it off and restarting
is actually very slow.
Now,
why does it need a few hundred milliseconds?
It was mentioned
in the original RedOne paper.
They said,
if we say
turning it off and restarting
is a major factor
in causing this delay,
we can try not to turn it off and restart.
If you don't turn it off and restart,
they can't make it work
at that time.
But they estimate that
if you don't turn it off and restart,
it may only take
a microsecond
to reach
the goal of re-adjustment.
If we say
our future network
can be seamless,
that is,
if I want to re-adjust,
I can re-adjust immediately.
Then,
of course,
our research
has nothing
to do with
their original research.
Because we basically
don't lose anything.
So,
I think this question is very important.
In the end,
how is it done on hardware?
Can it be done?
Yes, it can be done.
Is there any other
research requirement on hardware?
Yes,
that is,
how do we adjust
this modulation
dynamically?
In fact,
there are many ways
that can be thought of.
For example,
we can send the modulation
in advance,
right?
Then I will tell the other person
when I start
to use this new modulation.
In the middle,
it may need
some ways
to let the two sides communicate.
For example,
you want to use a clock.
That is,
you want to make
the timing
good enough.
For example,
I will immediately switch
both sides at 7 o'clock.
This is actually quite difficult
because you have to
synchronize both sides.
That is to say,
your time is consistent.
In fact,
sometimes it's not that easy.
Another way is
you send some
this packet,
send some information.
That is,
in addition to your
information,
send some
control messages
to the other side
and tell him
I want to start using it.
Then,
which packet
do I start using?
For example,
it's a little more complicated.
Because the current
system is not designed like this.
Their original system
may have imagined
that once you turn it on,
what is the modulation?
Just keep using it.
So, in the middle,
there are actually
a lot of research that can be done.
Does this answer your question?
Yes.
So, you said
Microsoft
changed
the modulation method like this.
How many times can it be improved?
Or how many percent?
Its improvement
is actually pretty good.
Let me find
its original paper.
I don't know if you can see
the original.
It's not good for me to show the paper directly.
But it doesn't matter.
Let's take a look.
When you show it,
before you finish,
you swipe to its title page
and show the author.
The author.
Do you know why?
Does it mean you can see the author?
Yes.
If you look at its original paper,
it's actually...
Let me see.
It can actually improve
a lot of traffic.
Or it can
avoid traffic drop.
But because their original
paper
talks about
a pretty simple
network.
It only has four points.
These four points
are in California.
So this
is just a prototype.
So
when it's actually used,
we can only say
it has a lot of potential.
But in the end,
when it's actually used,
it's not sure
if it's good or not.
But this idea
has a lot of potential.
This is the paper.
Whatsoever published this paper.
The purpose of this paper
is to say
this idea is pretty good.
But
our update
doesn't need to be so crude.
It can be more detailed.
This concept.
Of course, if we have better
hardware in the future,
then...
Go ahead.
My question is this.
When you're doing
your simulation,
basically,
you have to have some assumptions
about disturbance.
Yes.
What kind of
situation are you in
to compare?
So your disturbance
is like,
Google,
what do they do?
Or how do you
generate
the disturbance
in your simulation?
This is a good question.
So
what I actually generate
is not disturbance.
What I generate is
this link
the current state
and the next state.
So I actually
added a layer
of assumption.
That is to say,
let's assume that
my current link
can only send
50 gigabytes per second.
50 Gbps.
And then
because
the noise has dropped
I can send 100 Gbps now.
How should I update?
So
in the middle
I put the
relationship between
noise and signal
in there.
In fact,
in operation,
of course,
there are
other restrictions.
In fact,
there is also in the paper.
But I don't want to
show this paper again.
That is to say,
the adjustment of our screen width
is actually
not continuous.
That is to say,
the screen width
we can use
is not continuous.
For example,
25 Mbps,
50 Mbps,
100 Mbps,
150,
like this.
So,
you are actually
choosing these kinds.
No matter how much noise you have,
when it reaches
a certain point
you can probably
adjust it up.
You can adjust it
from 100 to 150
or 150 to 200.
But in fact,
why can you adjust
the principle
is what I just said
about the noise.
So, in fact,
how is it measured?
I don't have
this information.
I just
make an assumption
based on the range
it can adjust.
So, my assumption
is that
the original link
may be
in this
100 Gbps
mode.
Because
my
noise
may be reduced,
so now
suddenly this link
can reach 200 Gbps.
If it is
in this situation,
how do we
go from 100 to 200 Gbps?
So, a better way
is
you have already
assumed
your work goal
is to adjust like this.
But you tell it
how to be smarter.
Not that
it's not
that
it's not like
at the analog level
that
the noise pattern is like this,
so we should
decide
what state to adjust.
That is already
a given
assumption.
Yes, a given.
So, let's say
my device tells me
this thing.
I see.
My research
is usually
at a higher level.
So, let's say
the device tells me
these things,
how do I plan
this thing?
Okay, anyone else
have any questions?
Okay, if not,
let's
give another round of applause
to Shihai.
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you.
Okay, that's all
for today's lecture.
I'll...