Welcome everyone to participate in our presentation today.
I am the host today, Zhang Yuanping.
Our speaker today is very happy to invite Mr. Bojun to share his research with us.
As for the content, we will leave it to Mr. Bojun to share directly with everyone.
It will be about the熱傳熱導.
If I'm not mistaken, it should be like this, right?
Because it's not my major.
Everyone will know the details later.
Let's share the background of the teacher.
The teacher used to be Qingda Materials.
If I'm not mistaken, Qingda Materials.
After graduating, he went to Stanford to study materials.
Now, at the beginning of this year, he went to Duke.
At the beginning of last year.
At the beginning of last year, sorry.
At the beginning of last year, he went to Duke.
It's from the west coast to the east.
And it's almost a right-angled line.
It's not that right-angled, but a little bit.
Then I just missed the teacher.
Because I came back to Taiwan from UNC at that time.
And I came back to Qingda Materials.
So I just missed the teacher.
Otherwise, there should be a chance to meet in person.
I am very happy to have this opportunity today.
So let's not talk too much.
On behalf of everyone, I would like to warmly welcome the teacher to share with us today.
I'm going to take a picture.
OK.
You can share your screen.
It's at the top.
If you swipe over, there will be...
Do you know how to do it?
There are four buttons.
One of them is the share screen.
Then you do this.
OK, I saw it.
OK.
Then I'll turn off my microphone.
I...
OK, so you really can't see what I mean.
OK.
Thank you, Yen Ping.
Thank you for coming to listen to me.
Let me talk about the two little things I've been doing recently.
It's quite interesting.
It's mainly about how we can adjust our heat radiation.
And then let this building be more...
It's simple.
I just...
Yen Ping has already introduced my background.
Mainly, when I was at Stanford, I started doing nano.
And then I switched to doing some metal nanowires.
And then I started doing some textile research.
Textile, in my understanding, is actually related to energy.
Because...
I hope this slide will be clearer.
Because we actually spent a lot of energy
to provide us with a very comfortable hot environment.
In fact, most of the energy consumption in the United States
actually comes from fossil fuels.
That is to say, on the one hand, we have to push for renewable energy,
such as solar energy and wind energy.
On the other hand, if we can save the energy we use,
it will contribute a lot to reducing CO2 emissions.
The reason why I say that
textile and energy are closely related
is because if we look at...
This is also from the United States.
Let me ask everyone first.
Maybe I'll use a pointer.
Okay, yeah.
This is American consumption.
It's by different areas.
There's transportation, there's industry, and there's architecture.
Architecture is where we are now.
Just now, Yanping told me that
he's been looking for a parking lot for a long time.
We always go to a meeting place
to have a conference, class, and so on.
Even if you get off work, you go home.
So it's always in a building.
So it's not surprising that this building
takes up one-third of the energy consumption.
When we were young,
I think when we grew up in Taiwan,
we were taught to turn off the light
and turn off the faucet
to save electricity.
But in fact,
we didn't know until later that
most of the electricity
is consumed...
You're in this building.
You're consuming electricity.
Even if you don't turn on the light.
Because this building
needs to have a proper temperature.
You have to turn on the air conditioner in summer.
Taiwan doesn't need air conditioners in winter.
But in fact,
most places in the world
still have air conditioners in winter.
So HVAC is heating,
ventilation,
and AC is air conditioning.
This is a thermal air conditioner.
It basically takes up
17% of the energy in the United States.
You can imagine
if such a large amount of energy
is not consumed at all.
Because it is
the most basic living condition.
So the so-called textile
and energy-related places
are in this concept
called personal self-management.
In other words,
our traditional concept
is that we take this building,
the temperature of the whole building,
and make it very warm in winter.
Turn on the heater
and the whole building becomes very comfortable.
Personal self-management means
that we don't want to
make the whole building very warm.
Instead, we focus on
the environment around these people.
We try to make
these people feel warm.
After all, these tables and chairs
and decorations
don't really matter.
Textile is in this place.
We can make some new innovations
to achieve this goal.
Let's review
some of the past work
in personal self-management.
I mainly talk about radiative,
which is heat radiation.
In general, when we talk about a textile,
its cold or heat
is usually its flow
or evaporation,
how it is controlled.
Radiation is actually a very large piece,
but it has not been adjusted much.
So here we hope
that we can use some of the materials
and innovations to achieve different properties.
For example, we can
buckle the 7N wire
to the top of the clothes.
We can suppress the radiation.
In other words,
we can reduce our heat loss.
On the other hand,
we also made transparent clothes.
If you ask a physicist
how to make the coolest clothes,
the simplest answer is
not to wear it.
But obviously you can't do that.
So we can make clothes
that look colorful visually,
not transparent,
but don't seem to wear inside and outside.
This is the meaning of cooling textile.
Like this one,
it doesn't look very good,
but it's a prototype.
In the visible light,
it looks like a white vest.
In the infrared camera,
it looks completely transparent.
You can see the blood behind the clothes.
Radiation has a very special place
that is different from flow and evaporation.
Basically, it's like a TV.
It's like a light.
We all know that light has color.
Color is the nature of a surface.
Things can have two sides.
Two sides can have different colors.
So we can use this method
to make some traditional textiles
that can't be disturbed.
For example,
the textile of this Bill Maugham
looks the same on both sides
but it has a bilayer structure inside.
So when we put one side on the skin,
you will feel that your radiation is working,
so you will feel cooler.
But when you turn it over,
the other side is not so strong radiation,
so you will feel warmer
because it keeps your heat.
So with this Bill Maugham textile,
we can increase people's ability
to adapt to the environment.
For example,
for elderly people,
or people who get sick easily,
this can be a good protection for their immune system.
But there are also other ways to control it.
For example,
it's responsive to sweat.
When you sweat,
the textile becomes cooler,
and so on.
So the first thing I want to talk about today
is that when we finish these
heating, cooling,
and Bill Maugham textiles,
we find an interesting problem.
We find that the radiative heat management
actually has something to do with the substance underneath.
For example,
the reason this infrared transparent textile can work
is because this person is a very good radiator.
He's already radiating thermal radiation,
so we want to cool it.
The best way is to make this textile transparent.
So for a high-transmittance cooling,
for people,
a good radiator is more useful.
But if we want to manage things that are not people,
let's say a car.
Cars also need cooling.
That's not going to work,
because the metal itself is not a good radiator.
If you put a transparent thing in it,
it still doesn't radiate.
It's still very hot.
On the other hand,
if we want to do low-emissivity,
what is low-emissivity?
Emissivity is the ability to radiate thermal radiation.
The higher the emissivity,
the more radiation you emit.
The lower the emissivity,
the less radiation you emit.
So for a low-emissivity thing,
we want to use a high-emissivity device.
It's useful for low-emissivity objects,
but for high-emissivity objects,
it's a bit...
How can you be high-emissivity
if you don't have anything above that?
So from an engineer's point of view,
this is something that can't be tolerated.
Because when we make something,
we have to ask first
what kind of object this thing is suitable for.
In terms of design,
this is not a very perfect design.
Especially when we don't know what this object is.
It's easy to accidentally
make a lot of different devices
that can be useful for all objects.
On the other hand,
in terms of heating,
as long as we make this thing active,
it can always work.
This actually tells us that
today's transmittance,
emissivity, and reactivity,
these three modes need to be there
so that we can...
When we don't know what this object is,
we hope it can be controlled by heating and cooling.
We need these three modes
to have these three modes at the same time
on my device.
This is what I just said,
but in a more
quantitative way.
Basically,
when I use a transparent film
to cover an object,
the higher the coefficient of heat transfer,
the cooler it is.
The higher the emissivity,
If this is emissive,
let's say this thing is...
It becomes opaque.
So no matter what the thing underneath is,
the film above determines
whether it's cold or hot.
So you can imagine
there's a crossover
when the object underneath
is emissive,
you want to use the transmittance mode
to do the cooling.
So basically,
our goal is to
make a triple mode modulation.
At the same time,
this triple mode is also a completion,
because you want a light and an object
to be either opaque,
or absorb,
or reflect.
So basically,
as long as these three modes are available,
it's basically done.
So how do we do this?
First of all,
we choose an
infrared semi-absorbed elastomer.
Then we put this elastomer...
The surface of this elastomer
has some texture,
which is high-density adhesive.
Then we stretch this elastomer
to 100%,
and then put more metal on it.
So at this time,
this elastomer has two properties.
One is that its thickness becomes thinner.
The other is that
the metal is actually flat.
So at this time,
it's a better reflector.
This is a reflection mode.
So when we remove this elastomer,
so that it can be released,
two things will happen.
The first one is that the film becomes thicker.
Then this is its...
The metal layer we just cut,
it has an extra length.
So it becomes more wrinkled.
So we increase the thickness at the same time.
We also increase the surface...
What we call slow reflection,
which is scattering.
So overall,
we can increase
the composite absorption.
According to Kracov's law,
which is a very useful physical law,
it says that
in a thermodynamic equilibrium,
the more you absorb,
the more you release.
That is to say,
when we make a film with high absorption,
it also has high emittance.
So at this time,
it can do this cooling.
The third mode,
we just pulled this
100% film,
and then pulled it out.
We will pull this metal film.
After pulling it out,
of course,
the opened part becomes transparent.
Because this is a semi-absorbing elastomer.
So this is a state of high transmittance.
By using this open area
and relatively small thickness
to achieve this transmittance.
This is a simple evidence.
We made this material.
SCM is to look at the surface of the material
with an electron.
First of all,
we can compare this
emissive mode with static.
It's rougher.
It's rougher than it is.
And then it's all broken.
We also use a more static way
to explain the same thing.
Next,
we really want to prove that
it can be absorbed from the outside of the red
and then reflected and transparent.
So this is a
heavy-folding,
as I just said,
the nature of the three modes.
Of course,
we measured the entire spectrum
and then made a score.
But in short,
we started from 100%,
which is to pull and then cut the metal.
Then you put it in
the emissive mode.
And then you pull it back to the original state
when you pull it to 100%.
This is all reflected.
And then you pull it,
and you see that the green area becomes wider,
and the transmittance is dominant.
And then this kind of
trend-induced cycling
can last for a thousand cycles.
And then,
of course,
there's a little degradation,
but it's not a big deal.
In addition,
we also focus on switching from reflectance
to emittance
as a mechanism study.
As I just said,
the emittance mode
mainly comes from two factors.
The first is that its thickness becomes thicker,
and the second is that its surface becomes rougher.
So we can see that
the emittance mode
mainly comes from two factors.
The first is that its thickness becomes thicker,
and the second is that its surface becomes rougher.
So we can think of the contrast of emittance
as contributing to these two factors.
And this
is our experimental data.
We can do some simple fitting and modeling
to explain
what the surface roughness factor
corresponds to
in terms of surface roughness.
At the same time,
this is a smooth surface.
If you don't do surface texturing today,
you won't be able to achieve
such a high contrast of emittance.
As I just said,
texturing is very, very important.
At the same time,
we can also
artificially predict
if we push
its application technique today,
we may be able to
push it better.
For example,
if we can
make a perfect diffuse scattering
from a completely smooth surface
after it is released,
we can predict
a 0.7 emittance contrast.
In terms of the knowledge limit,
today's surface
is a perfect diffuse
surface.
So when the light hits it,
it will present a
it has a specific distribution.
And this distribution
has to do with the thickness
and the scattering rate of the material.
According to this thickness,
according to this scattering rate,
and according to this
the main thing is the scattering rate.
According to this scattering rate,
we can calculate
how much enhancement you have.
We can predict
if this is the limit,
we can have higher and higher emittance.
Next,
when we have this infrared measurement,
how much can it bring
the change in thermodynamics.
We also did a
heat transfer coefficient measurement.
The most important thing is to measure
the ability to control heating and cooling.
For example,
if we look at the red line,
the metal is at 100% strength.
It can go from 10 to 7.5
and then go a little higher.
Of course, this is completely customizable.
It depends on
whether you want more cooling
or more heating.
If it is blue,
it means there is a lot of heating mode.
In addition,
the picture on the right
is an experiment
to prove
what I said at the beginning.
I said,
if I don't know
the emissivity of the underlying object,
I can't
heat and cool all the objects.
For example,
if this blue thing
is a low emissivity material,
you will find that
when I use T-mode,
it is actually very hot.
The important thing is the temperature.
On the other hand,
if today I have a
high emissivity material,
I use T-mode,
which is actually cooler.
That is to say,
only when these three modes are available,
I can do the best
heating or cooling
for all the different objects.
Finally,
because we are adjusting the infrared now,
we made a
simple little device.
It's a
thing called
4x4.
We made a 4x4
pixel device
that we can use
to pump air
into a small chamber
or to draw vacuum.
We can adjust the
strength of the film above.
We made a
not very good-looking
but still
distinguishable letter D.
Then, of course,
we can adjust the other parts
to adjust the color
from non-radiative
to radiative.
I can pause here
and ask if you have any questions.
Hi,
if you have any questions,
you can ask directly.
Remember to turn on your microphone
or you won't hear the sound.
If not,
I will
continue.
Okay.
Okay,
so
this is just
for the infrared.
I just said
that
light and
infrared
are different from
radiation or radiation.
They are different wavelengths
and have different properties.
So we can have
different ways to adjust them.
The second part
is also
for architecture.
But we won't
do
this small device.
We will talk about architecture.
Excuse me, Bo-Jun.
Do you have a video?
I didn't see it.
Let's share it again.
Sorry.
Sorry for
interrupting.
Okay,
do you have it?
Do you have it?
Yes, I have it.
I have it.
Okay,
the second part is
that
another way
to save energy
from building
is to
use
renewable
energy
directly.
Renewable energy is
very simple.
We all know that
renewable energy is
a very mature industry.
Not many people
know that
there is another popular
field in the academic world
called radiative cooling.
Actually,
it has been happening
all the time.
When we
are in a vacuum,
besides the sun
giving you energy,
you are also radiating
to the earth.
It's hard to imagine,
but as I said,
infrared is a kind of light.
If you take a laser
and shine it to the sky,
you can shine it all the way to the moon.
So for light,
as long as nothing absorbs it,
it will keep going.
So when you are
on the surface of the earth,
let's say 25 degrees,
you are radiating to the universe,
which is 3 Kelvin.
So this is a very, very large temperature difference
that we can use
as a source of energy.
It's hard to say
why you don't feel
the energy
when you are outside in the daytime
because the sun is too strong.
This is why the academic world
has been doing
various materials
to make
what we call
daytime radiative cooling.
It can reflect
all the sunlight,
but there is still
a very strong radiation
that can do the cooling.
So this studio,
as Ye Min said,
I was at Stanford
and after my Ph.D. and postdoc,
I suddenly realized
that the world
has 4G.
In California,
it's basically the same every day.
The result of having 4G
is that when this building
may be good for heating
in winter,
but it needs cooling
in summer.
So buildings,
like people,
all need a control function
to have the best
energy saving
portfolio
in a year with 4G.
So we want to
have these two
sources of renewable energy
in the building
at the same time.
But it's not that simple.
The solar heating
and radiative cooling
require exactly the opposite
qualities.
As an ideal
solar heating material,
you want it to absorb
all the sunlight.
You don't want it to
keep all the
heat radiation
around you.
On the other hand,
for radiative cooling,
you want to do the opposite.
You don't want to absorb
any sunlight.
You want to maximize
the amount of heat
in the building.
But you can't
control these two
materials by adding
or subtracting.
You have to replace
the whole material
by chemical
or other methods.
So we chose
an engineering solution
with different
land scale tricks
and different performance.
But there is also
the possibility of
dual-mode control.
We made a film
that is very light
and can be
made into a roll-to-roll.
You can move
the film
in a roll-to-roll way.
We put the
solar heating
and radiative cooling
on the film.
We can use
the motor to switch.
First of all,
this material needs
good heating and cooling performance.
Let me briefly
introduce
the principles of these two parts.
In terms of heating,
we use
plasmonic absorber.
Basically,
it is used to make
small metal nanoparticles.
We have
used
a sound wave,
right?
The sound wave
has a fixed frequency.
The size of the sound wave
or the frequency of the sound wave
will have different frequencies.
The size of the nanoparticle
corresponds to the absorption
of visible light.
There are many different sizes of nanoparticles.
You can absorb
all the sunlight.
At the same time,
because it is metal,
it does not emit light.
I said in the last project
that if it is a metal nanoparticle,
it does not emit light.
A metal nanoparticle
can be designed
to be a perfect
solar absorber,
but it is a bad
infrared emitter.
On the other hand,
we use
PDMA.
PDMA is a transparent
rubber.
It is called silicone.
It is transparent
under visible light or sunlight,
but it is a good
absorber,
so the result is
a PDMA-covered
silver mirror.
We can reflect
sunlight, but it is a good
absorber.
We deliberately chose
these two materials
to be very scalable.
Because this thing
is going to be used by the building.
It is impossible to choose
a very unscalable
equipment.
Basically,
we are limiting
the size of the equipment
in our school.
For example,
a 12-centimeter-wide
film side-by-side.
This is
the opposite
optical quality I just mentioned.
Of course, it is not perfect,
but it is close to the
trend I just described.
Alpha and
Epsilon. Alpha is
the absorption of sunlight, and
Epsilon is the emission of infrared light.
For example,
PDMA is a very high
absorption of infrared light.
This is okay,
but it can
be lower.
Cooling is
visible light.
Solar does not need to be absorbed.
It is an infrared emission.
So this 2.7
is not
less than 5%.
Basically, you can't achieve
an effective cooling.
Because the sunlight is too strong.
The quality of both
materials
takes some time
to optimize the
material synthesis conditions.
In addition,
we use a
motor to
move the film to
make the material lighter
and thinner.
At the same time, it can also
reduce the energy
required for switching.
In addition, you don't want
the material to be too thick.
Because if it is too thick,
you have to spend some energy
to heat it or cool it.
It is more thermodynamic.
This is a simple demonstration
of its durability.
I did it 100 times.
Its performance is basically
unchanged.
The third point is
not so obvious,
but it is very important.
It is called reversible thermal contact.
You can imagine that when the film
moves to the left,
the solar heating will be very hot
and the water cooling will be very cold.
But if you can't
bring this heat or cold
to the building,
it will be meaningless.
Reversible thermal contact
is when we fix it,
we hope that it can
bring the heat down,
but it can also remove
and make a switching.
We use static electricity
as a driving force
to realize this function.
Basically, it is
a metal electrode
and substrate
as an electrode board.
As you can see,
the higher the voltage,
the higher the thermal contact.
On the right is the reference.
This is our film.
The higher the voltage,
the closer it is to the reference.
In other words,
it can bring all the heat
at the bottom.
This is a way
to reduce
or increase
its thermal contact conductance.
This is a relatively
simple way to describe it.
This is...
We want to demonstrate
that we don't need
to keep adding static electricity.
It's like today,
I know the capacitor.
After you add the voltage to the capacitor,
you break the voltage,
and the voltage is still there.
If you are
a circuit breaker.
So today,
as long as you don't
break the voltage,
it will stay there
until the water
or something else
takes the voltage away.
We measured
how long the voltage
can stay at the top.
After three days,
we can see the decay.
But it doesn't matter
if it's decayed.
We just need to touch it
a little bit
This is a video
of a real device
moving.
We use this motor
to move it.
The black part is
the solar heater.
The reflective part
is the radiator cooler.
This is the actual
roof of our school.
We did this experiment.
Doing this experiment
was actually
very difficult.
If it rains, we can't do it.
Anyway,
this is our
actual data.
The positive value
is for heating.
The negative value is for cooling.
We put a sensor
to measure this.
We also verified
the importance
of the voltage
in this device.
When we
gradually increase the voltage,
we can see that
the number of heating and cooling
has increased.
Switching
takes about one or two minutes.
In terms of
a building's time scale,
it's very fast.
Then we compare
the data
with the
model value.
The model value is
the weather,
the solar energy,
the humidity,
and the wind speed.
I can expect
how much heating
and cooling.
If the measurement
is close to the model,
it means that
the thermal contact
has been solved.
We can see
the black line
is the model value,
and the red line
is the model value.
Lastly,
we hope
that this
dual-mode device
can be used
in other places
in the United States.
As I said,
buildings
require
dynamic
and smart tuning.
With this
dual-mode device,
we expect
it can be used
in different climatic areas
in the most
effective way.
In fact,
if your building
can only do heating,
you can save a lot of energy
in the Five Lakes
and the Northeast.
Does it make sense?
Cooling is more average.
As you know,
in the East China Sea,
the East China Sea is
hot in the winter and cold in the summer.
In the West China Sea,
the four seasons are different.
Cooling is basically needed
in every place.
If you have dual-mode today,
you can choose
to do cooling or heating
when it is cold.
In different areas,
you can have a cool
or energy-saving
improvement.
Finally,
to summarize,
the two main tasks today
are dual-mode
and
I don't know
whether it can do heating
or cooling.
We also demonstrated
multi-spectral,
which is to say,
it can control
the two different
wavelengths.
Let's talk about
what kind of work
we want to do
from now on.
For example,
we can further subdivide
the concept of multi-spectral.
We know that although it is solar,
it also has visible light
and infrared.
Infrared is
coming from the sun,
but it can't be seen.
Today,
I just want to see the scenery.
If we can
subdivide it,
there will be more
useful functions.
In addition,
we need to use
telemetry to control it.
Basically,
these two tasks
are controlled by
mechanical methods.
For many applications,
moving part
is not a good thing.
It is easy to be damaged.
Telemetry has
advantages in this aspect.
Of course,
it is also more fun
in Fundamental Material Science.
For example,
Electrochromic,
we are doing a topic
about
wearable infrared
control.
Basically,
it can control
the radiation
from 1.5 times
to 1.5 times.
Another one
is
the work of
an audience called
Dai Yiqin Initiator.
It basically follows
the control of
Miraiya solar.
But we don't use
mechanical methods,
which is the same as before.
After we add electricity,
Miraiya becomes
higher,
solar becomes lower,
and vice versa,
solar becomes higher,
Miraiya becomes lower.
This is my talk today.
I should acknowledge
Lai Yiqin,
but that is
not the case.
The main work is
completed by my postdoc
and the students.
My collaborator is
Duke's
Willie Padilla,
and Wyoming's
Kang Tan.
Thank you.
Before we start,
I would like to
thank Lai Yiqin
for his wonderful talk.
Thank you.
I don't think it will be long.
I think the time is just right.
We usually have
this kind of time.
So,
I don't know
if you have any questions.
Since it is
over,
please turn on your mic.
If you are too shy,
you can ask me.
Can I ask a question?
No.
You can ask.
Oh, no. I was shot.
We are classmates.
We are college roommates.
Oh, right.
I just want to
thank Taira
for this great platform.
We haven't seen each other
for hundreds of years.
Let me introduce myself.
I am Ethan,
and I am doing research
in the field of materials.
We are college classmates.
This platform
is cross-field.
I don't want to get into
material science.
I don't want people to know
what we are talking about.
I want to ask a general question.
We are all overseas.
I believe this platform
is for Taiwanese
who are mainly scholars.
I want to ask you
to share your experience
in Duke.
You worked hard
to get a faculty position.
This is the light of Taiwan.
I want to ask
about your experience
in this platform
and your connection with Taiwan.
For example,
you interviewed students in Taiwan.
You also had a job interview
with some PhD students.
I want to ask you to share
what I think can be discussed.
First, what is the current situation of Taiwanese students?
For example, how active are they in studying abroad?
Second,
on a global scale,
what do you think
are the advantages of being Taiwanese?
What was the first question?
The first one is...
I know you didn't sleep well.
The second one is the level of activity, right?
Yes.
I think
in general,
everyone should have
a sense of crisis.
Of course, I think
Taiwan's society is stable
and prosperity is a good thing.
But I think
in terms of security,
at least
since we went abroad,
I've only heard about the situation in Taiwan.
But, for example,
there are fewer and fewer people studying abroad.
I don't think many people want to go abroad.
Actually, I'm curious about where everyone is going.
If it's a financial system,
it should be obvious.
Of course, everyone has their own...
Everyone has their own aspirations.
But I think
this distribution...
Fewer people
are doing academic research.
In the long run,
it's not good.
We'll be short of a lot of...
First,
let's say
in the first ten or twenty years,
there will be more potential
for growth.
But in
other countries,
the connection
will be weaker.
I still encourage
everyone to
take more risks.
What's the first question?
Share your experience
building connections with Taiwan.
Of course,
my experience is
taking care of Taiwanese people.
Let me give you an example.
I met
a Taiwanese
in a meeting.
We discussed
how to promote
Taiwanese students
to study abroad.
At the time,
I suggested...
It's simple.
I was teaching in
an American school.
If Taiwanese students
can get
a small living
allowance,
for example,
they can come to me
or other teachers
to do summer research
and get a recommendation.
I think it's easier
than
building a
school-to-school
memorandum.
If you sign a memorandum,
you'll know
you have a weak connection
with the teacher.
As a Ph.D.,
you can't do that.
If you can do that,
I think
it's possible.
Actually,
I brought this student
this summer,
but it became remote
due to COVID-19.
I don't know
how she'll do.
It's her first year.
But I think
it's a good summer experience.
For me,
I...
For her,
she has a very direct
teacher's recommendation
in the U.S.
It's very detailed.
It's different
from the teacher's
recommendation in Taiwan.
This is the style
between Taiwan and the U.S.
In Taiwan,
a lot of students
in the U.S.
would look at
when they met this student.
What was their first impression
when they first met her?
What project did she do?
What did she do?
Even if she was an exchange student,
it's not as detailed.
This is my...
This year,
I established a new
connection with Taiwan.
It's a new experiment.
I think it's a good point.
I'm a beneficiary.
We also have students
who are like you.
Visiting students.
Because of your recommendation,
we have some opportunities
for students
to exchange abroad
in college.
Of course, it's not much,
but it's a big difference
for a poor student.
Of course, we will try to make up for it.
We try to help with some costs,
such as experimental fees,
some space, and so on.
As for living expenses,
she may have to figure it out herself.
I believe it's across the board.
Many Taiwanese friends
are serving in different schools.
Let's see if there's a chance
to compete with her mother's school.
Of course, the school can do it.
If there is such an opportunity,
exchange students with Taiwanese students.
Of course, the main purpose
is to get a recommendation later.
And this thing
is easy to do.
Because for us,
today, of course,
there is a layer of alumni relationship.
But even if you go to
a non-alumni,
you tell him you have a free labor
to work for you.
No one will say no.
It will be very simple.
If you choose a more official
recommendation today,
but you have to admit your academic qualifications
and credit,
it will be very troublesome.
And let me tell you first
that now all schools
have some operations,
such as 2 plus 2.
It's a bit like Chinese people
stealing Western resources
to train their students.
At least I don't know other places,
but our whole country in Australia
has banned
signing MOUs with any place
in detail.
So you can't sign it.
You can't sign it at all.
So
I think
it's the first year
now.
Let's see how this student applies.
Of course, his application is mainly related
to his own ability.
But I think
this may help.
OK.
That's about it. Don't take up my time.
Yiting, do you have anything to add?
Yiting is my
first
Taiwanese student.
Hello, everyone. I'm Yiting.
I have a question.
Can you hear me?
Yes, I can.
Now
it's global warming,
so Taiwan's summer temperature
has reached 37-38 degrees.
I went with my uncle to visit
a orchid farmer.
They use a greenhouse.
During the day,
the sunlight comes in.
But because the temperature is too high,
they have to turn on the air conditioner all the time.
Because their orchids are very large,
their air conditioner power is not enough,
so many orchids die.
Now because of global warming,
Taiwan's orchids
also have other problems.
They can't lower
the temperature to the right temperature.
Do you have any suggestions?
Sure.
Like I said earlier,
first of all,
you have to let the light in.
The cheapest way
is to add a black cloth.
That's the cheapest way.
A more high-tech way
is to
block the part
where the sunlight
is only hot.
You can reduce it a little bit.
I think
in terms of greenhouse,
transparent is the first priority.
So this is a little bit
related to my last slide
about the future world.
Today,
for a very special requirement,
there will be a different approach.
The dual mode
just now
doesn't work because it's not transparent.
Orchids are all dead.
So we have to think of
a new material solution.
The interesting part is here.
For this different application.
Thank you.
Does anyone have any questions?
Our discussion today
is because we already asked
so we don't have to
ask about the content.
I think the content is really interesting.
I'm not a professional
so I can't ask professional questions.
I want to leave it
at the end
and let everyone
discuss first.
If there are any questions
related to the content,
we can discuss
whether it is
students studying abroad
or international cooperation
between teachers.
This is definitely
the core of Terra.
You can speak
later.
What time is our meeting scheduled?
In fact, there are only about 10 minutes left.
If everyone has something to say,
you can also be neutral.
If you want to stay and discuss later,
this room can be kept open.
After 10 minutes,
you can turn it off.
It's a bit stressful to talk while recording.
I've been waiting for you to turn it off.
I'll ask the next question first.
I'm going to turn it off.
What?
Are you going to turn it off?
Wait, let me finish my question first.
I have a question.
I just saw you talking about
the D
written in Chongqing style,
right?
I was thinking
when I went to see your website,
you mentioned
that the cloth becomes transparent
after it is covered,
but the white cloth
will pass the red line,
so there is no cloth
in Chongqing.
But if
the transparent cloth
doesn't pass the red line,
so you can see the cloth.
I was thinking
these things
can be used
for confidential communication
or other applications.
Do you know what I mean?
These possibilities are...
Can you answer this question?
Yes, of course.
Actually,
the red line
means
that
you can imagine
if
you have
a sensor
and you
take a picture of
the background
of the red line,
and you know
what the background looks like,
then you
wear a
pixel-by-pixel display,
and you adjust
the radiation on your body
to be the same as the background,
then you are
transparent in real life.
Yes,
there are many...
Yes, yes.
I was thinking that
it's like a encryption.
You put something on it,
but in a certain channel,
it's actually transparent.
You have to decode it.
It's like that.
You can think like that.
At least I thought like that when I saw it.
Yes,
basically,
we are talking about
a visible
material.
It can have
a color of
heat radiation.
You can control it
separately like this.
OK.
But in this case,
in the application of communication,
it will be
like what we usually
say,
like the encryption of visual data
and decode it.
Compared to that,
how efficient is it?
Because it's not a very...
When we do communication,
we don't think like that.
But in terms of concept, it's a bit like that.
Is it more efficient?
Or is its safety level
higher? I think the safety level is lower.
But
the efficiency seems to be quite high.
Because it can be...
It can be recorded.
The
amount of
data will be smaller.
I don't know.
I think if I really want to
push it like this,
I can think about it.
If you do it today,
suppose I only have
a very narrow
wavelength
with
specific text.
I can't see the other wavelengths.
Let me tell you
how many
wavelengths I'm going to use today.
Then you can see my text in this wavelength.
You can't see the other wavelengths.
In this case, it may be possible.
Because you talked about the
rush later, I think it's really cool.
So I just thought
it was a bit like what you said.
And because of
the control of the
current of the film,
you can have a schedule.
It doesn't have to be
a fixed wavelength.
It will change
according to some other conditions.
So even if you
really find that wavelength,
it's only for that second.
Because it's already
somewhere else.
So it's a
visual data
that covers it.
Because at least people
can't see it, so it's a visual data
method.
Yes.
I don't know.
I just thought about it.
I think
it's pretty cool.
But I don't have
a lot of ideas to realize this thing.
But I think it's okay.
You can think about it.
I'm done asking.
Because what I do
I'm not doing material science.
I'm not doing chemistry or physics.
I'm doing more communication research.
So I think about
this kind of thing.
Yes.
You can
brainstorm again another day.
Okay.
Do you have any more questions?
Then
if there are no questions,
I'll turn off the recording.
I'll turn it off.
1, 2, 3.