Yes, okay.
Welcome to the first lecture after the New Year.
I'm glad to have Sui-An here today
to share with us about psychology and law.
Law? I don't think so.
The application of psychology in law
and the development of it.
Before we talk about the topic,
let's introduce our speaker today.
Sui-An is a law major in NTU.
She studied law in NTU.
Then she became a lawyer.
She did well in the exam.
In the process,
she participated in many research and activities in psychology.
After graduating from law school,
she interned in a law firm
and later became a professional lawyer.
She also studied psychology in NTU.
In the field of law,
she majored in the case of death
and the defense lawyer.
That's her major.
In the field of psychology,
she did a combination of law and psychology.
She studied the testimony of children
in the court.
How to do it accurately and accurately.
After graduating from law school,
she went to Cornell
to continue her research.
Her research is about
cognitive psychology,
psychological development,
and the combination of law.
We can hear more details today.
Sui-An will share the details with you.
Finally, I will share a fun fact with you.
Sui-An,
besides...
Did I tell you I wanted to say this?
I don't think I did.
Sui-An,
besides her extensive academic background,
she is interested in drama performance.
She is also passionate about it.
In my previous research,
I majored in social psychology.
I needed an actor to play the victim.
I asked Sui-An to help me.
She is a professional actor.
Without further ado,
let's give the stage to Sui-An.
Let me give her a round of applause.
Thank you, Yen-Ping.
I feel a little shy.
Before we start,
let me give you a warning.
This is my first time
giving a live talk on the internet.
I'm a little nervous.
Please bear with me if I make any mistakes.
I want to say that
the audience today
may be from different fields.
I want to say that
after the talk,
if you are interested in this field,
you can read a book
or watch a TED talk on the internet.
This talk will be divided into four parts.
In the first part,
I will briefly introduce my background
and what is my relationship with this field.
I will also mention my relationship with Yen-Ping.
She is a great benefactor in my life.
In the second part,
I will talk about the research topics
in the field of law and psychology.
In the second part,
I will talk about the research topics
in the field of law and psychology.
The last part is about my own research.
Sorry, I made a mistake.
I forgot to mention some housekeeping.
Yen-Ping will talk to her PowerPoint.
She may not see
what you are talking about in the chat window.
If you have any questions,
you can leave a comment in the chat window.
I will read it for Yen-Ping.
Yen-Ping will find time
to answer the questions in the chat window.
Thank you.
Today's topic is
How can science help
establish a better legal system?
You can see three pictures here.
The left one
shows that although the legal world
is thought to be a humanistic
or socially scientific field,
the right one, the picture of DNA,
can help us
establish a better legal system.
The middle picture
is a classic
picture of legal psychology.
This is also a symbol of
American legal psychology.
It will also appear later.
It shows that psychology is a field
that studies human behavior.
The picture on the bottom right
is a picture of the brain.
There are many researchers
in the field of neuroscience.
They are thinking about
how to help us
establish a better legal system
through their research.
I am Suyi An.
I am a doctoral student
at Cornell University
Human Ecology
and Human Development.
Cornell University
has two different
fields of study
related to psychology.
One is psychology,
the other is human development.
I am in the field of human development.
There are three fields of study
related to human development.
I am in the field of
legal psychology and human development.
children, witnesses,
and cognitive research.
As Suyi An said,
I graduated from
the Faculty of Finance and Law
at Cornell University.
During my time at the Faculty of Law,
I worked as a research assistant
in two different
fields of psychology.
I worked as a research assistant
in two different
fields of psychology.
At first, I wanted to study
legal psychology
because I thought
since it is related to human development,
it should be related to human behavior.
I have been interested in psychology.
One day,
I was wondering
how I could get a chance
to study psychology.
At that time,
Professor Zhang Yanping
asked me to work as a research assistant.
I accepted his offer
and he took me in.
I have been studying psychology
with Professor Zhang Yanping.
At first,
I was working in
a social psychology lab
with Professor Lin Yizheng.
I was doing research
related to social psychology.
In my senior year,
Professor Zhao Yishan
was a vice-professor
at NTU.
He was a psychologist
who graduated from
Jianqiao University.
He was also a child witness.
I was interested in this field.
At that time,
Professor Lin Yizheng was about to retire.
I started doing research
related to child witnesses with Professor Zhao Yishan.
During my senior year,
I studied psychology
with Professor Zhao Yishan.
I have listed two pictures here.
NTU has developed
a new cross-field course
for legal psychology.
There are four professors
in three different fields,
legal psychology,
data science,
and information science.
I'm not sure
if this course will be online.
However,
cross-field students
are becoming more and more
popular in Taiwan.
Here are some
researches I did
when I was in Taiwan.
The first one
was with Professor Zhang Yanping,
who is now a doctor,
during Professor Lin Yizheng's
research period.
The second one
was with Professor Zhao Yishan
during his research period.
We did a study on
child witnesses.
The study
was mainly
about
how witnesses
would react
to a crime
in a different place
after witnessing
a crime.
The last one
was a study on children
in my master's thesis.
We wanted to see
if there were
many cases
related to child custody.
In those cases,
the legal terms
were quite complicated.
We also wanted to know
if there were any cases
related to divorce.
We wanted to know
if children could understand
the legal terms
related to child custody
and if they could
imagine what it means
to be divorced.
Something like that.
The second study
was with
Professor Zhong Chengyu.
He is currently
working at the Chinese Academy of Law.
He is also our guest today.
After I graduated
from NTU Law School,
I worked as a lawyer
for a period of time.
I mainly worked
at an international law firm.
The lawyer I worked with
was Mr. Huang Zhihao.
Mr. Huang's specialty
was psychology
and law.
He helped Taiwan
with many cases
related to child custody.
The so-called
case related to child custody
could be
a crime
related to
that could be
sentenced to death.
We called it
a crime related to
a crime
that could be
sentenced to death.
Mr. Huang's specialty
was psychology
and law.
He helped Taiwan
with many cases
related to child custody.
If you are interested
in working as a lawyer
for a crime related to
child custody,
you may be interested
in the concept of
judicial psychology.
For example,
when we come across
cases related to death
or cases related to
child custody,
we often see
the words
in red.
For example,
the evidence in the case
could be
related to
Taiwan's
Child Custody Rehabilitation
Association.
Many cases
are
based on
scientific evidence.
We need to
examine
whether the scientific evidence
in the case
is reliable
and what is the
evidence
that can be
re-examined.
In Taiwan,
we often see
cases related to
interrogation
or the
possibility of
further testing.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to
examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
We also need to examine
whether the
evidence in the case
is reliable
and what is
the evidence
that can be
re-examined.
I'd like to share
a documentary I watched a while ago.
It's about
a country in Africa
whose name I don't remember.
In their
modern
judicial system,
a part of it
is about
how to control
their maids.
Because the maids fly away,
they need chains to
control their
maids.
They will be punished
if they
join a national
ceremony.
They even formalize
the existence of maids
and write it in their laws.
This is still a thing
in the modern world.
Wow, that's amazing.
Thank you for your complement.
That's a scary story.
Let's move on.
In fact,
the reason why
many maids
were found guilty
was because of their children's testimony.
It's interesting that
some books
say that after the children grew up,
they regretted
not seeing
what the maids
were doing.
Maybe they were
afraid of the adults
or other factors.
That's why they said those words.
They were doubtful.
In other words,
did the children lie
or did they
believe what they said?
Because of
external or internal reasons,
they
might not
believe
what they said.
They might not believe
everything they said.
It's interesting.
In the early 20th century,
the earliest research
came from Alfred Binet.
If you're a psychologist,
you might know him.
He was one of the
most important
researchers and
inventors
of modern IQ tests.
He had a legal background.
Although his research
was based on IQ tests,
according to
our Tibetan teachers,
his research
was based on
the credibility of testimony.
He published
a book in 1901.
He said that
through his research,
he thought that
the credibility of testimony
of men and women
was based on
the ability of human
to react to
the information
they received
from others
and
the ability
to
resist.
He was very interested in this.
From 1901
to
1960 and
1970,
no one paid attention to this.
In the 1960s and 1970s,
children's testimony
became a hot topic.
As women
and children
started to
pay attention to
children's rights,
many people started to
pay attention to
children's rights
in kindergartens,
and there were many cases
about
inappropriate contact
with their family members.
Under these circumstances,
the law and cases
changed the situation
so that most of the children
could not testify in court.
Suddenly, the condition
for children's testimony
to testify in court
and the age
for children to testify in court
led to many children's
testimonies
in court.
The judge didn't know
how to deal with it,
and the psychologist
didn't know what to do.
My teacher
was an expert
who studied
children's intelligence
and memory.
He was an expert
in pure academic theory.
He found that
a boy
was involved in a murder case.
The father
seemed to have hit his mother
with a stick.
He asked the boy
if he had seen
his mother
being dragged
to the back door
after the argument.
The judge wanted to know
if the child's testimony
was credible,
because it was related
to the father's crime.
My teacher thought
that as a well-known
child memory expert,
he couldn't answer the question.
So he gathered
about 30 experts
from the U.S.
to hold a meeting
in Cornell.
The purpose of the meeting
was to discuss
how to transfer
psychological knowledge
related to children
to the court
and make it
a practical knowledge.
So the experts
held a three-day meeting
in Cornell,
and came up with
a white paper
that slowly influenced
the combination
of psychology and law.
In the 1980s,
there was a famous case
called Mark Martin's
Family Trials.
It was about a kindergarten
run by a family.
Suddenly,
dozens of children
claimed to have
been sexually harassed
or sexually harassed
by various members
of the family
with different objects
of interest.
Most of the charges
were revoked
or turned into
conjury.
The reason was
that the child testimony
in the case
seemed to be
impossible to find physical evidence.
Many experts
used psychological research
to help determine
whether the child testimony
was true or not.
There's a documentary
about the case
that you can check out.
Mark Martin
published a book
in 1995.
After the meeting
in Cornell,
he began to receive
many letters
from lawyers
asking him
if he wanted to be
a part of the case.
The lawyer said
he didn't mind
as long as
the child testimony
was easy to understand.
You can check out
the documentary
online.
The documentary
is about
how psychological research
can be applied
to children.
Any questions?
Let's move on.
The child testimony
is about
a man who
is a good man
but a very careless man.
It's a pre-testimony.
There may be
some guidance issues.
The child testimony
is about
a man who
is a good man
but a very careless man.
The child testimony
is about
a man who
is a good man
but a very careless man.
The child testimony
is about
a man who
is a good man
but a very careless man.
The child testimony
includes
many additional
evidence
that may
have to do with
law and psychology,
including how
electric vehicles
can be applied to
law,
and when children
develop the ability to
lie.
In some specific crimes,
judges and judges
may have different
sympathies
for different
cultures,
social status,
and different
ways of
raising children,
so we are
currently doing
a research
to explore
the different
aspects of
the child testimony.
We hope
this research
can help
you understand
the different
aspects of
the child testimony.
I am also
working with
Charles Brenner
on a research
called Fuzzy Trace Theory.
Fuzzy Trace Theory
is a method of
memorization
in which
we try to
visualize
the memory
of the victim
in a specific way.
For example,
we try to
visualize
the victim
on the African
prairie,
and see if this
special way
can enhance
the memory
of the victim.
I am also
working with
a professor
in the Department of
Law on
whether
most states
in the U.S.
are able to
evaluate the
ability of
this method
of memorization
in the U.S.
I am also
working with
Cornell
on a research
called
World Anti-Torture Center.
We are also
working on
a book
on the
possibility
of
taking home
the message
that if you are
interested in
law and psychology,
you should
go to the
American Psychological Society
to learn more about
law and psychology.
In Europe,
there is a
law and psychology
association
called
the American Psychological Society.
I think
it is a great resource
for people
who want to
study abroad.
This book is
written by
Elizabeth Loftus,
an expert on
the study of
memory.
It is a
great resource
for people
who want to
learn more about
law and
psychology.
That's all
for today.
If you have
any questions,
please feel free
to ask.
Before we
start,
I would like to
ask you
a question.
You can turn on
the microphone
or leave a comment
and I will ask.
How to turn on
the microphone?
Go to
Blue Dream
and you will
find a
picture of
Blue Dream.
Click on it and
you can talk.
Please go ahead.
It's okay.
I just have a question.
No, I mean
you can ask now.
Okay.
Do I need to introduce myself?
Sure.
I am
Feng Mengzhang,
and I am studying social science.
Hi.
So
I was thinking
about the issue of
the gap between
children's
testimony and
objective situation.
I am curious
about
how to
distinguish
the gap
between
the children's testimony
and the objective situation.
Is it the memory
or the memory
that is affected
or the expression
that is affected?
For example,
the stereotype
that the person
was affected
by the stereotype.
The description
of the stereotype
is the difference
between the control group
and the treatment group.
One possibility is
that the stereotype
may cause
some mistakes
in the process
of memory
or memory.
Another possibility
is that
the stereotype
may cause
some mistakes
in the process
of memory
or memory.
Another possibility
is that
the stereotype
may cause
some mistakes
in the process
of memory
or memory.
Another possibility
is that
the stereotype
may cause
some mistakes
in the process
of memory
or memory.
Another possibility
is that
the stereotype
may cause
some mistakes
in the process
of memory
or memory.
Another possibility
is that
the stereotype
may cause
some mistakes
in the process
of memory
or memory.
Another possibility
is that
the stereotype
may cause
some mistakes
in the process
of memory
or memory.
In fact,
there is no way
to distinguish
the information
given by
the person
and how he or she
remembers it.
In fact,
there is no way
to distinguish
the information
given by
the person
and how he or she
remembers it.
In fact,
there is no way
to distinguish
the information
given by
the person
and how he or she
remembers it.
In fact,
there is no way
to distinguish
the information
given by
the person
and how he or she
remembers it.
In fact,
there is no way
to distinguish
the information
given by
the person
and how he or she
remembers it.
There is another
big question.
I majored in
economics,
so I will
think about
what is
the cause and effect
of human behavior.
Back to the question
of children's
testimony,
I was thinking
about the cause
and effect of
children's testimony
in court.
I can imagine
the cause and effect
of children's testimony
in court.
For example,
adults know that
there will be legal responsibility
if they testify,
but children
may not understand
the legal effect
behind the behavior.
For example,
the prosecutor may like
the father or mother
and want to tell
the good words
to the one he likes.
The prosecutor may
want to please the authority
and obey the authority.
If there is a big difference
between the cause and effect
of children's testimony
and adults' testimony,
there may be
different contents.
I was wondering
if anyone has
analyzed this issue.
Yes,
I have seen
a lot of research.
You just mentioned
a lot of things.
For example,
some of the research
has been converted
into a method
to interrogate children.
The first method
is not to promise
the child
good or bad answers
or what kind of actions
the child will take.
For example,
if the police take the child
to McDonald's,
the child will not
be attracted to McDonald's.
The second method
is not to promise
the child good or bad answers
or what kind of actions
the child will take.
The third method
is to give the child
a chance to
choose the right answer.
For example,
most of the research
in Europe and America
does not recommend
the use of a telegram doll.
Telegram dolls
are very interesting
to most children.
If you tell the child
to do certain things
with the doll
and not to do
certain things with the doll,
it will affect
the child.
In this process,
if you tell the child
to do certain things
or not to do certain things,
it will affect the child.
We are working on
how to maintain
the focus of the child
in the process of
asking questions to children,
but not to give the child
too many external questions.
Many people are studying this.
I think this question
is professional and good.
Thank you.
You just answered
the questions I wanted to ask.
The next question I want to ask
is from
someone else.
Thank you.
Let me guess.
I used to work
at the Family Violence
and Sexual Assault Prevention Center
about six or seven years ago.
You just said
that telegram dolls are not recommended.
We use a lot of them.
We try to
at least
use them
if there are
research papers.
If you really
have to use a tool,
telegram dolls
are the last step.
They are too easy to use
because they have holes.
Children
may want to
insert different
body parts or objects
in order to
interpret the behavior.
So,
a better way
is to use a time line
or a pen
to
telegram the child.
Or,
if you really need
to point out a specific part,
telegram dolls
are less likely
to have body parts.
So,
if you have
DNA evidence,
children
are likely to be
sexually assaulted.
So,
I don't recommend using them.
Okay.
Next,
let me see his name.
Is his name
Mingxin?
Hi, everyone.
Thank you.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
Hi,
I'm Mingxin Zhu.
I'm a doctoral student
at Northwestern University.
Yiyan is my classmate
in the Department of Law.
Thank you, Yiyan.
I have two questions.
The first question is
when a child
gives his testimony,
the job of a lawyer
is to
incorporate his testimony
into the law.
So,
from a psychologist's point of view,
if you find that
the testimony is likely to be contaminated,
or if the contamination
is significant,
if the contamination is light,
is it possible
to correct it
or give it
a different weight
instead of throwing away
the entire testimony?
Is there a difference in the amount
rather than just having it or not?
That's my first question.
What about the second question?
Have I finished my question?
Okay,
let's start with the first one.
You asked about the evidence
and the evidence.
From a psychologist's point of view,
do you only discuss
the evidence and not the evidence?
In fact,
most people
in this field
are still trained
in psychology,
so they don't think
much about how
a lawyer or a prosecutor
or an attorney
should use the evidence.
For example,
let's say that
this case has repeated interrogation.
The contamination
may not have been discovered at the beginning,
but it was discovered later.
Of course, you can ask an expert
to verify that
in the first two interrogations,
there was no inducement
or contamination.
In the first two interrogations,
what was provided?
In the third interrogation,
there may be some external
inducement or
inappropriate reasons,
so the child's testimony
may have been contaminated
or even changed.
In fact,
it can be used in the first two interrogations.
Psychologists may evaluate
the possibility of
external contamination
in each interrogation.
As for
how lawyers
use scientific reports,
I think it's more like
a lawyer's strategy.
As far as I know,
ordinary children's legal psychologists
don't interfere
with how lawyers
use scientific reports.
On the one hand, it's not suitable
because it's a legal profession.
Ordinary children's legal psychologists
don't understand this profession,
so they provide
very pure scientific analysis reports.
This is what I know
from my experience.
I mean,
with your background,
from a psychological point of view,
is it possible that
the level of contamination
can be reduced
to a point
where there is no evidence?
Or is it possible
that it still exists
and only needs
some correction
on the basis of
the level of contamination?
I've discussed this with my teacher.
He rarely
accepts students
with dual backgrounds like me.
I asked him
if I needed to
give expert advice.
He said it's simple.
I can't be an expert
on the same case
and defend the same case.
He suggested
that this kind of thing
can be done
by
reducing the level
of contamination
to a point where
there is no evidence.
First of all,
even if I think this way,
my child can't
have no evidence.
It's not a scientific term.
It's a legal term.
I see.
In my scientific report,
even if I have a dual background,
I can't
cross-reference
the legal part.
I should leave it
to my legal team
to do it,
even if I have a dual background.
My second question
is that
your school has
a plan to
conduct an investigation.
Yes.
I'm curious
about the role of psychology
in the court in Taiwan.
For example,
is there any possibility of
cross-referencing?
After our legal department
was sentenced to death,
there are only some procedural
issues that can be reviewed.
For example,
are there any other
legal procedures?
However,
I'm curious
about the role of psychology
in the court in Taiwan.
I'm curious
about the role of psychology
in the court in Taiwan.
I think
it might be related
to the logic of religion.
There are two judgments
in the Supreme Court
for the death penalty.
The logic is that
a person can only
be held accountable
for the crime he committed.
If a person
has a mental state
during the execution
or even before
the execution,
which means
he can't be held
accountable for the crime
he committed,
he shouldn't be sentenced to death.
This doesn't mean
he should be sentenced to death.
In Taiwan,
as far as I know,
there is still
no assessment
on this issue.
The reason is that
there are three
common psychological
abilities
related to the death penalty.
The first one is
whether the person
has the ability to
communicate with the lawyer
and defend himself.
The second one is
whether he has the ability
to be held accountable
for the crime he committed.
The third one is
the ability to be executed.
As far as I know,
in Taiwan,
the ability to be held
accountable for the crime
he committed
is not necessarily
acceptable
or is still
a difficult concept.
It's even more difficult
when it comes to the ability
to save the life
in the later stage,
or the ability to be held
accountable
according to the law.
As far as I know,
Taiwan's judicial system
doesn't deal with the issue
of the ability to save the life
and the ability to be held accountable.
Some states require
the lawyer to apply
at the last minute,
so they are now
looking at
which states
don't allow
the application
of the ability
to be held accountable.
They are still
doing statistics
on the case
of the death penalty.
I see.
There's a minor point
that I'd like to add.
You mentioned that the witch
wanted to see
if there's a chance
to confirm the death penalty.
Yes, I saw that
and I think you're right.
It's a minor point.
Thank you.
Thank you, Cha-Zheng.
Okay.
Let me ask
another question.
You mentioned
that
a friend here
asked a tricky question.
He said,
it sounds like psychology
has a great influence
on food in the US and Europe.
I'm curious
if it has an influence
on Taiwan's courts.
You mentioned that
psychology
evaluates
the person
or the defendant
I'm guessing
whether the person
has the ability
to be held accountable.
But you didn't mention
that psychology
has a great influence
on the evidence
in Taiwan's courts.
Can you comment on that?
As far as I know,
there are five kinds of evidence
in Taiwan,
such as human evidence,
book evidence,
and so on.
As far as I know,
human evidence
has a great influence
on the evidence
in Taiwan's courts.
As far as I know,
for example,
Mr. Zhao Yishan
is a consultant
in the Ministry of Public Security.
Due to his influence
and the promotion
of some private groups,
there is a new law
called
Sexual Harassment Prevention Act.
According to the law,
it should be
carried out
by experts
in the field.
As far as I know,
there are many
psychologists,
clinical psychologists,
and so on.
Psychologists
are also
working on
the establishment
and modification
of articles
related to
sexual harassment.
As far as I know,
in the past few years,
Taiwan has been
more and more aware
that
first,
science can enter the court,
and second,
science is not only
the so-called hard science,
such as forensic evidence,
and so on.
There is also
the so-called soft science,
and so on.
I think more and more
legal figures
in the legal system
are paying attention to it.
Not only judges,
but also prosecutors and lawyers
are doing different
training.
I think it's pretty good.
That's the situation in Taiwan.
Okay.
I have a question.
It's my own question.
Do you have any other questions?
Let's think about it.
I'll go first.
Excuse me. Can you hear me?
Please go ahead.
I'd like to ask
that
the study design
you're using now
is based on quantitative research,
or
is it qualitative?
Because
in the evidence part,
I know that
I've seen the related research.
They are
using the model of
the Maga Jury
to look at the decision
between the patient groups.
They are in the qualitative part.
So I think
the first question is
that you want to do a
quantitative research.
Is it based on
the data you presented before?
Or is it based on the quality?
If it's a cross-border research,
we are considering
both quantitative and quality.
For quantitative research,
the easiest way is to look at
the level of guidance
in each country.
For the quality,
we are considering
the level of guidance
in each country.
So we are considering
the level of guidance
in each country.
So we are considering
the level of guidance
in each country.
The second question is
How old is the child?
We currently have two groups.
One is 5 years old
and the other is 8 years old.
5 years old is
half of 8 years old.
8 years old is half of 8 years old.
5 years old and 8 years old.
I have seen
online
that the relevant
children's interviews
are usually not appropriate
for the age of 11.
So I am not sure
if the same problem
will occur
in the law psychology.
Thank you.
We are considering
two groups.
One is the kindergarten group and the elementary school group.
There are several reasons.
First of all, the children's testimony
is what I saw
or what we did in the lab
or what I did
when I was in the elementary school class.
Many of us will mention the age under 11.
Because in the field of children's testimony,
when it was created
or when everyone was doing research,
it was to solve the problem of food.
However, many cases
of child-like
disability
include victims
or witnesses.
They may be children
who are quite young.
In the United States,
most of them are children
in kindergarten age.
So in the field of children's testimony,
especially in the field of pedagogical research,
the kindergarten group is usually included.
As for the text of my testimony,
we are still thinking about
the issue of openness.
We are still thinking about
We don't know
how rich the content
of the child's testimony
will be.
However, there is a mystery
that can be solved.
If the child is
very child-friendly
and not too high-pressure,
the issue of openness
will be solved.
However,
the child can speak a lot
in kindergarten.
We are now
trying to solve the issue of openness
to collect the text of the testimony.
We don't know
how the result will be.
Sorry, I want to add one more thing.
If you want to work in Taiwan,
the IRB
may be a little
more difficult.
This is my personal experience.
Because Talking Age
is for children.
They will require these things.
The IRB is now running.
So,
fingers crossed.
The IRB in Taiwan
is probably the easiest
to work with
in the middle age hospital.
If it is in other medical institutions,
it may be very troublesome.
That's right.
Now,
the IRB in Taiwan
is running.
So,
fingers crossed.
Thank you.
Taiwan
involves children.
Thank you for
your encouragement,
support and advice.
Thank you.
So,
do you have any other questions?
Let me ask you a question.
Do you have time?
Yes.
Please go ahead.
I'm sorry.
You just mentioned a lot of research
about
the situation when children
were drawn for testimony.
Whether they were
sedated or
not,
and so on.
It's all about the situation
when children were drawn for testimony.
I'm thinking about
an extreme situation.
If the situation is not reliable,
let's say we get an article.
The article says
that this is the testimony of a child.
It's written as an article.
We don't know what happened.
Is there any way
to
estimate
the credibility
of the testimony?
Why do I think
it's like
we don't know
what happened
to the journalists.
But we can
see from the news
that it's fake news.
We have that ability.
Is there any way
to study the credibility
of the testimony?
I know that
a lot of people
would go directly.
If it's just a text,
and there's no recording,
let's first see
how the text
is made.
For example, in Taiwan,
a lot of text
is not written in text
because it's easier to record.
It's actually a sample.
It's hard to analyze
from a scientific point of view.
If the quality is better,
it's really a text.
There's a way
that
I'm not sure
if it's possible.
You can analyze
the form of the question.
Is it an open-ended question?
If not,
does the way it's designed
have any guidance?
For example,
is there any information
that hasn't appeared
during the interrogation?
For example,
did your dad
touch your sister?
It's obviously a guidance question.
But if it's
like,
hello, I'm a policewoman.
Can you tell me
what your dad did to you?
Your dad might be a guide.
If there is
a more complete text,
and you can tell
the form of the question,
you can analyze
the form of the question
and see how much
guidance it has.
I have no more questions.
Anyone else?
If not,
let's give Yilan another round of applause.
That's all for today.
Thank you.