Hello everyone, welcome to today's 9.19 Taira Talk. I am the host today, Hong Shi-an.
We are very honored to invite Liao Kun-yan to speak for us today.
Liao Kun-yan is currently a Ph.D. student in the Materials Engineering Department at Tokyo University.
Previously, he obtained a master's and master's degree from the German University of Munich.
He is mainly interested in electronic microscope and neutron scattering material analysis technology.
He is mainly interested in the structure of inorganic glass, the high-angle crystal, and the origin-density spectrum.
Today, he is going to talk about EELS, Electron Energy Low Spectroscopy.
Let's give him a round of applause to welcome him to give us today's talk.
Everyone, please turn on your microphones.
We'll leave the time to you.
Okay.
I'll start now.
The topic of my talk today is EELS.
I want to talk about why it is thought to be a synchrotron in electronic microscopes.
In addition to the introduction just now, let me introduce the department I am in now.
Our department is a department that attaches great importance to electronic microscopes.
We have about 20 electronic microscopes in our department.
We have about four or more electronic microscopes.
Our field includes instrument development, ceramic interface, crystal defects, and quasicrystal crystal.
Our department specializes in EELS and DFT calculation.
In order not to be the same as them, we specialize in non-static, liquid, and gas.
In the past, we have done a lot of liquid and gas EELS.
But this is a special instrument, so I won't talk about it in this talk.
My own research is that I am very interested in glass.
In addition to the fact that most of the glass you see on this screen is transparent and well-balanced material,
if you look at the inside of the glass from a nanometer perspective,
it may have a very small domain.
This is because of the domain caused by its phase separation.
It will also cause it to have different shapes and colors.
It will have different structures and textures.
My first year is mainly to study this.
Today's talk will also talk about some.
This year, my own theme is to adjust to the dopan in the glass.
Is the dopan in the glass a cluster or a particle?
Or is it a dopan that is separated from one atom by one atom?
What impact does it have on the quality of the glass?
This is my own theme.
I won't talk about this today.
Another thing I will mention is that I have measured the thermal expansion coefficient of some crystal surfaces.
I may have a chance to mention it today.
This is related to optical characteristics and PLASMO.
I will mention it later.
Basically, this is the outline of today's speech.
I will first tell you why we want to make electronic microscope.
How do we see the origin?
Finally, I will talk about EOS.
It may take a lot of time in the first half.
After all, I'm not sure what the audience's background is.
So I will talk about what the electronic microscope is doing.
Basically, all microscopes, no matter what particle you use,
The earliest microscope should be the optical microscope invented by Hucke in 1665.
Hucke is the most familiar with its spring, Huckelo.
But in fact, he also did a lot of things.
One of them is the optical microscope.
Then he went through a very simple observation of what the cells and insects look like.
Then he drew it down and got some new knowledge from it.
But this is in 1665.
Of course, for the people at the time, this may be a very incredible research.
Then he really told us a lot of things.
But if you only have optical microscopes,
In fact, it is not enough today.
The reason is that if you only have optical microscopes,
You won't know what happened to us this year.
That is, if you don't have an electronic microscope,
In fact, you can't see the virus.
Then you can't see the coronavirus.
You won't know what happened this year.
This photo is from the Institute of Health in the United States.
Photos of the coronavirus, electronic microscope photos.
Then the one on the right is the structure of the virus.
Photos of the electronic microscope.
It was also published this year.
The electronic microscope seems to have won the Nobel Prize in Chemistry in 2011.
It is also a very popular field.
But I won't mention it because I'm doing it completely.
So we won't discuss the electronic microscope today.
But it is also a powerful tool.
So seeing this kind of small-scale thing,
It is an advantage that makes electronic microscopes unique.
So if you look at it from the perspective of a microscope,
Because what I learned myself is material science.
Material science is a very complicated subject.
The reason is that it is a cross-level problem.
For example, I used to do metal materials.
Suppose you want to design a metal material.
You have to consider a lot of things.
You have to consider what happens to its surface at the level of a microscope.
Is there a crack?
You have to find out how many phases are there in the material.
What is its texture?
Is there any adsorption?
Finally, return to the characteristics of the metal material.
To deal with such a problem,
In fact, we need a lot of different tools in different systems.
For example, if we need EBSD for the level of a microscope,
We need some mechanical tools to measure.
At the level of a microscope, we need high-resolution TEM.
Even if you need a very high-resolution spectrum like AtomPROP
To confirm your chemical composition.
On the other hand, if you are doing simulation,
You will find that the people of mechanics
The most important simulation they do is called Finite Element Method.
Finite Element Method simulates some of the characteristics of mechanics.
But in the Finite Element Method,
You still have to have physical properties.
So you have to do some molecular mechanics,
Modicaro, and even DFT, Programme Mechanics.
So simply put,
If you really want to fully understand material science,
You have to have all of these things.
In comparison, the level of a microscope
In fact, the knowledge we currently have in technology
In fact, it is already very sufficient.
Basically, there is nothing you don't know.
Most of the problems on the level of a microscope can be solved.
But at the level of a microscope,
We will have a lot of difficulties just measuring.
That's why I want to talk about this today.
In particular,
If you look at it from a physical point of view,
In fact, we deal with these problems.
There is a tool called Large-Scale Facility.
That just happens to be STEM, Singleton Radiation, and Neutron Source.
I have done these three experiments.
I also want to briefly talk about their differences.
In general, Taiwan currently has the middle one and the left one.
Some universities in Taiwan have the left one.
The middle one is Neutron Radiation.
Taiwan's Neutron Source.
It is the third generation of Neutron Radiation.
It is also a very powerful method.
There is a big difference between them.
In addition to the type of radiation you use,
This one uses electrons, this one uses light, and this one uses neutrons.
Their sample duration is actually very different.
For example, if you look at a microscope,
The property you get, the amount you get,
Or the area you observe,
It's actually a very small range.
Simply put, there is a saying,
See the tree but not the forest.
You can only see the tree, but you ignore the forest.
A microscope is a bit like looking at a tree.
So your resolution is around nanometers.
It's great.
But if you want to go to a higher resolution,
In fact, Neutron Radiation is a more suitable tool.
Because what you see in your Neutron,
The size of your crystal sample is about micrometers.
If you want to study more industrial problems,
To the size of millimeters, centimeters, or even meters,
Neutron Radiation is a very good choice.
Because you can put a centimeter sample in.
When I was at Muniher,
At that time, there were some BinLine.
Muniher is the headquarters of BMW.
They can put a whole car engine
Put it in the BinLine of Neutron Radiation.
To see some images of its engine.
In addition to the sample size,
Its interaction with matter is also very different.
Neutron, whether you are magnetic radiation or nuclear scattering,
It's all very weak.
It doesn't destroy your sample.
But electrons are easy to destroy.
Or change your sample.
This is also something we need to pay attention to.
If you say so,
There is a big difference.
The middle and the far right,
They are all user facilities.
That is, you don't need to know anyone in there.
You just need to apply for your project.
If your project passes, you can do the experiment.
Even if you have nothing to do with it.
But it's a pity that in the electronic microscope,
In fact, there are not so many user facilities.
So most electronic microscopes are still owned by a small number of people.
If you want to do a similar experiment,
You have to know someone.
There are some user facilities.
At the end of the speech, we will tell everyone.
If you want to do it, you don't know anyone.
You can go there and do it.
It will be put at the end of the speech.
What kind of user facilities can be used?
In fact, people in the past have never thought about
To turn electronic microscopes into
Such a public instrument such as neodymium magnets or copper radiation.
One of the reasons is because
Electronic microscopes were not so powerful at the time.
It can't do so many things.
But recently, it can really do a lot of things.
If you are interested, you can look at this paper.
Why neodymium magnets in electronic microscopes
It really causes electronic microscopes to become a single-chrome radiation.
If you are interested, you can refer to it.
The biggest problem I want to talk about today is
Between me and the audience
Maybe a lot of people have different views on electronic microscopes.
Of course, some people have similar views.
If you are from the Microscopic Society, you may have a closer view.
The first thing I want to talk about is
How do we see atoms?
In fact, this topic has won awards in 2011 and 2020.
Wolf Prize, Cavalier Prize, and Nano Prize
I showed a picture here.
It is a high-resolution TEM image.
Its material is iron.
Iron is a popular topic.
If you don't know much about electronic microscopes,
I think you can ask three questions.
I want to answer these three questions in the next section.
The first thing is how to see such an image.
If you have the opportunity to use an electronic microscope,
Is it easy or difficult to see such an image?
This is the first question.
The second question is if you observe this image
If you look at its atoms, it will have yellow, orange, and blue atoms.
If you look at the left and right, you will find that the orange atom is at the top of the blue atom.
The orange atom is at the bottom of the blue atom on the right.
You will find that we can observe the deviation of several atoms.
The second question is how do I know which atom represents which element?
What kind of atom is the image it sees?
How do we distinguish the atoms?
This is the second question.
The third question is what is not in such an image.
The information in such an image is the electrical field and magnetic field.
If there is an electronic microscope,
I can't see the electrical field and magnetic field with the latest electronic microscope.
This is the third question I want to answer.
Let me give you a brief introduction.
Electronic microscopes are very different from optical microscopes.
But the structure is basically the same.
You have a light source.
This is an electron.
You have a condenser lens.
The only difference is that the optical microscope on the left is a glass lens.
The electron on the right is a conductive electron.
So you use a magnetic lens to focus on the electron.
There is also a sample.
There is also a fog lens.
There is also a projection lens.
So the simplest way to understand is that the electronic microscope is an optical microscope.
Just use the electron as a light source.
If you understand this way,
In fact, most things can be solved.
Because most people should have encountered optical microscopes.
The only difference is that you need a large electronic microscope.
It needs high vacuum.
But in addition, you can really use it as an optical microscope.
Of course, electrons and substances have different effects.
The biggest reason why I use electronic microscopes is
In fact, the wavelength of electrons is much smaller than that of normal visible light.
If you have studied physics and are familiar with light, you may know that there is a formula called Abbey Diffraction Limit.
Basically, what he is talking about is that no matter how small the light is, the resolution will still be limited to the wavelength.
This is a physical limit.
The maximum resolution is your wavelength divided by 2.
Of course, this limit was broken in 2011 by the Super Resolution Optical Microscope.
But in general, this is the limit of optical microscopes.
If you look at this formula, you can intuitively see that if you want to improve your Abbey Diffraction Limit,
You have to find a way to make your wavelength smaller.
The reason why I use electrons is actually because of the resources.
Because when you apply a very strong electric field, the wavelength of electrons can be very small.
For example, if you apply 300 kV, your electronic wavelength can be up to 1 picometer.
In principle, you should be able to see the resolution of 1 picometer.
But this is actually wrong.
Then I will explain why this is wrong.
But the basic concept is that the reason you use electrons is because the electromagnetic wavelength is very short.
Then it can help you see things more clearly.
Why is it wrong?
It's because our lens is actually not perfect.
There is something called Spherical Aberration Curve.
To put it simply, you start from the same point from different angles.
You can't actually focus on the same point through different angles.
Of course, if you read a high school textbook, it will tell you that no matter which angle you start from, it will focus on a focus point.
But in fact, you can't actually focus on a point.
To be more specific, what is Spherical Aberration Curve in real life?
It's a bit like you take a glass cup and put it on a floor with patterns or sandpaper.
You will find that the part you see clearly is only a small area in the middle.
But the sides are all curved.
This is the reason for Spherical Aberration Curve.
The more you move away from the center of the light, the more you can't actually focus on the same point.
So what you see is curved.
In fact, in the electronic microscope...
Can you hear me?
Sorry, I'm not sure what happened just now.
But there is also this problem in the electronic microscope.
So the first thing you see is how to fix this problem.
In fact, this story can be recited for a very long time.
But simply put, there are four people who contribute in this field respectively.
The story began in the early 1940s.
After 40 or 50 years of hard work,
people found this problem and solved it.
The method they used was to use a lot of electronic probes to try to correct this difference.
Of course, this electronic probe is a very complicated result.
According to my research, in the latest electronic microscope,
you need to have 20 layers of this kind of electronic probe to achieve a good resolution.
But in short, this is a success.
So now we can see the origin through this Spherical Aberration Curve.
Most users don't really need to know how to control it.
Basically, the maintenance staff will help you adjust it.
So if you use an electronic microscope now,
how much resolution can you get?
I have a picture here.
On one side is TEM, and on the other is STEM.
The one in the middle is the resolution before correction,
and the one in the back is the resolution after correction.
Of course, you can't see how well it has changed in this picture.
But it's obvious that it's clear.
For most people, this is enough.
If you look at the picture on the right,
it's actually a silicon.
There's a certain angle in the middle.
If you do a Fourier Transform,
you'll see this kind of Diffraction Pattern.
It's obvious that if you don't have a corrected picture,
the Diffraction Pattern limit you see is about 1.92 Angstrom.
If you go through the correction,
you can see that the limit is about 0.76 Angstrom.
That's 76 picometers.
This resolution is probably in 2002.
The data I found,
if you are a modern electronic microscope,
it should be able to reach more than 50 picometers.
As mentioned earlier,
the Cornell DMV group,
if they do Tycography,
it can reach 40 picometers.
That's the current record.
Your resolution is higher than 40 picometers.
If you hear this,
I think some people may have a question.
Why do I need such a high resolution?
I'll give you two examples.
Why do we need this resolution?
The first example is a carbon nanotube.
If you look at this picture,
the picture on the left,
if you don't do analysis,
you can't see any difference.
This is a very beautiful
atomic resolution carbon nanotube.
But if you do analysis,
every point,
intensity,
if you do Gaussian fitting,
you will find that you can analyze
one atom, one atom,
how many positions it deviates.
You can see this value.
This color represents the distance it deviates.
All units are picometers.
That is, through modern electronic microscope,
you can see from the position of the atom,
you can know its
carbon nanotube
the distribution of gravity.
Then you can know which atom is deviating.
Do this kind of very
high-precision measurement.
This is very important for imaging.
It is also important for EOS,
for light sampling.
The reason is because
if you want to see
the light sample of a single atom,
you must look at it very clearly
to understand which atom is what.
This work is
Suenaga,
he is Japanese,
a Japanese broadcaster.
The main idea of this work is
he wants to look at
the green one,
the common graphene carbon,
and the two-handed carbon
on the edge of the graphene,
to this one-handed carbon.
What is the difference in its light sample?
What is its impact on the quality of graphene?
He really went to do it.
I have a question.
Sorry,
I'm not an electronic microscope,
so I might ask a very out-of-the-way question.
You said that your displacement
is probably at
dozens of picometers,
this level.
You can probably say
how much of this displacement
comes from the incident particle,
which is your electron,
plus the displacement.
What is the percentage,
or what is the percentage?
I don't know.
The first thing I want to say is
this is
how to say it,
that is,
modern,
you can,
because electronic microscopes
are actually quite long-standing
studies,
so a lot of information,
like how much energy
your electron emits
to a single atom,
you can use calculations,
and you can also calculate
how much it heats up
to a single atom.
But what you said,
that is,
in the end,
for example,
how much impact
it has on carbon nanotubes,
this is a very good question.
You have to,
for each different material,
you have to discuss this matter.
I can't tell you directly
that it probably stands to reason,
but I can tell you very clearly
that you do today,
like this carbon nanotube,
the impact of electrons on a single atom
is definitely higher than
you take it to look at
metal or ceramics.
Maybe ceramics,
you don't even,
electrons,
that is,
your atoms
don't cause any change at all.
But in this kind of carbon nanotube,
indeed,
electrons may
have an impact on the position of the atom.
But I can't tell you
exactly how much
it accounts for.
Sorry.
Yes, I understand.
Thank you.
Yes,
simply put,
of course,
the question you just asked
is also a very practical question.
You have to
study this matter.
But simply put,
because there is a spherical refractor,
we can see the atom very accurately.
That is,
people who do EOS
can go to
each atom,
each single atom,
to see what is the difference
between its light waves,
such as green,
blue,
and red.
There are some differences.
Of course,
green and blue
may be very different,
and blue and red
may not be so different.
But if you do the calculation,
you can know
why they are different,
and what the difference
means.
This can be interpreted.
Sorry,
I have a question.
OK.
Yes,
can you hear me?
I can hear you.
You can hear me.
How do you look at
the energy loss
in the 2D
part?
In theory
or in practice,
how do you look at
this thing?
What kind of energy loss
does it have?
I will put it
in the second session.
I will put EOS's structure 2.
But simply put,
you see this image.
In fact,
it is
EOS's structure 2.
It is
In fact,
because you
have a
regressed electron,
you
are
detecting
the energy
loss
of the
regressed electron.
So EOS
is usually
placed at the
bottom of
the electron microscope
.
A
general
instrument
is placed
at the
bottom.
You
put the
light
spectrum
like this
and
analyze the
energy loss
of the
same electron.
Then you can
see the
light spectrum
like this.
I will
talk about
the specific
structure
in the
next
section.
Okay,
the part
I just
talked about
is about
how we
can see
an electron
very precisely
.
This matter
is very
important.
Because
if you can't see
the electron,
you can't
study the
light spectrum
of the
electron.
The
red frame
here
is the
element
that
ordinary
people
will
encounter.
The
element that
is not listed
below
may not
be an
element
that
ordinary
people
will
encounter.
Let me
give you an
example.
You can
think about
what you
expect to
see in
the electron
.
The
answer is
that all
the elements
in this
frame can
be seen,
including
light and
light.
I have
a picture
here.
The
most important
element
I just
talked about
is the
light
element.
This is
my
recent experiment.
You can
see the
white
bismuth
forming
particles
or
single
atoms.
In the
glass,
bismuth
is definitely
something
that
is easy
to see.
The
light element
is special
because it
has only
one
light
element.
The
first time
it was
seen was
in 2011
in the
YH
crystal.
You
can see
the
faint
intensity,
but
basically
you can
see the
light
element.
This
method,
in fact,
the first
method to
do this
is the
method
that
you can
see the
light
element.
Of
course,
it's not
that simple,
but
theoretically
you can
see the
light
element.
The
first
question
I'm
going to
talk about
today is
that
many people
seem to
be doing
STEM,
but
no one
knows
why.
This is
not a
traditional
electron microscope.
It's a
technology
called
STEM.
It's
very different
from a
optical
microscope.
STEM
actually
focuses
the
electron
into a
very small
probe
and then
does
scanning.
The
traditional
optical
microscope
will
look
very
different.
To
put it
simply,
because
it does
this
scanning,
it can
put
detectors
at different
angles
in different
places.
These
detectors
can
tell you
different
information
in
different
places.
The
electron
microscope
is
very
sensitive
to
the
intensity
of the
electron.
You
can
tell
the
intensity
of the
electron
by
looking at
the
intensity
of the
electron.
The
other
technology
is
the
brightfield
microscope.
It
is
similar to
the
TEM
microscope.
The
last
technology is
the
detector.
It
is
very
sensitive
to
light
particles.
In
other
words,
if
you
have
a
small
electron
in
the
microscope,
you
can
detect
light
particles
in
a
small
electron.
You
can
detect
light
particles
in
a
small
electron.
You
can
detect
light
particles
in
a
small
electron.
You
can
detect
light
particles
in
a
small
electron.
It
is
a
very
sensitive
technology.
It
is
a
very
sensitive
technology.
It
is
a
very
sensitive
technology.
For
this
case,
let me
show
you
how
important
this
thing in
science
is.
This
is an
experiment
tailor-made
project
that
studies
Gold
in
liquid
ions.
This
is their
an original
image,
but
I don't know
if there is
any contrast
in this
picture,
that is,
there are some
lines,
but
you can't
see anything.
But
if you go
to the
hard
depth
image,
you will
find that
there are
actually
a lot of
gold ions
in
this
picture.
It
turns out
that
if you
do
such
research,
gold ions
can be
distinguished from
gold ions
and
it
becomes
a very
important
thing.
From
this
point of
view,
you
can't
see
anything
at
all.
On
the other
hand,
there
are several
ways.
The first
thing is that
this picture
is actually a
lithium-ion
liquid.
I forgot
whether it
was steam
or something,
but there is
a low
physical
mass,
so it
will not
become
gas in
vacuum.
You can
put it
in.
This is
a general
electronic
microscope.
If you
allow it,
you can put it
in.
In fact,
many people
don't like
doing this,
but in
principle,
it is physically
safe.
Another
method
is
called
a
liquid
holder.
It
has a
special
holder
that you
can put
liquid
in.
These
things
are
very thin.
My
understanding
is that
EM
has to be
cut very
thin.
Yes,
this
situation is
a bit like
a
lithium-ion
liquid.
There
should be
a
molybdenum
or copper
grid
on the
outside
.
At
the
beginning,
it
is
very
thin,
but
if you
heat it
a little
in the
vacuum
furnace,
it
will
actually
become
a film
like this
and
its
thickness
is
about
10 nanometers
.
This
material
can do
this.
This
material
is
very
thin
and
quite
mature.
The
most famous
is
Berkeley
Lawrence
Lab.
He
has done
a lot of
liquid experiments.
Didn't
they say
to wrap
things up
with
graphene?
That's
also a
method,
but
you
think about it
yourself,
it's
really in the
liquid environment.
The graphene
you just
talked about is
also a method,
but the
current mainstream
is to
use a
special
microwave holder
.
You can
really put
liquid in
.
Generally
it is
silicon nitride.
OK,
so it
is also
silicon nitride.
Thank
you.
The
other one
is
lithium
atom.
Everyone
is studying
lithium
atoms.
Our
department
originally
studied
ceramics.
He just
thought
lithium
atoms were
quite
interesting,
so he
used
ABF
as I
just
said.
We
developed a
method
to look at
lithium
atoms.
But
if you
charge it,
it will
run out
if you
don't
see it.
Then
you can
come in
by
health
charging.
Then
you can
judge
it by
intensity
.
If
you are
studying
lithium
atoms,
the
current
microwave
will
run out
if you
don't
charge
it.
So
that's
why we
don't
need
lithium
atom
technology.
Yes.
Finally,
I'm not
sure how
many people
are
interested
in
magnetic
and
electrical
fields.
This
has nothing
to do
with
electrical
or magnetic
fields.
Electrical
fields will
tell you
the direction
of the magnetic
field.
In the
past,
if you
only had
one detector
and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell
the
magnetic
field
or
magnetic
field
from
the
other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell
the
magnetic
field
or
magnetic
field
from
the
other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector
and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell
the
magnetic
field
or
magnetic
field
from
the
other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector
and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell
the
magnetic
field
from
the
other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell
the
magnetic
field
from
the
other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector
and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the
other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the
other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
if you
only had
one
detector and
didn't
have a
block,
you
couldn't
tell the
magnetic
field
from
the other
detectors.
So
spectroscopy
is very
important.
Of course
my time
is very
limited,
but
I can
simply
say that
EOS
is usually
at the
bottom
of
the
sample.
So
EOS
is
basically
IR
plus
Raman
UPS
plus
angle
reserve
plus
apex
XAS
In many of the blue squares, I have 5 to 6 hands.
This can tell you a lot about the nature of glass.
It can also tell you, for example, how many 5 or 6 hands you have on a point.
It will affect the nature of glass.
This is basically the information you can get from the structure map.
Other than that, I don't know, maybe a lot of people are interested in Transition Metal.
For example, you can have a 2-frame mesh and a 3-frame mesh.
If you just look at the image or the deflection, you can't tell.
But if you use EOS, you will find that the light source is in a different position.
If we don't mention the calculation, this is what it looks like in practice.
You have two atoms here, one is A and the other is B.
Then you also look at MnL2Cag.
You will find that the light source of EOS will change slightly between different atoms.
If you use EOS to calculate, you will find that the light source of 2Cag is in the middle, and the light source of 3Cag is outside.
This can tell you a lot of information.
In addition to knowing the location of the light source, you can also know the oxidation state of the light source.
Some EOS can even tell you if there is a transfer of electrons.
So far, this is basically what everyone is doing.
Doing this in practice is actually quite simple.
If you are interested, you can try it yourself.
In fact, this is not that difficult.
This is basically the most common application of Coros.
It's like this, 2Cag, 3Cag, 4Cag, this kind of balance state mapping.
Let me make a simple comparison here.
The EOS I just talked about is actually XAS, X-ray absorption spectroscopy.
In fact, it is very similar to the EOS function.
But their energy boundaries are not quite the same.
X-ray absorption is basically greater than the energy of 2KeV.
EOS is basically 1mEV to 10KeV.
The energy resolution is not much different now.
But if you add the non-committer, the latest EOS record can be up to 3mEV.
You can use it to study the body.
But the spatial resolution is very different.
The spatial resolution of XAS is about 50nm to micrometer.
In the case of EOS, you can go to angstrom to nanometer.
So if you are more interested in some nanometers,
you can consider doing an EOS experiment.
Then you can compare it with Bokeh.
The second section I want to talk about is the VALENCE section.
It is more about the transfer of light and snow.
You can think of it as the energy obtained in this section.
In fact, it has something to do with your relay parameters.
This is a raw data.
If you do fitting, you will find that there are different peaks in this fitting.
Some of them come from PLASMO, some of them come from the interband transition.
You may know that the VALENCE band is usually at the top and the CONDUCTION band is at the bottom.
This is the definition of the band gap between LUMO and LUMO.
If you use EOS, you can do the same thing.
We don't have time to go through the SURFACE PLASMO.
What I think is more interesting is that we can measure the band gap of some interfaces in some very special materials.
For example, the material here is actually oxidized aluminum.
Oxidized aluminum has different angles in the oxidized aluminum of polyethylene.
This is a metal defect.
If you measure its EOS, you will find that the black one is Bokeh.
Bokeh is basically the same.
But you will find that the red one has two band gaps in this interface.
In fact, each one is different.
You can analyze it.
For example, in the interface, your band gap becomes 6.7.
Originally it was 8.8.
What impact will this matter to your material quality?
You can also analyze how the interface will have a lower band gap.
How do you control this?
If you are a semiconductor person, this is very interesting.
Because you can measure a lot of interfaces in your software.
Is it good or bad for you?
I also think that the band gap measurement is not that simple.
But basically, EOS instruments can do this.
You can try it.
The last section is Valence EOS.
This section is a special one.
It is interesting that it can measure temperature.
The principle is to use Profile Fitting to feed PLASMON's energy.
Because its energy is related to the density of the electrode.
So if you change the temperature, the density of the electrode will change.
You can measure the temperature.
This diagram is a very simple temperature mapping.
This material is aluminum.
I'm not sure if it's a wet electrode or a wet electrode.
It should be a wet electrode.
You can see the temperature change in the aluminum.
Of course, it's not that simple.
But it can still be done.
This is the part of measuring temperature.
I've been doing it recently.
It's a bit like what I just said.
I'm going to measure the EOS changes in the interface.
It's not the same as the above.
I'm going to measure thermal expansion.
If you're interested, we can discuss it next.
Can I ask a question?
Yes.
Can you go back to the aluminum diagram?
The temperature next to you is almost normal.
Can you make it a little warmer?
Can you make it very low?
You mean low temperature?
Low enough that it doesn't overheat.
It's less than 1K.
I think it should be physically possible.
Because the way it gets the temperature is
Simply put, if you look at the peak shift of Plasmon Peak,
You can see how much the electronic density has changed.
If you get low temperature,
You may also know how low it is.
But in the electronic microscope,
It's easier to heat than to get low temperature.
So most people do thermal experiments.
Very few people do low temperature experiments.
Can I say something?
Yes.
Basically, I don't think you should say this in this picture.
Because I've talked to the author about this.
This sample itself is a silicon nitride membrane.
To carve out these patterns.
So when you're doing this experiment,
There's a big problem.
You're heating it up at the same time.
What you're looking at now is the shift of EOS.
It's actually bound to your silicon nitride substrate.
That is, you're not a freestanding aluminum wire.
So it's hard to say how big it is.
Back to the question just now.
If you put this sample in a liquid nitrogen holder,
You can look at it after it's cooled down.
So you can also put it in a heating holder.
You can also heat it up.
So if you want to know the temperature range,
It's possible.
Yes.
Thank you.
I don't know much about this sample.
Because he's been here before.
So he was very polite.
That's what his structure is like.
Because all of our papers.
Science papers here.
We all thought he was a freestanding aluminum wire.
But what he said was that there was supporting underneath.
So you go and look at the slice in front of you.
The slice in front of you.
Why is the temperature change so big?
That's why it shifts so little.
You're not a freestanding sample.
You don't know how reliable this knife is.
And your error is 0.06 electron volt.
Your resolution is only 0.03.
Then you have two pixels.
I think this experiment is actually quite risky.
Because you don't know where the error comes from.
So basically, we think it's more reliable than three pixels.
I see.
Because this paper actually has a lot of citations.
There are a lot of people who do something later.
Or look at some things.
Because if you're a freestanding sample.
It makes a lot of sense if you measure it.
But you're supporting.
Like a sandwich.
If the heat expansion coefficient below is very poor.
It's very different from the temperature above.
Then you might have a similar effect.
Then you can't measure what the real thing should be like.
I see.
After we heard the speech that day.
Why do you have to wrap that layer underneath?
But I didn't really measure the temperature myself.
In my case, I always let the temperature be very warm.
If it's in this situation.
Then what I measured is.
The change in electron density comes from heat expansion.
Of course, this is also a new paper recently.
Then I'm also trying to see if I can.
I'm actually not very clear right now.
You are now.
You slice like this.
Sorry, until the next experiment.
You slice this.
Because of your.
You are because the temperature is different.
Then look at the energy of PLASMA is different.
You are now.
I let everything be PLASMA.
Everything.
This sample itself.
The temperature has become the same.
I went to see the interface.
With Bulk.
His.
The change in heat expansion.
But the two pictures below you.
Is there a temperature change?
This is the temperature here.
This is after you fix a temperature.
After reading it, change it to the next temperature.
Yes, this is a very tiring experiment.
But we've been trying it lately.
Because the first paper to do heat expansion.
Is in the secondary material.
Then we did it ourselves.
A ceramic traditional material.
Try it out.
Can they be used in traditional materials?
Above.
I can't tell you now.
Is it good or bad?
But I can tell you.
I really have two.
I understand.
I just said you were processing this data.
Have you ever done the so-called.
How to say.
Uh.
Consider your thickness.
Because thickness.
You speak very well.
Because.
Because in fact.
When you do this.
You can go to one by the way.
Anyway, the area you are in now.
You can do the thickness.
Maybe you are now.
After fitting.
After decoupling.
You can do the analysis later.
Then a point is.
I am in the thick area.
The heat expansion of the two areas is different.
I mean.
It doesn't matter if you are thick.
Because as long as you take a full score.
You can do decoupling.
After decoupling.
In fact, you are using decoupling data.
To do these.
Plasma energy fitting.
Maybe what you see.
It may be the same as now.
It should be said that all the data.
I have done it.
It's the backlight.
But my own data.
In the thick area and the thin area.
This.
The change in the heat expansion factor.
In fact, more should be related to quantum.
It's the same in the past.
Not necessarily.
If you are thin today.
The area is less than 40 nanometers.
The data you make now.
I don't know how thick it is.
But.
For you to do this experiment.
I would prefer to say.
You are probably 40 to 80 nanometers.
The thickness is the most perfect.
Because below 40 nanometers.
You will be more serious.
So all of you.
You think the peak of Bulk Plasma.
Will shift to low energy.
When you have high energy.
You are after multiple scattering.
You may.
You may have to do a lot of processing.
With your average thickness.
For example, 40 to 80 nanometers.
Maybe a little worse.
But not so much worse.
So I think you can consider.
You are now in these two areas.
What you marked.
Is the thickness.
In fact, you can calculate.
What is the thickness?
How many lambda?
I can tell you.
This is about 80 nanometers.
This is about 20 nanometers.
Because you have too many surface effects.
So the energy you are doing now.
You have to consider the surface plasma.
Not your own Bulk.
If you have a vacuum area.
You just sweep past like this.
You can know your whole.
You want to identify.
Is the location of the Bulk Plasma shifted?
Then you know.
Your thinnest place.
The location of the energy you originally expected.
There is a deviation.
We can discuss this later.
Thank you very much for your comment.
I really don't know.
What you said above.
I don't really know.
What you just said.
Basically,
Valence.
I want to talk about this.
Finally, I want to add.
There is a new technology called Vibrational Yields.
That is also.
It was probably released in 2014.
It is a piece.
Its paper is.
Look at the optical phonon of boron nitride.
We ourselves.
In 2014.
Most of the time.
Look at the CH vibration of ionic liquid.
At that time, many people felt.
This is a mess.
But so.
We basically published it at the same time.
Then you can be sure.
The optical phonon of boron nitride.
You can see the phonon and the vibration.
A more popular method now.
It actually uses a model called.
You don't put the disease.
On top of your sample.
But outside the sample.
This mechanism.
It interprets.
It's all double scattering.
But they mean.
Your double scattering.
It's a signal.
The middle one.
It's more detailed.
Some people say it's virtual photon.
But this part.
I really don't understand.
What are they talking about?
But simply put.
You put the electron outside the sample.
In a specific position.
You can actually detect.
Your vibrational signal.
Through this matter.
In fact, since 2015.
Many people have been using this method.
To study some.
This should be biological.
Materials.
It can be.
Don't destroy your sample.
Detect outside.
Some of your material.
Vibrational mode.
If you are interested.
You can also look at some papers.
Or do this experiment.
In 2019.
I think it's more.
It may be a bit controversial.
Quite.
What people know is.
Carbon-12 and carbon-13.
That is, through EOS.
What I just said.
Since you can see.
If the molecules vibrate.
I believe.
Carbon-12 and oxygen bound.
Carbon-13 and oxygen bound.
Their vibrational mode.
In fact, it should be a bit different.
That's what Oak Ridge does.
You have carbon-12 particles.
To do EOS.
To distinguish these two.
Basically, they are using profile fitting.
Because now.
The resolution at this time in 2019.
Neon's system is about.
5 mV.
So they can distinguish.
Carbon-13 and carbon-12.
If you are interested.
Oak Ridge has been doing this experiment.
I am.
I am actually.
Take it to study my glass.
Because in my glass.
There are two-handed oxygen and three-handed oxygen.
Two-handed oxygen and three-handed oxygen.
General XAS.
Or other.
In fact, it is difficult to see the difference.
My glass also has.
Silicon Ridge and Aluminum Ridge.
I can clearly know.
What kind of structure I see.
So I really go to study.
What is the difference.
If you do profile fitting.
You will probably find it.
About 10 mV.
Then you can do some more analysis.
Tell you.
In the end, what you see.
Is it really from this oxygen coordination?
Change.
Or something from the hardware.
This is my own recent.
On Vibrational EOS.
Some research results.
If it is possible.
More people will be interested.
In fact.
Is this kind of Momentum Resolve.
Vibrational EOS.
In 2019.
Basically, some people started to study.
Since I can see the rope.
Then I also want to study.
This kind of phonon dispersion.
Is that you change the Q-vector.
You put your beam.
Like other.
Not directly on your.
Spectrometer.
If you give it a Q-vector.
Momentum transfer.
You can see.
This kind of phonon dispersion.
This picture is made in Japan.
To get this kind of experiment.
Suenaga.
They said they did it.
More than 60 hours.
But this year.
In 2020.
Two months ago.
Microsociety.
He studied.
Is that you are.
On the original spectrometer.
Add a layer.
You will get a lot at the same time.
Different Q-point.
EOS.
In 2019.
You have to do.
60 hours of such an experiment.
You use Neon's instrument.
With the latest method.
Can be done in 10 minutes.
If you are.
This kind of nanometer.
If you are interested.
You can check it out.
In the end.
It will become.
Electromagnetists.
Want to do atomic wave solution.
In 2020.
Recently.
He also did something like this.
Silicon on graphene.
He went to see.
His surrounding atoms.
Spectra of each atom.
Every one.
Of course it is a very difficult experiment.
But they are also using.
Very high Q-vector.
To see this kind of spectra.
So you can make sure.
Detected signals.
All come from a single atom.
I'm not sure.
How simple is this experiment.
How complicated.
Or where is its accuracy.
But this is the current field.
The latest research results.
If you are interested.
In the end.
The information you really want to bring home.
In fact.
Electromagnetism is not just a magnifying glass.
Although many people think so.
Modern STEM fields.
Is a very powerful tool.
If you want to do.
The experiments I just mentioned.
You can choose some open facilities.
Like Oak Ridge.
Molecular foundry.
Berkeley.
ERC in Germany.
STEM in the UK.
Nanotechnology platform in Japan.
You can apply for some.
You can write your proposal.
To apply for time.
Then do such an experiment.
The above is probably.
Today's content.
If I am also in.
I want to do more glass recently.
Then there are some.
Is the MOF glass.
Or the glass on the secondary material.
If there is such a similar sample.
Thank you.
Thank you for the speech.
Very complete.
Let's applaud first.
Thank you for his speech.
Then.
Let's go straight to the question.
Because the time seems to have passed.
Sorry.
It doesn't matter.
To add.
This is a thing called paradigm.
Also throw proposal.
Then we can do the experiment for you.
Cornell.
You mean.
You can also do this.
Yes.
Thank you.
If.
Finally, to add.
If you are very interested in 4D STEM.
Like I just said.
Or Berkeley.
Then if you are.
EOS.
If you are very interested.
Ocarina and Super STEM.
At present.
Basically the best in the world.
Everyone can.
Take it as a priority.
If everyone has no questions.
I actually have a question.
Sorry, you ask first.
OK.
This EOS.
Can you measure acetone?
Because the general RPEC.
The reason is because it can only measure single particles.
But EOS looks like.
Should be able to measure.
Because it looks like.
And it should be.
Can also measure.
Then.
I have seen someone.
Measure.
If it is vibrational.
Someone is measuring.
Then.
This paper.
It actually mentions a little.
Acetone effect.
But I'm not sure.
Does it have anything to do with what you said?
Because I am in this field.
I know nothing about acetone.
But there is also a strange question here.
Why does it have a selection rule?
I just can't figure it out.
Electron loss.
Is there any special selection rule?
You can think of it as.
Its mechanism.
General EOS.
It is still dipole scattering.
It is basically.
There is no resonant.
So it follows the selection rule.
That is Fermi golden rule.
If it is Fermi.
If it is simply Fermi golden rule.
You mean.
Is it like the Fermi golden rule of light and snow?
Yes.
It is.
Fermi golden rule of light and snow.
Then.
That is.
According to your.
Angle.
It is the focus angle.
And the absorption angle is different.
You will see your.
EOS signal will be different.
But.
If it is light and snow.
It should be optical phonon.
It can be absorbed.
Wait a minute.
I confirm.
Optical phonon is possible.
It is IR active.
Yes.
But.
I am looking at the paper.
What I see now.
The situation is.
The first.
You.
That is.
Its selection rule.
It is still more like IR.
We all say it is.
IR optical phonon under the magnitude of nanometer.
But if you put your Q vector.
Move to a very high Q.
Then greater than your.
The first non-dimensional area.
At present.
Everyone's statement is that you are like this.
You can see some.
The selection rule that you could not see.
Yes.
But.
The physical content should be.
The current formula is already there.
But I have to go.
Try to understand the formula.
Yes.
Can I interrupt?
You see this picture.
You think of it as the simplest.
If you put that to L.
It is called Gamma as a starting point.
Gamma to N.
In the crystal structure.
Facing the machine.
You have a different one.
Can run out.
This will form you.
Your so-called selection rule.
Come out.
Do you understand what I mean?
So this picture.
I saw this picture.
The first impression is that it is very strange.
All gray lines are theoretical calculations.
All red lines are experimental data.
Theoretical calculation.
Gamma to N.
Is symmetrical.
But it is not symmetrical in practice.
Oh, OK.
So this is when I saw this picture.
The first thing I feel is.
The area of Plasma.
Is symmetrical.
But this one.
Is not symmetrical.
I do not know at the moment.
What special things happen.
The first one.
This picture.
As far as I know.
Is done for more than 60 hours.
Experimental error.
Must be considered.
I mean.
In fact, we are doing.
Momentum Resolution.
Gamma to N.
This picture is very simple.
It should be symmetrical.
Phonon is difficult to do.
This energy is very low.
So it takes a long time to collect.
But.
I think no matter how long you are.
You will calculate.
The position of the real loss peak.
It must be.
From one point to another.
Slowly collect the data.
Piled up.
This is what I feel.
I can not understand from the beginning.
This picture is supposed to be.
textbook.
Or something else.
This energy should be symmetrical.
But your experiment is not symmetrical.
That's what I do not understand.
I can ask.
Goodman is.
Please say.
Your name and organization.
Which one is it?
My last name is Liu.
Liu Bei Liu.
Thought is humble.
Where are you now?
I am in the United States.
Maryland University.
Also specializing in EOS.
I am in Taiwan.
EOS.
I'm just a service here.
Taiwan is EOS.
Is a famous teacher.
I used to be in that group.
I understand.
What you just said.
In 1970.
You just mentioned.
David Muller.
David Muller is my teacher.
John Sircus.
I know.
The first.
I was in Taiwan University.
Postal boss.
He is the first doctor.
So you hear now.
The most famous should be David Muller.
David Muller is a countdown.
Before the lab shut down.
Doctor.
But David Muller.
He did not do EOS recently.
You have one in front.
Silicone dumbbell.
That's called Fee Bateson.
I know.
The second doctor.
That's it.
You are familiar with Fee Bateson.
Because Fee Bateson used to do.
Q-dependent EOS.
But not vibration.
Yes.
I am.
Because our group does not have a device.
I can only use.
I can't.
Do such a thing.
This is actually.
Because Fonon has been doing it for a long time.
So this is not expected.
Because if you say Plasma.
About five seconds to solve.
You mean like.
You just this picture.
Your last picture.
This is not.
It is scanned with Scanning TM.
So.
Your whole spectrum.
What are you talking about?
How long do you scan the spectrum image?
How long will it end?
It just needs to do some.
This.
Processing.
But before.
In the John Sialkas group.
What they do is Q-dependent EOS.
This one came out.
No need to do.
At most because it used to be a photo.
So at most just do.
Data to identify.
But it's just a picture.
It's the picture you see now.
It is a.
It used to be a photo.
But because there is no.
How to say.
After you take a picture.
You have to put the skill bar on it.
Calculate energy.
So the role of Fee Patterson is.
The digital computer.
To put the coordinates.
The number of coordinates.
Then my teacher is.
My teacher is a watch.
He is a computer watch.
So it is.
But I think the future.
Momentum Resolve.
This year.
After he used a slide.
I think that way.
Copy the most primitive way.
He put a slide on it.
You can do it.
You can get it in 10 minutes.
You can get it in a minute.
His slide is.
The earliest David Muller.
The device they use.
That's right.
You just change your EOS.
Yes.
But this is.
You can do it on EOS.
But we can't do it ourselves.
You can change it on EOS.
Or you.
In your.
You usually have a screen now.
You can change it on your screen.
Anyway, you just use a slide.
That's it.
It's not hard.
We used to change it.
If you want to cooperate.
I think it's not difficult in Asia.
It's harder in America.
Because you have to call the manufacturers.
That's right.
It's hard for us.
So you guys.
The whole experience of the University of Tokyo.
A lot of.
That's what the lab does.
Is that what it means?
About a dozen, at the moment.
More than 10 is open to the public.
That is the nanotechnology platform I mentioned at the end.
The nanotechnology platform I mentioned at the end.
But there's a part of the teahouse.
I just said a lot.
a lot of developers.
A lot of developers.
It's their lab.
So I want to ask you.
You just mentioned 4D.
Especially the part of the power plant.
You still have to use it now.
What I know is.
There is no commercial software.
Let's just do it.
You still have to have some of your own.
Now.
This kind of DPC.
No, no, no.
You're the one on the right.
You're the one on the left.
I'm on the right.
You're on the right.
This is what we do.
They're doing this.
So they write the code themselves.
But now.
I'm going to this year.
If you go to SEMO Fisher Japan in July.
The latest SEMO Fisher.
You can do DPC.
Because I thought.
We still have to use Python.
If you look at it now.
You can think of it.
The one I went to see with the teacher.
It's not even Titan's DPC.
Python code.
There are a lot of commercial software.
Because of our biggest gold.
And there's a bear.
He has been addicted recently.
Because it's the first time he developed it.
But I.
The thing that's below you.
The next one I remember one day.
Just this one.
The first page.
This thing.
No, it's on the next page.
Sorry.
So that's it.
Right.
This thing was first
made by a Japanese
named Nims.
A Japanese named Nims made it.
Ah, Nims.
I go there often.
What's it called? Kimoto.
Koji Kimoto.
And.
I thought it was commercialized.
But in fact, they said they didn't.
They only
finished the 4D
process.
But later,
at that time,
in 2011,
they did it manually.
But now
you don't see such a good result.
Yes.
Most of the 4D
that are made now are made in Europe and America.
I can assure you that
there are very few people
who do this in Japan at this stage.
Very few.
But I know Kimoto was the first one to do it.
I know Kimoto was the first one to do it.
I will go to Kimoto's factory
to do the experiment next week.
Because this thing.
Sorry.
We are talking too professionally.
To put it simply,
when every muscle
has an order
and a specific direction,
in Kimoto's theory,
I know this muscle,
I know its muscle structure.
In terms of muscle structure,
you have the so-called symmetry.
The most important thing about Kimoto
is that he talked about
the symmetry of the Atomic Scale,
not the
symmetry of a large muscle.
He used the
rightmost picture
called the most typical
Pythagorean Theorem.
He can make
the so-called
4D
figure of the
Pythagorean Theorem.
After the 4D figure
comes out,
based on the
inner ring and outer ring,
you can know the symmetry
of the muscle structure.
More importantly,
in addition to proving this,
Kimoto also talked about
why in electromagnetic microscope,
especially in scanning TM,
the loss of the atomic scale is larger,
the loss of the atomic state is second,
and the loss of the oxygen is the last.
In his diffraction pattern,
he told you
why the image I see now
has such a big intensity change
when I circle
it.
So in fact,
I read that paper for a long time,
and I found that
I thought there was a commercial software
that could do the
post-processing,
but there was no
post-processing after
the commercial software
did the 4D.
I think the biggest problem
now is that,
as you just said,
Kimoto himself wrote.
Yes, because the first time I heard this
was also in UC Irvine.
They have a group
doing this.
Then when they talked about it,
I realized that
in the past,
they might have
read Kimoto's paper
as reading,
but they didn't mention it,
because the concept was the same.
It used to be called Scanning CBET.
No, the word Kimoto used
was more fancy,
called Atomic Scale Symmetry.
Oh, I see.
Yes, it's Atomic Scale Symmetry.
Because if you really do
the calculation of CBET,
the CBET pattern
made by these three elements
is really different.
We seem to be talking too professionally.
Can I ask you a question?
Sure.
Sorry.
Do you have any questions?
If you have any questions
about CBET,
you can ask.
Hello.
Can you hear me?
Yes, I can.
I want to add
that UC Irvine
also has
user facilities
for training
and samples.
They also have staff
to do experiments.
Our group often
goes to UC Irvine to do TEM.
I have a question about
when we were doing
some low-melt point
metal TEM,
we were doing
cryo TEM,
but when we were
using cryo holder,
we couldn't get
a very good resolution
when we were doing
stem HEDF
mapping.
I want to know
if there are
other ways
to do
low-melting materials
to get
a better
Z-contrast
or other
resolutions.
Thank you for your question.
My understanding is
that you can't get
a very good resolution
when you are doing cryo
because your liquid nitrogen
actually flows.
You have
touched liquid nitrogen
or liquid nitrogen gas,
and you know
that it actually flows.
I think this is
a big reason
why you can't get
a stable Z-contrast.
You just mentioned
if there are
other ways to
change this or get
a better resolution.
I haven't done
anything like this,
but what I want to mention
is that
for example,
when you look at
high-resolution images,
you can't get
a very good image
because your strength
is too weak.
David Miller Group
used a method
called TychoGraphy
in 2018,
which is 4D stem.
They used this method
to get a more blurry
graphic image
with higher resolution
and higher resolution.
That paper is also
a very famous paper
by Nature.
If you have any
information about
David Miller Group,
you can add it.
But as far as I know,
it is very suitable for
people who can't get
a high resolution image.
This 4D stem can help you.
I think that's it.
I guess
Cryo's problem is that
your sample stage
moves too fast,
so you can't get a good image.
There are several ways
about this.
One way is to scan very fast
and scan a lot of pages.
Then you fold it up
in a post-processing way
to get a good image.
This method was developed
by Lena Kakoudis
Cryo Stem.
We can try it.
Thank you.
I have a question.
Before I talk about this question,
I have a small comment.
Because I am
the speaker today,
Project Hera.
We are staff.
I strongly recommend
you to keep in touch.
If you can keep in touch
and help each other,
it is the biggest reward for us.
You feel the same, right?
Yes.
This is a small comment.
I suggest you
to keep in touch.
If you think Project Hera
is helpful to you,
you can recommend it to others.
My question is this.
This is a crazy idea.
If I have a sample today,
what if I put it down
for five years?
Keep taking pictures.
What is the resolution
you want to achieve?
A sample
can be placed
in the middle of your screen.
Actually,
I want to measure
the distance between
all the atoms.
But I am waiting
for something to happen.
Why do I want to monitor?
Because what I expect
is not static.
The distribution of the atom
is like this,
but suddenly it moves.
Why did I
take a picture of you
for a long time?
Because I think
what I expect
is the time scale
from 10s to 100s microseconds.
So if you take a picture
for two seconds,
you will miss it easily.
I just said
taking a picture for two seconds
means a lot of pixels.
One pixel is
about 20 microseconds,
which I often use.
But maybe
I still can't catch
what you want.
Another big problem
is that I'm not sure
how much electron radiation
your sample can withstand.
Because this is
a key problem
for TEM.
If your sample can withstand
infinite electron radiation,
of course you can do
similar experiments.
But if your sample can only withstand
one minute,
you will have damage,
or you have some carbon damage,
or you can even
pierce your sample.
Then you won't be able to do such experiments.
I think
I will think
from this perspective.
Actually,
this is what I think.
Radiation damage.
We are used to discussing
what is an electron,
one, two, three.
We rarely discuss
what is an electron.
But basically,
this is what happens in electrons.
Yes.
Actually, there is such a lab.
In Sandia National Lab,
they have connected
a particle beam
to hit your sample,
to look at your
radiation damage.
There is such a thing.
Time resolution can barely reach millisecond.
There are
faster detectors,
about 400 frames per second,
or 2000 frames per second.
It can barely reach
millisecond.
Okay, let me ask.
We are actually doing
carbon-based
spectroscopy detector
in Sandia.
Okay, thank you.
They mainly look at
radiation.
I can comment on
the microscope in Sandia.
If they use
photoelectron,
they can make the electron pulse to nanosecond.
So if your sample
is beautiful enough,
although it does not show
a sample like a sample,
but if it sounds
like a millisecond,
for example,
if you want to do it in a shorter time,
you can do it.
I want to ask a question.
You just mentioned
that it can measure electric field
and magnetic field.
How good is the sensitivity?
I can tell you that
they all say
atomic resolution,
but I'm not sure
how good it is.
I don't know if you've heard of
something called
SCAMEL.
Some people use
such a device to measure
SCAMEL.
If you want to go to
atomic resolution,
that is,
for example,
I think
this TEM
considers
whether the magnetic field
penetrates your sample.
This is a key question.
If you use
something without any magnetic field penetration,
you can really determine
if your magnetic field
really comes from a very local area.
But if you always have
a general TEM,
that is, there is a magnetic field
that penetrates your sample,
I'm not sure
how good your resolution is.
Sorry, my question is
that you may have misunderstood my question.
My question is not about
how good the spatial resolution is.
My question is,
for example,
what is the magnetic field
or magnetic field
that can be measured
at a micrometer level?
I'm sorry,
I don't know how much this number is.
Because what we currently see
is that its principle
is to look at your electron,
at least the principle of DPC
is to see how much your electron beam
deviates.
You can know its direction
and its strength
by doing this.
You get something like this,
for example,
a map of the direction
from the center.
To be honest,
I'm not sure
how strong it is.
OK, I can go back and look at these questions.
Thank you.
OK,
if there are no other questions,
I will end the recording
here.