Okay, thank you all for being able to participate in our project today.
Tara's online speech.
Then we are very honored today to invite Dr. Shihai Long to ask us a question about lower back pain.
OK, please allow me to briefly introduce some of Dr. Shihai Long's experience.
He has a lot of experience, so I might just read it slowly.
OK, I hope everyone can understand.
His experience is that he used to be an assistant at Taiwan University's Motion Science Research Lab.
He was also a physical therapist in the Taiwan University's Sports and Fitness Team,
a physical therapist in the Taiwan University Women's Volleyball Team,
a physical therapist in the Taiwan University Medical School,
and a physical therapist in the Hsinchu Hospital.
In the end, he was also an assistant professor at the University of South Carolina's Motion Science and Physical Therapy Department.
His degree is from the University of South Carolina's Motion Science and Physical Therapy Doctorate.
He is about to participate in his graduation ceremony in August this year.
Today, it is a great honor for Dr. Shihai Long to introduce to us the potential impacts of lower back pain on the body.
How do we identify the problems that many middle-aged people face?
Dr. Shihai Long's topic today is the footprint of pain,
the investigating persistence of the outer trunk control in recurrent low back pain.
OK, now let's have Dr. Shihai Long give us a speech.
Thank you.
OK.
The floor is yours.
Hello?
OK.
OK, thank you for the introduction.
The topic we're going to talk about today is actually my paper research.
But I will try my best, because I know that the audience may not be in the same field,
so I will try to explain it in more detail.
I will also omit some of the more detailed parts, so if you have any questions, you can ask me later.
My paper research focuses on the recurrence of lower back pain.
Does it have anything to do with the way we change our posture after the pain occurs?
First of all, lower back pain is commonly referred to as back pain.
I'm sure many of you have had this experience.
In fact, it is a very common problem in modern life.
About 80% of people have experienced lower back pain at least once in their lives.
The main problem is that most of the lower back pain
can't be explained in terms of image or structural deformation.
So it's more difficult to diagnose and treat.
Research has shown that about 56% of people experience lower back pain once,
and the pain recurs within a year.
This is a long-term problem,
because the pain is constantly going up and down in the lower back.
So it's a long-term problem.
Now, in medical or physical therapy,
we can help people with lower back pain.
However, we haven't done a good job of preventing the recurrence of lower back pain.
The main reason is that we can't find the cause of the recurrence of lower back pain.
So if we can find the cause of the recurrence of lower back pain,
we can find a way to treat it.
We've found that people who have had lower back pain before
may have more episodes in the future.
This doesn't give us any information.
However, we have developed a set of hypotheses.
People who have had lower back pain before may have had episodes in the past,
so they may have changed their behavior.
This behavior may protect them from lower back pain in a short period of time,
or avoid the pain.
But will it have some negative effects in the long run?
Will it affect their symptoms?
Will it cause recurrent symptoms?
So my research is mainly about
treating people with lower back pain,
but first, when they have pain,
we measure their behavior.
When they don't have pain,
we bring them into the lab and do the same test again.
In this way, we can see
if there are behaviors that are different from those of healthy people without lower back pain.
Does this behavior continue to exist even when they don't have pain?
So I'm going to talk about two directions today.
There are two directions for the behavior model.
The first is the sectional control part.
The second is the attention part.
I'm going to explain why these two are important issues for patients with lower back pain.
The first is the sectional control.
There are two groups of people.
The first group is people with lower back pain.
Their sectional control is relatively tight.
What is tight?
The muscles in their body continue to work hard.
In addition to working hard,
there may be some inefficient ways to work hard.
The muscles in the opposite direction may also exert force together.
In this case, it is more inefficient.
This may also lead to the separation of joints.
This may lead to the separation of joints.
Since there is
only one motion in the chewing motion,
there is less tension between the joints.
In other words, the motion may bring constrictions.
In other words, the joint will not move in the same way as before.
In other words, if we have limited attention at a certain time,
we may not be able to perform other tasks.
We may not be able to perform other tasks.