Ok, let's start.
Ok, first I need to introduce myself.
Please introduce yourself, thank you.
Ok, I have prepared a few videos.
I will use them to introduce myself.
Today, I will talk about the simple introduction of metal solvents.
My name is Zeyu Lin, and I am a post-doctoral researcher in Japan.
First, I will give a brief self-introduction.
As I mentioned, I am a post-doctoral researcher in Japan.
My department is the National Research and Development Department of the Institute of Materials and Materials Research.
My main job here is...
Sorry, let me use the laser pointer.
My main job here is to connect the material's microstructure with its mechanical properties,
as well as its related performance characteristics.
At present, I am working on the development of high-strength and high-durability ferrous alloys,
as well as the microstructure of permanent magnets,
as well as the development of some raw materials.
Today, I would like to introduce my post-doctoral research...
No, I mean my work accumulated during my post-doctoral studies,
and my post-doctoral research in February this year,
which is about four years of work.
The field of research is mainly the solid-state integration of copper,
which is similar in nature, as well as liquid metal.
The integration technology used is a technology called ultrasonic integration.
Its principle is to use high-pressure and high frequency vibration to achieve the deformation of the material to form the node.
It can be used in steel, high-strength steel, or aluminum alloy, etc.
It can be used in...
The main scene that can be considered is that the composite structure of multi-materials,
such as the structure of the car body,
can achieve the goal characteristics of lightweighting and high strength.
Sorry, I just made a mistake.
I graduated from Tokyo University of Japan in 2019,
and majored in material engineering.
My other major is the Department of Chemical Engineering at Tsinghua University of China,
and the Department of Chemical Engineering at Tsinghua University of China.
That's all for the main self-introduction.
Next, I'm going to start introducing today's main speech topic,
which is mainly about the integration of solid-state and liquid metal materials that are similar in nature,
and then use ultrasonic integration to observe the strength of its interface.
First, I will give a simple background introduction.
In the engineering background,
listeners may be more familiar with the fact that
steel is a very solid base.
It is one of the basic and indispensable materials.
The picture on the left shows that
there are about 15% to 20% of steel in the world every year.
Because there are a lot of steel applications,
including architecture, general people, military facilities, transportation, etc.
It accounts for about 15% to 20% of transportation.
It is mainly applied to the construction of car parts and the structure of the car body.
There are a lot of types of steel used,
including soft steel, medium-strength, high-strength, and ultra-high-strength steel.
At present, the development field of materials is mainly focused on
how to improve its extensibility and high-strength, etc.
The picture on the lower left is called DynamoCurve,
which is a curve distribution like a banana.
Why is there such a distribution?
It is mainly derived from the fact that the strength of the material increases,
but the extensibility does not decrease.
Based on the background of traditional physics,
such strength and extensibility are indispensable.
However, many scientists are using various methods
to try to get out of this field.
The current research situation is to try to achieve the high strength and high extensibility of both, etc.
Why do we need such a high-strength steel development?
It is mainly used when the car body is hit by a heavy object.
High-strength steel can often provide stronger support
to avoid fatal damage to passengers.
In order to improve safety,
the current material development is mainly focused on high-strength and high extensibility, etc.
What kind of steel is used?
Different strengths of steel are used in different areas of the car body structure.
This is a simple introduction.
You can clearly see that
if the car is hit by a heavy object,
the stress and gravity come from the front and back, etc.
At this time, you need a high-strength structural material
to support the entire car body.
The current high-strength steel developed by traditional physics
has reached 780, 980, 1180, etc.
This represents the strength of steel,
which is about 550 MPa.
The current mainstream high-strength steel is
concentrated in the front and back of 1000 MPa.
This is the current situation in which the structural material is used.
On the other hand,
if we don't use steel,
and we use a high-strength material,
it will not be able to support the entire car body.
On the other hand,
if we don't use steel,
and we use a high-strength material,
such as aluminum, copper, and carbon fiber, etc.
If we use this material,
it can be made very lightweight
and has sufficient safety.
However, the price is also very high.
As you can see here,
for a good car like Audi R8,
the recommended price in 2020 is about $70,000.
This price is hard to meet for ordinary people.
So we mainly use traditional steel
and aluminum and carbon fiber.
In this respect,
you have to make a choice
in terms of cost and mechanical quality.
The name of the car body structure we often use in our industry
is a multi-material structure.
Multi-Material Structure
As you can see here,
in addition to steel,
it also has a lot of external body parts,
such as the door, engine cover, etc.
In order to make it lightweight,
we usually use aluminum alloy.
The main maintenance material is aluminum alloy.
In this respect,
when the car body is assembled,
we mainly use
high-strength steel
and aluminum alloy.
In this respect,
they need to be fixed and processed
to form a complete structure.
It is conceivable that
some processes need to be processed
to combine them together.
In recent years,
in addition to the emission of environmental regulations,
the demand for lightweighting is increasing.
On the right side of the slide,
there is a picture of
the materials used in the field of cars
in 2030,
including aluminum and high-strength steel.
HSF stands for High Strength Steel.
The ratio of these two materials
will increase from 29% to 57%.
In the near future,
in order to establish high strength
and lightweighting,
we will use more aluminum
and more high-strength steel.
Therefore, how to combine
iron and lightweighting alloy
in the manufacturing process
is quite important.
Now we will introduce
the traditional way
of combining materials
and manufacturing technology,
i.e. welding.
Traditionally,
we define welding
as a process
in which two separate materials
are heated
to a high temperature
and then combined
to produce
sufficient quality
welding.
In this process,
the defects
will gradually disappear.
At such a high temperature,
along with the change
in the structure
of the fibers
and the growth
of the center,
heat is also affected,
and so on.
In this regard,
the material itself
is mechanically affected
by the change
in the structure
of the fibers.
After the welding point
is formed,
all the fibers
around it
will undergo
huge changes.
Such changes
are sometimes not
completely positive.
How to prevent
low-performance
welding?
The first point
is to use
a high temperature
to melt steel
and aluminum.
There will be several problems.
The first is that
aluminum and steel
have very different melting points.
The melting point of aluminum
is about 600 degrees,
while that of steel
is about 1400 to 1500 degrees.
At high temperature,
it will generate
a huge
for aluminum,
at such a high temperature,
it will generate a huge
firepower,
and it will generate a lot of expansion.
Expansion will form
various compounds
between steel and aluminum
in the interface.
This compound
has a very poor mechanical performance.
Why?
Because the problem it encounters
is very brittle,
and it is very impenetrable.
After a little impact,
it will crack like ceramic
or glass.
That is to say,
the function of the melting point itself
will fail.
At the same time,
there will be cracks
in the interface
due to high temperature
.
This is quite disadvantageous
to mechanical manufacturing.
That is to say,
at high temperature,
it is quite disadvantageous
to combine steel and aluminum
with general combination technology.
In other words,
what we may consider next
is how to
reduce the temperature of the combination.
That is to say,
the combination technology at low temperature
can prevent
such a problem
to a certain extent.
That is to say,
we will focus on
how to combine steel and aluminum.
That is, we want to combine
at the melting point of steel and aluminum,
which is about 660 degrees.
Combining at this temperature
is called solidification.
That is to say, there is no
fusion between the two.
Next,
I will introduce
solidification.
As I mentioned earlier,
it can combine
two components
and
there will be no fusion
during the process.
Its heating is also
lower than the melting point of any material.
What we need
is to introduce more
sufficient deformation
in the material interface.
At sufficient temperature,
the interface will expand.
After the expansion,
the defects will gradually disappear.
That is to say,
the effect of combining.
Here, our main
design concept is
that the main concept of solidification
is how to make
the defects on the interface disappear,
including holes and
cavities, etc.
At the same time,
most materials
usually have a layer of
pollutants on the surface,
such as carbon
and oxygen,
and other compounds.
At the same time,
there will be a certain
degree of oxidation film
on the surface.
You may have heard
that aluminum
is very easy to oxidize.
It forms a layer
of very self-destructive oxidation film
on the surface.
This oxidation film
is self-destructive enough
to protect the material inside
from further oxidation and deformation.
This kind of oxidation film
is quite beneficial in the
combination.
Traditionally, we still have to
achieve the contact between the
pure atom and the atom
in solidification.
That is to say,
the contact between the
pure atom and the atom
or the metal atom
is formed.
On the other hand,
we can say that
we have introduced
enough deformation
at high temperature
to make it like clay
to stir
and form a
interlocking interface structure.
OK
Here,
I will
make a brief introduction
to solid-state integration.
In traditional
solid-state integration,
the first method is called expansion integration.
The main principle is to use
high pressure and high temperature
to apply on two objects
that need to be combined.
With such high temperature and high pressure
condition, it can form
interlocking structure in enough time.
Such
integration method can be applied
on metal or ceramic
or metal
or even carbon fiber.
But the problem is that
its integration time is quite long and
requires a higher integration temperature.
At the same time,
assuming that the interface is over
high temperature and over a long time,
it will form an
overly complex structure,
including a metal-based object,
which is what we mentioned earlier,
forming a layer
like a ceramic,
a non-extensible middle layer.
This middle layer
has a very weak mechanical nature,
and is not conducive to the overall integration strength.
On the other hand,
the other
is friction-mixing integration.
Its principle is
to use a high-speed
rotating
welding head.
The surface friction
forms a high temperature.
After the high temperature, the material
gradually softens,
but it is not yet at the melting point.
So it will be like
clay.
After it softens,
the welding head can be pressed down
and start to move.
Then move along
the seam between the two.
Let the interface
gradually pass through
the welding head.
But on the other hand,
this material
can be used in all kinds of
aluminum alloy, aluminum-ferrous alloy,
etc. Its application range is quite wide.
For example,
let's take the
Japanese alloy as an example.
It mainly uses
this kind of
alloying technology
for the
combination of
materials.
On the other hand,
its shortcomings are
that it takes a long time to
combine, and
after it is combined,
there will be some
differences in the interface.
At the same time,
on the other hand,
the time it takes to combine
also takes a long time to
combine.
As a result,
based on
this background,
based on this background,
we use another
type of alloying technology.
This is called ultrasonic welding,
which is ultrasonic welding.
The principle of ultrasonic welding
may be mentioned earlier.
It is a certain degree of pressure
on the two overlapping
blades,
which is about
15,000 to 24,000
degrees,
and then the
interface is
friction-heated.
In this case,
the interface will
develop a
deformity
that will
form a
fiber structure
that causes
the surface
interface to
be damaged.
Therefore,
it is not
conducive to
the production of
metal-fiber products
with mechanical strength.
Therefore,
it is expected to
be used in
car lightweighting
and high-strength
composite structure
materials manufacturing in the
future.
At the same time,
there is also a lower
combination temperature
compared to the
general ultrasonic welding.
At the same time,
the friction heat
formed in the
interface is
quite small.
The friction heat
formed in the
small area
affects the strength
of the material
and the machine itself,
and it can be fully combined
to produce less
micro-structural changes.
This is quite beneficial
to the overall production.
On the other hand,
the picture below
is the application
of the current
ultrasonic welding
on the base
and the
high-speed vibration of
the water and the
friction heat of the
interface and the
transformation of
water and water
to form a
composite
and
carry out
the process of
mechanical manufacturing.
About the
1960s,
the main application
scene was used
on the
printing circuit board
to make the
chips.
It is a technique
often used in
circuit board manufacturing.
It also uses
pressure and vibration
to complete the
combination on the
surface of the
chip.
Combining the
main principles,
we can make a
more detailed introduction.
Traditionally,
there may be hundreds to
thousands of newtons of
pressure on the
pressure.
After the
pressure is
fixed, the
vibration is usually
20 to 60 microns.
The vibration is
about 15,000 to 24,000
per second.
In such a short
and dense vibration,
the interface will
generate a lot of deformation
and a lot of friction
heat.
The temperature of
friction heat and deformation
can be completed
by combining the
shape of the interface.
However,
due to the
high-speed deformation of the
interface,
various phenomena such as
heat and expansion
will occur.
Therefore, in so many
interfaces, including heat,
expansion, and deformation,
the interface formation mechanism
is not easy to
understand, especially
when it comes to
soft metal materials.
For harder materials,
such as steel and
carbon,
it is quite rare
to use the
scene to
combine the
formation of the
interface mechanism.
If we now
further
progress to
how to use the
superfine fiber to
apply it on hard materials,
mainly in some
preliminary research,
most of the
superfine fiber is used
in aluminum alloy or
aluminum alloy, etc.,
which is called soft material.
The interface will form
after it reaches a high temperature,
like clay,
such as deformation and compression.
The deformation and compression
process causes a lot of
changes in the
fiber structure of the
interface.
However,
if the superfine fiber
is used
on steel,
iron,
and carbon,
this part needs to be
further explored.
On the other hand,
if it is used on hard materials,
the combination of
iron and aluminum
has been done in
a lot of preliminary research.
They are mainly concentrated
in a short time,
within a few seconds,
they can form
about 30 minutes
in the expansion
process.
IMC is mainly
intermetallic,
which is not
conducive to
mechanical properties.
Most of the research
is focused on this later stage
of intermetallic
formation.
On the other hand,
in the early stage,
the material was rubbed,
molded, and then transformed.
After the transformation,
how will the
interface
form?
This mechanism is relatively rare,
but this part is also right.
Superfine fiber
application
has a significant impact
on the combination of
iron and aluminum.
Therefore,
we mainly
use superfine fiber
for the
interface of
superfine fiber and
iron.
First, we will
divide it into
interface reactions
when it is combined.
On the other hand,
we will use another type of metal
combination to discuss
how to combine
in a shorter time
.
Here,
I may have mentioned that
the first part is
to understand
its interface
when it is combined
.
We will use iron and aluminum,
and iron and iron.
The main purpose is that
there is no interface reaction
between the two,
so we use iron and aluminum.
After the combination,
the interface analysis will be more difficult.
As a contrast,
we use iron and aluminum to combine.
On the other hand,
from the principle introduction above,
it can be said that
only high-speed friction
will cause contact between the interface.
The deepening of the contact point
and the roughness of the material surface
have a significant impact.
Research in this area
is not sufficient.
On the one hand,
one part of the research
focuses on the roughness of the surface
and the impact on the strength of the combination.
On the other hand,
because we have to use iron
and other materials to combine,
the mechanical performance of iron
such as hardness and strength
will also have an impact
on the nature of the combination.
Therefore, the hardness of the iron itself
and the different micro-structures
will also have an impact
in the next introduction.
On the other hand,
why do we choose these two combinations
such as iron and aluminum
and iron and titanium
?
The main reason is that
aluminum and titanium
have different deformation capabilities
at high temperatures.
Therefore, we plan to
explore the impact of
these two different materials
.
Because of time,
we will directly enter the
experimental step.
First of all, it is the combination of
iron and aluminum.
The material we use
is a soft
non-metallic atomic steel,
a medium-strength steel,
and a pure aluminum plate
as a research subject.
On the surface,
it is exposed to the mirror.
After the exposure,
we will measure the roughness
of the surface.
Next, we use superfine steel
to make superfine steel.
The main combination
condition is that we use
a pressure of about 2000 newtons,
which is applied to
about 10 times the
thickness of the steel,
which is about 20,000 times per second
and about 40 microns
.
The combined time is about
0.01 seconds to
2.0 seconds.
After the superfine steel
is combined,
the next step is to
stretch the time to judge
its combined strength.
After the stretching is broken,
suppose that it is broken on the interface,
we will observe
the electronic microscope
and analyze the microstructure.
On the other hand,
if it is not suitable for stretching time,
we will prepare another batch of
samples that have not yet been stretched.
After the sample is cut
into two halves,
the surface is exposed
and the electronic microscope
is used
to observe
its image
and the deformation
of the interface
.
First of all,
suppose we use
steel and iron,
and iron and iron
and iron and iron and iron
on the interface,
we use
superfine steel to combine,
we can see that the horizontal axis
is the combined strength and the vertical axis
is the combined time.
It is obvious that
it only takes about
2 seconds.
Its strength
is about
2,000 newtons.
This sufficient pull strength
is enough to break
the IF steel,
that is, the infrared atomic steel itself.
It is greater than
the strength of the steel itself.
On the other hand,
if we compare it with other combinations,
such as expanding
and combining iron and iron,
it takes a relatively long
time, about 50 seconds,
and requires a certain degree of
high temperature.
In this case,
if we compare
the microstructure of the interface
with the microstructure of the microscope,
we find that the deformation of the interface
is quite concentrated,
about only 10 micrometers
before and after.
On the other hand,
if we compare it with the FASW
combined with friction mixing,
it is about 15 to 20
micrometers.
At the same time, it is accompanied by a very serious deformation.
Such a severe deformation
is reliable to the welding point itself.
That is to say,
its durability is
also a subject to
consider.
Therefore,
the superimposed interface
shows that it can be done
in a short time without
a lot of deformation
.
On the other hand,
if it is used on
the interface of iron and iron
and iron and nickel,
this part
is that we did
electronic microscope
and EBSD analysis on it.
We found that the
formation of the interface
will form a small
friction particle on the interface.
This friction particle will gradually increase
and at the same time be accompanied by friction
to friction the upper and lower
nickel and iron body.
After enough time
and temperature, it will
gradually be compressed.
After the compression,
it will produce a serious deformation
and then spread to the entire
integrated interface
to complete the formation of the integrated interface.
At the same time,
it is accompanied by the
interface and
the
interface.
If
with enough time,
the superimposed
interface
can form enough
partial and
serious deformation.
It can be completed in a short time.
On the other hand,
the surface of the superimposed
interface is
on the other hand,
if we use a thicker
interface, the
time of the
interface will be shorter
and the time of the
interface will be longer.
If it is a thicker
interface,
it will form a thicker
and larger
situation such as
how to compress
these three peaks and three valleys.
It takes a longer time and
pressure to compress it,
and then the interface will form such a
deformed surface to form more
integrated interfaces.
Therefore, a slightly smoother
integrated interface
does not have any
pollutants or oxidizers,
etc. It is powerful.
On the other hand,
if it is
the type of steel itself,
if it is replaced,
because what we mentioned earlier
is that it uses a
relatively
average fiber structure
of ferrite
IF steel.
Next, we will use
polystyrene
and ferrite
neutral carbon steel
and 14% nickel steel
and 0.08%
low carbon steel.
Their hardness and
microstructure will be
a relatively
close comparison.
This part is
ferrite itself.
In addition to the
IF steel used at the beginning,
we also prepared different types of steel.
Here,
ferrite, porcelain steel, and
martensite steel have different hardness.
As the hardness increases,
the combination of strength
is getting lower and lower.
Compared with the beginning,
nickel and IF steel only need
2 seconds to complete the combination.
On the other hand,
ferrite and ferrite
neutral carbon steel
need about 5 seconds to
complete the combination.
On the other hand,
once the hardness of
martensite steel is about
200 to 300 hardness,
it needs more time to complete the combination.
Why do we have
different situations?
We analyzed the interface
and found that
for the same steel photo,
the bottom is
porcelain steel,
the right bottom is ferrite.
Ferrite and nickel
will form more friction resistance.
This friction resistance has a
partial shrinkage and deformation.
On the other hand,
ferrite and nickel
have a relatively low deformation.
At the same time,
the interface
still has a defect.
That is to say,
steel steel
requires a long time to complete the combination.
At the same time,
we can get
a conclusion
that
ferrite steel
has a relatively similar
hardness.
It can provide
more
shrinkage and deformation.
This large-scale shrinkage and deformation
is conducive to the increase in the strength of the combination.
Therefore,
this part is
the friction
generated by the
combination.
Friction has
different mechanisms.
It is mainly divided into
ferrite and
nickel friction.
The main difference between the two is that
the interface
on the ferrite and nickel
will form
something like a friction resistance.
On the other hand,
if it is nickel,
in the case of
nickel,
the harder material
on the ferrite
will break down
and form
friction.
In other words,
such a situation occurs
when the hardness difference is relatively large,
such as nickel and ferrite.
In other words,
the first part of the
conclusion here
focuses on the appearance of
friction particles
with a relatively large
friction resistance.
On the other hand,
if it is ferrite,
the friction loss
in the ferrite itself
will take longer
to eliminate
such interface defects
to complete the
formation of the combination.
The second part
is the
strength of the combination.
In other words,
in the case of
a reaction,
the formation of the
combination interface
will be skipped.
In other words,
at the initial stage,
before the formation of
the interface,
how does the
interface system evolve?
This is the part
to be discussed.
First of all,
in the case of
ferrite,
we use the traditional
IF steel mentioned earlier,
as well as 5000-grade aluminum alloy,
and then superimpose the
interface.
During the process of
interface, we will
stick a thermocouple
to measure the temperature of
the interface.
The picture on the right
shows the change in
strength of the
interface.
After 1 second,
the strength of the
interface increased rapidly
to 2.5 seconds,
and the
interface was
completed.
After that,
the strength of the
interface decreased
gradually,
and the
temperature of the
interface increased
rapidly.
The temperature of the
interface increased
rapidly.
In about 1 second,
the temperature reached
about 400 degrees.
We compared it with
the previous study,
and found that the temperature
obtained in 1 second was
about 400 degrees.
The ability of the
interface to transform
increased rapidly,
and the
interface's
defective adjustment
and integration were
enough to
complete the
interface.
On the other hand,
we used the
electromagnetic microscope
to observe the
defective adjustment
and integration of the
interface.
The defective adjustment
and integration of the
interface were
enough to complete
the complete
integration of the
interface in 2.5 seconds.
Therefore,
we can classify the
whole phenomenon
as the initial
phase of the
interface.
After the
interface was
frictionized,
it would break off
from the
machine's side
and attach to the
iron's side.
As time went on,
the interface's
ability to transform
under high temperature
was not as obvious
as that of aluminum.
On the other hand,
some basic
physics concepts
may know that
iron is a hexagonal
metal.
If the hexagonal metal
is subjected to friction in
transformation,
it will have many
limitations.
Therefore,
we can see that
the integration strength of the
interface gradually
reached a platform
before 2 seconds.
It reached a
stable state.
However,
after 2 seconds,
the strength of the
interface increased dramatically.
Why did this happen?
At first,
before the
interface reached
a stable state,
we thought that
after 2 seconds,
we would find that
once it passed
600 degrees,
it would
produce a
lower
contact point
on the
left side
of the
interface.
That is to say,
from the original
HCP type
to the BCC type.
BCC's
transformation ability
is better than
the hexagonal
metal's
HCP,
the densest hexagonal metal.
In the next step,
in order to verify
our assumption,
we observed the interface
and found that
at about 2.0 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type
and stick to the
metal's side.
After 2 seconds,
the interface's
original gap
would disappear
after 2.0 seconds.
The gap would
gradually disappear.
So,
3.0 seconds
is enough to
complete the interface.
In contrast,
the expansion interface
mentioned earlier
usually takes
about 1-2 hours
to complete
the metal-type interface.
We also found that
after about 2.0 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the left side of the
HCP type.
We also found that
at about 2.0 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
2.5 seconds
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
In contrast,
after 2.5 seconds,
the interface would
break off on the
left side of the
HCP type.
Thank you.