You can find the recording online a week and a half later.
If you have any questions during this process,
you can leave a comment in the chat box.
We will have Q&A time at the end for everyone to ask questions.
Let's get started.
Thank you everyone for listening to my presentation.
Hello everyone, I'm Lai Jun-Hai.
You can call me Matt.
First of all, I would like to thank Tyra for inviting me to share my research.
Let me introduce myself.
I'm from Yonghe, Hsinchu.
I graduated from National University of China.
I worked as an engineer for a year and a half at BASF in Taiwan.
Then I went to UCLA to study engineering.
I graduated in 2017.
I am currently working at Startup Battery Streak.
At the same time, I am also a visiting scholar at UCLA.
My main work is focused on the development and mass production of new battery materials,
as well as the transfer between the company and UCLA.
Today's topic is
Designing pseudo-capacitance for fast-charging batteries.
That is, how to apply the mechanism of solid-state batteries to fast-charging batteries.
First of all, why do we need fast-charging batteries?
The first motivation is the accumulation of electromagnetic traffic.
Charging stations are currently set up in three levels.
The first level is the plug-in that everyone puts at home.
It can charge 3 to 6 kilometers per hour.
The second level is the charging station in the parking lot.
It can charge 20 to 30 kilometers per hour.
The third level is the fastest Tesla charging station.
It can charge 5 kilometers per minute.
Interestingly, the current charging station is still far less than the gas station.
But it is almost impossible to see such a long queue at the charging station.
Not everyone has an electric car,
but 5 kilometers per minute is still too slow compared to the time required for gas.
The second application of fast-charging batteries is the popularization of renewable energy.
As of last year, renewable energy has reached one-third of the global power generation.
50% of the power generation comes from renewable energy.
Other European countries also reach 20 to 30% of renewable power.
We all know that when wind and solar energy are converted into electricity,
they must be paired with suitable batteries.
However, these batteries can't be charged quickly,
so they are inefficient.
For example, when the wind speed is fast,
there will be a momentary large current.
The batteries that can't be charged at low power
will become waste heat and reduce the life of the battery.
So basically, this concept is the same as the concept of fast-charging batteries paired with aging cell phones.
The third application of fast-charging batteries is plant-based medical equipment.
Generally, the supply of such equipment is made up of a battery paired with a capacitor,
which is in the box at the bottom left.
Generally, the battery is used to monitor the function of low power for a long time,
while the capacitor is used to respond to high power in a short time.
Due to the limited size of the equipment and the need for different organ parts,
a single high-power battery is used to replace the two-in-one mode.
This has always been the trend in the development of this type of equipment power supply.
Of course, in addition to the above three applications,
there are other applications.
I won't go into detail here.
So in this main speech,
it mainly introduces how to improve the power density and energy density of the storage components using the materials of the capacitor.
As shown in the picture on the left,
the x-axis is the energy density,
and the y-axis is the power density.
First, I will briefly introduce the materials of the storage components and the techniques required for analysis.
Then, the first part will start with the high-power supercapacitor material in blue.
Then, the high-power characteristics will be achieved by using a non-oxidized carbonate residue.
The second part will start with the lithium battery.
Here is an example of fluorine,
L-NBOPF,
which achieves high power density by nanomerizing the battery material.
Generally, batteries or supercapacitors are basically composed of two terminals.
The positive terminal and the negative terminal are placed on the aluminum foil and copper foil respectively.
The two terminals are separated by a multi-hole separator,
which is the middle part of the separator,
to avoid short-circuit.
When charging the battery, the lithium battery moves in the capacitor,
and the battery material produces an oxidation reaction.
At the same time, the battery moves in the external circuit to achieve the balance of the electric current.
The electric current is the main focus of our discussion today.
It is mainly composed of the storage material, carbon, and the high-voltage supercapacitor.
The electric current needs to have a certain vacuum.
It is like a sponge.
It must contain enough electrolysis.
At the same time, it must have enough conductivity to be a high-voltage supercapacitor.
Although the structure of the battery and the capacitor are the same,
the storage mechanism is completely different.
The mechanism of the capacitor is absorbed by the lithium.
In the external circuit, the aluminum foil and the copper foil are separated and absorbed by the surface of the battery.
Because the lithium is absorbed by the surface for a short time,
this mechanism is most conducive to fast charging.
The disadvantage is that its surface area is limited,
so the density of energy is generally low.
In contrast, the storage method of the battery
uses the oxidation reaction inside the material.
In this case, the lithium can enter the material,
and its energy is far greater than that of the capacitor.
However, since the lithium moves very slowly inside the material,
it is therefore unable to do high-speed charging.
Next, we will introduce how to distinguish the battery from the capacitor.
Basically, it is based on electrical chemistry analysis.
We will make the pre-analyzed material into an electrolyte
and test it in the same electrolyte solution.
Generally, the device to be tested
has a single-phase electrolyte test on the upper left,
and a double-phase torque battery test on the lower left.
There are two main methods of testing.
The first method is the cyclic voltammetry,
which is abbreviated as CV.
The principle is to change the speed of voltage change
to measure the change in current.
The second method is the DC voltage test,
which is abbreviated as GC.
In the case of DC voltage charging,
it measures the change in voltage of the battery
and makes a diagram of the voltage.
Now we use GC and CV to get the diagram
to distinguish the battery from the capacitor.
They are two different storage mechanisms.
The capacitor on the left can be seen that
the CV is a rectangle,
while the GC is basically a diagonal.
The battery on the right is composed of a set of peaks,
while the GC is mainly composed of a horizontal line.
Now that we know how to judge the material of the battery
and the material of the capacitor,
we can look for the material of the fast charging battery.
What characteristics do we hope the fast charging battery has?
We hope it has the characteristics of electromagnetic chemistry on the left,
which allows it to be a fast charging battery.
It also has the characteristics of the material on the right,
which increases the density of energy
by storing energy through the reaction of oxygen-chloride.
This is the material we are looking for.
The material of the capacitor
not only has a rectangle CV,
but also a diagonal GC,
and it stores energy through the reaction of oxygen-chloride.
Next, I will talk about the main character I will introduce today,
which is the T-Phased,
Orphohombic Phased,
NB205.
Next, I will call it NIOVIA.
In addition to having the characteristics of electromagnetic chemistry,
its energy density
is equivalent to the energy density of lithium carbon dioxide,
which is in the lithium-ion battery.
Its energy density is 10 times that of the capacitor.
Its power density,
which is the power of its fast charging,
can also reach 10 times that of the battery.
Its only drawback is that
it is still oxygen-chloride,
so its power consumption
is the first topic we are going to fix.
The first part
is to mix carbon with NIOVIA
to improve the properties of NIOVIA.
We need to deduce a good NIOVIA,
and we will eventually deduce
what kind of properties a good NIOVIA battery needs
to show the characteristics of its lithium-ion battery.
A good NIOVIA battery
basically needs two parts.
The first is the high-voltage part,
and the second is the part that can have a high pore density.
In this study,
we mainly used three materials.
The first material is our protagonist, NIOVIA.
The second material is our chemical-capable
Reduced Graphene Oxide, also known as RGO.
Its purpose is to provide short-term conductivity.
The third material
is the one on the far right,
Carbide Derived Carbon, also known as CDC.
It is a kind of carbon dioxide.
Its main purpose is that
it has a polypore structure
and its size is in the micrometer level,
so it can provide long-term conductivity.
The way we prepare the battery
is to first plant NIOVIA on RGO.
Next, we combine NIOVIA RGO with CDC
to get NIOVIA RGO CDC,
also known as NRC.
Finally, we make NRC
into a commercial-grade battery
and test it to prove that
it has a high-power and high-density
storage characteristics
at the right pore density.
This slide shows the details of the material equipment.
The main equipment is
the water-heating method.
We put the precursor
into the autoclave
and heat it up to 180°C
for 12 hours.
Next, we wash the particles
and dry them.
After drying,
we heat it up to 500°C
to get the body structure we want,
which is T-phase,
or ophiobic phase.
Next, we combine NIOVIA RGO
with CDC.
The main purpose is to
make this composite material
in the form of surface electrolysis.
Next, we make it into a battery
and test it.
We have 20% NIOVIA,
40% NRC20,
and 60% NRC20.
The BET on the right
is the analysis of the surface electrolysis.
It shows that
the surface electrolysis of the material
increases with the
composition of the CDC.
This means that
this composite method
does not cause the CDC to lose its surface area,
or the CDC to be less airtight,
or its structure to collapse.
Therefore, we can use
a simple ratio to
achieve the airtightness we need.
There are also two black dots on the picture.
These two black dots
are where we directly plant NIOVIA
on the CDC.
If we
do not use
this composite method
but use
the water-heat method
to directly plant it on the CDC,
at high temperature,
the CDC's
surface area
will...
Because the surface area is too large,
the surface area will decrease
at high temperature.
We want to use the CDC
to improve the airtightness
of the electrode.
This is the idea.
Next, we need to
use the CV to judge the electrode.
Let's see if it is like a battery material
or an electric material.
In the case of changing the minority,
we can get the corresponding current.
Therefore, we use the current
to make judgments with the change of the minority.
If the
material is like a battery,
the change of the current
will be multiplied by the minority.
If the material
is like a capacitor,
the current
will be multiplied by the minority.
In other words,
when the minority is doubled,
the current will be doubled.
Combining these two formulas,
we can get
the following formula
from the experiment.
The current is equal to the magnitude
multiplied by the minority.
This is called
B-value analysis.
We want the material
to be as fast as the capacitor.
Therefore, we want the B-value
to be as close to 1 as possible.
This proves that the material
can do high-speed charging.
Next,
the NRC
can store different
current
at different speeds.
On the left,
we use the minority
to burn the NRC.
The lowest value
is 100% Cdc.
The way
we control the minority
is from the slowest 30-minute
charging point on the left to the
90-second charging point on the right.
The y-axis is the energy generated by me.
As time goes by,
the energy generated by me
will be reduced.
We want the line to be as flat as possible.
This means that the material
can do high-speed charging
as well as low-speed charging.
The lowest value is 100% Cdc.
As the amount of niobia increases,
the density of the NRC
will also increase.
Up to 40%, the increased current
will not be affected by the minority.
From 0% to 20% to 40%,
the current will remain as flat.
Up to 60%,
from the NRC 60,
we can see that
the current is lower than
40% at 90 seconds.
The highest value is 100%.
Although the amount of
niobia is
higher than 40%,
we can expect that
according to the trend,
when the charging time is less than 90 seconds,
the NRC 40 will increase.
On the right is the B-value
introduced in the previous page.
When the curve
is closer to 1,
we mainly do CV
for different materials.
Then we do the
B-value analysis.
The result of the analysis is in the lower right corner.
When the curve is closer to 1,
it means that the charging speed is faster.
By this, we can judge
that the charging speed of
NRC 40 is faster than
NRC 60 and 100% niobia.
This also proves that
when there is 60% CVC
stored in the electrode,
the electrode has sufficient airtightness
to accommodate sufficient electrolysis
to show the characteristics of
niobia lithium-ion battery.
Finally,
we combine the NRC 40
with the traditional lithium-ion electrode
to form a full electrode
to do
CV and GC analysis.
In terms of CV,
we can get
the characteristics of lithium-ion,
which is a rectangular CV.
In terms of the
GC,
we also get a
oblique GC.
At the same time,
because of the combination of niobia,
we not only
increase the energy density
at low power,
but also increase the energy density
at high power.
At the power of
3000W per kg,
we can store
up to 23W
per kg of energy density.
Next,
I will use the picture on the right to summarize.
The first part
is that we use the amount of Cdc
to adjust the airtightness and
electrolysis of the NRC composite material.
At the same time,
the electrode has high energy
and fast charge characteristics.
In other words,
we use Cdc as the starting point
to mix different niobia
to increase its energy density.
By maximizing airtightness and electrolysis,
we can increase
the overall
energy density of the electrode
and preserve
the high power characteristics of Cdc.
The second part
I want to share is
the LNVOPF material
as a medical equipment energy supply application.
Speaking of medical equipment energy supply,
I will use
an implantable
cardioverter
defibrillator
ICD
as an example.
Its Chinese name is
implantable defibrillator.
It basically
detects your heart beat.
When your heart beats abnormally,
it will use
high current to stimulate your heart beat.
For example,
when your heart stops beating,
it will stimulate your heart beat.
I am not a medical background,
so I only understand
the basic concept of this device.
The main usage method
is still left to the doctor.
ICD
mainly uses
high current and low current output.
The low current part
is mainly responsible for the battery.
The high current part
is responsible for the circuit board.
There is also a device size
at the bottom.
The size is about one-fourth of the heart.
Most of the area
is actually from the low-voltage circuit.
Another
medical device
is
DBS
Deep Brain Stimulator.
This type of device
has the same principle,
but the current demand
is smaller than ICD.
DBS mainly stimulates
the brain nerve.
The power supply
is also made up of
a battery and a circuit.
When we want to
put this medical device
in the body,
we hope that
its size can be smaller and better
to save more space.
When we find the material,
it has the characteristics
of a battery and a circuit.
So,
we can use a single device
to make a circuit
or a battery.
We prefer the battery
because the battery size is smaller.
A single storage device
will provide the supply of
the current.
We can save more
the power supply
of medical equipment.
This material
is
L-NBOPF.
NBOPF
comes from
NASKON,
which is a transformer.
When it is mixed,
the voltage
of this material
will increase
with time.
This means it can store more energy.
And
when I
use it,
the voltage
will
decrease
with time.
This means
the material
will last longer.
The storage density
is the same as
the lithium carbon dioxide
in the battery.
Most importantly,
this material has
the characteristics of a battery
and a circuit.
Next,
we will introduce another way
to distinguish a battery from a circuit.
We will use X-ray
diffraction
to judge
whether the material
is
changing
with the
structure of the crystal.
This is what we call
X-ray diffraction.
X-ray diffraction
occurs when the battery is charged.
Let's analyze
NBOPF.
NBOPF has two peaks
that are opposite to each other.
The peak at low voltage
is parallel.
The peak at high voltage
is not parallel.
This means that
the material can be used
as a battery at low voltage
and as a circuit at high voltage.
However,
this is not that simple.
The material
is charged twice
per hour
Let me introduce
a little bit.
When we talk about charging,
we use a unit called C-ray.
We use a unit called C-ray.
C-ray
has several Cs.
This means that it can charge several times
in an hour.
When this material
charges twice per hour,
when this material charges twice per hour,
which is the part of 2C,
it can store
80-90% of the power.
However,
when you shorten the charging time
to 3 minutes,
it can only charge 8%.
The reason is that
during the charging process,
it will charge the battery first.
Then it will charge the capacitor.
However, the charging speed of the battery
is too slow,
so I can't even charge the capacitor.
So,
it's a bit like this.
The main reason is that the charging speed of the battery
is too slow,
resulting in a decrease
in the overall charging speed.
What we are going to do next
is to
use the material
as a nanometer
to shorten the time
and distance
of the particles in the material
to increase the charging speed
of the material.
Next,
we are going to synthesize
this nanometer NVOPF
and discuss the size
and characteristics of fast charging.
First,
the way we make it is
to put all the materials
in the
solvent thermal
to synthesize.
We also put it in the pressure suit.
Then,
after 12 hours,
after 185°C,
we take the material out
and clean it.
We will dry it.
Next, we use
XRD, X-Ray Diffraction, to confirm the material.
After confirming that
there is no problem with the material
and there is no impurities in it,
we will make an electrode
for electromagnetic testing.
Here,
we can get
different types of
NVOPF
based on
the ratio of the material
and the temperature of the synthesis.
Basically, NVOPF
is a rectangular body.
We usually get
brick-shaped
and if it is longer,
it becomes rod.
If it is shorter,
it becomes pellet.
We will discuss
the shape of the
NVOPF
and the impact of its size
on its reaction rate.
Next,
we will use bValue
to analyze
the properties of the fast charge.
In the first step,
we make different
cVs for the material.
From these four peaks,
we can get
individual bValue.
Then, we make
bValue with different
aspect ratio
and its size
to see
how it changes.
On the left is
the NVOPF pellet.
On the right,
we change
the rod
to reduce
the aspect ratio
to the brick
and the pellet.
We can see that
the bValue
decreases as the aspect ratio decreases.
This means that
when we decrease the aspect ratio,
the characteristics of the fast charge
will be more and more like the current.
It can become
the material
for the fast charge.
On the other hand,
we also
compare the
particle size
to the bValue.
We combine
the microns
and microns
to reduce the nanometers.
The nanometers
are reduced to a few tens of nanometers.
We can see that
when the size decreases,
the bValue also increases.
The increase in bValue means
that the smaller the particle,
the more suitable it is
for the fast charge.
The more suitable it is
The focus here is
on the microbrick.
Its peak bValue
is close to 0.5.
0.5 means that it is
like a battery.
When we make a nanoparticle,
all of its
oxidation-reduction reactions
have a bValue
of 0.7 or higher.
Next,
we will do a charge-electric charge test.
The nanoparticle
of the microbrick
can charge up to 90%
in 2 hours.
This means that
the bValue of the
NBOPF
has increased
significantly
after the nanoparticle
has been nanoparticle.
The bValue of the
bValue of the
bValue of
cV meters
compared to the current specifications
our current current
is greater than
greater than these functions
greater than these specifications
our frequency
because of the device
on the device
we can only measure
a few microseconds
so we only measured
50Hz
also covers some
function frequency
next
I will use this graph
to make a brief summary
the second part
we use nanoparticle
to convert this
NBOPF
to fast charge
in addition
we also proved
the feasibility of
NBOPF
finally
I will make a brief summary
what is
the so-called
Taekwondo Message
first, I hope everyone
knows what is a nanoparticle
nanoparticle
is actually a storage mechanism
it has the power of the nanoparticle
and the density of the battery
and
the second point
is how we can judge a nanoparticle
of course, through
the method of electromagnetic
we have such a CV
we have such a oblique
GC
and in the process of my oxygenation
the material did not change
finally
how do we design a nanoparticle
mainly
here I demo three points
the first is
the first is the conductivity
and the airtightness
I control the conductivity and airtightness of my electrode
to make my
NBOPF optimized
the second
is to make the material nanoparticle
and adjust its phase change
to make our general battery material
it is not affected
by
the transfer of ions
too slow
let it
in the part of the battery
can reach the high speed charge point
the effect
thank you
if you have any questions
please let me know
thank you
thank you Matt
now we can
start the Q&A
in the chat box
there are some questions
do you want to unmute
and ask your question
I want to ask
what is the electrolyte used
when you start to make your battery
it should be organic electrolyte
right
yes
I use
LIPF-6
ECDMC
the general
electrolyte used
so we can understand
why the lowest voltage
should be around 1.2V
another question
what is the
diagonal direction of
the nitrogen oxide
nitrogen oxide
not supercapacitor
it should be
interesting
or important
basically
the diagonal direction
is between
1.2V to
1.2V to 3V
this is
here
the diagonal direction
is 1.2V to
1.2V to 2.5V
this is
the nitrogen oxide
the capacity
should be
from 1.2V to
2.5V
90% of the voltage
comes from here
it means
when it is below 1.2V
2.5V will be disconnected
the electrolyte will be disconnected
the material will not be disconnected
when it is above 2.5V
you can't see
the current
the current will be
close to 0
like this picture
sorry
the CV is the same
it will be
no current
basically no current
ok
you just showed this slide
so I want to ask the following question
how do you calculate the B-value
and the voltage graph in the lower right corner
now we have
different CVs
each CV
has a current
in each voltage
so every current
will be analyzed
for the change
does the B-value have to use the peak current
or does it have to be any current
so today in pseudo-capacitance
pseudo-capacitance
basically
it has many
continuous
redox reactions
so when you produce a box
you can't
only analyze
the peak current
you are not fair to
the other currents
so
basically
in pseudo-capacitance
you can use this formula
on all the voltage graphs
to draw the continuous curve
another story
behind this
is that the redox
happens below 2V
so it doesn't have redox
so what do you see
you see EDLC
what does EDLC mean
EDLC is the
reaction rate
on the surface of the electrode
so EDLC
from the electrode
far away
to the surface of the electrode
what do you mean by diffusion control
yes
so here we increase
the density of Cdc
so the vacuum of the electrode
increases
so when there is no redox
the kinetics
increases
so when there is
redox
the kinetics increases
any other questions
ok thank you
the last one is later
so if you have any questions
I will ask later
any other
questions
hello
I want to ask Matt
some questions
please
Matt thank you for your speech
my main question is
on your first project
you were doing
I want to ask
how big is the particle size
of Nairobia
the particle size is
here
you can see on the upper right
the size is
20-30 nm
so you
reduce graphene oxide
and Cdc
to increase
the conductivity of short-circuit and long-circuit
yes
Cdc also provides the vacuum
ok
I was doing research on
hierarchical porous carbons
and
there are small
micropores
and big macropores
so I was thinking
if you combine
other porous materials
does it increase the
potential of the capacitor
yes
because
I have enough porosity
my particles
can be
I can
absorb more electrolyte
so I can
there is a slide
I didn't show
because I have some time
so you can see
why Nairobia
needs big porosity
basically
it comes from
ok
basically this slide
I was doing different
this is the result from consul
so
basically it comes from Nernst equation
and Poisson
equation
Poisson equation represents
how much
the dielectric constant is
so under different voltage
how many particles are on the surface
so when the voltage
moves to
in the middle of the graph
basically
it represents
how many particles are on the surface
but when it
moves to
below a certain level
Nairobia starts to react
I need a lot of
particles to enter the material
so when it needs a lot of particles
to enter the material
it will cause the surface porosity
the surface porosity
is the reason why
Nairobia's kinetics
so
this is the reason why
this material needs
high porosity
so that
it can maintain
the characteristics of the dielectric
or the characteristics
of the dielectric
I want to
follow up
how did you come up with
reducing graphene oxide
plus Cdc
has another advantage
on the synthesis
basically if you want to
grow oxide
graphene oxide
the ligand of oxygen
can be the nucleation site
of these synthesis
no matter if you want to grow metal particles
or oxide particles
basically it can easily grow on top
because it has a lot of sites
the particles you grow
are small
so
graphene oxide
is like an additive
it can make your particle size very small
second, it also increases
the conductivity
for graphene oxide
there are several ways
for example, you do filtration
you filter it
it is
a two-dimensional structure
so when you do filtration
when you do filtration
it will become
a very dense electrode
if it is very dense
the electrode can't get in
so we want to
find a structure
like Cdc
this
structure
of graphene oxide
to mix in
but we don't want to mix too much
because
the density of the energy
is relatively low
I understand, thank you
any other questions?
if not
I will ask my last question
after talking about ZMath
I mentioned
how to distinguish
between solid electrolyte and
solid electrolyte
but now
there is a popular topic
solid electrolyte
or solid electrolyte
I want to see
the difference between
solid electrolyte and
other two
how to distinguish
how to judge
actually
I didn't do the
because I talked about
the second topic
solid electrolyte
yes, it was
but we took it
basically
we just changed its structure
then we took it as an electrolyte
basically
solid electrolyte
yes
I don't know much about this
what I know about solid electrolyte
is
its conductivity
it must be very thin
because its conductivity is not as fast as liquid
although it is solid electrolyte
but it is not as fast as liquid
another thing
everyone says
solid electrolyte
it doesn't
we can
avoid the SEI reaction
but actually
this is a loss
actually solid electrolyte
in its first cycle
its SEI
has a big impact
in our group
in addition to high-speed charge
another part is
3D battery
3D battery is
the structure of the battery
to make it a satellite battery
that part
in solid electrolyte
of course we want to use solid electrolyte
because solid electrolyte
its density
is much higher than liquid
so we can save a lot of liquid
needed volume
but they found that in the first cycle
this SEI
actually still occurs
and after it occurs
because it is solid
so it is very difficult to solve
basically your material
at first it is a tight connection
it will separate
thank you
anyone else have questions?
if no questions
Max, do you have your email?
yes
I put it in the last slide
if you have any questions
you can
email me
thank you
for coming
and thank you Max
for giving us such a wonderful speech
this recording
you can watch it again
in a week
and you can continue
to discuss with Max
related research
so I will stop recording now