Recording has started.
In fact, he was originally a law student at NTU Law School.
He had studied in the Department of Law at Hokkaido University in Japan for a year.
Not only did he complete his law degree, he also obtained a lawyer's license.
He also worked at a large law firm in Taiwan and Japan.
To add to that, Ming-Hsi and I have known each other for a long time.
We were classmates in the same year at NTU Law School.
In our hearts, Ming-Hsi has always been a strong character like a god.
We thought it was difficult for him to study law.
We didn't expect him to be able to study history.
Not only that, he is also the president of NTU's Food & Beverage Association.
To us, he has always been a very strong god.
He also won countless books.
I think it's very impressive.
What's cool about Ming-Hsi is that he always follows a two-way path.
He studies both law and history at the same time.
At the moment, he is in the Department of History at NTU Law School.
He also combined his two-way background with his major.
His field of research includes modern international law history,
East Asian legal modernization,
Sino-US relations history,
international economic law and tax law, and so on.
I was thinking about today's topic, foreign law.
For many people, foreign law is a familiar and uncertain concept.
So let's talk about the rules of today's speech.
Today's speech is actually quite simple.
If you have any questions,
you can either turn on your microphone and ask the speaker directly.
Ming-Hsi likes this kind of interactive speech mode.
Or if you are shy or worried about affecting the speaker's flow,
you can also post your questions in the chat area.
I will find the right time to ask.
After Ming-Hsi finishes his speech,
we will also have a Q&A session.
If everyone is okay,
let's welcome Ming-Hsi.
Hello, everyone.
Can you see my PowerPoint?
Okay.
Thank you for your introduction.
As Yi-An said,
we are both university classmates.
But in the legal department of NTU,
I think Yi-An and I are quite different.
Yi-An left the legal department to study psychology
and became a lawyer.
I am honored to have Yi-An as my host.
Today's topic is
controlling US citizens in China.
This is my research plan for the first-year students
in the history department of NTU.
This plan is still in the early stages,
so I would like to share it with you.
I found that in this project,
there are fewer liberal arts students.
So I will spend a little more time
to introduce to you
the current situation of humanities
and legal studies in the US.
So today's speech will be divided into several parts.
One is self-introduction.
But I don't think I need to introduce too much,
because Yi-An has given me a very detailed explanation.
The second part is to share with you
what history is.
This is actually a common question for everyone.
And I am often asked by teachers
in different departments or classmates.
Because history is abstract.
We can say that what happened in the past is history.
There are so many things in history.
As a historian or a doctoral student in history,
how do we choose the topic?
How do we do research?
In other words, what are the doctoral students
in the history department doing?
Why do I want to study legal history?
What is the relationship between law and history?
In particular, why do I want to choose the topic
of international law as my research topic?
After the introduction of these major subjects
and the background,
I will talk about my initial research in the first year.
That is, what is the foreign law in the United States?
In the past, in high school textbooks,
we often heard that foreign law
is a part of an unequal treaty.
In the past, our country or China
suffered a lot of unequal treatment.
Then it was a matter of losing power.
Is it true? Is it true?
Did the United States benefit from this?
Who benefited from this?
The first research in the history department
is to clarify some facts and some institutional backgrounds.
The higher level is to develop theories.
So in the end, I want to talk about my future plan.
How do I develop these facts and their theoretical meanings
and then carry out my future research?
So here, actually,
Yi-An has already introduced it to me.
I'm not drunk.
I want to talk about the last point.
That is, why do I want to study history?
In fact, my initial goal was
to teach in a law school in the United States.
Here, I think there is something very interesting
that I can share with you.
In the United States, professional schools,
such as law schools,
their practice is very different from
what we usually do in history, physics, or math.
As a historian, I will tell you
what the origin and evolution of this system is.
As you know,
in the world of legal education,
North America is very special.
They do not have legal education in the university.
Unlike in Taiwan, Japan, Germany,
the United Kingdom, or France,
we can choose the law department
after graduating from high school.
After graduating from the law department,
you can take a law exam.
Then you can become a lawyer
or continue to study for a master's degree
and return to the law department to teach.
This is not the case in the United States and Canada.
The U.S. Department of State does not have a law department.
You have to graduate from the Department of State
before you can get your first law degree,
which is called JD, or Juris Doctor.
It's the same as MD.
It has the title of a doctor,
but it's not a Ph.D. doctor.
So traditionally,
when there was a law school in the United States,
they thought that
law was a skill,
not a subject.
So in the 19th century,
the teachers of the law school
were some senior lawyers,
judges, or food workers.
And the education of the law school
was to have these food workers
tell you how to become a good lawyer.
So the course of the law school
was very food-oriented.
It taught you how to sign a contract,
how to act or defend in front of the jury,
how to interact and interrogate,
how to get along with the judge,
and so on and so forth.
Later, everyone thought
that if you teach at school,
you still need to have a little bit of academic knowledge.
But there was no such thing as a law Ph.D.
So what should you do?
There is still a method
taught at law schools in the United States
called traditional track,
which allows you to become a teacher of the law school.
What is traditional track?
It's when you graduate from college
and become a JD,
your first law degree.
After that,
you become a lawyer for three years
or a judge assistant for three years
to gain food experience.
After gaining food experience,
you go to the law department of the university
to apply for the position of teacher.
When you're a teacher,
it's usually three years.
You have to teach on the side.
What you teach is to teach some legal writing,
mathematical writing, and so on.
These are related to food.
During the three years you teach,
you have to write a master's thesis.
If this master's thesis is well written,
you can go to various schools
and apply for the position of assistant professor.
Once you become an assistant professor,
you'll be like other departments.
You'll start writing thesis,
升等,教書, and so on.
But later,
in the 1970s or 1980s,
we found that
the failure of being a fellow
and not becoming an assistant professor
is very high.
This can also be seen.
In JD for three years,
you're learning how to write a book,
and then you become a lawyer for three years.
It doesn't make sense.
When you go back to law school,
you suddenly start writing a thesis.
Like everyone here,
we all study Ph.D.
We all know that
writing a thesis requires a lot of practice,
and then you need someone to lead.
You need a lot of research methods, and so on.
So later, the U.S. Law School
came up with a new way
to make you a teacher,
which is the so-called JD Ph.D. double degree.
In other words,
you get a Ph.D. in another field,
such as history, economics,
politics, language,
psychology, and so on.
Then you go to JD,
and then you become a lawyer for two years.
At this point, you don't have to be a fellow,
and you can take your Ph.D. thesis
and apply for a job at the U.S. Law School.
Basically,
all the new professors at the U.S. Law School
are JD Ph.D. double degrees.
This is my original goal.
I want to get a Ph.D. in history first,
and then I want to get a Ph.D. in JD.
Then I can apply for a job at the U.S. Law School.
There are more and more Chinese people
applying for a Ph.D. degree
at the U.S. Law School
through this kind of double degree.
But as far as I know,
no one in Taiwan
has applied for a Ph.D. degree
at the U.S. Law School in this way.
So I want to give it a try.
Next,
in the past,
most of the Ph.D. and JD degrees
were obtained at different schools.
For example,
Professor Ian Ayers,
who is very famous for
doing legal economic analysis
at Yale University.
He was MIT's Econ Ph.D.,
plus Yale's JD,
and then he taught at Yale.
For people in mainland China,
for example,
Professor Li Ji at UC Irvine,
he was a political science Ph.D.
at Northwestern University,
plus Yale's JD,
and then he taught law at UC Irvine.
So this is what I want to challenge.
I want to practice and hone my knowledge
in the history department,
learn the methods of history,
and write papers.
Later on,
in the last stage of my Ph.D. program,
in the 6th, 7th, or 8th year,
I applied for a Ph.D. degree
at another school.
I was a lawyer in the U.S. for two years,
and then I taught at a law school.
This is a brief explanation
of why I want to
apply for a Ph.D. degree in history.
On the one hand,
I always have this idea of cross-field.
I think this kind of training and environment in the U.S.
is the best fit for my research.
The last thing I want to add is that
I just said that
Taiwanese have not yet read Ph.D. and JD,
right?
The next question must be
that in Taiwan's law department,
there are many legal scholars
who claim to have obtained a Ph.D. degree in the U.S.
What kind of degree did they read?
What kind of career path did they embark on?
Since they are different from Americans
who cultivate law schools,
they must have a different set of things, right?
So I wrote LLM and JSD here later.
Here I would like to explain to you
what this is.
LLM is generally translated as
a legal master's degree.
It is a Latin abbreviation.
It means that
if you are not in the U.S. today,
for example, the U.K., France,
Taiwan, or Japan,
you have already studied law in college.
So it is an abbreviation
for a legal master's degree
for foreigners.
This is called LLM.
You only need to study for nine months
without writing a paper.
Then you can be qualified
to be a lawyer in New York.
So in most cases,
in general, in Taiwan or Japan,
if you have been a lawyer for three or five years
and you think you need to retire,
you can go to the U.S.
and study for nine months.
Among these LLM students,
some may be interested in academics.
So you can find a professor
who is willing to teach you
while you are studying LLM.
Then you can enroll
and become a JSD,
which we generally call
a legal master's degree.
This JSD is actually very different
from our general Ph.D.
Because once you enroll,
you are a doctoral candidate.
So you don't need to take classes,
you don't need to be a teacher,
you don't need to be a lecturer.
In principle, if you write a paper,
you can graduate after the exam.
So there are some very famous
LLM teachers in China.
They may only study JSD for a year and a half
or two years
before they graduate.
There are a lot of people like this.
Because JSD is not like
our Ph.D. training,
you have to take classes,
take exams,
be a lecturer,
teach, and so on.
So the problem with a JSD graduate
is that
their quality is not very certain.
Some people are JSD,
their boss has very high requirements for them,
asking them to continue to take classes,
continue to study methods,
or take the qualification exam with them.
Or some students are very smart.
I have a lot of JSD teachers
in the Department of Law in Canada.
They are very smart.
They watch the lecturers
have a seminar in the law school every day,
and they will kill each other.
They watch Huashan's paper every day
and become a big family.
After they return to China,
they can be a Ph.D.
and teach law in Taiwan.
But in the US Department of Law,
you can hardly see any teachers
who are JSD.
Because they are
Ph.D. for foreigners.
This is a brief introduction.
I used to think that
if I went to the US to study law,
I could just study LLM and JSD.
But I thought,
no,
I want to try to
receive the same training as Americans.
If Americans want to become a professor of law,
I will become a professor of law.
So I started with Ph.D.
Later,
in my senior year,
I will see if I can get a J.D.
and try to find a job
in the US Department of Law.
Next, I will answer a question.
What is history?
I am often asked this question.
But I think this is a disaster question.
It's like I want to ask,
what is physics?
What is math?
It is difficult to define a subject.
But I think I can try
to look at this subject
from a more specific perspective.
What is it?
I think from the perspective of abstract theory,
in the Western context,
history is also a method of philosophy.
In other words,
the research we do in history
is the same as asking a question,
giving it a false hypothesis,
and then verifying it, right?
It is the same as philosophy, physics, and chemistry.
We need to ask a question,
and then use some methods to answer it,
to verify if your hypothesis is correct.
Of course, this is a bit of nonsense.
Because anyone who studies Ph.D.
has to do this kind of study.
So I think we can look at history
from a different perspective.
Whether it is Greece or China,
people in ancient times
have a cycle of history.
By cycle of history,
I mean that
for them,
history is something that
happens over and over again.
For example,
in the Tang Dynasty,
Emperor Taizong said that
history is the key to understanding the mind.
In other words,
as long as you study the past,
you will learn some lessons.
By cycle of history,
I mean that
there is nothing new under the sun.
So I understand the past,
and I understand the future.
Because what happened in the past
will keep happening over and over again.
So as long as I know the past,
I will know how to face the same thing in the future.
What should I do when it happens again?
But as we all know,
this is a kind of fantasy.
How is it possible that
people 200 years ago
would face the same problems
as we do now?
Of course, it is different.
In the 18th and 19th centuries,
history was taken over by the state.
There was a very
purposeful approach
to help
build a democratic country.
For example,
when Germany was about to be unified,
a group of historians came out
and wrote history of Germany.
They told us that we were different
from the Italians.
We have a glorious history.
Who is German?
We have a common memory.
This also happened
in the end of the Qing Dynasty
and the beginning of the Republic of China.
Chinese historians told you
that we are all descendants of the Yan Emperor.
So we have a common ancestor.
We must agree that we are all Chinese.
So for a while,
history was used by the state
to build the common memory of the nation.
In the 19th century,
there was another trend.
Social science,
political science,
and other social sciences
wanted to become
like natural science
and discover the common principles
of human society.
They wanted to analyze
why the French Revolution happened,
what its causal relationship was,
and what its social background conditions were.
If we can build
a abstract theory
that the French Revolution
will happen
when the four conditions
are met,
we can predict
when the next revolution will happen
or prevent it from happening.
Another famous example
is Marx.
He said that human history
has a process.
We will go from feudalism
to a small class revolution
to a large class revolution.
Many historians' work
is to prove
the theory of social science
and the process
of social science principles.
Until now,
many historians in mainland China
are still trying to prove
the process of Marxism
in China.
This is the purpose
of the third kind of history.
The fourth kind of history
is similar to the second kind of history,
but it starts to ask smaller questions.
Historians want to
understand the history of the past
and develop quantitative studies
of economics or politics.
The most famous example
is Professor Daniel Clerman
at the University of South Carolina.
He taught at the University of Chicago
because his wife was a lawyer
who was afraid of the cold.
His family moved to South Carolina.
He is a history doctor
and a law professor
at the University of Chicago.
His research is very interesting.
He uses the documents
and information
he discovered
in history training
and his strong
statistical and quantitative background
to do some
theoretical practical research.
Some questions
are difficult to answer.
Does judicial independence
help economic development?
We are not like natural science,
which can control all variables
in the laboratory.
When we want to study this topic,
we have to do some social experiment
to do the cause-and-effect theory,
and we need to find
a lot of agent variables.
Every time a country
does judicial independence reform,
it often follows
many other reforms at the same time.
This is the best way
to understand the relationship
between judicial independence
and economic development in the UK.
Professor Dan Clearman
has some very good information.
For example,
he found that
in the 18th and 19th centuries,
the UK was doing judicial independence reform.
At the same time,
East India Company
was listed
in London Stock Exchange
because
there was no
good information transmission system.
Therefore, news from London
had to wait three or five days
before it could be sent to Amsterdam.
He thought
that the agent variables
of economic development
were the high and low prices
of East India Company's shares.
Whenever a judicial independence
law or reform
occurred in the UK,
East India Company's shares
would rise or fall
when the news
was sent to Amsterdam.
He used statistics
to infer the situation in the UK.
In the end,
he concluded that
every judicial independence reform
in the UK
had something to do
with the rise of
East India Company's shares.
Without historical training,
East India Company's shares
would not have risen.
This is another theory.
In the early years,
there was a theory
that asked
why there was
no China in the West.
In the early years,
historians liked to ask
why there was no capitalism in China,
why there was no scientific revolution in China,
and why there was no
revolution in China.
The next theory is
very popular recently,
but it is a bit similar
to the idea of a national state.
Historians believe that
the people's historical memory
should not serve the country.
Therefore,
historians began to write
some important historical memories.
For example,
transitional justice should tell you
that the Nazi massacre
against the Jews
was really horrible.
We should remember this
forever.
Because it happened once,
it may happen again.
The main consciousness of Taiwan
must be awakened,
because the people of Taiwan
have been oppressed for the past 400 years.
These popular historical writings
are actually shaping historical memory.
Another group of people
believe that
history should not serve the country,
so there are a lot of historical studies
to deconstruct the national state.
For example,
tradition is invented,
and tradition does not have
a long history of 5,000 years.
The so-called descendants of the King of Japan
only appeared for 100 years.
The so-called Japanese cuisine
was invented after the Ming Dynasty.
In the Middle Ages,
the Emperor of Japan believed in Buddhism,
so he told everyone not to eat meat.
In ancient East Asia,
there were four categories of animals
in the world,
such as grass fish and birds.
At that time,
the Emperor of Japan said
that everyone was not allowed to eat meat,
grass fish and birds.
In fact,
before the Ming Dynasty,
the Japanese did not eat beef or pork,
so the so-called barbecue and fried pork chops
were far-fetched Japanese cuisine.
They appeared in the late 19th century
and even in the early 20th century.
Finally, I think history
is different from everyone else.
In politics and sociology,
they ask more objective questions,
but in history,
they also ask subjective questions.
Traditional sociology
may ask a question,
such as
whether the exam system
has promoted social movement.
So some historical sociologists
will look for a lot of past history
to see if there are some
poor and hard-working people
who became good officials
because of the imperial examination,
and then flew to Tengda
and became famous
from the Han dynasty.
But historical sociology
will ask a question.
Objectively,
even if the imperial examination
really promoted social movement,
did the people at that time
really realize that
the imperial examination
promoted social movement?
In the Han dynasty,
there were some economic works.
We can find out from economics
what is the meaning of
Chou Chou's The Theory of Economics?
What does it mean in economics?
But historians may ask
a person who has not studied
modern economics,
has not studied Adam Smith,
or has not studied economics
in NTU,
how can he write The Theory of Economics?
I think this is the difference
between historical sociology
and other subjects.
The next question is
what is legal history?
Why is legal history
a field worth studying
for me?
The first argument is,
of course,
all the legal experts in the court
are historians,
because the court can only
judge what has happened.
I am going to discuss
whether Su Jianhe killed someone
in the past or not.
Is he guilty or not?
We can only discuss
whether he killed someone in the past.
The court cannot decide
whether he will kill someone in the future.
This is a matter of fact.
The court can only deal with
what has happened.
From the legal point of view,
when we make a judgment,
the court will always
make a judgment.
In the tradition of British and American law,
there are many cases
that are not in the text,
so you have to tell everyone
whether the case in front of you
is the same as the case in the past.
If it is the same,
you should apply the same law.
If it is different,
you should make another explanation.
There are some famous cases
where, for example,
a court said that
A car must pay
$10,000.
Later,
a new case came out
where
A was hit by B car.
Then
A told the court
that the driver of B car
should pay me $10,000.
But the lawyer of B car said
no, no, no,
our case is different from A car.
Because A car is black
and B car is red.
Because humans are more alert
when they see a red car.
So
when they are hit,
they have to take more responsibility
because they see a red car.
British and American law
has been debating this kind of thing,
so you have to keep looking at
the past cases
as they are now.
Then you need a lot of
historical training
The second thing is that
there is a saying in English
that the past is like a foreign country.
So when we study
the history of law,
it's like we are studying
another country.
So it's like we are now in Taiwan,
we are going to legislate.
We will refer to what the Japanese do,
what the Germans do,
what the Americans do.
Because these comparisons
can give you some ideas.
But if you refer to other countries,
you will be surprised.
Because from a psychological point of view,
people all have this
in-domain effect.
It's not good to play big
in front of the case.
But you will think
what you have is the best.
But sometimes when you look at
foreign things,
you will know that
there are many different ways
in this world.
For example, if I want to control
cigarettes,
can I refer to
how people controlled
opium in the past?
Of course, opium and cigarettes
are different things.
But you can think about
some new ideas.
The second thing is that
we all know that
humans have a path to rely on.
There is one thing that people
have been doing for a long time,
and the legal history
can help you understand
the background of this system
and its reasons.
What did people think at that time?
After understanding the reason for
the path to rely on,
we should now verify that
this condition no longer exists
or the condition has changed,
which means that
we should do something different.
For example,
in the debate on same-sex marriage,
it is said that two people
of the same sex can get married.
If not, why?
If there is, why?
Has it really changed now?
Another common legal history
is the debate on
the structure of mainstream.
For example, we used to think
that Hitler's Nazi was terrible
because he killed Jews.
He set up a prison court
and let the judge judge
that homosexuals and Jews
are inferior species
and are not suitable for having children.
On the other hand,
the United States
is a free and democratic defender.
Through World War II,
the United States
liberated
these oppressed people.
James Whitman,
a professor at Yale University,
is also a doctor of history.
He wrote a book
called Hitler's American Model.
He said that
Hitler's
racial discrimination law
was widely referred to
in the United States
as the law of racial discrimination
that oppresses black people.
In fact, Hitler once said
that Americans were too fierce to black people.
We can't be so fierce.
So, how did Hitler
know how to use the law
to oppress minorities?
It came from the United States.
This is what I am doing now.
I am using the third world approach
to look at the international law.
In the past,
we thought that the international law
was a principle of equal interaction
between sovereign states.
But in fact, it was not.
We know that the international law
was once used to oppress
and to colonize.
The Third World Approach
to International Law
has a group of scholars.
Their goal is to tell you
how the international law
from the European international law
to the international law of the world
has contributed a lot to China,
Japan, Latin America, etc.
They want to tell you
that the international law
is a tool of oppression.
We should not allow the international law
to become a tool of oppression again.
We must preserve these historical memories.
This is what I think
the legal history is doing.
Before I share my research,
I would like to know
if you have any questions.
I can answer first.
I would like to know
what is the general history
and what is the legal history.
I think I have learned a lot.
Even if I am a lawyer,
Should I continue?
It seems that
everyone is still digesting.
The information is a bit large.
I will try to speak in plain language.
I don't know if
everyone can understand.
I think I have made it clear.
I have heard a lot of concepts
for the first time.
I am not sure
but you have made it clear today.
The language is very good.
I think it has helped me
to digest so much information.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
I have a question.
I am curious
about the background
you set up
in the beginning.
What is history?
The front part
and the back part
are there any differences in views?
If so,
what do you think?
Today's speech
is mainly to
deconstruct nationalism.
In the past, foreign law
was described as
a symbol of
a third world people,
Chinese, Japanese,
or non-Western people
being oppressed.
But I will tell you
that the actual operation
of this theory
is based on two things.
The first is that
I want to improve
the meaning of the theory.
In the future,
I may want to
use other methods
of political,
economic,
and socialization
to make it more abstract
and more applicable.
I also hope you can
give me some advice.
Many people
are not familiar with
law and history,
so I hope I can
give you a brief introduction
of what I am doing in this field.
I also want to
take this opportunity
to let you know
what is the purpose
of the American Academy of Law
and what is the purpose
of the American Academy of Law.
Did I answer your question?
Yes, you did.
Thank you.
If not,
please continue.
Thank you.
I think the training
from Northwestern University
is very interesting.
Foreign students
have to take a class
in English.
The teacher will teach us
some tips.
When you don't know what to say,
just take a sip of water.
No one will ask you
why you are drinking water.
Sometimes,
you can relax
and think about
what you want to say.
Let's move on
to the topic of
extracurricular law.
Extracurricular law,
at least for me,
is a term
but we don't know
what actually happens
to it.
To put it simply,
extracurricular law
is the privilege that
foreigners are not
under the jurisdiction
of the local courts.
In other words,
in 1900,
if an American
stole or committed a crime
in China
or any other country
wanted to sue him,
the Chinese government
and the Chinese courts
couldn't do anything
because he was under the jurisdiction
of the local courts.
Only the U.S. courts
or the U.S. courts
can deal with such cases.
This is extracurricular law.
Extracurricular law still exists
in some countries.
For example,
if an American
raped a woman
or a child
in a local court,
the Japanese courts
couldn't bring him to trial
because he was under the jurisdiction
of the U.S. courts.
It's not that the U.S. courts
couldn't bring him to trial,
but the U.S. courts.
It sounds unreasonable.
Let's move on.
The first time that
the U.S. signed a treaty
was in 1842,
the Treaty of Nanjing,
China signed a treaty
after the Opium War.
In this treaty,
the U.K. required
China to provide
extracurricular law to the U.K.
The U.S. signed the treaty
in 1844,
the Treaty of Wangxia,
China.
In Chinese textbooks,
extracurricular law
is a symbol of
imperialism.
Today, our country's citizens
are being bullied.
Why doesn't our country
promote justice?
Why does the U.S. court
have to bring him to trial?
The U.S. court
must be very biased.
must tolerate
the U.S. people
because the U.S. people
betrayed the sovereignty
of China.
The U.S. court must
revolutionize the U.S.
The U.S. court
must abolish extracurricular law
so that the Chinese people
will no longer be bullied.
Is it really like this?
Let's move on.
For example,
when the U.S. came to China
to negotiate the Treaty of Wangxia,
the U.S. diplomat,
William Cushing,
gave a speech
in the U.S. Congress.
He said,
his proudest moment
was when the U.S. wrote
the extracurricular law
in the Treaty of Wangxia.
Because China
is an uncivilized place.
The judges in their countries
do not have three powers.
The county magistrates
How can the county magistrates
be the judges?
In Taiwan,
can He Wen-je be a judge?
No.
Administrative and judicial
should be separated.
China is an uncivilized country.
If you commit a serious crime,
you will be imprisoned,
you will be tortured,
you will be beaten.
If our people
are the most advanced species,
how can we obey the laws of the barbarians?
Therefore,
obtaining the extracurricular law
is a civilized victory.
It sounds like a good idea.
However,
historians have found
that before 1868,
we could not find
any Chinese history
against the extracurricular law.
This is actually
a very strange thing.
If China is so powerful,
why does China never object
to all the negotiations?
China thinks it is good.
Why?
If you want to extracurricular law,
we will give it to you.
This question
is related to a very popular research topic
in recent history,
which is the multidimensionalism
of the empire and the law.
In fact,
the majority of human history
is dominated by the British
and the Germans.
In fact,
the majority of human history
is dominated by the Empire.
What is the Empire?
The simplest definition
is that
under a regime,
there are many different
ethnic groups
and activists.
For example,
the Qing Dynasty
was an empire
with Han people,
Tibetans,
Mongols,
ethnic minorities
and Xinjiang people.
The next question is
that we all know that
there is a law called the Qing Dynasty Law.
But did the Qing Dynasty Law
apply in Tibet?
Did the Qing Dynasty Law
apply in Xinjiang?
In fact, it did not.
Although the Qing Dynasty Law
applied to most empires,
the Roman Empire
also applied the law to the Jews.
In the Qing Dynasty,
the Mongols still applied
the traditional Mongolian law,
while the Tibetans still applied the Tibetan law.
Only the Han people
applied the Qing Dynasty Law.
This is understandable.
When a country is very large
and is an empire,
how could it be possible
to force a Mongolian
to marry in a Confucian way?
This is also a question of
the cost of rule.
In order to maintain the operation of an empire
and the coordination of the ethnic groups,
you must use different laws
to treat different people.
This is now called
the law pluralism.
Does Taiwan want to do the same thing?
Should the indigenous people
apply the indigenous law
or not?
From the perspective of China,
in 1842,
the British said
that they wanted to
apply the British law in China.
Think about it.
What's wrong with
the Mongolians
applying the Mongolian law
and the British applying the British law?
At that time,
foreigners could only
move around
when they came to China.
Basically,
it did not affect the original life of the Han people.
Therefore,
there is nothing wrong with
giving you a piece of land
and having your own law.
In 1842,
foreigners were limited to Guangzhou.
We call it the Guangzhou system.
Originally in Guangzhou,
in 1842,
China had already admitted
that the Americans could apply the British law
in Guangzhou.
Therefore, in 1842 and 1844,
foreigners came to China
and told the negotiators
that they wanted to apply the foreign law.
The Chinese thought it was good,
so they gave it to them.
However, in 1868,
people found that something was wrong.
At first,
there were many cases
in which
foreigners committed crimes
in China
and could not be punished.
In these cases,
too many countries had foreign law,
so the legal vacuum was created.
Finally,
in 1910,
there were 23 countries with foreign law in China.
We often see in the files
that an American
committed a crime
and was arrested in the U.S. Court.
The first defense he made was
that he was not an American,
but an Englishman.
Because he had a lot of passports,
he kept hiding.
Later, he made Shanghai the most
famous criminal heaven in the world,
because everyone would not be arrested.
This problem became more and more serious,
affecting China's security,
China's economic development,
and so on.
Later,
he began to think that
it was a matter of right to enter the country,
and we had to oppose it.
To this day,
there is a modern meaning.
For example,
every year on January 11th,
there is a Judiciary Day,
and the Judiciary Council
holds a seminar and a celebration.
Why is there a Judiciary Day
on January 11th?
Because January 11th, 1943
was the day
when China and the U.S.
signed an equal treaty
and abolished foreign law.
They thought that from that day on,
the judicial system of the Republic of China
would no longer be dominated by the West.
Since then,
the Nationalist government
moved to Taiwan in 1949,
so the Judiciary Day
is still on January 11th.
Do you still remember
the Lincoln case?
It was about a British man
who died in Taiwan.
Later, he fled the country
and returned to the U.K.
At that time,
when the U.K. Supreme Court
ruled that Lincoln
should be transferred back to Taiwan,
the representative of the U.K.
was Ambassador St. Luke.
I took his class with Ian.
Ambassador St. Luke was
the Minister of Foreign Affairs
at the time,
and I took his class with Ian.
He wrote in the newspaper
that Lincoln should have
a symbolic meaning.
Because the law of the U.K.
and its citizens
cannot be transferred to
an uncivilized country.
At that time,
Ambassador St. Luke wrote
that the Lincoln case
proved that the U.K.
had already become
a legally civilized country,
so the U.K. would be willing
to transfer people back to Taiwan.
However, when the U.K. Supreme Court
overturned the ruling,
the U.K. was defeated.
As a result,
the U.K. had to
fight against foreign law.
My question is very simple.
Is it really easier to fight against
foreign law?
We can see that
the U.S. has to maintain
a court in China,
and it has to invest a lot of money.
And we can also
intuitively find that
if a U.S. court
in China
favors U.S. citizens,
Chinese people
should not do business
with U.S. citizens.
Chinese people do not want to
get along with U.S. citizens,
which will worsen Sino-U.S. relations
and damage U.S. business interests in China.
My question is
if foreign law is really better,
how does it actually work?
Let's look for its file.
Excuse me, can I ask a question?
Yes, go ahead.
I want to ask...
You can go back to the presentation.
Okay.
I want to ask...
I want to explain that
the person who asked the question
can introduce himself.
Okay.
I'm Hong Shaoming.
I'm also a post-doc at Caltech.
I graduated from the Department of Psychology at NTU.
I want to ask...
When you talk about foreign law,
you put foreign law
and multilateralism
together.
But their essence is the same.
At least on the surface,
when you talk about
multilateralism,
it feels like you're talking about
a country with different laws
for different groups.
But foreign law is about
the relationship between
countries.
You mentioned that
before 1868,
China didn't oppose foreign law.
Maybe they thought
foreign law was one form
of multilateralism.
After 25 years,
they thought it wasn't right.
It wasn't the same as we imagined.
It's about the relationship
between countries.
Do you have any opinion on this?
Thank you.
I should say that
under the pre-modern rule,
everyone can accept multilateralism.
Because it's a low-cost
method that can maintain national governance.
So most of the current research
believes that
before 1868,
Chinese central government officials
simply believed that
it was a matter of multilateralism.
It's not necessarily within a country.
For example,
when the Pope came to China,
China also respected the idea
of using its own laws to deal with
its own problems.
After 1868,
I think it was because
China wanted to modernize.
So in the process of modernization,
it hoped that the whole country
would adopt the same laws.
Because this approach
can achieve the central authority
and mobilization that modern countries want.
We can also see that
after the founding of the Republic of China,
China hoped that
Tibet, Mongolia, and Xinjiang
would adopt the laws of the Republic of China.
China no longer respected its autonomy.
Its autonomy became very limited.
The current People's Republic of China
also hopes that
Mongolia, Tibet, and Xinjiang
will adopt the laws of the People's Republic of China.
I think the same is true for Hong Kong.
At the beginning,
China thought that
it had adopted multilateralism,
and that Hong Kong people could continue
to use the law of the Republic of China.
However, when China wanted to
modernize the country,
it wanted to adopt
multilateralism.
After all, we are one nation,
one country.
Why can't we all
use different things?
I think this idea
is related to the nature of a nation.
If all people,
whether you are Mongolian,
or Tibetan,
are different,
it means that China
is not a single nation.
I think the real difference
between multilateralism
and unilateralism
is the effect
it brings
on the central power
and sovereignty
in the process of
transferring from the empire
to a democratic country.
I think multilateralism
and unilateralism
are different things.
Not necessarily.
Unilateralism is
a legal multilateralism.
Let me think.
Yes, they are different things.
It should be said that
under a democratic country,
it wants its people
to adopt the same set of laws.
The reason why foreigners
have adopted the same set of laws
is because
they have the potential
to show the spirit
of legal multilateralism.
In some countries,
however,
legal multilateralism
and unilateralism
are different things.
They think they are different things.
Legal multilateralism is possible,
but unilateralism is not.
They can also explain
why China did not object
to unilateralism.
In the beginning,
they thought it was the same thing.
They found that
it was a different thing.
When it interfered with
the sovereignty of our country,
they began to oppose it.
If such an attack is established,
legal multilateralism
does not seem to be able
to support whether foreign law
is good or bad.
I think I will go back to
what I said at the beginning.
Historians will ask
why they could not find
opposition in 1868.
We will think that
the subjective will of
the historical activists
mixed them with
legal multilateralism.
That's right.
The reason why
people did not object
is that
people at that time
did not think
it was the same thing.
In the beginning,
they thought it was the same thing,
so they did not object.
Later, they found that
it was not the same thing.
It seems that
the range of influence
is not the same.
Anyway,
we have spent too much time
on this topic.
Thank you.
Oh, is that so?
Does it prove that Taiwan
is a civilized country?
Well,
the main reason why
Taiwan was invited
was to ask
whether there was a significant difference
between the British and the Taiwanese
in terms of mass movement.
I see.
Please go on.
OK, I will finish it soon.
I seem to have a little bit of plagiarism.
I will finish it soon.
So,
my research mainly focuses on
the judicial reform of the United States
in Shanghai in 1906.
From 1844 to 1905,
the U.S. did not establish
a formal court in China.
Therefore,
we often hear the term
consular trial.
What is a consular trial?
It is when a diplomat
consulates as a judge.
He will be sent to the local consulate
to be tried.
Who is a judge?
It is a diplomat.
Sometimes,
this diplomat also has some legislative powers.
This is a tricky situation.
When the U.S. criticized
China's law of non-discrimination
and non-civilization,
the U.S. did not discriminate.
The diplomat is an executive,
and he has the right to be tried.
At the same time,
the diplomat is not civilized at all.
The diplomat is more like
a governor-general,
or even more like
a magistrate in China,
like Bao Qingtian,
who is both a mayor and a judge.
Furthermore,
the U.S. was not a rich country
at that time.
The U.S. did not invest
a lot of personnel,
finance,
and legal professionals in China.
For example,
the U.S. sentenced a person to prison.
At first,
the U.S. did not even have a prison.
The U.S. even rented a prison
to the British and French,
because the U.S. built a prison
in Shanghai earlier than the French.
Why did the U.S. have
a legislative reform in 1906?
For me,
this is a modern Chinese country
that has encountered
the U.S. imperialism.
In this video,
we can see two figures.
The first figure is
the date when the U.S.
acquired the colony.
We can see Hawaii,
Wake Island, Samoa,
the Philippines,
and Panama.
They were all acquired
at the end of the 19th century
or the beginning of the 20th century.
In other words,
between 1844 and 1900,
the average trade volume
between China and the U.S.
increased significantly
and even doubled.
This expansion of the U.S. imperialism
brought a lot of trade
between China and the U.S.
At that time,
the U.S. business community
began to respond
to the U.S. federal government
that the Supreme Court
was not enough
to resolve the trade dispute
between China and the U.S.
Because these judges
are not legal people.
They are just diplomats.
As we all know,
our diplomats abroad
are also responsible
for business affairs.
They do not have legal expertise
and are not able
to do a trial.
So the efficiency of the court
is very low
and it is very painful
for these people
including sex workers,
gamblers, and vagabonds.
At that time,
U.S. missionaries in China
believed that these illegal immigrants
had a serious impact on the image
of the U.S. in China.
In 1900,
there was a protest in Shanghai
against the U.S. import movement.
The U.S. consulates
were highly tolerant of sex workers.
So in 1900,
all the white prostitutes in Shanghai
said that they were American.
At that time,
the word American Girl
meant prostitutes.
When a prostitute was arrested,
she would say,
I am American.
When she was sent to the U.K.
court,
she would say,
I am American.
When she was sent to the U.S.
court,
she would say,
I am American.
So we can see that
the word extraterritoriality
and consular jurisdiction
were not important
concepts to the U.S.
until 1900.
The frequency of
extraterritoriality
and consular jurisdiction
increased significantly
after 1900.
On the other hand,
we all know that
the Eight-Nation Allied Forces
were attacked in Beijing.
After the attack,
Beijing signed the Qing Dynasty
Treaty.
After the Treaty,
the Qing Dynasty began
to reform the modern legal system.
At that time,
the reform of the modern legal system
was to transform Chinese law
into Western modern law.
Basically,
we see so-called
Legislative Codespotism
and white light law
later.
We will see some citations
of that book
referred to
the Great Qing Ming-Liu case.
This case was
published in 1906.
As a result,
in 1903,
the arms tribunals
signed an agreement
that China
should start
legal and judicial reform.
Western countries should help us.
If they help us,
we will abolish
foreign law.
At that time,
the U.S. faced two pressures.
The first was
the expansion of
the U.S. Empire
and the development of
Sino-US trade relations
and the reform of
the U.S. Constitution.
The second was
the reform of
the U.S. Constitution.
If the U.S. becomes
a modern,
civilized,
and three-party
court,
the U.S.
will not have
a place to stand.
In 1906,
the U.S. established
the United States Court for China.
It appointed a judge
who had graduated from
the University of Yale
and was the director of
the Philippine Procuratorate
and established a modern
and formal court.
After the judge came to power,
he did three things.
The first thing he did
was to declare that
he would not have any
business dealings with the U.S.
because the U.S. business community
wanted him to deal with
some business cases and disputes.
Instead, he dealt with
brothels and casinos.
He felt that there were
many U.S. lawyers
who had a bad image of the Chinese.
So he called all the U.S.
lawyers in Shanghai
for a lawyer exam.
The U.S. lawyer exam
made 80% of the people
think that U.S. lawyers
should not come to the U.S.
court.
The next thing he did
was to sue the boss
of eight brothels
and four casinos.
In the past,
the U.S. lawyers used
the same trick
to say that
they were not U.S.
lawyers,
but the judge
who asked them
if they used
U.S. consulates.
He even asked the U.S. consulate
to open their diplomatic documents
and see if they had
a passport in the U.S. consulate.
Some of the U.S. lawyers
did not give a reason
and said,
I do not care,
you are an American.
He wanted to eliminate
the legal vacuum
that caused
a fierce backlash
among the U.S. community
in Shanghai.
The U.S. judge was
impeached and resigned
a year later.
The next U.S. judge
did not care.
In the future,
I think there are several
theoretical meanings
that can be developed.
The first is
that cross-border trade
is very common.
For example,
if a Japanese
signs a trade contract
with a Singaporean,
he or she can use
the New York State Act
to settle the dispute
in Paris.
I think
the current situation
is similar to the past.
China in the 19th century
pushed the situation
to extremes.
For example,
there are nine countries
in Tianjin.
In Tianjin,
there are ten laws
in the same city.
There are some
theories that can be developed.
The next is
system competition.
We know that
in a globalized era,
many countries
will look for
low-cost institutions.
For example,
labor laws
or environmental laws
are relatively loose.
At that time,
there were more than
20 countries in China
who competed
with each other
for the greatest interests
in China.
I don't know
if there are more theories
that can be developed.
The next is
modern foreign law.
For example,
the US military
has foreign law in Chongqing.
Is there any way
to push back
or deny the existence
of foreign law
from the actual
implementation of
the United States?
At that time,
the United States had a very
intense backlash in China,
which made it believe
that the United States
should not throw
taxpayers' money
overseas for foreign law.
In fact,
Americans have been
faced with the fact
that they cannot
manage their citizens
without the support
of the United States.
Is it really beneficial?
For example,
the image of the United States
is so bad,
and if the court is not fair,
the Chinese will resist your goods.
Therefore,
foreign law
is not something
that can be implemented
indefinitely.
In addition to the law itself,
it is also necessary
to understand the context
of these systems,
and then think about
more theoretical and abstract things
according to your research.
That's all for today.
Thank you.
By Mr.
Parry.
Thank you.