Ok, let's start.
Ok, first I need to introduce myself.
Please introduce yourself, thank you.
Ok, I have prepared a few videos.
I will use them to introduce myself.
Today, I will talk about the simple introduction of metal solvents.
My name is Zeyu Lin, and I am a post-doctoral researcher in Japan.
First, I will give a brief self-introduction.
As I mentioned, I am a post-doctoral researcher in Japan.
My department is the National Research and Development Department of the Institute of Materials and Materials Research.
My main job here is...
Sorry, let me use the laser pointer.
My main job here is to connect the material's microstructure with its mechanical properties,
as well as its related performance characteristics.
At present, I am working on the development of high-strength and high-durability ferrous alloys,
as well as the microstructure of permanent magnets,
as well as the development of some raw materials.
Today, I would like to introduce my post-doctoral research...
No, I mean my work accumulated during my post-doctoral studies,
and my post-doctoral research in February this year,
which is about four years of work.
The field of research is mainly the solid-state integration of copper,
which is similar in nature, as well as liquid metal.
The integration technology used is a technology called ultrasonic integration.
Its principle is to use high-pressure and high frequency vibration to achieve the deformation of the material to form the node.
It can be used in steel, high-strength steel, or aluminum alloy, etc.
It can be used in...
The main scene that can be considered is that the composite structure of multi-materials,
such as the structure of the car body,
can achieve the goal characteristics of lightweighting and high strength.
Sorry, I just made a mistake.
I graduated from Tokyo University of Japan in 2019,
and majored in material engineering.
My other major is the Department of Chemical Engineering at Tsinghua University of China,
and the Department of Chemical Engineering at Tsinghua University of China.
That's all for the main self-introduction.
Next, I'm going to start introducing today's main speech topic,
which is mainly about the integration of solid-state and liquid metal materials that are similar in nature,
and then use ultrasonic integration to observe the strength of its interface.
First, I will give a simple background introduction.
In the engineering background,
listeners may be more familiar with the fact that
steel is a very solid base.
It is one of the basic and indispensable materials.
The picture on the left shows that
there are about 15% to 20% of steel in the world every year.
Because there are a lot of steel applications,
including architecture, general people, military facilities, transportation, etc.
It accounts for about 15% to 20% of transportation.
It is mainly applied to the construction of car parts and the structure of the car body.
There are a lot of types of steel used,
including soft steel, medium-strength, high-strength, and ultra-high-strength steel.
At present, the development field of materials is mainly focused on
how to improve its extensibility and high-strength, etc.
The picture on the lower left is called DynamoCurve,
which is a curve distribution like a banana.
Why is there such a distribution?
It is mainly derived from the fact that the strength of the material increases,
but the extensibility does not decrease.
Based on the background of traditional physics,
such strength and extensibility are indispensable.
However, many scientists are using various methods
to try to get out of this field.
The current research situation is to try to achieve the high strength and high extensibility of both, etc.
Why do we need such a high-strength steel development?
It is mainly used when the car body is hit by a heavy object.
High-strength steel can often provide stronger support
to avoid fatal damage to passengers.
In order to improve safety,
the current material development is mainly focused on high-strength and high extensibility, etc.
What kind of steel is used?
Different strengths of steel are used in different areas of the car body structure.
This is a simple introduction.
You can clearly see that
if the car is hit by a heavy object,
the stress and gravity come from the front and back, etc.
At this time, you need a high-strength structural material
to support the entire car body.
The current high-strength steel developed by traditional physics
has reached 780, 980, 1180, etc.
This represents the strength of steel,
which is about 550 MPa.
The current mainstream high-strength steel is
concentrated in the front and back of 1000 MPa.
This is the current situation in which the structural material is used.
On the other hand,
if we don't use steel,
and we use a high-strength material,
it will not be able to support the entire car body.
On the other hand,
if we don't use steel,
and we use a high-strength material,
such as aluminum, copper, and carbon fiber, etc.
If we use this material,
it can be made very lightweight
and has sufficient safety.
However, the price is also very high.
As you can see here,
for a good car like Audi R8,
the recommended price in 2020 is about $70,000.
This price is hard to meet for ordinary people.
So we mainly use traditional steel
and aluminum and carbon fiber.
In this respect,
you have to make a choice
in terms of cost and mechanical quality.
The name of the car body structure we often use in our industry
is a multi-material structure.
Multi-Material Structure
As you can see here,
in addition to steel,
it also has a lot of external body parts,
such as the door, engine cover, etc.
In order to make it lightweight,
we usually use aluminum alloy.
The main maintenance material is aluminum alloy.
In this respect,
when the car body is assembled,
we mainly use
high-strength steel
and aluminum alloy.
In this respect,
they need to be fixed and processed
to form a complete structure.
It is conceivable that
some processes need to be processed
to combine them together.
In recent years,
in addition to the emission of environmental regulations,
the demand for lightweighting is increasing.
On the right side of the slide,
there is a picture of
the materials used in the field of cars
in 2030,
including aluminum and high-strength steel.
HSF stands for High Strength Steel.
The ratio of these two materials
will increase from 29% to 57%.
In the near future,
in order to establish high strength
and lightweighting,
we will use more aluminum
and more high-strength steel.
Therefore, how to combine
iron and lightweighting alloy
in the manufacturing process
is quite important.
Now we will introduce
the traditional way
of combining materials
and manufacturing technology,
i.e. welding.
Traditionally,
we define welding
as a process
in which two separate materials
are heated
to a high temperature
and then combined
to produce
sufficient quality
welding.
In this process,
the defects
will gradually disappear.
At such a high temperature,
along with the change
in the structure
of the fibers
and the growth
of the center,
heat is also affected,
and so on.
In this regard,
the material itself
is mechanically affected
by the change
in the structure
of the fibers.
After the welding point
is formed,
all the fibers
around it
will undergo
huge changes.
Such changes
are sometimes not
completely positive.
How to prevent
low-performance
welding?
In general,
if we use
a high temperature
to melt steel
and aluminum,
we will encounter several problems.
The first is that
aluminum and steel
have very different melting points.
The melting point of aluminum
is about 600 degrees,
while steel is about
1400 to 1500 degrees.
Therefore,
at such a high temperature,
it will produce
a huge
expansion.
The expansion
will form
many compounds
between
steel and aluminum.
This compound
is not
conducive to
mechanical performance.
Why?
The problem is that
it is very brittle
and unbearable to impact.
After a little impact,
it will crack
like ceramics
or glass.
At the same time,
it will also
produce cracks
in the joint
between the
welding points.
This is
quite disadvantageous to
mechanical manufacturing.
That is to say,
it is quite disadvantageous
to use general
combination technology
to combine steel and aluminum
at high temperature.
In other words,
what we may
consider next
is how to reduce
the temperature of the
welding point
to a certain degree.
In other words,
we will focus on
how to combine
steel and aluminum.
We need to combine at
the melting point of
aluminum, which is about
660 degrees.
At this temperature,
it is called solidification.
Next,
I will briefly introduce
solidification.
As I mentioned earlier,
it can combine
two components
and
it will not
melt during the process.
Its heating is also
lower than the melting point of any material.
We need to introduce
more concepts
such as sufficient deformation
at the material interface.
At sufficient temperature,
the interface will expand.
After the expansion,
the defect will gradually disappear
to achieve
the effect of combination.
Here is our main
design concept.
The main concept of solidification
is how to make
the defect on the interface disappear,
including holes and
cavities, etc.
At the same time,
most materials
usually have a layer of
pollutants on the surface,
such as carbon
and oxygen,
and other compounds.
At the same time,
there will be a certain
degree of oxidation film
on the surface.
You may have heard
that aluminum
is very easy to oxidize.
It forms a layer
of oxidizing film
on the surface.
This oxidizing film
has a sufficient quality
to protect the material
from further oxidation.
This kind of oxidizing film
is quite beneficial
in combination.
Traditionally, we still
have to achieve the contact
between the atomic and
pure atoms
to form an aqueous bond.
In other words,
the bond between the
atom and the atom
or the metal bond,
etc.
On the other hand,
we can say that
we have introduced
enough deformation
at high temperature
to make it like clay
to stir and form a
interlocking interface structure.
OK.
Here,
we will
make a brief introduction
about solid-state integration.
Traditionally,
the first way of integration
is called expansion integration.
The main principle is to use
high pressure and high temperature
to apply on two objects
that need to be integrated.
With such high temperature and high pressure,
sufficient time can form
a bond.
This way of integration
can be applied on
metal or ceramic
or metal or even
carbon fiber.
But the problem is that
the integration time is quite long
and requires a higher temperature.
At the same time,
if the interface passes
a high temperature and a long time,
it will form an
overly complex structure,
including metal-based objects,
which we mentioned earlier,
forming a layer
like ceramic,
a non-extensible middle layer.
This middle layer
has a very weak mechanical nature
and is not conducive to the overall integration strength.
On the other hand,
the other
is friction-mixing integration.
The principle is
to use a high-speed
rotation
weld head
directly on the surface
to form a high temperature.
After the high temperature,
the material will gradually soften,
but it is not yet at the melting point.
So it will be like
clay.
After it softens,
this weld head can be pressed down
and then start to move.
Then move along
the seam between the two.
Let the defect of the interface
gradually pass through
and move and soften.
But on the other hand,
this material
can be used in all kinds of
aluminum alloy, aluminum-ferrous alloy,
etc. Its application range is quite wide.
For example,
let's take the
Japanese alloy as an example.
It mainly uses
this type of
alloying technology
for the
combination of
interfaces.
On the other hand,
its shortcomings are
that it takes a long time to
combine.
At the same time,
on the other hand,
the time it takes to combine
also takes a long time to
combine.
This may be due to the
shortcomings of the interface
and the shape of the
intermetallic alloy.
So
based on this
background,
based on this research background,
we use another type of
alloying technology.
This is called ultrasonic welding.
The principle of ultrasonic welding
may be mentioned earlier.
It is a certain degree of pressure
on the two overlapping
bows.
It is about
15,000 to 24,000
degrees of vibration.
Then the interface is friction-heated.
In this state,
the interface will
deform unilaterally.
After deformation,
it will form a fiber structure
that forms a ring.
This causes the surface
interface to disappear
and the welding point to form.
In this respect,
we believe that
it can be used in
the future.
Because it does not
follow the fusion,
it will not produce a large amount of
intermetallic alloys that are
not conducive to mechanical strength.
Therefore, it is expected to be
used in the future.
It can be used in
car lightweighting
and high-strength composite
structure materials manufacturing,
etc.
Its advantages include
lower
fusion temperature
compared to
normal welding.
At the same time,
its interface friction
heat is formed in a
relatively small area.
The friction heat
formed in the small area
is relatively small
for the overall
fiber structure change.
In this way,
under the strength
of the material itself
and the machine itself,
it can be fully combined
to produce a relatively small
fiber structure change.
This is quite beneficial
to the overall manufacturing.
On the other hand,
the picture on the
bottom right is the
application of the current
superfine wave fusion
on the machine-made
rolling wheel.
In the rolling wheel,
it is the high-speed vibration
of the water and the
friction heat of the interface
is formed and the
water is transformed
into a fusion
to carry out
the machine-made
process.
The superfine wave
fusion itself is not
a relatively new technology.
It was first used in the
1960s.
At first, the main application
scene was the
printing circuit board
and the wiring of
various chips.
It is a technology
often used in
circuit board manufacturing.
It also uses
pressure and vibration
to complete the
fusion on the machine board.
It is a process
of pressure and vibration.
Combining the main principles,
we can make a
more detailed introduction.
Traditionally,
there may be hundreds to thousands
of newtons of pressure.
After pressing,
the two bows
will be welded
and the base will be fixed.
High-speed vibration will begin
to form.
The vibration is usually
about 20 to 60 micrometers
per second,
which is about
15,000 to 24,000
per second.
In such a short and
dense vibration,
the interface will
generate a lot of deformation
and a lot of friction heat
will appear.
Friction heat and deformation
combine to form the interface.
In this process,
the interface
will undergo high-speed
deformation.
After the deformation,
different phenomena such as
heat and expansion
will appear.
Therefore, in so many
interfaces,
the interface formation mechanism
is quite difficult to
understand,
especially in the case of
soft metal materials.
In the case of harder materials,
such as steel and
carbon,
it is quite rare
to study the formation
of the interface mechanism
in the scene.
Therefore,
our main research
is on the hard materials.
Assuming that
we are now
progressing to how to
use superfine fiber
in the application of hard materials,
mainly in some
advanced research,
most of the superfine fiber
is used in aluminum alloy
or plastic alloy,
which is a soft material.
The interface will form
a different degree of friction flow,
that is, after it reaches a high temperature,
it will constantly
deform and squeeze.
The deformation and squeezing process
causes a lot of changes
in the fiber structure of the interface.
However,
such a situation will not
appear in the human position
on the hard material.
If you want to combine
superfine fiber
on a steel
with a higher strength,
steel, iron, and
aluminum alloy,
this part needs to be further explored.
On the other hand,
if it is used in hard materials,
the combination of steel and aluminum
has been done
a lot of advanced research
in the superfine fiber combination.
They are mainly concentrated
in a short time,
within a few seconds,
they can form
about 30 minutes
in the expansion combination
of superfine fiber
and intermetallics.
Such a combination
is not conducive
to the mechanical properties
mentioned earlier.
Most of the research
focuses on this later stage
of superfine fiber
formation.
On the other hand,
in the early days,
the material was friction
and deformed after friction.
How will the formation
of intermetallics
evolve?
This mechanism
is relatively rare.
However, this part is also true.
The application of superfine fiber
in the combination of steel
and aluminum has a significant
impact.
We mainly
understand
how to use superfine fiber
in the superfine fiber
combination
situation.
This is divided into two parts.
The first one
will be divided into
the phenomenon of
no interface reaction
when combined.
On the other hand,
we will use another type of
metal combination
to discuss
how to combine
superfine fiber
in the superfine fiber
combination situation.
The first part
is to understand
how to combine
superfine fiber
in the superfine fiber
combination situation.
We will use steel and aluminum.
Why do we use steel and aluminum?
The main purpose is that
there is no interface reaction
between the two,
so it is difficult
to analyze the interface.
As a comparison,
we use steel and aluminum to combine.
On the other hand,
from the previous principle introduction,
it can be known that
only high-speed friction
will cause interface contact.
The depth of the contact point
and the roughness of the material surface
have a significant impact.
This research
is not enough.
On the other hand,
one part of the research
also focuses on the roughness of the surface
and the impact on the strength of the combination.
On the other hand,
because we have to use steel
and other materials to combine,
the mechanical performance of steel
such as hardness and strength
and other changes
will also affect the nature of the combination.
Therefore, the hardness of the iron itself
and the different microstructures
will also have an impact
.
On the other hand,
this part is the combination of hard materials
such as steel and aluminum, steel and titanium, etc.
Why choose these two combinations?
Mainly because the two
aluminum and titanium have different
deformation capabilities at high temperatures.
Therefore, when we plan to explore
the origin of the combination,
what impact
these two different materials
and their deformation capabilities
have on the combination of the two?
Because of time,
we will directly enter the
experimental step.
First of all, it is the combination of steel and aluminum
to form the interface.
The material we use
is a non-metallic atomic steel,
which is a relatively soft
medium-strength steel
and a pure aluminum plate
as a research subject.
On the surface,
we will use
a mirror-surfacer
to measure the roughness
of the surface.
Next,
we use a superfine grain
to make a superfine grain
combination.
The main combination condition
is that we use a pressure
of about 2000 newtons,
which is applied to
about 10 times the
power of the steel head,
which is accompanied by
about 20,000 times of vibration
. The combination time
is about 0.01 seconds
to 2.0 seconds.
After completing the
superfine grain combination,
the next step is to
stretch the time to judge the
strength of the combination.
After the stretching is broken,
suppose that it is broken on the interface,
we will observe the electronic
microscope and
analyze the microstructure.
On the other hand,
if it is not suitable for
stretching time, we will prepare
another batch of samples that have not yet been stretched.
After the
two halves are cut in half,
the surface is exposed
and the
electronic microscope
and the back image electronic
3D EBSD are observed
to observe the image
and the
deformation of the interface.
First of
all, suppose the
steel head is used,
made of steel and iron,
and the iron plate using
superfine media
on the interface can
be seen for the
angle of integration,
the combination time
against the middle is
stressed.
Its crystal here
is about
2,000 newtons,
which is enough
to break the
IF steel,
that is, the
infinite-sphere atomic steel itself.
It is greater than the strength of the steel itself.
On the other hand,
if we compare it with other
integrations,
such as the expansion integration
using iron and iron,
it requires a relatively long
time, which is about 50 seconds,
and requires a certain degree of
high temperature.
In this case,
if we compare it with the
microstructure of the interface,
its interface deformation
is quite concentrated,
about only 10 micrometers
before and after.
On the other hand,
if we compare it with the
friction-mixing-combination FSW,
its deformation is greater,
about 15 to 20
micrometers.
At the same time, it is accompanied by a very severe deformation.
Such severe deformation
is reliable to the welding point itself.
That is to say,
its durability is
also a subject to
consider.
Therefore,
the superfine-mixing-combination
can be done in a short time
without a lot of deformation
to complete the
superfine-mixing-combination.
On the other hand,
if it is used on
the interface of iron and iron
and iron and nickel,
this part
is that we did
electronic microscope
and EBSD analysis
and found that the
formation of the interface
will form such a
small friction particle.
This friction particle will gradually increase
and at the same time be accompanied by friction
to friction the upper and lower
nickel and iron body.
After enough time
and temperature, it will
gradually be compressed.
After the compression,
it will produce severe deformation
and spread to the entire
interface to complete
the formation of the interface.
At the same time,
it is accompanied by
this
seam,
the seam and
the segment.
If
there is enough time,
it is
superfine-mixing-combination
can form enough
partial and
severe shrinkage deformation.
It can be completed in a short time.
On the other hand,
superfine-mixing-combination
is the surface.
On the other hand,
if we use a thicker
seam, the time of
combining will be shorter.
The time of shrinkage will be longer.
Why does it get longer?
If it is a thick seam,
it will form a thicker
and larger
seam, such as
seam seam and seam seam.
In this way,
how do I compress
these three peaks and three valleys?
It takes a longer time and
pressure to compress it
to form the interface and
form the friction force
to form more combining time.
Therefore,
a slightly smoother
combination interface
does not have any
pollutants or oxidants
at the same time.
What about the type of steel itself?
Assuming that it is replaced,
because what we mentioned earlier
is that it uses
relatively
average fiber structure
ferrite
IF steel.
Next, we will use
polyester
and ferrite
neutral carbon steel
and 14% nickel steel.
There is also 0.08%
low carbon steel.
Their hardness and
microstructure, we will make a
more detailed
comparison.
This part is the
ferrite itself.
In addition to the
IF steel used at the beginning,
we also prepared different types of steel.
Here,
ferrite, porcelain steel, and
martensite steel have different hardness.
As the hardness increases,
the combination strength
is getting lower and lower.
Compared to the beginning,
nickel and IF steel only need
2 seconds to combine.
On the other hand,
neutral carbon steel, including
ferrite and ferrite,
takes about 5 seconds to
combine.
On the other hand,
once the hardness is higher,
about 200 to 300 hardness
martensite steel,
it takes longer to combine.
Why do we have
different situations?
We analyzed the interface
and found that
for the same steel photo,
the bottom is
porcelain steel, the bottom left is
porcelain steel, and the bottom right is ferrite.
Ferrite and nickel will form
more friction resistance.
This friction resistance has a larger
coefficient of friction resistance.
On the other hand,
ferrite and nickel
have relatively low deformation.
At the same time,
there are still
interface defects.
That is to say,
in a harder steel,
it takes a long time to
complete the combination.
At the same time,
we can get
a conclusion that
ferrite and nickel have
relatively similar hardness.
On the other hand,
ferrite and nickel have
relatively similar hardness.
It can provide more
deformation.
Such large-scale deformation
is conducive to the rise of
the combination strength.
This part is
the friction
generated by the
combination.
There are different mechanisms.
The main difference is
the friction between
ferrite and nickel.
The main difference between the two
is that the interface
on the ferrite and nickel
will form
something like a friction resistance.
On the other hand,
if it is nickel,
in the case of nickel,
the harder material
will be
deformed
in the ferrite material
and form a friction resistance.
In other words,
such a situation
occurs when the hardness
gap is relatively large,
such as ferrite and nickel.
In other words,
the first part of our
conclusion can be concentrated
in the appearance of
friction resistance particles
with a relatively large
friction resistance.
On the other hand,
if it is ferrite and nickel,
the friction loss
in the ferrite itself
will take longer
to eliminate
such interface defects
to complete the
combined formation.
The second part
is the
combination strength.
In other words,
in the case of a reaction,
the combined interface
is formed.
As mentioned earlier,
we skip this part.
In other words,
at the initial stage,
before the bonding structure
is formed,
how does the combined interface
develop?
This is the part
to be discussed.
First of all,
in the case of ferrite and nickel,
we use the
traditionally mentioned
IF steel and 5000-gram aluminum alloy.
Then we
do superimposed bonding.
In the process of bonding,
we will stick a thermocouple
on the interface to measure
the temperature of the bonding structure.
The picture on the right shows
the change in strength and time.
It can be clearly seen that
before 0.5 seconds,
the combined strength was very weak
and could not be measured.
After 1 second,
the combined strength rose rapidly
to 2.5 seconds,
and the bonding was completed.
At the same time,
it gradually decreased
due to the serious deformation
of the aluminum itself,
resulting in the fracture
in the aluminum.
Why is there such a change?
We can see that
if we
combine the temperature changes
here,
it rises very rapidly
at the initial temperature,
and it can reach
about 400 degrees in about 1 second.
Here, we have
compared it with the previous study,
and found that the temperature obtained
in 1 second is about 400 degrees.
Once it exceeds 400 degrees,
the aluminum itself
will shrink
and its deformable ability
will increase rapidly,
which is enough to
remove the defect of the interface
and combine it.
On the other hand,
we used the electronic microscope
to observe its interface
and found that as time went by,
it was indeed about 1.1 seconds
that the interface became sticky
and the defect was concentrated in the aluminum.
As time went by,
the interface was gradually completed,
and the defect on this side of the aluminum
gradually disappeared,
and it took 2.5 seconds
to complete a fully integrated interface.
As time went by,
the interface became
more and more sticky.
Therefore,
we can categorize
the whole phenomenon here.
At the beginning of the integration,
the factor of
the strength being too low
caused the aluminum to be friction,
and it will break off from the aluminum
and attach to the iron side
and the IF steel side.
As time goes by,
the aluminum itself
has enough deformable ability at high temperature,
it will gradually be compressed
and the defect can
gradually disappear to complete the integration.
OK.
The other part
is the combination of iron and titanium.
The reason why we
use titanium
is that the deformation ability of
titanium itself at high temperature
is not as obvious as aluminum.
On the other hand,
some basic
physics concepts
may know that titanium is a hexagon.
If the hexagon is deformed
and subjected to friction,
it will have a lot of defects,
so it is a metal
that has relatively little extension ability.
In this way,
the superhexagon
can be found
under the similar conditions
mentioned earlier.
Before 2 seconds,
the strength of the integration
gradually reaches a platform,
which is a stable state.
But after 2 seconds,
the strength of the integration
has increased dramatically
during 2 seconds to 2.5 seconds.
Why does this happen?
At first,
we think that
after 2 seconds,
we will find that
once it exceeds 600 degrees,
it may produce
the hexagon of iron and titanium
on the left.
On the hexagon,
you can see that
there is a lower point of contact here.
At this point of contact,
it will be found that
once the iron has a certain degree of
about 15 to 20%
, it will produce the hexagon.
That is to say,
from the original HCP type
to the BCC type,
BCC's beta type.
BCC's deformation ability
is that
the deformation ability of the
BCC is better than
the HCP of the hexagon
and the most dense hexagon.
In the next step,
in order to verify
our assumption,
we observed the interface
and found that
at about 2.0 seconds,
the interface will
break off
on the side of the
machine itself and stick
to the side of the iron.
After 2 seconds,
up to 2.5 seconds,
the interface's
original gap
will disappear
and become
a hole.
As time goes by,
these holes will gradually disappear.
So,
up to 3 seconds
can complete the interface.
Compared to the expansion
interface mentioned earlier,
it usually takes
about 1 to 2 hours
to complete the interface
of iron and iron type.
On the other hand,
if you use a transverse interface,
you will find that
after about 2.0 seconds,
it will appear again and again.
Why does this happen?
As mentioned earlier,
the initial interface
is still an alpha type
of the hexagon machine at 2.0 seconds.
On the other hand,
as time increases to 2.5 seconds,
it will form
such a BCC
structure beta type
when the temperature
is high enough
to make the gap
disappear.
Therefore,
we can conclude that
BCC type has the
power to
combine the interface.
Therefore,
the summary of the second part
of the interface
is mainly here.
Here you can see that
it only takes about 450 degrees
On the other hand,
if you use iron and type,
type takes longer.
Why? Because it needs
a temperature of more than 600 degrees
with the expansion of iron
to complete the interface.
The method of completing the interface
is to convert type from the
original alpha to beta type.
Therefore, the last part
is the summary of this speech.
Here we mainly
talk about the first part.
In the similar hard material
combination, we will find
such a BCC.
BCC can provide greater
partial deformation,
and at the same time,
the combination can be completed
in about 2 seconds.
On the other hand,
if you use a harder material
such as porcelain, iron,
or martensite,
it will damage the internal structure
and cause such a defect to disappear.
On the other hand,
a smoother combination is
conducive to integration.
At the same time,
if you use a more
similar hard material,
it is also conducive to
the increase in the intensity of the integration.
On the other hand,
if it is a hard material,
we must consider
the enough deformation ability
to introduce deformation.
These are the interesting points
that have been discovered
so far.
In this speech,
we have mentioned
that in the combination,
we will produce rapid and large-scale deformations,
and there will also be
contact friction damage,
or metal decomposition,
and image transformation, etc.
What we have learned
is that in the future,
we expect to apply
the multi-component composite material
to structure manufacturing
or further 3D metal decomposition.
OK
That's the main part of
today's speech.
Thank you.
It's a very interesting speech.
Now it's Q&A time.
We can ask
because there are
two questions
in the chat box.
We can ask Kunyan
to use
your microphone
to ask your questions.
OK
The first question is
how do you measure the temperature and heat
of your composite?
Traditionally, I use
thermal electric heating.
If you can see me,
I'm welding at the edge of the material.
Wait a minute.
I use this method
to weld at the edge of the material itself.
At the edge,
it is subjected to direct pressure
from the welding head.
Under the pressure,
it can be guaranteed that
although the combined temperature
is the middle one,
the heat of the metal interface
will disappear immediately
after the welding is over?
Will it disappear immediately?
Or will it remain the same?
Under its condition,
the thermal profile
can be seen.
That is,
after the combined time
is over,
it will be about 1000 degrees
per second.
Why is it so fast?
Because once the welding is over,
it is touched
by the welding head
and the base.
This kind of contact will make
the heat dissipation very fast.
Yes, I understand.
One more question.
You just mentioned
that
the combination of
alpha and theta
changes to beta and theta.
But if your cooling speed
is so fast,
is your interface
pure beta titanium
or will it produce martensite?
In fact,
this picture at 3.0 seconds
actually forms
a martensite structure.
It is a Weissmannian structure.
It is formed by alpha and beta
passing through.
Under extreme cold conditions,
it forms a martensite structure
like this.
On the other hand,
why doesn't it
form such a transition structure?
Mainly because iron
also expands at high temperatures.
After expanding to the side of theta,
we actually analyzed it.
We found that there is about
5-10% iron in it.
This iron
is a beta-theta stabilizer.
This was also mentioned
in the preliminary study.
OK.
Thank you.
Can we ask
Y.H. Guo
to explain your question?
OK.
I'm more of an application person.
Can you hear me?
I can hear you.
I'm more of an application person.
But there are also people in my lab
working on materials.
So I understand
that it may be a practical
application issue.
First of all,
I mentioned the AM part.
I'm more curious about
the AM part.
Is it locked in any application?
For the AM application,
we are working on
lightweight...
Traditionally...
In the preliminary study,
they didn't mention
the AM part in detail.
But the possibility
is that
the AM application
is made
from super-thin-waves
combined with
aluminum alloy
and copper.
After forming
such a composite structure,
it will be cut.
In this way,
the super-thin-waves
will be cut.
It's like
creating a composite structure.
Yes.
In the end,
it will be cut.
But in this way,
the material consumption
will not be as much as
traditional CNC cutting.
OK.
And...
In your conclusion,
you mentioned
the super-thin-waves.
I'm more curious about
how thin it should be
to be good enough.
Because it will affect
the smoothness of the
manufacturing process.
Yes.
For the super-thin-waves,
we want to provide
a very flat surface.
Because it's flat,
once two blades
are pressed together,
the contact point of the interface
is not enough.
Here, I use
a relatively flat surface.
The RASA is about
0.1 microns.
OK.
Yes.
But this is the result of
oxidized aluminum powder.
We didn't do it for a long time.
About 10 to 20 seconds.
The surface is really smooth.
OK.
And...
You mentioned that
aluminum and iron
don't mix.
Is that right?
Yes.
I understand.
Aluminum and iron
don't mix.
are oxidized.
Aluminum and iron
meet.
are oxidized.
Aluminum and iron
Ningnew
are oxidized.
Sorry,
I have a question.
I made a video
with
Laser Metal 3D
When they were scanning
the metal powder,
it was a bit like melting.
They used a welding machine.
I'm curious.
When I made that video,
you mentioned that
there are oxidization problems.
Will aluminum oxidize
in your research?
In fact,
in most cases,
aluminum oxidizes
after grinding.
We will measure the thickness of the oxidizing film.
The thickness of the oxidizing film
may be less than 100 nanometers.
It doesn't affect
our research.
You can see that
we focus on
SEM.
SEM is a few microns ahead and behind.
In this case, we didn't see
any obvious oxidization.
About oxidization research,
there are a lot of advanced research.
They use a small-density analysis method.
So this method
doesn't need to be done in a non-oxidized environment.
In fact, it doesn't need to be done in a non-oxidized environment.
Why?
Because after high-temperature bonding,
it doesn't affect
the atmosphere
in the middle of the bonding point.
Therefore,
when we cut it in half
and look at the interface analysis,
we found that there was no obvious oxidization.
OK.
If there is, it's all micro-density.
It has to go to PPM,
such as using atomic carbon
OK.
Got it.
Thank you.
Can we ask Matt Sly
to ask you a question?
Hello.
Thank you for
your wonderful speech.
I have three questions.
First, you said that
IMC has an impact on strength.
I want to know
how to define
its impact on strength.
Since IMC can form bonding,
its strength should be stronger.
Why is its strength
not good?
Yes.
Regarding the strength of IMC,
we have established it
in a more basic concept.
Traditionally,
thick IMCs
usually form a large amount of IMCs
at high temperatures.
A large amount of IMCs
has a negative effect.
On the other hand,
if we
control the bonding conditions
precisely,
it can form
a more detailed IMC image.
On the other hand,
it has a better impact
on the bonding strength.
This diagram
shows that
IMC thickness
has an impact on bonding strength.
However,
if it is too thick,
its bonding strength will decrease.
I see.
The second question is
you just mentioned
the roughness.
Basically,
the whole technology
requires some roughness
on the surface.
When you have high temperatures,
it can melt the surface
at the same time.
You also mentioned
the better the surface,
the better the bonding strength.
Is there a
roughness limit?
The roughness limit
is based on
the smoothness
of the surface.
For example,
if we use 1 micrometer
of oxidized aluminum
to measure the surface,
we can see that
the surface is smooth
and the surface surface is smooth.
However,
if we use a
thicker surface
to measure the surface,
the contact point
will be reduced.
The less contact points,
the less bonding strength.
The more contact points,
the better bonding strength.
On the other hand,
as you mentioned before,
there should be contact points.
If the surface is smooth
and there are no contact points,
there will be no friction.
Theoretically,
it is possible.
However,
in terms of
our current technology,
it is OK
if the surface is smooth to a certain extent.
However,
this is what we can imagine.
Thank you.
My last question is
that you said that
it should be applied
to the frame of the car.
Basically,
the frame of the car
is three-dimensional,
and the experiment
you do here is
two-dimensional.
In the future,
will it be possible
to make a car frame
that is three-dimensional
with three-dimensional
car frame?
Because in the future,
there will be no
three-dimensional car frame.
We don't know
whether the car can be
made in three-dimensional.
We don't know
if it can be
made in three-dimensional.
In other words,
it can be applied
to some points
in the three-dimensional
structure of the car body.
It is mainly
the connection between
the engine cover,
and the structure of
the car body.
It is relatively difficult
to combine large areas of
supercardioid combination
as of now.
Can we ask Mr. Huang
to ask you a question?
Yes.
Can I ask a question?
Sure.
I have two or three questions.
The first one is
that what you are doing now
is basically based on
a balanced project.
I have a curious question.
How do you control
whether it produces IMC
or solid solution?
It mainly depends on
the combination of
the two materials.
In the beginning,
our judgment was based on
a two-dimensional picture.
In addition,
let's take this picture as an example.
It is enough for us to increase
to about 5,600 degrees.
With some expansion,
we can get
such a BCC structure.
On the other hand,
if the BCC is too high,
but the expansion also increases,
the amount of expansion also increases,
it may form another aspect,
such as IMC, solid solution,
or solid-solid solution, etc.
In other words,
the control of the
product itself
mainly depends on
the conditions of interface reaction,
such as temperature, time, etc.
It's hard to judge.
The second question is
because both are
single elements,
if the other side is
BCC,
or some special
metal-solid solution,
is it possible that
it will produce some
unequal attacks during the manufacturing process?
In this case, will it affect
the interface?
Or will it not affect the interface
during the process?
The temperature of the BCC
may be higher than the temperature of the BCC.
Yes,
if it's a low-temperature material,
it's true that it can be
liquefied.
For example,
the new solution
is only 400 degrees Celsius.
If it's more than 400 degrees Celsius,
the temperature of the BCC
will exceed the temperature of the solution.
In this case,
you have to consider
whether the strength of the BCC
has a positive effect on the interface.
If it's a negative effect,
you may choose to skip
the application of this material.
The previous question
is about multi-elements,
such as BCC
or metal-solid solution.
Is it possible
that it will produce some unequal attacks?
It's possible.
Because it's a short-term solution,
it will produce some
unequal attacks.
It's possible that
the overall analysis will be difficult.
Generally speaking,
if there is an interface issue,
it may not be a good thing for bonding.
Yes,
why is it not necessarily a good thing?
Because once the interface
has an issue,
it will slowly go back to the temperature.
The cooling effect
will change the volume.
Most of the time,
you will see that
there are many unequal holes
under the temperature.
These holes are usually not conducive
to the strength of the interface.
I see.
The last question is about the interface.
You will produce this IMC.
So, in your opinion,
this IMC is the main cause
of the linear deformation.
Is that right?
Linear motion.
Is your IMC
generated later or linear motion?
It still supports linear motion.
Because it's harder,
it will lead to linear deformation.
Generally speaking,
it is generated
after the surrounding
linear deformation ability
is better.
Then, it may be formed
by the interface as the integration point.
Sometimes,
you will find that
the IMC will be erased.
It is brittle.
It can't improve the ability
of linear deformation
on the whole.
So, it has no auxiliary function.
Yes.
So, it is quite hard.
It is generated
from the expansion layer
and the manufacturing process.
It's like this.
It's possible.
Let's take this picture as an example.
Let's say it reaches 500C.
At the end of the friction,
the temperature may drop.
Although it's a short time,
it may be generated
in this situation.
But we don't have the so-called
zero tower observation.
So, it's hard to be sure
whether the IMC is generated
here or at the end.
Is there any specificity of the IMC
or is it random?
The specificity depends on
the material itself.
Some are obvious,
some are not.
For example,
it's not obvious
because it's too small.
It's beyond EBSD's
detection limit.
I see.
It's quite interesting.
Thank you.
Any other questions?
No more questions?
If they have any questions,
they can send an email to you.
Okay.
It's the same email.
The traditional email.
Okay.
Thank you for your
wonderful presentation.
Thank you for coming
to explain your research.
It's very interesting.
You're welcome.
That's all
for today's presentation.
If you
haven't
joined
Taira's team,
you can
fill in the form.
I will
stop the recording
now.