Hello, everyone. Welcome to the summer special series activities of Taira at the end of September.
This year's summer special series activities are a bit long. We will actually extend it to October.
Today's topic is called, what's wrong with high-profile, high-profile reform workers forum.
We are very honored to invite three speakers from different perspectives and fields to talk about high-profile reform for a long time.
The first thing I want to do is to introduce our speakers to you.
Our first speaker is Dr. Chen Xiaoyu. He is currently a vice-researcher at the National Institute of Science and Technology Policy Research and Information Center.
He is also a member of the Taiwan High-Level Educational Industry Association.
The second speaker is Dr. Xu Ruifu. He is currently a doctoral student at the Taiwan University Telecommunications Institute.
He was the president of the former Taiwan University Graduate Association.
At the same time, he is also a youth consultant member of the Executive Yuan.
He has been very active in participating in high-profile reform, especially from a student's point of view.
The third speaker is Dr. Xie Ruizhe.
But we may not call him that today.
Because everyone is used to calling him Zha Shi.
So we may also call him Zha Shi.
You can also call him that.
He is now the policy assistant of the Legislative Yuan Educational and Cultural Committee.
So he can also bring you different points of view in this regard.
I will not mention it again today.
But let me talk about it first.
Today's three speakers, their bosses are very willing to let them share.
But based on their experience, they will speak on behalf of themselves.
I will talk about it for them.
Okay.
So this is what we are going to do today.
We will invite the three speakers to talk about how they view the issue of high-profile reform.
Then we can start discussing from what they have said.
Let's start with Xiaoyu.
How do you view this issue?
Okay. I am Xiaoyu Chen.
Thank you for the invitation.
And thank you to the other two speakers, Ruizhe and Zha Shi, for their participation.
When it comes to high-profile reform,
I dare not say that I have been involved in reform for many years.
I basically want to share some observations on high-level education.
Okay.
My interest in research is mainly high-level education.
I also read this in my class.
The topic I want to talk about today is about high-level talents.
If you have seen my Facebook page,
which is LaoYuNanJie,
I have a fan page.
I often write on it that Taiwan issues are global issues.
But we also have different domestic issues that need to be discussed.
I cut from three perspectives of human resources management.
The first is the part about talent selection.
In fact, my country's current problem of doctoral education,
I personally think that it is not that no one reads doctoral classes,
but that excellent talents are not willing to read doctoral classes.
That is the problem of our country.
Okay. This is the part about talent selection.
Everyone can discuss this later.
From the part about the budget and the budget flow,
I personally think that there are two things,
some things are worth discussing.
The first is the talent selection.
The first is the part about doctoral education.
What kind of doctoral education do we provide in China?
Do we treat everyone as paper machines,
lab workers,
or do we really need to train people to solve problems?
And then in the future,
I hope that the industry or the academic world
will develop more and more.
I think this is a very important issue.
I hope that the industry or the academic world
will develop more and more.
Okay. The other problem is the mechanism.
The mechanism will be discussed by the other two speakers.
I personally think there are two parts.
One part is about the part about study abroad scholarship.
The related planning and distribution of the field
is how to proceed.
The more serious problem for our domestic doctoral class
is that at present
the domestic doctoral class
only has the part about study abroad scholarship.
Whether you are a TA or an RA,
the education of the doctoral class
does not have the so-called scholarship system.
In other words,
we do not have the so-called fellowship.
The third part is
mainly about the flow of money.
The human resources management
likes to talk about the flow of money.
The part about the flow of money.
My personal opinion is that
whether you are a senior talent,
a doctoral talent,
an academic talent,
or an industrial talent,
in other words,
if you want to develop into the academic world
or the industry,
basically,
the mechanism of the talent
is a part of the global flow.
Regardless of which university you graduate from,
or which direction you want to go in the future,
for example,
if you want to go to a foreign university
or research institution
in the future,
I suggest that
we should think about
how to cooperate internationally in the future
and help these talents
to have a good development abroad.
If you want to come back to China,
whether it is a university,
research institution,
or industry development,
in fact,
we consider,
for example,
whether you apply for
a job in China,
to be honest,
in my personal experience,
if you really come back to China
and apply for a job in China
or do research,
of course money is a very important factor,
but money can never
solve all the problems.
In fact,
we need more related support,
for example,
for young scholars.
In fact,
if you want to
enter the industry,
my personal opinion is that
in fact, there are many doctors in Taiwan
and there are many questions related to
Dr. Liu Lang.
Basically, if you can pass the doctorate exam,
you basically have a certain
ability or a certain degree.
My personal opinion is that
if you finish your doctorate,
you have to have a bottom line,
which is to know that
you may not be able to develop
as much as you want,
but you have a lot of things you can do.
Like me,
to be honest,
I am a Ph.D.
in the Department of Philosophy
at the National University of Private University.
To be honest,
we are the weakest group.
I graduated from the Department of Literature
and then I studied a doctorate,
but after I graduated,
I found that I could not
engage in teaching at all.
Even when I was laid off
from school for a while,
I was thinking that
there was no other possibility.
So my friends called me
a truck driver.
I have a driver's license
in Taiwan.
In other words,
if the school or my legal agency
doesn't want me,
I can find it the next day
and I can drive a bus right away.
We often joke that
the school or my legal agency
doesn't want me
because my colleagues
don't want me to hurt passers-by.
This is my report.
Thank you.
Let me summarize a little bit.
As Xiaoyu mentioned,
Taiwan has talented people,
but it seems that
there are very few people
who are willing to be a Ph.D.
Also,
Taiwan is obviously
without a Ph.D. system.
Thirdly,
we either have talented people
or they don't come back.
It seems that
somehow we don't have such a balance
to achieve such a fluid balance.
We can discuss this later.
Before we discuss,
let's change the order.
As Xiaoyu and Ruifu
just introduced,
let's have Zha Shi
to talk about
the reform of higher education.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
I'm Zha Shi.
Today, I'm going to
talk about something
that I don't understand.
After all, the Legislative Yuan
has to supervise the education committee
for a long time,
so I think the government
should do more.
What are these actions?
Today's audience
has a different point of view.
From the beginning,
I think the talent cultivation,
the ability to retain talents,
and the ability to retain talents
is a national security strategy.
I think everyone can accept this.
We all think
this is a national strategy,
but if more and more people
in Taiwan are missing
or unwilling to be a Ph.D.,
this is definitely a national security crisis.
From this perspective,
starting with the local Ph.D.,
we have indeed encountered
a lot of situations and problems.
But let's start
with a big vision.
If Taiwan wants to be
a country with international competitiveness
and global competitiveness,
first of all, our local Ph.D. students
like Xiaoyu said,
these excellent Ph.D. students are not willing to study.
This is definitely the first part of the problem
that we have to solve.
In fact, talents are not only
local talents, international talents,
and overseas talents
like you.
Can Taiwan do this?
Because we have been dealing with
an overseas study and
international education specialization.
This is related to
To echo what Xiaoyu said,
many of our Ph.D. students
have a healthy
education plan system overseas.
This part allows us to
recruit more international students
in Taiwan.
We focus on Ph.D. students.
They have more planning resources
to go to the world
to have more international experience,
more international education experience.
But for Taiwan,
the last piece of the puzzle
is the new economic immigration law
that we did not finish
in the 9th session of the last meeting.
This is actually a lot of pieces.
Starting with local Ph.D. training,
this is very important.
Because I believe that many
academic professors
will have this goal
in the end.
So local Ph.D. training
is very important.
But in terms of international flow,
do we have such a healthy
international education
that allows everyone to
communicate internationally?
In the end, there is a very good
talent or flow policy,
which is our new economic immigration law.
We have been following it recently.
So I think this is a part of the
perspective to think about
every link is important.
But although every link is important,
I personally feel that
there is still very little
discussion on local Ph.D. training.
For me,
a local Ph.D. training
needs to have many important aspects.
The first is economic support.
We just talked about
a lot of Ph.D. students
have to get a two- or three-year Ph.D.
and have to work outside
to complete their research.
This is the first economic support.
Next,
is there a good training plan?
Whether it is in China,
there can be better
forward-looking academic research
or production planning
or to become a more practical Ph.D.
This is the second piece
that I think is very important.
The third piece is entry.
Whether it is to become
a forward-looking academic or a practical Ph.D.,
what is the government's
thinking in Taiwan?
I think this is an interesting part
that can be discussed.
From the government's point of view,
we have to deal with these things.
But which role in the government
is the most qualified
and should play
such a role?
In fact, what we see now is
that the national integration is very bad.
How do I put it?
For example, the Ministry of Education.
Of course, everyone will think that
all the questions we just talked about
are the Ministry of Education.
It has a huge responsibility.
But for the Ministry of Technology,
it also has a very important
responsibility to train
these senior talents
as a research talent.
Is the Ministry of Economy important?
If we are going to talk about
the important support for industry transformation,
is it important for the
connection between enterprises?
It is very important.
Next is the Ministry of Labor.
For these young graduates,
do they have a better way
to help them?
So we can actually know that
the issue of talent training
actually has a certain responsibility
in different departments.
Of course, the most important thing
is the Ministry of Education
When we do a lot of interviews,
we will find that the Ministry of Education
will do the Ministry of Education.
The Ministry of Technology will do the Ministry of Technology.
The connection between the ministries
is actually lacking.
Let me give you an example.
Last year, the Ministry of Technology
did an excellent doctoral student scholarship program.
Simply put,
it hopes to recruit many excellent talents
to Taiwan.
These students in Taiwan
are willing to study for a doctorate.
The Ministry of Technology
will give them about $500,000.
Of course, the Ministry of Technology
will cooperate with the universities.
But the Ministry of Technology
will provide the greatest assistance
in economic support.
This plan has been discussed for a long time.
The Ministry of Technology
has been looking for the Ministry of Education
to cooperate.
But in the end, the Ministry of Education
did not want to join.
The Ministry of Technology
is more likely to join
than the Ministry of Education.
The Ministry of Education
is more likely to join
than the Ministry of Technology.
The Ministry of Education
did not want to join.
This is a problem
that cannot be solved.
Sometimes, it cannot be solved
and it cannot cooperate.
Why?
In the Ministry of Education
or Ministry of Technology,
the Ministry of Education
is a single unit
in the constitutional system.
It has a budget
and it has to implement these plans every year.
The Ministry of Education
and the Ministry of Technology
are equal and respect each other.
Nobody can lead the other.
This is an interesting discussion.
In other countries,
the Ministry of Education
and the Ministry of Technology
are tied together.
When we do not have
a comprehensive strategy
for the country,
the Ministry of Education
seems to have only completed half of the plan.
The Ministry of Technology
seems to have only completed the other half.
But can these two ministries cooperate?
This is a big question mark.
We will try to push them.
But after all,
the Ministry of Education and the Ministry of Technology
have a strong fundamentalism.
So many plans
will not meet.
So I think
from the biggest point of view,
I think the local
or international
or overseas talents
come back to Taiwan.
This is what our government
needs to complete
through some legal procedures.
But gradually,
in fact,
there are some problems
in the division of labor.
The Ministry of Education
does not do this.
This is because it is called the Ministry of Labor
in the system.
The Ministry of Labor has its own restrictions.
So there is a lot of support
that has been talking about
whether the Ministry of Education
and the Ministry of Technology
can be combined.
Or is there a higher unit,
such as the National Development Committee?
This kind of high-level ministry
can do the integration of the ministries.
The plan of the ministries
really has its similarities.
Where is the integration?
How to do it?
I think this is a very interesting part.
So from the point of view
of government supervision,
this is probably the part I mentioned today.
Thank you.
I think this is very interesting.
That is to say,
let's find another person
to talk to you.
Let's ask Ralph to talk about it.
He used to be the president
of the Taiwan University Graduate Association.
Then he was a youth consultant
at the Executive Yuan.
Of course, now he is also a PhD student
doing TA and receiving scholarships.
Ralph, what do you think?
What is your opinion?
Let me post my Facebook first.
You can talk to me later.
Because I often
write articles or have some new plans.
If I have a chance,
I would like to find everyone to do it together.
Let me briefly talk about
the whole process and the path of participation.
There may be more issues
to be discussed later.
I think this experience is very important.
Because I have always been
participating from a student's point of view.
Then I saw the first line of the problem
and thought about how to change it.
I started to participate
in 2016.
At that time, I was recommended
to join the Executive Yuan Youth Consultation Committee.
Why is there this organization?
It is because
in 2014,
after the Taiyanghua School,
the government slowly realized
that the voice of the youth is very important.
In addition to social movements,
the government
established a youth consultation committee
and held a public election.
Later, after Tsai Ing-wen came to power,
she slightly changed her approach.
Because they felt that
many of the youth consultants
wanted to directly participate in politics and elections.
They felt that this approach
was not OK.
In practice, they became conservative.
They changed their approach
to let the officials of the committee recommend them.
Of course, the recommended candidates
are conservative,
but there are also some more advanced candidates.
So in practice,
it is more like
the committee has some policies that have been implemented.
Then you can make some amendments on it.
In fact, it is not possible
for example, at that time,
you can take any action.
At that time,
I was in office for two years.
It happened to be the time when
my research institute was in its first year.
I proposed two proposals.
It happened to be in the office of Lin Quan and Lai Ching-teh.
One of the proposals
was aimed at
some of the problems
in TA.
After the proposal,
the problem was not solved.
The second proposal
happened to be the opportunity
for UCLA scholars
to visit us.
I think the cooperation experience
of international research and academic exchange
is very important for an academic talent.
So I asked
if we should encourage more scholars
in our research institute.
Maybe it's not just a collaboration
with the teacher.
It is to let students have more research experience
and expand their international vision.
There are also some opportunities for international development.
Although the proposal was approved,
the result was not ideal.
The reason is that
about 80% to 90% of the content
was written
by the Ministry of Science and Technology
and the Ministry of Education.
They wrote an article
and replied to me.
The result of not communicating
is more like
you not only need to know
what they have done
in advance,
but also need to point out
which part of what they have done
is problematic
and they are willing to accept
what you have said.
It's not just that you may see
a problem from the outside
and think how to solve it
would be better.
Next, I will talk about the second part.
In that period of time,
I have a conclusion,
observation or summary.
If a problem can be improved,
there may be three motivations
or three reasons.
The first one is the government official.
The government official is the minister,
so he may not be able to achieve
what he wants to do.
But the will and choice of the government official
are very important.
The second one is the civil society.
The civil society is not only
publicizing information
or giving actual consultations.
For example,
Xiao Yu and Zha Shi
are the representatives of the civil society.
The pressure of the civil society
should be combined
through private meetings
or public speeches
to make people pay more attention.
This is also a very important way.
After that,
I had no choice
but to choose
the president of the Taiwan University Research Association.
In the position of president,
I have done
two things
for the Taiwan University Research Association.
First,
I had a meeting with the president
of the Taiwan University Research Association
and the director of the Ministry of Education
to discuss the improvement
of the student's treatment.
In fact,
the meeting was not very pleasant.
At that time,
we raised some issues
that we observed.
At that time,
we were not mature enough
to point out what he did wrong
and figure out how to solve the problem
and convince him.
We were not mature enough.
However,
some senior officials asked us
that if doctors
are unemployed
and unable to work,
we can easily invest more resources
instead of causing more unemployment.
Secondly,
how to convince the society
to invest more social resources
is really valuable.
Therefore,
the meeting was not pleasant.
At that time,
I observed
how to promote
the change of policy
to reduce the pressure of public opinion.
In the field of doctors,
there was a gap.
In the past,
there were many issues
about the student's point of view
at the Taiwan University Research Association
However,
the student's point of view
was always a problem.
For example,
the Taiwan University Research Association
had been promoting
the social movement
for 6 or 7 years
mainly for the employees
who had been working hard.
They made a lot of efforts
but I think
what they did
was meaningful.
First of all,
it was hard to continue
their movement.
Secondly,
the fundamental problem
was that the TA's salary
had not increased
from the 1930s to the present.
So,
it was a basic salary
of a supermarket.
This was a big problem.
It was the investment of social resources
rather than the calculation
Finally,
one of my goals
when I stay in Taiwan
is to improve the environment.
In the long run,
I hope that
the TA's education level
can be similar
to the higher education system
in the world.
No matter what,
it is important
to fulfill the TA's point of view.
According to our professors,
we need good researchers
and local academic development.
Whether it is academic development
or the development of industry,
we need these talents.
So,
it is important to
achieve a balance.
I am thinking about
organizing a national
TA's organization.
I hope that
we can continue to
organize it.
I will share more ideas with you later.
Thank you.
After hearing
the three
TA's statements,
we can hear
a clear
point of view.
Everyone mentioned
what is the role of a doctor?
What is the value of
cultivating these high-level talents?
If we understand it,
can we discuss
how to do it?
Then, the TA's
mentioned the resources.
After having the resources,
how can we
implement the policy?
Can we start from the beginning?
I will ask the three
TA's questions.
What do you think
the role of cultivating
these high-level talents
should be?
What is our
imagination?
Does anyone want to volunteer?
Sorry,
you can also
ask questions in the chat.
Let's go back
to the question.
I saw that
Xiao-Yu typed something.
Xiao-Yu, why don't you go first?
Not everyone can read the chat.
For example,
what do you think
the role of cultivating
these high-level talents
should be?
This is a difficult question.
I will go first.
Please.
Actually,
this question is also
to thank Zha Shi
after I graduated.
At that time,
I met him and he was
a professor.
I always felt that
Taiwan did not have a
continuous discussion
of high-level policy
and the power of continuous development.
Whether it was a group of French
or a political group
or various units.
At that time,
I met the biggest difficulty.
For example,
I was a doctor at
the University of Taiwan.
The power of continuous development
and innovation and transformation.
But this is not the case
in other fields.
Because the industrial development
is not the same
or there is no industry at all.
After I graduated from the master's class,
I did one thing.
I classified the three academic subjects
of the Department of Humanities and Social Science
in the Ministry of Education.
Then I found
the professors in these three fields.
According to their status,
they regularly
come to the Legislative Yuan
to discuss the direction
of policy development.
So this is really a more
top-level issue.
But I think
the other aspect of my talk
is that for this issue,
it is easy to limit
one's own learning experience
and one's own professional field.
So it becomes
more ideal
to have a more
top-level policy
of coordination and integration.
So I didn't directly answer this question,
but I just gave feedback on the other aspect.
Do you have any comments?
The other two.
Let me mention
because the Legislative Yuan
is held twice a year
in Taiwan.
Once is from February to May.
Once is from September to
the end of December.
This meeting is also called
the Budget Meeting of Taiwan.
We will start to review
the entire budget
proposed by the ministries
as a role of the Legislative Yuan.
So we normally have
a lot of discussions
with the Ministry of Education
about the budget report.
In this budget report,
all the ministers sit at the bottom.
In fact, I also asked directly.
This may be a very difficult question
and there is no standard answer.
What kind of talents
do we need to cultivate?
Is it a food type
or is it a front-line teacher?
What do we need to cultivate?
OK, then the head of the faculty
will talk first.
He said that as a main unit
of the faculty education,
we certainly hope that our faculty university
is a type of application
study.
Of course, if you want to study
a doctor,
we hope that they focus on
food type research.
OK, then the head of the faculty
will talk next.
We also know that
this is also a different faction.
Some people think that
it is a research faction and
some people think that
it is a food faction.
There are a lot of people
talking about this.
I myself am a lecturer
at the Institute of Electrical Engineering
with a background in technology.
So I also know that
today we are going to talk about
going to the workplace
and helping food companies.
This matter actually makes a lot of sense.
However, it is also because of the
many meetings we held together
at the University of,
we began to understand that
the doctoral students in the
humanities group and the social group
are completely different,
even none.
In this situation,
it is difficult for me to say
that I have always used the point of view
of technology.
In fact, it should be said
that from the point of view of the
government, I think that
it should be more responsible
to break down the humanities,
social science and technology,
even if the three groups are divided.
In fact, the different departments
are in technology.
For example, ecology,
one is a doctor of ecology,
and ecology and biology are completely different.
In fact, although it is just
such a standard under a big theme,
in fact, there are many
differences in each group.
So in fact, my own feeling is
that the government must have
sufficient height and policy resources.
It can go to the face.
The most ideal, of course,
is the science department in each field.
How much is the academic demand
at the academic end?
Will there be an industrial demand?
If these are all there,
it should be put back to the front end of education.
How do we do
a policy of recruiting students?
And of course, the other
part of the ideal is that for each student,
I believe that there must be students
who want to enter the enterprise to do industrial transformation,
do more experience in food.
There will also be these academic
research goals.
In fact, I think from the perspective of students,
how can they choose more freely?
Knowing that this choice
will have a job opportunity in the future,
but will there be a job opportunity?
I think the government
should take a
big responsibility to play.
But now we see that
it's more passive.
What do you use?
I'll cut your number
by less than the ratio of your recruitment.
Or say that our country has a key industry.
It seems that we want to develop these key industries,
so we come to add these positions.
But I think the most fundamental problem
is that it still takes a lot of time.
In this part, the government
should make more efforts.
The above is probably the case.
What do you think, Xiaoyu?
I think this is
a big problem.
In fact, this goes back to the policy.
In other words, is the high-level education
of our country a planned economy,
that is, government control,
or a free market?
If it is the United States,
to be honest, the doctoral program
is a free market.
In other words,
only graduate schools
can offer doctoral programs.
What kind of field or science
does the doctoral program provide?
In fact, it is mainly
dominated by various schools.
As for the job,
in my country,
we are actually under the control
of the Ministry of Education.
In this case,
what should we do?
How much should we do?
This matter is worth considering.
In other words,
of course, if you are a doctor,
you mainly want to
follow the academic path,
or want to develop the industry.
It is true that there are
social and scientific fields
that are not related
to the industry.
But in fact,
we have a lot of things to do.
So,
is the doctoral program
completely
aimed at the profession?
Or is it
still a basic ability
or a more professional ability
to hope to
move towards
long-term development in the future?
So,
this is actually
from a policy position.
So,
what should we do?
To what extent should we do?
Of course,
I also admit that
the relevant government,
whether it is the Ministry of Education,
the Ministry of Science and Technology,
or other units,
to be honest,
we are not fully equipped.
I actually heard you all say
that first of all,
there should be a policy
that is above the current level
of cross-departmental structure.
Or we should have a comprehensive strategy.
Let's put it this way.
And then to promote this strategy,
there is a very important one.
What kind of product
do we want to produce
to convince our government
to carry out what kind of policy
and then what kind of resources
do we need?
Do you have any practical ideas?
Of course, this is my ideal picture.
We can do this.
But do you have any experience?
Or do you have any
actual proposals?
Or any countries
have done this?
Or have you ever thought about it?
Or the government has actually done it,
but people have no feeling about it.
Or in fact,
do you have anything to share?
You are all very polite.
Otherwise,
let's start from the previous order again.
Otherwise, let's go back to RAVE.
So your question is
what are the more clear
policies that have been proposed
or what is the situation?
Yes.
Then I will use
the experience of
our recent meeting with
the senior teacher to explain to you.
Because what we did this year
was to go to the Legislative Yuan every month
to have a meeting.
Then the professors of Humanities, Social Sciences and Technology
made their own reports.
After everyone discussed,
the final conclusion was to
integrate the opinions of the overall report.
In the report at that time,
the general direction was
that the whole meeting
lasted about one hour,
almost two hours.
The meeting schedule can also be
divided into several parts.
In fact,
we have just discussed
several parts.
For example,
I mentioned that
last year,
the Ministry of Science and Technology
held a seminar on the
talent improvement of doctors.
At that time,
there was a professor at
the University of Jianqiao
who was in charge of the
training of researchers
from policy execution
to human resources.
At that time,
I also mentioned that
perhaps the Ministry of Education
should provide more resources
to establish a role
like a research center
if there is no difficulty
in the implementation
of this plan.
He was thinking about
the continuity of these policies
not only in the field of
post-doctoral studies,
but also in the development
of the entire career of a doctor.
On the other hand,
doctors should have
a basic knowledge system.
For example,
how did we explain to him
that we have transferred
the current data
to the professors of
major universities in Taiwan
every year,
and there are about
1,200 people
who are professionals
in the field of
post-doctoral studies,
so you can think
about the size of the market.
There are about 2,000
new job opportunities.
Since these 2,000 people
are important people
in the Ministry of Education,
let's say the employees
of the Ministry of Education,
so the Ministry of Education
should have a basic
education guarantee
for these so-called
educational staff,
or you should have
a basic environment.
If you evaluate
this number,
there should be
4,000 or 5,000
new doctoral students
every year,
so you can
say that if
at least 1,000 people
become professors every year,
2,000 people are
highly educated people,
what kind of
basic resources
should these people
be given?
For example,
there was a proposal
that the former
Minister of
Administration and
the Ministry of Education
should have a basic
education guarantee.
If there are
industrial development resources,
it can be added
to make it higher.
So when we see
this proposal,
even the Ministry of Education
has already
prepared to
approve it.
We think it is
a good idea.
However,
the proposal was
stopped after
Yalda left,
and it was not
carried out.
Later,
we had a meeting
with the Ministry of Education,
and they said
they were afraid that
if more resources were
invested,
the proposal would be
rejected.
Of course,
we have some
opinions,
and there are many
other opinions.
If you are more careful,
you can refer to
the document.
In my opinion,
the bigger structure
is like this.
I also found
that when the president
wants to do something,
the Ministry of Education
will send out the proposal
and write a version.
For example,
there is a 5 plus 2
key industry policy
in our country's
industrial talent policy,
and it is to investigate
which talents are missing
in the key industry.
We found that
the Ministry of Education
did not even investigate
how many PhDs are
in the industry development
or transformation,
let alone the policy
and implementation.
We think it is ridiculous.
After our meeting with
the Ministry of Education,
they said that
it is just a form,
and they did not
investigate this.
As mentioned earlier,
the integration of all ministries
is really difficult.
It requires specific
inspections and changes.
Otherwise,
there may be other channels.
Do you have anything
to add?
Or do you want to comment?
Let me talk about it.
I am Zashi.
I mentioned a lot of
specific policies
that we mentioned to the mayor.
From my point of view,
in recent years,
everyone knows that
Taiwan's government,
whether it is the Ministry of Technology
or the Ministry of Education,
has mentioned some
international talent planning
projects,
such as Yushan Scholar,
Qianlima,
and so on.
However,
in recent years,
the Ministry of Education
has proposed
these projects
to the schools
every year,
and the money
will be allocated
to each school.
However,
we started to
focus on international talent
because we need
a good professor
and a good teacher.
If these teachers
don't have good students,
will the teacher
really have a strong
research motivation?
This is what we see.
These talent planning projects
have already started,
but how do you return
these important talents
to Taiwan?
During the meeting with the
Minister of Education,
we specifically mentioned
that in recent years,
these talent planning projects
are aimed at
increasing the salary of professors
and teachers,
but is it possible
to create another project
that is more friendly
to students?
Our view is simple.
If you have good teachers
and good students,
it's meaningless
if you don't have good professors.
The Ministry of Education
is concerned about
whether these projects
will attract
a large number of
professors in the future.
However,
these projects
are aimed at
excellent professors.
We fully agree with this.
In my opinion,
some things
need to be adjusted
from a small place.
For example,
we have been talking about
the Doctor's Scholarship Program,
the Ministry of Science and Technology's
Doctor's Scholarship Program.
I talked directly with the
Director of the Ministry of Science
and Technology.
I told him
my thoughts on
this project.
When we interview,
we usually
talk about the exact salary,
such as how much
the annual salary is.
At least the annual salary is like this.
If the company operates better,
I will add a few more months.
This is a means that a company
will definitely use
when it is lazy.
But in Taiwan,
for example,
you may have a chance
to apply for this scholarship
when you come to Taiwan.
You may apply for it
and you will get
NT$40,000 scholarship
every month for four years.
I started to talk to them.
Can't we give
the school or push the school
to have a more corporate thinking model?
Today,
Ralph is an excellent doctor.
When he came in,
I already told him
that we think
he is an excellent doctor.
We hope that
you will have a lot of economic support
in this stage of your research.
One of them is this project.
If you choose to study at NTU,
I will give you this project.
Because we think your conditions are in line.
Even for those students
who hesitate whether to study at NTU
or NTU,
can't these schools
be more active in
applying for scholarships?
Do we have to tell them
that you may have a chance when you come in?
In fact, the Ministry of Science and Technology
heard this idea
and they also want to move in this direction.
Although it seems that
it is difficult to say at the university level.
In fact, every university
may be allocated
some positions in each department,
but they may not dare
to be so brave
to apply for scholarships.
In fact, I think
this is a very important direction
to discuss.
So, in my own experience,
it will be like this.
That's all.
OK.
I am Xiaoyu.
What Justin just mentioned
is that
if NTU teachers
are very active
in applying for scholarships,
NTU teachers
can find the best students.
But I also know that
this is not
what NTU professors
should do
through their personal strength.
There should be
a more comprehensive
at least at the school level.
For example, NTU itself
should have more specific plans
to assist teachers.
Instead of giving money to the school
and saying,
OK, you can do it yourself.
You have to provide
all kinds of assistance to do it yourself.
My point of view
on doctoral education
is that
from our educational point of view,
our scholarship
is not a bonus, but a benefit.
In fact, in doctoral education,
to be honest,
from the point of view of
the government,
we actually only look at one thing,
that is, we only give it to excellent people.
But in fact, doctoral education
is not only like this,
there is also a free market.
If someone is willing to come to
the doctoral class and graduate,
we will also open it to you.
But the related packages
may not provide
you to pay for yourself,
you may have to work harder
or cooperate with the professor, etc.
In addition,
this is my general idea.
Let's open it to the audience
to see if there are
any other questions.
Thank you.
I have a question.
Are there any three people
or sorry,
two people besides Xiaoyu
who want to add to what Xiaoyu just said
or what else do you think?
At the moment,
everyone is very enthusiastic,
so we have a lot of questions.
Or do you want to
discuss the audience's questions?
Of course.
Sorry,
because there are a lot of questions,
we probably can't see all of them,
and there are really a lot of words,
so I may miss it,
so I apologize to everyone first.
Let's start from the beginning,
because maybe some people
want to add to what Xiaoyu just said.
Xun Yu asked,
sorry, let me go back a little bit.
The sustainability of policies
is terrible.
Recently, I heard a rumor that
the Columbus Peace Project
is about to die.
No, I mean it's about to end.
I don't know if the government
is specifically referring to
the Love Song Project,
but the sustainability.
I don't know what you think.
Besides how to look at it,
what should we do?
OK.
Are we answering directly?
Yes, yes.
OK, let me talk about it.
I've been studying this topic recently.
In fact, this goes back to
the question I asked at the beginning.
In fact, let me talk about
the so-called Columbus or Einstein Project,
which are all called
the Young Learners Development Project
of the Ministry of Science and Technology.
That is, the preliminary basic construction budget
may be a four-year
continuous plan like this.
Because we are now
moving towards the third phase,
every four years,
we are now slowly moving
towards the third phase and starting to implement it.
In fact, to answer a comprehensive
question,
the current situation is
that the budget should be reduced a little.
If I remember correctly,
is it 2.3 billion?
I need to look it up again,
because I have such preliminary information in my hand.
The preliminary report of the last issue
is about the budget of the Young Learners Development Project
and the preliminary plan
that is going to be reviewed
in this issue.
It seems that the budget is a little less,
but it is not terminated.
Back to the question I'm concerned about,
why is this thing
very interesting?
Because every year when I review the budget,
we, as a supervision unit,
will write a summary of the budget
or freeze it,
or the main resolution.
These are all the parts that need to be
formally replied to you,
and they are usually very worried about
the budget of the legislators.
So usually
they will be very concerned about
all the things we write.
I write one thing every year.
I said that the Ministry of Education has a budget plan,
the Ministry of Science and Technology has a
Young Learners Development Project,
and the Chinese Academy of Sciences,
a research unit,
they also have their own budget plans.
And sometimes
in the budget of those international talents,
the target that everyone is looking for
is not too far away.
So let's go back to the beginning.
Is there any way
to have a better integration?
In fact, the Ministry of Science and Technology said
that I was looking for
research experts.
The Ministry of Education said
that the researchers
actually operate
like this.
That is really a very vague situation.
So in fact, I think
the plan is not to be broken,
but we will pay more attention to
the different parts of the plan.
In fact, 1 plus 1 must be greater than 2.
And in fact, the attitude of the Ministry of Science and Technology
every year is that their budget is really not much.
We support all their plans.
Because I am
in charge of the Ministry of Science and Technology
and I am in charge of the
consultation policy or bill
or budget supervision.
So I can really
say that I fully support
many of the plans of the Ministry of Science and Technology.
The Ministry of Education really does less.
But in some of the plans,
I actually think they must cooperate.
So every year we will continue to
push this department.
That's about it.
OK.
I am Xiaoyu.
My question is whether the
plan of the Ministry of Science and Technology
will continue.
As far as I know,
just like what
Dr. Zha mentioned,
the plan of the Ministry of Science and Technology
and Einstein is really
a special budget.
So in other words, it is the
budget of the front-end plan.
In fact, he said that
there is a reduction of
more than 2.3 billion.
So I think that
after the new 520 minister
took office,
in fact, the plan of
the Ministry of Science and Technology
or the talent cultivation plan itself,
in fact, they will already have a
relatively long-term
view of this matter.
In other words,
we are not pushing a short-term
plan like the five-year plan,
but in the future,
I believe it will be announced soon
that this matter needs to be
promoted for a long time.
In other words, our country
will have different plans for
the cultivation of young scholars,
whether they are young scholars,
middle-aged scholars,
or senior scholars.
OK.
Ralph, do you want to add something?
Or are we looking for another question?
It doesn't matter.
I just saw an interesting question.
I think we should
give this question to Ralph.
This may be the most
in line with your experience.
Sorry.
He said,
what is the relationship
between the Association of Researchers
and the school?
Can you explain the financial
situation of the school
and the allocation of funds?
Then,
Jeff,
the Association of Researchers
in the U.S. can check the
financial situation of the school
and ask them to provide
specific welfare conditions
for the students,
labor conditions,
and living conditions.
What is the situation
in Taiwan now?
I just answered
the question.
The Association of Researchers
mainly plans the use of
the annual budget
in the Association of
Researchers.
Unless there are special cases
that need to be approved
by the school council,
most of the discussions and
decisions will be made there.
At present,
there is no student representative
in the Association of Researchers.
In addition to the Association of
Researchers,
there is another important
participation channel called
administrative meetings.
Administrative meetings
are held by the principal,
dean,
and director
to discuss
how to plan
the administration
of the school.
At that time,
there will be at least
one student representative
in the meeting.
The current situation is that
when the school council
feels that this matter
is related to the students,
they will issue a meeting notice
saying that you can come to practice.
By practice,
it means that you do not
have the right to vote,
but the school will listen to
your opinion.
However,
this is usually the last straw.
When the school feels that
this matter is not
controversial,
they will come to discuss with you.
However, as you know,
last year and the year before last,
there was a lot of discussion
about the principal,
so some teachers
who support the principal
or conservative teachers
will feel that
some student representatives
have this tendency,
so they failed.
I am not depressed about the failure.
So,
I can listen to
everyone's opinion
more.
Especially today's discussion
is very valuable.
Someone said that
it may be related to
the financial structure
or the position of the school
in general.
Ray has mentioned
a very interesting thing.
I don't know what the other two
think.
He mentioned that
this is related to
the role we give them
or their own role.
What do you think
about this?
For example,
Xiaoyu or Zashi.
Are you talking about the role of the university?
Yes.
How does the university
set its own role?
Will they decide how to do it?
You mean
if the school
thinks it is
a research university
or a teaching university
or other types of universities,
such as industrial universities
or entrepreneurial universities?
Or something else?
Let me add something.
I think the financial structure
and the right of students
are not necessarily related.
What is the reason?
For example,
private colleges in Taiwan
have a tuition fee of
50% to 70%.
But private colleges
don't pay much attention to students.
That's it.
On the one hand,
the atmosphere of students' self-participation
is not so good.
On the other hand,
they don't pay much attention
to students.
So it may be a sufficient condition,
but not a necessary condition.
If you have time,
I see Jeff
wants to ask a question.
I think it's a good time.
So,
if it's convenient for Jeff,
please turn on the microphone
to talk about REEF.
Thank you.
I'm a third-year student
at the University of Indiana
in the United States.
I used to work
as a teacher
for several years.
I think
REEF's
information about Taiwan is very good.
I think
since Taiwan is different
from the United States,
the United States is a market mechanism.
Taiwan is mainly
caught by the Ministry of Education.
In this case,
from the perspective
of the Legislative Yuan,
I think REEF
is an important role
in the school
role management process.
In terms of supervision,
can the school
implement this mechanism?
In addition,
in addition to the REEF,
REEF will also form a union.
The union
is different from the
REEF.
The union actually
starts from the perspective
of the Legislative Yuan
to talk about the lack of
wage and salary.
What the school
will do
is to mobilize
demonstrations
and make demands.
As I mentioned
in the chat,
these demands
come from
more information.
For example,
the salary of the school
is transparent.
I can share with you
that REEF
did some reports
and mentioned
the salary of the
football team
coach
is as high as
6 to 7 million Taiwan dollars
a year.
They feel that
the school
cannot hide
this information.
Therefore, the school
cannot stand still.
I think the transparency of this information
is very important.
Taiwan is not a market mechanism.
The Ministry of Education
should implement
this transparent mechanism
through the Ministry of Education.
Perhaps this will
be helpful
to solve the problem.
That's all. Thank you.
I think this is
a process of transformation.
In the process of transformation,
I think it is very important
to ensure the legalization.
Of course,
in the next session,
we will focus on
the so-called school dismissal.
However,
many rights and interests
are included in the Ministry of Education
in the University Act
or the school fund management
in the Ministry of Education.
These things should be reviewed.
Recently,
many groups of students
have come to
communicate with us
on the University Act.
In terms of
these self-government groups,
can they have more
guaranteed things?
For example,
we heard that
some schools
charge two different
channels for their
school fees.
You can't pay online.
You have to pay by paper.
This is incredible.
Or some schools
because the students
group, for example,
the source of the money
is the tuition fee.
Basically,
the student council
can decide
what to do
and how to do it.
Even if the money
is the tuition fee,
the school has to do it.
In fact, the student rights
are moving forward.
However,
many schools still
have a conservative attitude.
What should we do?
I agree with what Jeff said.
The student rights
can't be a hostage.
If you are willing to communicate
with a good principal,
you will have more opportunities.
Sometimes it's hard to be a principal.
In the school council,
he didn't just say it.
Many teachers are there.
He wants to give students
more space,
but sometimes it's hard to do it.
Legislative establishment
is necessary.
Through the university law
and the school fund,
it's two different things.
However,
the legislative process
is still ongoing.
Hello, I'm Xiaoyu.
Is Jeff studying
at Indiana Bloomington?
I also graduated
from this school.
I majored in higher education.
As far as I know,
the tuition fee
for public universities
is transparent.
It's in the US.
In my impression,
the IU Foundation
is not open
to the public.
I don't know
if there are any adjustments.
Some employees
are transparent.
In my impression,
the professors are not transparent.
In Taiwan,
the HR department
often discusses
whether the tuition fee
is suitable for the public.
In other words,
will it cause
some kind of
malicious competition?
I think we should
be careful
and consider
whether the tuition fee
is suitable for the public.
In the future,
will there be
a union
or some rights protection?
I think we can
work on it.
Through the union,
the tuition fee
can be improved.
I think it's
a positive step.
That's all.
I don't understand
one thing.
It's my personal question.
Why Taiwan
or other countries
like Japan
have such
poor
marketing
system?
What's the reason?
Why do we
become different
from the US?
In the US,
for the sake of talents
and PhD students,
they hire people
with their salary.
But in Taiwan,
the power of the labor market
is the opposite.
In other words,
we need to ask
the school to pay us tuition.
If we don't pay
the tuition fee,
no one will
pay the tuition fee.
That's my question.
Why is Taiwan
such a poor market?
What's the reason?
Does anyone
want to
answer this question?
It looks like
Yu wants to answer.
Let me answer
briefly.
When we had a meeting
last year,
Yu asked
this question.
Why is Taiwan
not legalized?
What's the current situation?
Yu's answer
was
there are
several doubts.
First,
all the departments that don't make money
may be shut down.
Because universities
are the only indicators.
Second,
the whole society
is divided.
What is our
view of education?
I may need to look up
the meeting notes.
There may be other answers.
However,
people generally
look at it
as a negative effect
on the society.
What's the difference
between legalization
and marketization?
That's all.
I'm Yu.
I have a question
about whether
higher education
is a capital market.
Is it necessarily good?
It involves many things,
such as regulation
and so on.
In my opinion,
universities should not
rely on the Ministry of Education.
Almost all universities
However,
the Ministry of Education
spends
less than half
of their budget.
As for
legalization,
such as Japan
or other countries,
it may lead to
the collapse of
non-profit science.
To be honest,
non-profit science
is still
maintained in the United States.
For example,
it is still maintained
in the top universities
in the field of
human and social science.
In my country,
the National University
is a national university.
It is responsible
for maintaining
non-profit science
in the field of
human and social science.
I think
there should be
more communication
between universities.
It is not just
trying to
promote non-profit science.
We should listen to
everyone's opinions.
That's all.
What about Zha Shi?
Do you have any opinion?
It's okay.
Ralph has already said that.
Okay.
It has been more than
an hour.
It will be an hour and a half
in 10 minutes.
That's what we didn't mention.
If you are curious or
want to know more,
you can ask our speaker.
Or did I miss something?
Okay.
Sorry.
Go ahead.
I just want to share
our high-profile
video and meeting
with you.
Okay.
Sorry.
I have a question.
Do you know
how many high-profile researchers
are needed in Taiwan?
Are there too many
high-profile researchers?
Can we
focus on some of them?
It's a classic question.
Can we ask
this way?
How many high-profile researchers
are needed?
How many schools?
How many teachers?
How many students?
It's a classic question.
How many schools?
How many teachers?
How many students?
Do you have any opinion?
Do I have to say?
It's the biggest
problem we have.
Obviously,
there must be a big employment problem.
Let me give you an example.
When we had a meeting,
there was a simple calculation.
There are so many
high-profile researchers you can hire
in a year.
There is no shortage of
people in the industry.
Every year,
there are at least
10 jobs
in the industry.
There is a big gap.
So, we asked the Ministry of Education
about the plan
of the whole
graduate school
or the whole
human resources evaluation.
To be honest,
the result we asked
was that
they didn't do well
in the special graduate school.
For example,
I said that
the Ministry of Education
did not investigate
the high-profile talents
for the development of 5 plus 2.
So,
if you want to say
if it's too deep now,
it must be too deep.
But what is a reasonable number?
Especially now,
it's a decimal trend.
When the industry transforms,
is there any organization
or a policy-making unit
that can provide
the answer?
In my experience,
I don't think
there is one.
Hello,
I'm Xiaoyu.
I think
to find the problem
or to find
the future trend,
I think
we can do it.
But what I'm confused about
is that we can't find the solution.
That's what I'm confused about.
Of course,
I think the industry needs
our supply and demand
must be
accurate.
That's what I'm confused about.
But now,
whether it's a PhD
or a future talent
evaluation,
I think
it's very difficult.
The industry
may not know
the relevant information.
But they may not know
the future development
of their company
or how many people
they need
in the next few years.
Even if you ask TSMC,
they may not know.
That's what I'm confused about.
How many students
do we need?
I agree that
with the number of students
and enrollment,
let's say
4,000 to 5,000 people a year,
the demand in the academic world
may be around 1,000 a year.
There is a big gap
between supply and demand.
But the problem is
that I think
PhD education
is half of
what we need
to find
excellent academic talents.
I think half of it
is the market mechanism.
Half of it is the economic planning,
half of it is the market mechanism.
In other words,
if a lot of people
are willing to take a PhD,
it's OK for us.
But you may be burdened
and take it as
a part of the economic planning.
For us,
it's more important
how to attract excellent people
to take a PhD.
This is what we may
focus on in the future,
whether it's research or industry.
As for the school,
as I mentioned at the end,
how many universities
or teachers
or students
or staff
are there?
Some of you may know
that if you calculate it,
you will know that
in the next 10 to 15 years,
I guess
there are only
national universities
and medical universities
with competitive
medical departments
in the future.
To be honest,
other schools will not be able to
take a PhD or transfer.
This is my personal opinion.
I guess
that
in the future,
the number of teachers
may be
around 40,000
or 50,000.
At that time,
there may be
only about 20,000 teachers
in the country.
This is our current estimate.
If you are interested,
you can keep calculating
and see if it's what we think.
Our idea is
to increase the number
of students
in national universities.
This so-called increase
is a situation
where the total number
is under control
and the number
of students
is constantly increasing.
The question is
about schools, students and teachers.
In fact,
we say that this meeting
must be held
school withdrawal regulations.
Otherwise,
from the perspective
of the Ministry of Education,
the Ministry of Education
has a budget
of more than 26 million yuan every year.
37% of the budget
is spent on higher education,
which is about 100 billion yuan.
The current direction
of the Ministry of Education
is to cut
some of the basic expenses
and apply for
a higher education upgrade plan
for the school.
Of course,
although private universities
are not public,
they still have some subsidies.
So all schools
say that the scholarship is not enough
to apply for a higher education upgrade plan.
In fact, this is just
a basic default.
I can't make some breakthrough plans.
These things are actually
so many from the entire Ministry of Education.
But maybe we are going the wrong way in Taiwan.
That is, from Guangzhou University
to today,
we have to close
these universities one by one.
In fact, we all know
how difficult this is in practice.
Why didn't the school withdrawal regulations
in Taiwan
take too much power?
If you want to close my private school,
how many people
will be affected?
How much is the interest structure?
So everyone stepped on it and didn't do it.
This is a very real
situation.
Now we are focusing on the industry
and pushing it to each school.
Now it's all like Xiaoyu said,
extra fees.
In fact, this is also a statistic.
Now the total enrollment
of universities in Taiwan
may be 250,000
or 260,000.
But the number of students we actually recruit
seems to be only 160,000.
What about the key industry now?
It's extra fees.
You will think,
how can there be such a gap in numbers?
But now as long as it's a key industry,
telecommunications, 5 plus 2,
the national defense industry,
I'll give you an extra fee for your school.
This is a strategy.
But why do this?
In the end, it's still a cruel thing.
You're going to cut the enrollment
of schools today.
What you touch is the teacher's
current teaching.
We can all understand
what the actual problem may be.
So when I think about
this question,
maybe I'm a minister.
I often
communicate with many people
about their own
fundamentalism.
And many times it's really
a huge thing.
It's really not that easy.
Maybe you have to start from a young age.
Do you think the Ministry of Education
is actually calculating
how many schools are left in the future?
I believe they won't do it.
But now,
just like the current version of the Ministry of Education
that is to say,
I encourage you,
I give you a way,
you can go.
But the Ministry of Education's attitude is
that in addition to this,
it has no way to follow more actively.
It has already planned
the number of schools that may be left in the future.
The rest of these are
going to be challenged in the future.
It early deployed
to tell these schools
that you should retire first.
In fact, this is really a very,
very difficult thing.
Many people give their opinions.
But from the perspective of the Ministry of Education,
it has a lot of pressure
from schools,
even a lot of teachers.
I think this is a big problem.
But indeed,
from the total number of recruits
to the actual number of recruits,
in fact, just having such a big gap,
we know that we definitely need
more clues.
I think there are many more
things to discuss.
We seem to have a question.
I think this question
is very suitable for an interlude.
This question comes from
Liao Kunyan.
His question is this.
In Taiwan,
among all kinds of problems,
does the public really care about
the education issue?
This is a very cruel question.
His answer is,
do you have any specific ideas
to help the public
solve this problem?
Let's take this question
to sum up today's event.
Let's go back to the order
from the beginning.
Let's start with Xiaoyu.
I am Xiaoyu.
I am a high-level educator.
But I often joke that
high-level education
is not professional.
The so-called lack of professionalism
is that we do not pay much attention
to the public's opinion.
As long as it is the public,
as long as it is someone who
used to go to college,
or as long as it is a college teacher
in the school,
everyone thinks they know
high-level education very well.
But in fact,
high-level education
is a very complicated
and a situation
that requires a lot of
details to be discussed.
In fact,
high-level education
is mainly based on
research universities.
In other words,
I can even say that
it is mainly based on
professors from the University of Taiwan.
But in fact,
professors from the University of Taiwan
have a disadvantage
that they cannot see
the situation of other types
of schools,
but the problem is that
we are really facing
a problem.
In fact, we cannot come up
with a solution
to solve the problem
to help the high-level education
industry or
other schools
to have a better development.
In this case,
it is difficult for me to say
whether the public is
concerned about high-level education
or not.
But in fact,
we should also help
other schools or institutions
to propose specific solutions
to the current situation
of high-level education.
Thank you.
Let's move on to Justin.
OK.
In fact,
I think that
high-level education
today is more focused on
post-doctoral or post-doctoral education.
In fact, this is a stage
of the pyramid.
Legislators want votes.
Which ethnic group has the most votes?
It is the state.
Because all people go through state education.
Most people go to college,
but today we are concerned
about the rights of doctoral students.
When we talk about this matter,
it is obvious that
it is so small.
But is it important?
Does it have anything to do
with national security and national competitiveness?
Absolutely.
I think
from this perspective,
we probably know
that legislators
who are really concerned
about this issue,
and even peers of the Ministry of Education,
when they are concerned about high-level education,
they will spend more time
and energy.
After all,
fewer and fewer students
and fewer and fewer people
are concerned about it.
In fact,
I think
it is important
to start from
what we are concerned about.
We must have our own reasons
and things we believe in,
so we come out to pay attention.
We call on more people
who are concerned about this issue.
In fact,
when I first heard about
what REEF was going to do in the future,
it was very, very important.
How can we get
more people
who are concerned about this issue
to pay more attention
and communicate more?
And through an organization,
the actual energy
you can generate is very strong.
I think it is very important
to cooperate with these
external units.
Because in the end,
as REEF said at the beginning,
from an official,
even from the president
of the Executive Yuan,
whether he supports it
or not,
it is up to the leaders
of these ministries
and legislators
to pay attention.
There is no way to call
a person who is already working
and not studying for a doctor
to pay attention to this issue right away.
But this is actually very distant.
So I think it is very pragmatic
to bring people who are willing to pay attention
together through more activities
as much as possible,
so that we can do something together.
That's all.
Okay, then it's REEF's turn.
If you think about it
in a pragmatic way,
after we held the meeting
of REEF,
we thought that
instead of doing more research
and policy development
for the Ministry of Education,
we should think about
how to continue
a long-term power
that can continue to happen
with so many problems.
Assuming that
there is no sudden
interest in
high-ranking or doctors,
because of the issue of
the ballot,
and assuming that
there is no sudden interest
in government officials,
I think
there are two possible
possible options.
There are three possible directions.
One is that
government officials have a certain chance
to pay attention,
and maybe they can
have some formal
legal institutions
to do the research
on the policy.
The second is that
universities should have
more resources
or be more serious
in this area.
There will be a more
stable power in it.
The third is what I'm thinking
and what I want to do.
When I asked the
High-Level Education Association,
they were
proposing some
reform proposals.
However, the youth
association under them
has no manpower
because everyone
has to go to work after graduation.
Although the situation
is difficult,
there are some organizations
and organizations
around me
who are willing
to pay attention.
I hope to
form some consensus
to form an organization.
Instead of
proposing a proposal
or a policy study,
it is more feasible
to gather everyone's
opinions and
deepen
or discuss
and form an organization.
That's it.
Thank you for watching!
Translated by Hua Chenyu English Subs