You can find the recording online a week and a half later.
If you have any questions during this process,
you can leave a comment in the chat box.
We will have Q&A time at the end for everyone to ask questions.
Let's get started.
Thank you everyone for listening to my presentation.
Hello everyone, I'm Lai Jun-Hai.
You can call me Matt.
First of all, I would like to thank Tyra for inviting me to share my research.
Let me introduce myself.
I'm from Yonghe, Hsinchu.
I graduated from National University of China.
I worked as an engineer for a year and a half at BASF in Taiwan.
Then I went to UCLA to study engineering.
I graduated in 2017.
I am currently working at Startup Battery Streak.
At the same time, I am also a visiting scholar at UCLA.
My main work is focused on the development and mass production of new battery materials,
as well as the transfer between the company and UCLA.
Today's topic is
Designing pseudo-capacitance for fast-charging batteries.
That is, how to apply the mechanism of solid-state batteries to fast-charging batteries.
First of all, why do we need fast-charging batteries?
The first motivation is the accumulation of electromagnetic traffic.
Charging stations are currently set up in three levels.
The first level is the plug-in that everyone puts at home.
It can charge 3 to 6 kilometers per hour.
The second level is the charging station in the parking lot.
It can charge 20 to 30 kilometers per hour.
The third level is the fastest Tesla charging station.
It can charge 5 kilometers per minute.
Interestingly, the current charging station is still far less than the gas station.
But it is almost impossible to see such a long queue at the charging station.
Not everyone has an electric car,
but 5 kilometers per minute is still too slow compared to the time required for gas.
The second application of fast-charging batteries is the popularization of renewable energy.
As of last year, renewable energy has reached one-third of the global power generation.
50% of the power generation comes from renewable energy.
Other European countries also reach 20 to 30% of renewable power.
We all know that when wind and solar energy are converted into electricity,
they must be paired with suitable batteries.
However, these batteries can't be charged quickly,
so they are inefficient.
For example, when the wind speed is fast,
there will be a momentary large current.
The batteries that can't be charged at low power
will become waste heat and reduce the life of the battery.
So basically, this concept is the same as the concept of fast-charging batteries paired with aging cell phones.
The third application of fast-charging batteries is plant-based medical equipment.
Generally, the supply of such equipment is made up of a battery paired with a capacitor,
which is in the box at the bottom left.
Generally, the battery is used to monitor the function of low power for a long time,
while the capacitor is used to respond to high power in a short time.
Due to the limited size of the equipment and the need for different organ parts,
a single high-power battery is used to replace the two-in-one mode.
This has always been the trend in the development of this type of equipment power supply.
Of course, in addition to the above three applications,
there are other applications.
I won't go into detail here.
So in this main speech,
it mainly introduces how to improve the power density and energy density of the storage components using the materials of the capacitor.
As shown in the picture on the left,
the x-axis is the energy density,
and the y-axis is the power density.
First, I will briefly introduce the materials of the storage components and the techniques required for analysis.
Then, the first part will start with the high-power supercapacitor material in blue.
Then, the high-power characteristics will be achieved by using a non-oxidized carbonate residue.
The second part will start with the lithium battery.
Here is an example of fluorine,
L-NBOPF,
which achieves high power density by nanomerizing the battery material.
Generally, batteries or supercapacitors are basically composed of two terminals.
The positive terminal and the negative terminal are placed on the aluminum foil and copper foil respectively.
The two terminals are separated by a multi-hole separator,
which is the middle part of the separator,
to avoid short-circuit.
When charging the battery, the lithium battery moves in the capacitor,
and the battery material produces an oxidation reaction.
At the same time, the battery moves in the external circuit to achieve the balance of the electric current.
The electric current is the main focus of our discussion today.
It is mainly composed of the storage material, carbon, and the high-voltage supercapacitor.
The electric current needs to have a certain vacuum.
It is like a sponge.
It must contain enough electrolysis.
At the same time, it must have enough conductivity to be a high-voltage supercapacitor.
Although the structure of the battery and the capacitor are the same,
the storage mechanism is completely different.
The mechanism of the capacitor is absorbed by the lithium.
In the external circuit, the aluminum foil and the copper foil are separated and absorbed by the surface of the battery.
Because the lithium is absorbed by the surface for a short time,
this mechanism is most conducive to fast charging.
The disadvantage is that its surface area is limited,
so the density of energy is generally low.
In contrast, the storage method of the battery
uses the oxidation reaction inside the material.
In this case, the lithium can enter the material,
and its energy is far greater than that of the capacitor.
However, since the lithium moves very slowly inside the material,
it is therefore unable to do high-speed charging.
Next, we will introduce how to distinguish the battery from the capacitor.
Basically, it is based on electrical chemistry analysis.
We will make the pre-analyzed material into an electrolyte
and test it in the same electrolyte solution.
Generally, the device to be tested
has a single-phase electrolyte test on the upper left,
and a double-phase torque battery test on the lower left.
There are two main methods of testing.
The first method is the cyclic voltammetry,
which is abbreviated as CV.
The principle is to change the speed of voltage change
to measure the change in current.
The second method is the DC voltage test,
which is abbreviated as GC.
In the case of DC voltage charging,
it measures the change in voltage of the battery
and makes a diagram of the voltage.
Now we use GC and CV to get the diagram
to distinguish the battery from the capacitor.
They are two different storage mechanisms.
The capacitor on the left can be seen that
the CV is a rectangle,
while the GC is basically a diagonal.
The battery on the right is composed of a set of peaks,
while the GC is mainly composed of a horizontal line.
Now that we know how to judge the material of the battery
and the material of the capacitor,
we can look for the material of the fast charging battery.
What characteristics do we hope the fast charging battery has?
We hope it has the characteristics of electromagnetic chemistry on the left,
which allows it to be a fast charging battery.
It also has the characteristics of the material on the right,
which increases the density of energy
by storing energy through the reaction of oxygen-chloride.
This is the material we are looking for.
The material of the capacitor
not only has a rectangle CV,
but also a diagonal GC,
and it stores energy through the reaction of oxygen-chloride.
Next, I will talk about the main character I will introduce today,
which is the T-Phased,
Orphohombic Phased,
NB205.
Next, I will call it NIOVIA.
In addition to having the characteristics of electromagnetic chemistry,
its energy density
is equivalent to the energy density of lithium carbon dioxide,
which is in the lithium-ion battery.
Its energy density is 10 times that of the capacitor.
Its power density,
which is the power of its fast charging,
can also reach 10 times that of the battery.
Its only drawback is that
it is still oxygen-chloride,
so its power consumption
is the first topic we are going to fix.
The first part
is to mix carbon with NIOVIA
to improve the properties of NIOVIA.
We need to deduce a good NIOVIA,
and we will eventually deduce
what kind of properties a good NIOVIA battery needs
to show the characteristics of its lithium-ion battery.
A good NIOVIA battery
basically needs two parts.
The first is the high-voltage part,
and the second is the part that can have a high pore density.
In this study,
we mainly used three materials.
The first material is our protagonist, NIOVIA.
The second material is our chemical-capable
Reduced Graphene Oxide, also known as RGO.
Its purpose is to provide short-term conductivity.
The third material
is the one on the far right,
Carbide Derived Carbon, also known as CDC.
It is a kind of carbon dioxide.
Its main purpose is that
it has a polypore structure
and its size is in the micrometer level,
so it can provide long-term conductivity.
The way we prepare the battery
is to first plant NIOVIA on RGO.
Next, we combine NIOVIA RGO with CDC
to get NIOVIA RGO CDC,
also known as NRC.
Finally, we make NRC
into a commercial-grade battery
and test it to prove that
it has a high-power and high-density
storage characteristics
at the right pore density.
This slide shows the details of the material equipment.
The main equipment is
the water-heating method.
We put the precursor
into the autoclave
and heat it up to 180°C
for 12 hours.
Next, we wash the particles
and dry them.
After drying,
we heat it up to 500°C
to get the body structure we want,
which is T-phase,
or ophiobic phase.
Next, we combine NIOVIA RGO
with CDC.
The main purpose is to
make this composite material
in the form of surface electrolysis.
Next, we make it into a battery
and test it.
We have 20% NIOVIA,
40% NRC20,
and 60% NRC20.
The BET on the right
is the analysis of the surface electrolysis.
It shows that
the surface electrolysis of the material
increases with the
composition of the CDC.
This means that
this composite method
does not cause the CDC to lose its surface area,
or the CDC to be less airtight,
or its structure to collapse.
Therefore, we can use
a simple ratio to
achieve the airtightness we need.
There are also two black dots on the picture.
These two black dots
are where we directly plant NIOVIA
on the CDC.
If we
do not use
this composite method
but use
the water-heat method
to directly plant it on the CDC,
at high temperature,
the CDC's
surface area
will...
Because the surface area is too large,
the surface area will decrease
at high temperature.
We want to use the CDC
to improve the airtightness
of the electrode.
This is the idea.
Next, we need to
use the CV to judge the electrode.
Let's see if it is like a battery material
or an electric material.
In the case of changing the minority,
we can get the corresponding current.
Therefore, we use the current
to make judgments with the change of the minority.
If the
material is like a battery,
the change of the current
will be multiplied by the minority.
If the material
is like a capacitor,
the current
will be multiplied by the minority.
In other words,
when the minority is doubled,
the current will be doubled.
Combining these two formulas,
we can get
the following formula
from the experiment.
The current is equal to the magnitude
multiplied by the minority.
This is called
B-value analysis.
We want the material
to be as fast as the capacitor.
Therefore, we want the B-value
to be as close to 1 as possible.
This proves that the material
can do high-speed charging.
Next,
the NRC
can store different
current
at different speeds.
On the left,
we use the minority
to burn the NRC.
The lowest value
is 100% Cdc.
The way
we control the minority
is from the slowest 30-minute
charging point on the left to the
90-second charging point on the right.
The y-axis is the energy generated by me.
As time goes by,
the energy generated by me
will be reduced.
We want the line to be as flat as possible.
This means that the material
can do high-speed charging
as well as low-speed charging.
The lowest value is 100% Cdc.
As the amount of niobia increases,
the density of the NRC
will also increase.
Up to 40%, the increased current
will not be affected by the minority.
From 0% to 20% to 40%,
the current will remain as flat.
From 0% to 60%,
the NRC will be
charged at 90 seconds.
The current is
less than 40%.
The highest value, 100%,
although the total
current is
less than 40%,
we can expect
that when the charging time
is less than 90 seconds,
the NRC will increase by 40%.
On the right is the B-value
introduced in the previous page.
When the curve
is closer to 1,
we mainly do CV
for different materials.
Then we do
the analysis of B-value.
The result of the analysis is in the lower right corner.
When the curve is closer to 1,
it means that the charging speed is faster.
By this, we can judge
that the charging speed of
NRC40 is faster than
NRC60 and 100%
of NIOBIA.
This also proves that when 60%
of the CVC is stored in the electrode,
the electrode has sufficient airtightness
to accommodate sufficient electrolysis
to show the characteristics
of NIOBIA lithium-ion battery.
Finally,
we combine the NRC40
with the traditional lithium-ion electrode
to form a full electrode
to do
the analysis of CV
and GC.
In terms of CV,
we can get
the characteristics of the lithium-ion
we just talked about,
which is that it is a rectangular CV.
In terms of GC,
we also get
a oblique GC.
At the same time,
due to the combination of NIOBIA,
we not only
increase the energy density
at low power,
but also increase the energy density
at high power.
At the power of
3000W per kg,
we can store
up to 23W
per kg of energy density.
Next,
I will briefly summarize the figure on the right.
The first part
is that we use the amount of Cdc
to adjust the airtightness and
conductivity of the NRC composite material.
At the same time,
it has high energy and
fast charging characteristics.
In other words,
we use Cdc as the starting point
to mix different NIOBIA
to increase its energy density.
By maximizing the airtightness and conductivity,
we can increase
the overall
energy density of the NRC
and preserve
the high power characteristics of Cdc.
The second part
I want to share is
the LNVOPF material
as a medical equipment energy supply application.
Speaking of medical equipment energy supply,
I will use
an implantable
cardioverter
defibrillator
ICD
as an example.
Its Chinese name is
implantable defibrillator.
It basically
detects your heart beat.
When your heart beats abnormally,
it will use
high current to stimulate your heart beat.
For example,
when your heart stops beating,
it will stimulate your heart beat.
I am not a medical background,
so I only understand
the basic concept of this device.
The main usage method
is still left to the doctor.
ICD
mainly uses
high current and low current output.
The low current part
is mainly responsible for the battery.
The high current part
is responsible for the circuit board.
There is also a device size
at the bottom.
The size is about one-fourth of the heart.
Most of the area
is actually from the low-voltage circuit.
Another
medical device
is
DBS
Deep Brain Stimulator.
This type of device
has the same principle,
but the current demand
is smaller than ICD.
DBS mainly stimulates
the brain nerve.
The power supply
is also made up of
a battery and a circuit.
When we want to
put this medical device
in the body,
we hope that
its size can be smaller and better
to save more space.
For example,
we want to find a material
that has the characteristics of a battery and a circuit.
We need to make a device
either a circuit
or a battery.
We want to make a device
that prefers a battery
because the size of the battery is smaller.
We use a single storage device
to provide these two currents.
This way we can save a lot of
the power supply
and medical equipment space.
This material
is
LNVOPF.
LNVOPF
mainly comes from
the transformation of
the structure of
the nascon-nucleotide conductor.
After being mixed,
the voltage of the
LNVOPF
increases,
which means it can
store more energy.
When I
put this
in the body,
the change in
the size of the
LNVOPF
also decreases.
This means that
the size of the
LNVOPF
is similar to
the lithium carbon dioxide
in the battery.
The most important thing is
that this material
has the characteristics of
battery and current.
Next we will introduce
another way to
distinguish the battery
from the current,
which is to use
X-ray diffraction
XRD analysis
to find out
if there is a change
in the structure of the
metal body,
which is the
x-ray diffraction
in the material.
In general, the charge of the
battery follows the
x-ray diffraction,
while the charge of the
nucleotide is
stored in the
solid.
In low voltage peak,
it follows the x-ray diffraction,
while in high voltage peak,
there is no x-ray diffraction.
This means that this material
can be used as a battery
in low voltage,
and can be used as a current
in high voltage.
But this
thing is not as simple as you think.
This material
is charged twice
every hour
Here,
let me introduce a little bit.
When we talk about charging,
we use a unit called C-ray.
This unit
C-ray
Everyone says a few Cs,
which means it can charge several times
in an hour.
So in this material,
it charges twice
every hour,
which is the part of 2C.
Basically, it can also store
80-90% of the charge.
But when you
shorten the charging time to
3 minutes, it can only charge
8%.
The reason is that during the charging process,
it will charge the battery first.
Then it
goes through the capacitor part.
But because the charging speed of the battery part
is too slow today,
I can't even charge the capacitor.
So
it's a bit like this.
Mainly because the charging speed of the battery
is too slow,
the overall charging speed
will decrease.
Next,
this study
is to use
the material nanometrization
to shorten the time
and distance
of the particles in the material
to increase the
charging speed of the material.
Next,
we are going to synthesize
this nanometer NVOPF
and discuss
the size of the size
for fast charging.
First, the way we make it is
to put all our
materials into
this solvent thermal
method to synthesize. We also put it
into the pressure suit.
After
12 hours,
after 185°C,
we take out the material and
clean it.
We will dry it.
Next, we use
XRD, X-ray diffraction, to confirm the material.
After confirming that the material
has no problems and no impurities
in it, we will make it
an electrode for electromagnetic testing.
Here,
we use
the ratio of the material
and the temperature of the
synthesis to get different
shapes of NVOPF.
Basically, this NVOPF is a
rectangular body.
We usually get a brick
shape.
If it is longer,
it becomes a rod.
If it is shorter, it becomes a pellet.
If the pellet is small, it becomes a particle.
We are going to
discuss the shape
of the NVOPF
and the size of it.
We will also discuss the impact of its
reaction speed.
Next, we
use the b-value method
to analyze
the properties of the fast charge.
In the first step, we
make a different number of
CVs for the material.
From these four peaks,
we can get
individual b-values.
Then, we make
b-values with different
aspect ratios,
different widths,
and its size
to see
how it changes.
On the left,
this is the NVOPF
pellet.
On the right,
we use the rod
to make changes.
The aspect ratio
gradually decreases to
the brick shape,
and finally to the pellet shape.
The b-value
decreases as the aspect ratio
decreases.
When we decrease the aspect ratio
of the material,
the characteristics of the fast charge
will be more and more like a capacitor.
It can be used
as a material for high-speed charge.
On the other hand,
we also
compare
the particle size
to the b-value.
We combine
microns
and microns.
Then, we reduce to nanometers.
From hundreds of nanometers
to dozens of nanometers.
We can see that
when the size decreases,
the b-value also increases.
The increase in b-value
means that the smaller the particle,
the more suitable it is
to be used
as a capacitor.
The focus here
is on the microbrick.
Its peak b-value
is close to 0.5.
0.5 means
the same reaction as a battery.
When we make a nanoparticle,
all the reactions
of the oxidation reaction
have a b-value
of 0.7 or higher.
Next,
we do the charge-resistance test.
The nanoparticle
of NVOPF
can charge up to 90%
in 2 hours
in 3 minutes.
This means that
after the nanoparticle
of NVOPF
has been nanoparticulated,
the reaction rate
of the battery
has increased significantly.
This also leads to an increase
in the reaction rate of our capacitors.
The NVOPF
and nanoparticles
of NVOPF
can charge up to 80%
in 100 seconds.
We mainly test
two temperatures.
The first is room temperature.
The second is 37 degrees,
which is our human body temperature.
The main reason for this test
is that we want to put this material
into the human body.
In this environment,
the NVOPF
can charge up to 80%
in 100 seconds
in the human body
temperature.
The energy
of the NVOPF
can reach
100 watts
per kilogram
in 4000 watts
per kilogram.
This means that
the energy density
of the NVOPF
can reach 100 watts
per kilogram.
Finally, we apply
this material
to the
Deep Brain Stimulator
DBS application.
We all know that
this device
must have
a soldering mode
and a battery mode.
We charge it
with a fixed current.
Then the current
will convert the energy
to output
in the form of a capacitor.
So we designed
two different modes.
The first is the capacitor mode,
which means that both charging and discharging
are soldering.
The capacitor mode
allows us to
detect
the overall
amount of current
in the body.
The discharging mode
allows us to
give feedback to the body
and use the current
to perform different
treatments.
So there are these two modes.
The battery mode
uses the soldering mode
to charge the battery.
The capacitor mode
uses the
discharging mode
to discharge.
So the capacitor mode is
discharging.
The battery mode
uses the discharging mode
to discharge.
So basically,
we use these two modes
to operate the battery.
The battery
can discharge
up to 1,000 rounds
in this mode
with the
electric current
and the high-speed
discharging current
of the soldering current.
In each round,
it can provide
at least 3,000 soldering
to measure
and give feedback.
The battery can also
provide 60% electric current.
Let's compare
our battery
with the current
DBS specifications.
Basically,
our output current
is from 4,000
microampere,
which is 4 mA
to 12 mA.
Compared to the current specifications,
our current
output current
is greater than
these specifications.
In terms of frequency,
we can only measure
a few microseconds
on the device
because
the device
only measures 50Hz.
This 50Hz
also covers
the frequency required
for some of these functions.
Next,
I will use this graph
to make a brief summary.
In the second part,
we use nanoparticle
to convert the
NBOPF, which cannot be
fast charged,
into fast charge.
In addition,
we also proved the
feasibility of the
soldering current
in DBS.
Let me make a brief summary.
What is
the so-called
take-home message?
First, I hope everyone
knows what a soldering current is.
A soldering current is
actually a storage mechanism
that has the power of the
soldering current and the
density of the battery.
The second point is
how we can judge the soldering current.
Of course, it is through
the method of electromagnetic mechanics.
We have such a CV,
a oblique GC,
and no change
in the material during
the oxidation process.
Finally,
how do we design a soldering current?
Mainly,
there are three points in my demo.
The first is
the conductivity and
airtightness.
The conductivity and
airtightness of my electrode
can optimize my soldering current.
The second point is
to nanomaterialize the material
and adjust its phase change
so that the material of our
general battery
is not
too slow
in the transfer of ions.
In the part of the battery,
it can
reach the high speed
charging point.
Thank you for your attention.
If you have any questions,
please feel free to ask.
Thank you.
Thank you, Matt.
Now we can
start the Q&A.
In the chat box,
Gavin has some questions.
Do you want to unmute
and ask your question?
I would like to ask
what is the electrolyte used
when you start soldering?
It should be an organic electrolyte.
Because your reference electrode
is for aluminum.
That's right.
I use
LiPF6
ECDMC.
It is an electrolyte
for lithium battery.
So we can understand
why your lowest voltage
is around 1.2V.
Another question is
what is the distribution
of the oxygen-oxide
in the electrode?
Because recently,
there is no supercapacitor.
I believe the distribution
of oxygen-oxide
should be an interesting
or important question.
Basically,
the distribution
is between
1.2V and
1.2V to 3V.
Here.
The distribution
is from 1.2V
to 2.5V.
Here.
The capacity
of niobium oxide
should be
200mA.
When it is full, it is 200mA.
From 1.2V to 2.5V
means 90% of the voltage
comes from here.
Does it mean that
when it is less than 1.2V,
it will be more than 2.5V?
When it is less than 1.2V,
the electrolyte will be dissociated.
The material won't be dissociated.
When it is more than 2.5V,
you can't see
the value of the current.
The current will be
close to zero.
It is the same as
this picture.
The CV is the same.
It will be less than
3V.
Basically, it is less than 3V.
OK.
You showed this slide,
so I want to ask you
the following question.
How do you calculate
the B-value and the electrolyte?
We scan different CVs.
Each CV
has a current
at each voltage.
We analyze
each current
for the change of the minority.
B-value should be
less than 3V,
or it doesn't matter
even if it is any current.
In pseudo-capacitor,
basically,
there are
consecutive
redox reactions.
When you produce
a box,
you only analyze
the current at the peak.
You are not fair
to the electrons
Basically,
in pseudo-capacitor,
you can use this formula
on all CVs
to draw the continuous curve.
Another story
behind this is
the redox happens
below 2V.
It is less than 2V.
What do you see without redox?
You see EDLC.
What does EDLC mean?
EDLC means
the reaction
of the electron.
For example,
the electron travels
from far away
to the surface of the electrode.
What do you mean by diffusion control?
Yes.
In addition,
we increase
the density of Cdc,
which increases the vacuum of the electrode.
Without redox,
the kinetic
energy of the electrode
increases.
With redox,
the kinetic energy of the electrode
also increases.
Any other questions?
Thank you.
The last question
is the last one.
Any other questions?
I will ask later.
Any other
questions?
Hello.
I would like to ask Matt
some questions.
Matt, thank you for your speech.
My main question is
about your first project.
At that time,
I would like to know
the particle size of
Nairobia.
The particle size
is about
here.
You can see it in the upper right corner.
The particle size is
about 20-30 nm.
20-30 nm.
So,
you will combine
reduced graphene oxide and Cdc
to increase
the conductivity of the electrode.
That's right.
Cdc also provides vacuum.
OK.
I am doing research on
hierarchical porous carbons.
There are
small micropores
and large macropores.
So,
I am thinking
that if we combine
other vacuum materials,
will it increase
the conductivity of the electrode?
Yes.
Because
I have enough vacuum,
I can
absorb more
electrolytes
into the electrode.
There is a slide
that I did not show.
We still have some time.
You can see
why Nairobia requires
a large vacuum.
Basically,
it comes from
OK.
This slide
shows the result
calculated by
Nernst
equation
and Poisson equation.
Poisson equation
represents the
dielectric constant
of the material.
So, under different voltages,
how many electrons
are on the surface.
When the voltage
moves to
the middle of the graph,
the capacitive part
shows how many electrons
are on the surface of the material.
But when the voltage
moves to a certain level,
Nairobia starts to react.
I need a large amount of
electrons to enter the material.
So, when it needs a large amount of electrons
to enter the material,
it will cause a surface vacuum.
The surface vacuum
is the reason
why Nairobia's
connectivity drops.
That's why
the material needs
higher concavity
to maintain
the characteristics of
the capacitive part
at high speed
or at high voltage.
I have a follow-up question.
How did you come up with
reducing graphene oxide
with Cdc?
Reducing graphene oxide
has another advantage
in the synthesis.
Basically,
if you want to grow oxide,
the oxygen ligand
of graphene oxide
can be the nucleation site
of these oxides.
Whether you want to grow metal particles
or oxide particles,
they are easy to grow on top.
Since there are many sites,
the particles can grow
very small.
Graphene oxide
is like an additive.
It can make your particle size very small.
Second, it also increases
the conductivity.
In the case of graphene oxide,
there are several ways to produce electricity.
For example, when you do filtration,
you use filtration to make it stack together.
Because it is
a two-dimensional structure,
so when you do filtration,
it will naturally
become a very dense electrode.
If it is a very dense electrode,
basically,
the electrolyte cannot penetrate.
So we want to find
a special structure,
which is Cdc.
This kind of
structure of graphene oxide
is mixed inside.
But we don't want to mix too much,
because if we mix too much,
the density of the energy
will be relatively reduced.
Got it.
Thank you.
Are there any other questions?
If not,
I will ask my last question.
After talking about ZMath,
you mentioned
how to distinguish the battery,
but now
in the telecom industry,
there is a more popular topic,
which is solid-state electrolyte or solid-state electrolyte.
I want to know
the difference between
solid-state electrolyte
and the other two,
or how to distinguish them.
Actually,
I haven't done the study electrolyte part.
You want to ask
the study electrolyte part, right?
Because I mentioned that
the second topic,
solid-state electrolyte,
is also a popular topic.
Yes, it used to be
solid-state electrolyte,
but we changed
its structure,
and used it as an electrolyte.
Basically,
solid-state electrolyte,
I don't know much about it.
What I know about solid-state electrolyte
is that
its conductivity
must be very thin.
Because its conductivity is not as fast as liquid.
Although it is a solid-state electrolyte,
it is not as fast as liquid.
Another thing is that
everyone says that
solid-state electrolyte
can avoid
SEI reaction.
But in fact,
this is a mistake.
In fact, solid-state electrolyte
will have a big effect
on its SEI
in its first cycle.
In our group,
in addition to doing high-speed charge,
another part is
3D battery.
3D battery is to make some
electrical structure to make it a satellite battery.
In that part,
for solid-state electrolyte,
we hope to use solid-state electrolyte.
Because solid-state electrolyte
has a higher density
than liquid.
So we can save a lot of liquid
needed volume.
But they found that in the first cycle,
this SEI
will still occur.
And after it occurs,
because it is a solid-state electrolyte,
it is very difficult to solve.
Basically, your material is closely connected at the beginning.
But after the first cycle,
it will separate.
Thank you for your answer.
Are there any other questions?
If there are no questions,
Max,
did you leave your email?
Yes,
I put it in the last slide.
If you have any questions,
you can
send me an email.
Thank you for your participation.
Thank you, Max,
for giving us such a wonderful speech.
This recording
will be available online
in about a week.
You can continue
to discuss
with Max
related research.
Thank you.