Welcome everyone to participate in the online speech of Tara today.
Today, we are very honored to invite Lu Yiquan, a Ph.D. candidate at UC Berkeley, to help us do a talk on his research.
Tara is an online platform that focuses on Ph.D. students from Taiwan and abroad,
and we hope that these Ph.D. students can do their own research on the Tara platform.
We also hope that this platform can attract talents in the same field to exchange and collaborate with each other.
This is our end goal, and this is the main work that Tara is currently doing.
Today, Lu Yiquan will mainly talk about the topic of 3T-Humans in GCM,
when and where are the first livable places on Earth.
Lu Yiquan is a Ph.D. student at the University of Taiwan Physics Department,
and later graduated as a Ph.D. student at the University of Taiwan Physics Department,
and is now a Ph.D. student at UC Berkeley,
so he is very loyal to physics.
It's not like me, I just jumped into a lot of different fields.
Looking at this GCM, Global Climate Change Model,
I am a bit familiar with this name, but I am a biologist.
GCM in our biology is called Glial Missing Homology,
which is another protein name.
So there are a lot of, you know, sometimes these abbreviations are so-called mixed up.
So when I saw this topic, I suddenly wondered if it was related to my biology.
No, it has something to do with global climate change.
Okay, we are honored to have Yiquan to do this talk for us today.
Okay, the stage is yours.
Okay, thank you, host.
Okay, so what does this topic mean?
I'll tell you later.
The main question I want to answer in this speech is the following.
That is, in the future world,
which place on Earth will be the most unsuitable for humans to start living in?
This project is a project that I have been doing with my professor David Rums.
Okay, at the beginning of the speech, I want to give you a sentence first.
Let's see if it makes sense.
This sentence is like this.
He said that now on Earth,
basically every place is suitable for living.
Okay, every place, including the South Pole and the North Pole.
Can you think about it?
Is this possible?
In fact, it is possible.
For example, what would we do if we were in a hotter place?
If it's really too hot, our temperature starts to rise.
Then we may start to sweat.
Sweating is a great heat dissipation mechanism.
Because when the sweat evaporates, it can take away a lot of heat.
If it's in a colder place,
for example, the South Pole and the North Pole.
At this time, of course, we don't need to sweat.
But we can, for example, put on clothes.
Then, if necessary, we can start to tremble.
Trembling can increase our metabolism.
Metabolism will increase our body temperature.
So basically, whether you are in a hot place or a cold place,
our body temperature can remain stable.
Our body temperature is about 37 degrees Celsius.
When we do science, we use the Kepler scale.
It's about 310 Kelvin.
This is our standard body temperature.
If it's too hot, we sweat.
Keep your body cool and dissipate heat.
If it's too cold, we tremble.
Increase metabolism.
But this is the current state of the Earth.
Whether it's cold or hot,
we are all suitable for survival.
But if we ask a question now.
In the future, if the climate starts to warm up,
is the Earth still suitable for human survival?
Is it possible that in some places,
because it's too hot,
even if we sweat,
we still can't survive.
Because our body temperature is too high,
we can't survive.
Is it possible?
Basically, I want to answer this question.
If it happens in the future,
where will it happen?
In which year?
Before answering this question,
we need to understand how the human body dissipates heat.
We have a very simple human model here.
This human model
basically divides the human body into two parts.
One is our core.
The other is our skin surface.
The core and the skin surface
have their own temperature.
T-Core refers to our core temperature.
It's about 37 degrees Celsius.
T-Skin refers to the surface temperature of our skin.
The surface temperature of the skin can be high or low.
For example, under the sun,
the surface temperature of the skin may be higher.
In a cold place,
the temperature of the skin will be lower.
But basically,
our core temperature
is basically 37 degrees Celsius.
It won't change.
After having this model,
we want to understand
under what circumstances
our core temperature will start to change.
I'll use a little bit of math here.
But don't worry.
There's no high-level knowledge in this math.
Basically, it's to tell us
how our core temperature changes with time.
I wrote something on the left.
It's called the T-Core.
It means
how our core temperature changes with time.
The core temperature can rise or fall.
What makes it rise?
First, it's our metabolic rate.
The metabolic rate is the heat produced
by chemical changes in the human body.
For example, if we sit still
and listen to a lecture,
the metabolic rate is about 100 watts.
100 watts is the unit of energy.
The metabolic rate can increase our body temperature.
It's very useful in winter.
If you feel cold in winter,
the metabolic rate will be higher.
It can increase our core temperature.
After the heat is produced,
our core wants to dissipate the heat.
The mechanism to dissipate the heat
is conduction.
The core will transfer the heat
produced by the metabolic rate
to our skin.
The skin is not an oil lamp.
After it receives the heat,
it will try to dissipate the same heat
into the atmosphere.
We can also write a similar formula.
This is a mathematical detail.
Because our skin is too small,
the heat is very small.
We can assume that
the temperature of our skin changes instantly.
It won't rise or fall like our body temperature.
I deliberately write 0 on the left side of the function.
This is a mathematical technique.
We don't have to think about
how the skin changes at any time.
We only need to know
how the temperature of our skin changes.
How does the temperature of our skin change?
First, it will receive the heat
from the core,
which is conduction.
Conduction will raise the temperature of our skin.
It can also dissipate the heat
to the outside world,
which is heat loss to air.
This is what it means.
Let's take a look at the first function.
I don't know if you can see the mouse.
It's okay.
Can you see the mouse?
Okay, thank you.
The meaning of the first function is
if the core temperature is higher,
it will raise the core temperature.
If the core temperature is higher,
as you can see the symbol,
it will lower the body temperature.
Basically, my body temperature
is determined by these two factors,
metabolism and conduction.
The temperature of my skin is the same.
Conduction will raise the temperature of my skin.
But it will also dissipate the heat to the outside world,
which is heat loss to air.
So the temperature of the skin will start to drop.
What we want to know is
what situation
will our core temperature
continue to rise
and continue to drop?
Now let's take a look at the following function,
which is heat loss to air.
What kind of way does the skin
send heat to the atmosphere?
There are three mechanisms.
I now change the function
to three functions.
The first function is called long wave.
What is long wave?
Long wave is any object with temperature
will emit electromagnetic waves.
The wavelength of the electromagnetic waves
is determined by the temperature of the object.
For example, the temperature of the sun is very high,
about 6000 degrees.
So the electromagnetic waves emitted
are very short.
Because the human body temperature
is only about 37 degrees Celsius,
the atmosphere is about this temperature.
So the long wave emitted
is very long.
So I wrote a long wave here.
It means that
compared with the electromagnetic waves of sunlight,
the electromagnetic waves that the human body can emit
are very long.
So I call it long wave.
The human body can dissipate heat
by the long wave.
This is the first mechanism.
The second mechanism is sensible heat.
In Chinese,
I checked it yesterday,
it should be called顯热,
which means obvious heat.
It actually means
the transmission between the skin and the atmosphere.
That is to say,
if you encounter a cold air today,
your skin temperature will start to drop.
If the temperature of the atmosphere is relatively high,
your skin temperature will start to rise.
This is sensible heat.
The last one is called latent heat.
Latent heat is called
潜热.
It means that
if you start to sweat now,
and the skin is covered with sweat,
when the sweat starts to evaporate,
it can take away the temperature of the skin.
This is latent heat.
Of course, if you want to say
if this person doesn't sweat,
then we don't have the third one.
We only have the first two.
So the third one must sweat
to be in here.
Now let's think about
the human body model.
What kind of question do we want to answer?
We want to ask
if we will die from too much heat in the future.
So we imagine that
when you feel very hot,
you may be dying soon.
What would I do then?
We may take off all our clothes.
We may think,
forget it.
I'm dying soon,
so I'll take off all my clothes.
When you're not wearing clothes,
basically longwave and sensible heat
can work very well.
Because you don't have clothes to block
the heat between you and the atmosphere.
So when we take off our clothes,
it actually helps dissipate the heat.
At the same time, we may be too hot,
so the whole body may be full of sweat.
So the third one also exists.
We hope that our human body surface
is full of sweat.
Of course, you may think that
some people,
such as the elderly,
may not sweat much.
People like this
are not easy to dissipate heat.
I don't know why
the elderly
don't know what the relationship is.
Maybe it's because
their heat dissipation mechanism is poor.
One reason is that
they don't sweat much.
But what we want to ask now is that
healthy people
can sweat moderately.
In this case,
will they still die in the future?
So we're going to make
a very strong assumption now.
Let's assume that
this human model
doesn't wear any clothes,
and it's full of sweat.
Assume no clothes,
now fully covered by sweat.
This is why our topic
is called
Sweaty Human in a GCM.
Sweaty Human means
this person is full of sweat.
OK.
So this is the first part of the topic.
I have a question.
Yes, please.
I have a question
about the sign
on your test paper.
Today,
we all discussed that
inhabitable
is mainly heat death,
not cold death,
right?
Yes.
If that's the case,
I instinctively feel that
the T-core,
the T,
should be positive.
But if it's positive,
the higher the conduction,
the higher the temperature.
So how do you define
the sign now?
I don't understand.
OK.
Very good.
If the conduction is positive,
that means
the heat is
from the core
to the surface of the skin.
So this arrow
means
the direction of conduction.
If the conduction
is negative,
that means
the heat is
from the skin to the core.
So now,
if I'm not mistaken,
the condition of death
is
T,
Tc,