Recording has started.
In fact, he was originally a law student at NTU Law School.
He had studied in the Department of Law at Hokkaido University in Japan for a year.
Not only did he complete his law degree, he also obtained a lawyer's license.
He also worked at a large law firm in Taiwan and Japan.
To add to that, Ming-Hsi and I have known each other for a long time.
We were classmates in the same year at NTU Law School.
In our hearts, Ming-Hsi has always been a strong character like a god.
We thought it was difficult for him to study law.
We didn't expect him to be able to study history.
Not only that, he is also the president of NTU's Food & Beverage Association.
To us, he has always been a very strong god.
He also won countless books.
I think it's very impressive.
What's cool about Ming-Hsi is that he always follows a two-way path.
He studies both law and history at the same time.
At the moment, he is in the Department of History at NTU Law School.
He also combined his two-way background with his major.
His field of research includes modern international law history,
East Asian legal modernization,
Sino-US relations history,
international economic law and tax law, and so on.
I was thinking about today's topic, foreign law.
For many people, foreign law is a familiar and uncertain concept.
So let's talk about the rules of today's speech.
Today's speech is actually quite simple.
If you have any questions,
you can either turn on your microphone and ask the speaker directly.
Ming-Hsi likes this kind of interactive speech mode.
Or if you are shy or worried about affecting the speaker's flow,
you can also post your questions in the chat area.
I will find the right time to ask.
After Ming-Hsi finishes his speech,
we will also have a Q&A session.
If everyone is okay,
let's welcome Ming-Hsi.
Hello, everyone.
Can you see my PowerPoint?
Okay.
Thank you for your introduction.
As Yi-An said,
we are both university classmates.
But in the legal department of NTU,
I think Yi-An and I are quite different.
Yi-An left the legal department to study psychology
and became a lawyer.
I am honored to have Yi-An as my host.
Today's topic is
controlling US citizens in China.
This is my research plan for the first-year students
in the history department of NTU.
This plan is still in the early stages,
so I would like to share it with you.
I found that in this project,
there are fewer liberal arts students.
So I will spend a little more time
to introduce to you
the current situation of humanities
and legal studies in the US.
So today's speech will be divided into several parts.
One is self-introduction.
But I don't think I need to introduce too much,
because Yi-An has given me a very detailed explanation.
The second part is to share with you
what history is.
This is actually a common question for everyone.
And I am often asked by teachers
in different departments or classmates.
Because history is abstract.
We can say that what happened in the past is history.
There are so many things in history.
As a historian or a doctoral student in history,
how do we choose the topic?
How do we do research?
In other words, what are the doctoral students
in the history department doing?
Why do I want to study legal history?
What is the relationship between law and history?
In particular, why do I want to choose the topic
of international law as my research topic?
After the introduction of these major subjects
and the background,
I will talk about my initial research in the first year.
That is, what is the foreign law in the United States?
In the past, in high school textbooks,
we often heard that foreign law
is a part of an unequal treaty.
In the past, our country or China
suffered a lot of unequal treatment.
Then it was a matter of losing power.
Is it true? Is it true?
Did the United States benefit from this?
Who benefited from this?
The first research in the history department
is to clarify some facts and some institutional backgrounds.
The higher level is to develop theories.
So in the end, I want to talk about my future plan.
How do I develop these facts and their theoretical meanings
and then carry out my future research?
So here, actually,
Yi-An has already introduced it to me.
I'm not drunk.
I want to talk about the last point.
That is, why do I want to study history?
In fact, my initial goal was
to teach in a law school in the United States.
Here, I think there is something very interesting
that I can share with you.
In the United States, professional schools,
such as law schools,
their practice is very different from
what we usually do in history, physics, or math.
As a historian, I will tell you
what the origin and evolution of this system is.
As you know,
in the world of legal education,
North America is very special.
They do not have legal education in the university.
Unlike in Taiwan, Japan, Germany,
the United Kingdom, or France,
we can choose the law department
after graduating from high school.
After graduating from the law department,
you can take a law exam.
Then you can become a lawyer
or continue to study for a master's degree
and return to the law department to teach.
This is not the case in the United States and Canada.
The U.S. Department of State does not have a law department.
You have to graduate from the Department of State
before you can get your first law degree,
which is called JD, or Juris Doctor.
It's the same as MD.
It has the title of a doctor,
but it's not a Ph.D. doctor.
So traditionally,
when there was a law school in the United States,
they thought that
law was a skill,
not a subject.
So in the 19th century,
the teachers of the law school
were some senior lawyers,
judges, or food workers.
And the education of the law school
was to have these food workers
tell you how to become a good lawyer.
So the course of the law school
was very food-oriented.
It taught you how to sign a contract,
how to act or defend in front of the jury,
how to interact and interrogate,
how to get along with the judge,
and so on and so forth.
Later, everyone thought
that if you teach at school,
you still need to have a little bit of academic knowledge.
But there was no such thing as a law Ph.D.
So what should you do?
There is still a method
taught at law schools in the United States
called traditional track,
which allows you to become a teacher of the law school.
What is traditional track?
It's when you graduate from college
and become a JD,
your first law degree.
After that,
you become a lawyer for three years
or a judge assistant for three years
to gain food experience.
After gaining food experience,
you go to the law department of the university
to apply for the position of teacher.
When you're a teacher,
it's usually three years.
You have to teach on the side.
What you teach is to teach some legal writing,
mathematical writing, and so on.
These are related to food.
During the three years you teach,
you have to write a master's thesis.
If this master's thesis is well written,
you can go to various schools
and apply for the position of assistant professor.
Once you become an assistant professor,
you'll be like other departments.
You'll start writing thesis,
升等,教書, and so on.
But later,
in the 1970s or 1980s,
we found that
the failure of being a fellow
and not becoming an assistant professor
is very high.
This can also be seen.
In JD for three years,
you're learning how to write a book,
and then you become a lawyer for three years.
It doesn't make sense.
When you go back to law school,
you suddenly start writing a thesis.
Like everyone here,
we all study Ph.D.
We all know that
writing a thesis requires a lot of practice,
and then you need someone to lead.
You need a lot of research methods, and so on.
So later, the U.S. Law School
came up with a new way
to make you a teacher,
which is the so-called JD Ph.D. double degree.
In other words,
you get a Ph.D. in another field,
such as history, economics,
politics, language,
psychology, and so on.
Then you go to JD,
and then you become a lawyer for two years.
At this point, you don't have to be a fellow,
and you can take your Ph.D. thesis
and apply for a job at the U.S. Law School.
Basically,
all the new professors at the U.S. Law School
are JD Ph.D. double degrees.
This is my original goal.
I want to get a Ph.D. in history first,
and then I want to get a Ph.D. in JD.
Then I can apply for a job at the U.S. Law School.
There are more and more Chinese people
applying for a Ph.D. degree
at the U.S. Law School
through this kind of double degree.
But as far as I know,
no one in Taiwan
has applied for a Ph.D. degree
at the U.S. Law School in this way.
So I want to give it a try.
Next,
in the past,
most of the Ph.D. and JD degrees
were obtained at different schools.
For example,
Professor Ian Ayers,
who is very famous for
doing legal economic analysis
at Yale University.
He was MIT's Econ Ph.D.,
plus Yale's JD,
and then he taught at Yale.
For people in mainland China,
for example,
Professor Li Ji at UC Irvine,
he was a political science Ph.D.
at Northwestern University,
plus Yale's JD,
and then he taught law at UC Irvine.
So this is what I want to challenge.
I want to practice and hone my knowledge
in the history department,
learn the methods of history,
and write papers.
Later on,
in the last stage of my Ph.D. program,
in the 6th, 7th, or 8th year,
I applied for a Ph.D. degree
at another school.
I was a lawyer in the U.S. for two years,
and then I taught at a law school.
This is a brief explanation
of why I want to
apply for a Ph.D. degree in history.
On the one hand,
I always have this idea of cross-field.
I think this kind of training and environment in the U.S.
is the best fit for my research.
The last thing I want to add is that
I just said that
Taiwanese have not yet read Ph.D. and JD,
right?
The next question must be
that in Taiwan's law department,
there are many legal scholars
who claim to have obtained a Ph.D. degree in the U.S.
What kind of degree did they read?
What kind of career path did they embark on?
Since they are different from Americans
who cultivate law schools,
they must have a different set of things, right?
So I wrote LLM and JSD here later.
Here I would like to explain to you
what this is.
LLM is generally translated as
a legal master's degree.
It is a Latin abbreviation.
It means that
if you are not in the U.S. today,
for example, the U.K., France,
Taiwan, or Japan,
you have already studied law in college.
So it is an abbreviation
for a legal master's degree
for foreigners.
This is called LLM.
You only need to study for nine months
without writing a paper.
Then you can be qualified
to be a lawyer in New York.
So in most cases,
in general, in Taiwan or Japan,
if you have been a lawyer for three or five years
and you think you need to retire,
you can go to the U.S.
and study for nine months.
Among these LLM students,
some may be interested in academics.
So you can find a professor
who is willing to teach you
while you are studying LLM.
Then you can enroll
and become a JSD,
which we generally call
a legal master's degree.
This JSD is actually very different
from our general Ph.D.
Because once you enroll,
you are a doctoral candidate.
So you don't need to take classes,
you don't need to be a teacher,
you don't need to be a lecturer.
In principle, if you write a paper,
you can graduate after the exam.
So there are some very famous
LLM teachers in China.
They may only study JSD for a year and a half
or two years
before they graduate.
There are a lot of people like this.
Because JSD is not like
our Ph.D. training,
you have to take classes,
take exams,
be a lecturer,
teach, and so on.
So the problem with a JSD graduate
is that
their quality is not very certain.
Some people are JSD,
their boss has very high requirements for them,
asking them to continue to take classes,
continue to study methods,
or take the qualification exam with them.
Or some students are very smart.
I have a lot of JSD teachers
in the Department of Law in Canada.
They are very smart.
They watch the lecturers
have a seminar in the law school every day,
and they will kill each other.
They watch Huashan's paper every day
and become a big family.
After they return to China,
they can be a Ph.D.
and teach law in Taiwan.
But in the US Department of Law,
you can hardly see any teachers
who are JSD.
Because they are
Ph.D. for foreigners.
This is a brief introduction.
I used to think that
if I went to the US to study law,
I could just study LLM and JSD.
But I thought,
no,
I want to try to
receive the same training as Americans.
If Americans want to become a professor of law,
I will become a professor of law.
So I started with Ph.D.
Later,
in my senior year,
I will see if I can get a J.D.
and try to find a job
in the US Department of Law.
Next, I will answer a question.
What is history?
I am often asked this question.
But I think this is a disaster question.
It's like I want to ask,
what is physics?
What is math?
It is difficult to define a subject.
But I think I can try
to look at this subject
from a more specific perspective.
What is it?
I think from the perspective of abstract theory,
in the Western context,
history is also a method of philosophy.
In other words,
the research we do in history
is the same as asking a question,
giving it a false hypothesis,
and then verifying it, right?
It is the same as philosophy, physics, and chemistry.
We need to ask a question,
and then use some methods to answer it,
to verify if your hypothesis is correct.
Of course, this is a bit of nonsense.
Because anyone who studies Ph.D.
has to do this kind of study.
So I think we can look at history
from a different perspective.
Whether it is Greece or China,
people in ancient times
have a cycle of history.
By cycle of history,
I mean that
for them,
history is something that
happens over and over again.
For example,
in the Tang Dynasty,
Emperor Taizong said that
history is the key to understanding the mind.
In other words,
as long as you study the past,
you will learn some lessons.
By cycle of history,
I mean that
there is nothing new under the sun.
So I understand the past,
and I understand the future.
Because what happened in the past
will keep happening over and over again.
So as long as I know the past,
I will know how to face the same thing in the future.
What should I do when it happens again?
But as we all know,
this is a kind of fantasy.
How is it possible that
people 200 years ago
would face the same problems
as we do now?
Of course, it is different.
In the 18th and 19th centuries,
history was taken over by the state.
There was a very
purposeful approach
to help
build a democratic country.
For example,
when Germany was about to be unified,
a group of historians came out
and wrote history of Germany.
They told us that we were different
from the Italians.
We have a glorious history.
Who is German?
We have a common memory.
This also happened
in the end of the Qing Dynasty
and the beginning of the Republic of China.
Chinese historians told you
that we are all descendants of the Yan Emperor.
So we have a common ancestor.
We must agree that we are all Chinese.
So for a while,
history was used by the state
to build the common memory of the nation.
In the 19th century,
there was another trend.
Social science,
political science,
and other social sciences
wanted to become
like natural science
and discover the common principles
of human society.
They wanted to analyze
why the French Revolution happened,
what its causal relationship was,
and what its social background conditions were.
If we can build
a abstract theory
that the French Revolution
will happen
when the four conditions
are met,
we can predict
when the next revolution will happen
or prevent it from happening.
Another famous example
is Marx.
He said that human history
has a process.
We will go from feudalism
to a small class revolution
to a large class revolution.
Many historians' work
is to prove
the theory of social science
and the process
of social science principles.
Until now,
many historians in mainland China
are still trying to prove
the process of Marxism
in China.
This is the purpose
of the third kind of history.
The fourth kind of history
is similar to the second kind of history,
but it starts to ask smaller questions.
Historians want to
understand the history of the past
and develop quantitative studies
of economics or politics.
The most famous example
is Professor Daniel Clerman
at the University of South Carolina.
He taught at the University of Chicago
because his wife was a lawyer
who was afraid of the cold.
His family moved to South Carolina.
He is a history doctor
and a law professor
at the University of Chicago.
His research is very interesting.
He uses the documents
and information
he discovered
in history training
and his strong
statistical and quantitative background
to do some
theoretical practical research.
Some questions
are difficult to answer.
Does judicial independence
help economic development?
We are not like natural science,
which can control all variables
in the laboratory.
When we want to study this topic,
we have to do some social experiment
to do the cause-and-effect theory,
and we need to find
a lot of agent variables.
Every time a country
does judicial independence reform,
it often follows
many other reforms at the same time.
This is the best way
to understand the relationship
between judicial independence
and economic development in the UK.
Professor Dan Clearman
has some very good information.
For example,
he found that
in the 18th and 19th centuries,
the UK was doing judicial independence reform.
At the same time,
East India Company
was listed
in London Stock Exchange
because
there was no
good information transmission system.
Therefore, news from London
had to wait three or five days
before it could be sent to Amsterdam.
He thought
that the agent variables
of economic development
were the high and low prices
of East India Company's shares.
Whenever a judicial independence
law or reform
occurred in the UK,
East India Company's shares
would rise or fall
when the news
was sent to Amsterdam.
He used statistics
to infer the situation in the UK.
In the end,
he concluded that
every judicial independence reform
in the UK
had something to do
with the rise of
East India Company's shares.
Without historical training,
East India Company's shares
would not have risen.
This is another theory.
In the early years,
there was a theory
that asked
why there was
no China in the West.
In the early years,
historians liked to ask
why there was no capitalism in China,
why there was no scientific revolution in China,
and why there was no
revolution in China.
The next theory is
very popular recently,
but it is a bit similar
to the idea of a national state.
Historians believe that
the people's historical memory
should not serve the country.
Therefore,
historians began to write
some important historical memories.
For example,
transitional justice should tell you
that the Nazi massacre
against the Jews
was really horrible.
We should remember this
forever.
Because it happened once,
it may happen again.
The main consciousness of Taiwan
must be awakened,
because the people of Taiwan
have been oppressed for the past 400 years.
These popular historical writings
are actually shaping historical memory.
Another group of people
believe that
history should not serve the country,
so there are a lot of historical studies
to deconstruct the national state.
For example,
tradition is invented,
and tradition does not have
a long history of 5,000 years.
The so-called descendants of the King of Japan
only appeared for 100 years.
The so-called Japanese cuisine
was invented after the Ming Dynasty.
In the Middle Ages,
the Emperor of Japan believed in Buddhism,
so he told everyone not to eat meat.
In ancient East Asia,
there were four categories of animals
in the world,
such as grass fish and birds.
At that time,
the Emperor of Japan said
that everyone was not allowed to eat meat,
grass fish and birds.
In fact,
before the Ming Dynasty,
the Japanese did not eat beef or pork,
so the so-called barbecue and fried pork chops
were far-fetched Japanese cuisine.
They appeared in the late 19th century
and even in the early 20th century.
Finally, I think history
is different from everyone else.
In politics and sociology,
they ask more objective questions,
but in history,
they also ask subjective questions.
Traditional sociology
may ask a question,
such as
whether the exam system
has promoted social movement.
So some historical sociologists
will look for a lot of past history
to see if there are some
poor and hard-working people
who became good officials
because of the imperial examination,
and then flew to Tengda
and became famous
from the Han dynasty.
But historical sociology
will ask a question.
Objectively,
even if the imperial examination
really promoted social movement,
did the people at that time
really realize that
the imperial examination
promoted social movement?
In the Han dynasty,
there were some economic works.
We can find out from economics
what is the meaning of
Chou Chou's The Theory of Economics?
What does it mean in economics?
But historians may ask
a person who has not studied
modern economics,
has not studied Adam Smith,
or has not studied economics
in NTU,
how can he write The Theory of Economics?
I think this is the difference
between historical sociology
and other subjects.
The next question is
what is legal history?
Why is legal history
a field worth studying
for me?
The first argument is,
of course,
all the legal experts in the court
are historians,
because the court can only
judge what has happened.
I am going to discuss
whether Su Jianhe killed someone
in the past or not.
Is he guilty or not?
We can only discuss
whether he killed someone in the past.
The court cannot decide
whether he will kill someone in the future.
This is a matter of fact.
The court can only deal with
what has happened.
From the legal point of view,
when we make a judgment,
the court will always
make a judgment.
In the tradition of British and American law,
there are many cases
that are not in the text,
so you have to tell everyone
whether the case in front of you
is the same as the case in the past.
If it is the same,
you should apply the same law.
If it is different,
you should make another explanation.
There are some famous cases
where, for example,
a court said that
A car must pay
$10,000.
Later,
a new case came out
where
A was hit by B car.
Then
A told the court
that the driver of B car
should pay me $10,000.
But the lawyer of B car said
no, no, no,
our case is different from A car.
Because A car is black
and B car is red.
Because humans are more alert
when they see a red car.
So
when they are hit,
they have to take more responsibility
because they see a red car.
British and American law
has been debating this kind of thing,
so you have to keep looking at
the past cases
as they are now.
Then you need a lot of
historical training
The second thing is that
there is a saying in English
that the past is like a foreign country.
So when we study
the history of law,
it's like we are studying
another country.
So it's like we are now in Taiwan,
we are going to legislate.
We will refer to what the Japanese do,
what the Germans do,
what the Americans do.
Because these comparisons
can give you some ideas.
But if you refer to other countries,
you will be surprised.
Because from a psychological point of view,
people all have this
in-domain effect.
It's not good to play big
in front of the case.
But you will think
what you have is the best.
But sometimes when you look at
foreign things,
you will know that
there are many different ways
in this world.
For example, if I want to control
cigarettes,
can I refer to
how people controlled
opium in the past?
Of course, opium and cigarettes
are different things.
But you can think about
some new ideas.
The second thing is that
we all know that
humans have a path to rely on.
There is one thing that people
have been doing for a long time,
and the legal history
can help you understand
the background of this system
and its reasons.
What did people think at that time?
After understanding the reason for
the path to rely on,
we should now verify that
this condition no longer exists
or the condition has changed,
which means that
we should do something different.
For example,
in the debate on same-sex marriage,
it is said that two people
of the same sex can get married.
If not, why?
If there is, why?
Has it really changed now?
Another common legal history
is the debate on
the structure of mainstream.
For example, we used to think
that Hitler's Nazi was terrible
because he killed Jews.
He set up a prison court
and let the judge judge
that homosexuals and Jews
are inferior species
and are not suitable for having children.
On the other hand,
the United States
is a free and democratic defender.
Through World War II,
the United States
liberated
these oppressed people.
James Whitman,
a professor at Yale University,
is also a doctor of history.
He wrote a book
called Hitler's American Model.
He said that
Hitler's
racial discrimination law
was widely referred to
in the United States
as the law of racial discrimination
that oppresses black people.
In fact, Hitler once said
that Americans were too fierce to black people.
We can't be so fierce.
So, how did Hitler
know how to use the law
to oppress minorities?
It came from the United States.
This is what I am doing now.
I am using the third world approach
to look at the international law.
In the past,
we thought that the international law
was a principle of equal interaction
between sovereign states.
But in fact, it was not.
We know that the international law
was once used to oppress
and to colonize.
The Third World Approach
to International Law
has a group of scholars.
Their goal is to tell you
how the international law
from the European international law
to the international law of the world
has contributed a lot to China,
Japan, Latin America, etc.
They want to tell you
that the international law
is a tool of oppression.
We should not allow the international law
to become a tool of oppression again.
We must preserve these historical memories.
This is what I think
the legal history is doing.
Before I share my research,
I would like to know
if you have any questions.
I can answer first.
I would like to know
what is the general history
and what is the legal history.
I think I have learned a lot.
Even if I am a lawyer,
Should I continue?
It seems that
everyone is still digesting.
The information is a bit large.
I will try to speak in plain language.
I don't know if
everyone can understand.
I think I have made it clear.
I have heard a lot of concepts
for the first time.
I am not sure
but you have made it clear today.
The language is very good.
I think it has helped me
to digest so much information.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
I have a question.
I am curious
about the background
you set up
in the beginning.
What is history?
The front part
and the back part
are there any differences in views?
If so,
what do you think?
Today's speech
is mainly to
deconstruct nationalism.
In the past, foreign law
was described as
a symbol of
a third world people,
Chinese, Japanese,
or non-Western people
being oppressed.
But I will tell you
that the actual operation
of this theory
is based on two things.
The first is that
I want to improve
the meaning of the theory.
In the future,
I may want to
use other methods
of political,
economic,
and socialization
to make it more abstract
and more applicable.
I also hope you can
give me some advice.
Many people
are not familiar with
law and history,
so I hope I can
give you a brief introduction
of what I am doing in this field.
I also want to
take this opportunity
to let you know
what is the purpose
of the American Academy of Law
and what is the purpose
of the American Academy of Law.
Did I answer your question?
Yes, you did.
Thank you.
If not,
please continue.
Thank you.
I think the training
from Northwestern University
is very interesting.
Foreign students
have to take a class
in English.
The teacher will teach us
some tips.
When you don't know what to say,
just take a sip of water.
No one will ask you
why you are drinking water.
Sometimes,
you can relax
and think about
what you want to say.
Let's move on
to the topic of
extracurricular law.
Extracurricular law,
at least for me,
is a term
but we don't know
what actually happens
to it.
To put it simply,
extracurricular law
is the privilege that
foreigners are not
under the jurisdiction
of the local courts.
In other words,
in 1900,
if an American
stole or committed a crime
in China
or any other country
wanted to sue him,
the Chinese government
and the Chinese courts
couldn't do anything
because he was under the jurisdiction
of the local courts.
Only the U.S. courts
or the U.S. courts
can deal with such cases.
This is extracurricular law.
Extracurricular law still exists
in some countries.
For example,
if an American
raped a woman
or a child
in a local court,
the Japanese courts
couldn't bring him to trial
because he was under the jurisdiction
of the U.S. courts.
It's not that the U.S. courts
couldn't bring him to trial,
but the U.S. courts.
It sounds unreasonable.
Let's move on.
The first time that
the U.S. signed a treaty
was in 1842,
the Treaty of Nanjing,
China signed a treaty
after the Opium War.
In this treaty,
the U.K. required
China to provide
extracurricular law to the U.K.
The U.S. signed the treaty
in 1844,
the Treaty of Wangxia,
China.
In Chinese textbooks,
extracurricular law
is a symbol of
imperialism.
Today, our country's citizens
are being bullied.
Why doesn't our country
promote justice?
Why does the U.S. court
have to bring him to trial?
The U.S. court
must be very biased.
must tolerate
the U.S. people
because the U.S. people
betrayed the sovereignty
of China.
The U.S. court must
revolutionize the U.S.
The U.S. court
must abolish extracurricular law
so that the Chinese people
will no longer be bullied.
Is it really like this?
Let's move on.
For example,
when the U.S. came to China
to negotiate the Treaty of Wangxia,
the U.S. diplomat,
William Cushing,
gave a speech
in the U.S. Congress.
He said,
his proudest moment
was when the U.S. wrote
the extracurricular law
in the Treaty of Wangxia.
Because China
is an uncivilized place.
The judges in their countries
do not have three powers.
The county magistrates
How can the county magistrates
be the judges?
In Taiwan,
can He Wen-je be a judge?
No.
Administrative and judicial
should be separated.
China is an uncivilized country.
If you commit a serious crime,
you will be imprisoned,
you will be tortured,
you will be beaten.
If our people
are the most advanced species,
how can we obey the laws of the barbarians?
Therefore,
obtaining the extracurricular law
is a civilized victory.
It sounds like a good idea.
However,
historians have found
that before 1868,
we could not find
any Chinese history
against the extracurricular law.
This is actually
a very strange thing.
If China is so powerful,
why does China never object
to all the negotiations?
China thinks it is good.
Why?
If you want to extracurricular law,
we will give it to you.
This question
is related to a very popular research topic
in recent history,
which is the multidimensionalism
of the empire and the law.
In fact,
the majority of human history
is dominated by the British
and the Germans.
In fact,
the majority of human history
is dominated by the Empire.
What is the Empire?
The simplest definition
is that
under a regime,
there are many different
ethnic groups
and activists.
For example,
the Qing Dynasty
was an empire
with Han people,
Tibetans,
Mongols,
ethnic minorities
and Xinjiang people.
The next question is
that we all know that
there is a law called the Qing Dynasty Law.
But did the Qing Dynasty Law
apply in Tibet?
Did the Qing Dynasty Law
apply in Xinjiang?
In fact, it did not.
Although the Qing Dynasty Law
applied to most empires,
the Roman Empire
also applied the law to the Jews.
In the Qing Dynasty,
the Mongols still applied
the traditional Mongolian law,
while the Tibetans still applied the Tibetan law.
Only the Han people
applied the Qing Dynasty Law.
This is understandable.
When a country is very large
and is an empire,
how could it be possible
to force a Mongolian
to marry in a Confucian way?
This is also a question of
the cost of rule.
In order to maintain the operation of an empire
and the coordination of the ethnic groups,
you must use different laws
to treat different people.
This is now called
the law pluralism.
Does Taiwan want to do the same thing?
Should the indigenous people
apply the indigenous law
or not?
From the perspective of China,
in 1842,
the British said
that they wanted to
apply the British law in China.
Think about it.
What's wrong with
the Mongolians
applying the Mongolian law
and the British applying the British law?
At that time,
foreigners could only
move around
when they came to China.
Basically,
it did not affect the original life of the Han people.
Therefore,
there is nothing wrong with
giving you a piece of land
and having your own law.
In 1842,
foreigners were limited to Guangzhou.
We call it the Guangzhou system.
Originally in Guangzhou,
in 1842,
China had already admitted
that the Americans could apply the British law
in Guangzhou.
Therefore, in 1842 and 1844,
foreigners came to China
and told the negotiators
that they wanted to apply the foreign law.
The Chinese thought it was good,
so they gave it to them.
However, in 1868,
people found that something was wrong.
At first,
there were many cases
in which
foreigners committed crimes
in China
and could not be punished.
In these cases,
too many countries had foreign law,
so the legal vacuum was created.
Finally,
in 1910,
there were 23 countries with foreign law in China.
We often see in the files
that an American
committed a crime
and was arrested in the U.S. Court.
The first defense he made was
that he was not an American,
but an Englishman.
Because he had a lot of passports,
he kept hiding.
Later, he made Shanghai the most
famous criminal heaven in the world,
because everyone would not be arrested.
This problem became more and more serious,
affecting China's security,
China's economic development,
and so on.
Later,
he began to think that
it was a matter of right to enter the country,
and we had to oppose it.
To this day,
there is a modern meaning.
For example,
every year on January 11th,
there is a Judiciary Day,
and the Judiciary Council
holds a seminar and a celebration.
Why is there a Judiciary Day
on January 11th?
Because January 11th, 1943
was the day
when China and the U.S.
signed an equal treaty
and abolished foreign law.
They thought that from that day on,
the judicial system of the Republic of China
would no longer be dominated by the West.
Since then,
the Nationalist government
moved to Taiwan in 1949,
so the Judiciary Day
is still on January 11th.
Do you still remember
the Lincoln case?
It was about a British man
who died in Taiwan.
Later, he fled the country
and returned to the U.K.
At that time,
the U.K. House of Representatives
decided that Lincoln
should be transferred back to Taiwan.
The representative of the U.K.
was Ambassador St. Luke.
I attended his class with Ian.
Ambassador St. Luke was
the Minister of Foreign Affairs
when he was the Minister of Foreign Affairs
at the University of Taitung.
He said in a newspaper
that Lincoln should have
a symbolic meaning,
because the law in the U.K.
cannot be transferred
to a country that is not civilized by the law.
At that time,
Ambassador St. Luke wrote an article
that the Lincoln case proved
that the U.K. had become
a country that was civilized by the law,
so the U.K. would be willing
to transfer people back to Taiwan.
However, when the second trial was overturned,
the U.K. was defeated.
However, in the hearts of many
lawyers and diplomats,
the rule of law
in the U.K.
must be carried on
by a civilized country.
My question is very simple.
Is foreign law really better?
We can see that
the U.S.
must maintain a court
in China,
and it must invest a lot of money.
In fact, we can also
intuitively find that
if a U.S. court
in China
favors U.S. citizens,
Chinese people
should not do business
with U.S. citizens.
Chinese people do not want to
get along with U.S. citizens,
which will worsen Sino-U.S. relations
and damage U.S. business interests in China.
My question is
if foreign law is really better,
how does it actually work?
Let's go to the U.S.
Can I ask a question?
Sure, go ahead.
I'd like to ask...
You can go back to your seat.
Okay.
I'd like to ask...
Can you tell us
who sent the question?
Can you introduce yourself
so that we can understand
the situation better?
Thank you.
Okay, I'm
Hong Shaoming.
I'm also a postdoc at Caltech.
I graduated from NTU Psychology.
I'd like to ask...
When you talk about
foreign law,
do you mean
foreign law and
multilateralism?
Are they the same?
At least on the surface,
when you talk about
multilateralism,
you're talking about
the international community.
But foreign law is about
the relationship between
countries.
This can also be applied to...
For example, you just mentioned
that before 1868,
China did not oppose
foreign law.
It is possible that
they have always felt that
foreign law is one form
of multilateralism.
After 25 years,
do you think
foreign law and
multilateralism are related?
Thank you.
I think
everyone can accept
multilateralism
under the previous rule.
Because it is a low-cost
way to maintain national governance.
So most of the current research
believes that
before 1868,
Chinese central government officials
did not oppose
multilateralism.
Because it is not necessarily
within a country.
For example,
when Western missionaries
came to China,
China also respected
the use of its own laws
to deal with its own problems.
After 1868,
I think it is because
China wants to modernize.
So in the process of modernization,
we can achieve the ability
of central power and mobilization
that modern countries want.
We can also see that
after the establishment of the Republic of China,
China hopes that
Tibet, Mongolia and Xinjiang
all use the laws of the Republic of China.
China no longer respects
China's autonomy.
China's autonomy has become very limited.
The current People's Republic of China
also hopes that
Mongolia, Tibet and Xinjiang
all use the laws of the Republic of China.
I think the same is true for Hong Kong.
At the beginning,
China thought that
Hong Kongers could continue
to use the law of the Republic of China.
However, when China wants to
modernize Hong Kong,
it wants to adopt
a new law of monolateralism.
After all, we are one nation,
one country.
Why can't we all
use different laws?
If you are a Mongolian,
a Tibetan, a Xinjiang or a Hong Konger,
you should adopt the same law.
You are not different.
If you are different,
you are admitting that
China is not a monolateral country.
I think the real difference
between legal pluralism and
legal monolateralism is that
in the process of
transferring from the empire
to a democratic country,
China wants to strengthen
Hong Kong.
In your opinion,
in a democratic country,
legal pluralism is
different from
legal monolateralism,
isn't it?
Not necessarily.
It should be said that
legal pluralism is
different from
legal monolateralism.
It should be said that
in a democratic country,
you should adopt the same law.
Foreigners adopt the same law
because they want to
show their national sovereignty.
Yes.
Your defense of
legal pluralism is that
it may show
the spirit of
legal pluralism.
But in some countries,
legal pluralism and
legal monolateralism are
fundamentally different.
First of all,
legal pluralism can,
but legal monolateralism can't.
Second, it can explain
why China did not oppose
at the beginning.
Because they thought
it was different.
At first, they thought
it was the same thing.
Their opposition was
when they found
that it was actually
different and
they could not support
whether it was good or
bad.
But when I first
talked about it,
historians would ask
why they could not
find opposition in 1868.
We would say that
we thought that the subjective
will of the activists
at that time
mixed it with
legal pluralism.
In other words,
the reason why historians
did not oppose
is that they thought
it was a mix of two things.
It is a bit like
what I just said.
At first, they thought
it was the same thing,
so they did not oppose.
But later they found
that it was different.
Anyway,
we have spent too much time
I would like to add
a cold knowledge.
My ex-boss is an expert
on the LinkedIn case.
Oh, really?
Did he prove that Taiwan
is a civilized country?
The main reason
why he was invited
was to ask
whether there was a significant difference
between the British and the Taiwanese
in terms of quantity.
I see.
That's all.
Please go on.
OK.
Sorry,
I am running out of time.
So,
in 1906,
the U.S. carried out
a judicial reform in Shanghai.
From 1844 to 1905,
the U.S. did not
establish a formal court
in China.
We often hear the term
that the U.S. sent
a diplomat to be a judge.
In other words,
if an American committed a crime in China,
he would be sent to the local consulate
to be tried.
Who is the judge?
It is a diplomat.
Sometimes, the diplomat
also has some legislative powers.
It is a tricky situation.
When the U.S. criticized China
for not having a separation of powers
and not being civilized,
because the diplomat is an administrator
and has the right to be tried,
the U.S. is a system
of three powers.
The U.S. is not civilized at all.
The U.S. is more like
the governor-general
or the county magistrate of China,
like Bao Qingtian.
He is a mayor
and a judge at the same time.
Next,
the U.S. was not a rich country
at that time.
The U.S. did not invest
a lot of people,
finance and legal experts
in China.
For example,
the U.S. did not have a prison
at the beginning.
The U.S. even rented a prison
to the British and French,
because the U.S. built
the British and French prisons
in Shanghai earlier.
Why did the U.S. have a legal reform
in 1906?
I will explain in the next video.
The U.S. began
the expansion of the empire
at the end of the 19th century.
In this video,
we can see two data.
The first is the date
when the U.S. acquired the colony.
Hawaii,
Wake Island,
Samoa, the Philippines,
and Panama were all
acquired at the end of the 19th century
and the beginning of the 20th century.
In other words,
between 1844 and 1900,
the U.S. did not trade much.
In the second table,
we can see that
between 1900 and 1912,
the average trade volume
of China and the U.S.
increased significantly,
and even doubled.
The expansion of the U.S.
brought a lot of trade between
China and the U.S.
At that time,
the U.S. federal government
responded that
the Judiciary
was not enough
to solve the trade dispute
between China and the U.S.
because these judges
were not legal people.
They were just diplomats.
As we all know,
diplomats abroad
were also responsible
for business affairs,
and they did not have
much influence on the U.S.
economy.
In addition,
as the U.S. expansion
spread,
a lot of smugglers
came to China,
including sex workers,
gamblers, and vagabonds.
At that time,
the U.S. missionaries
in China believed
that these illegal immigrants
had a serious impact
on the sex workers
in the U.S.
So in 1900,
all the white prostitutes
in Shanghai
said they were American.
At that time,
the word American Girl
meant prostitutes,
because every prostitute
said she was American
when she was arrested.
If you were sent to the U.K.
court,
you would be a prostitute.
At that time,
there was a lot of discussion
in the U.S.
As we can see in this picture,
foreign law was not
an important concept
for both China and the U.S.
It was not until 1900
that the word
extraterritoriality
and consular jurisdiction
began to appear
in foreign law.
On the other hand,
China also began to reform
the modern country.
In 1900,
the Eight-Nation Alliance
was established in Beijing.
After the establishment of the Eight-Nation Alliance,
Beijing signed the New Deal,
and the Qing Dynasty began
to reform the modern country.
At that time,
the modern country reform
was to transform Chinese law
into Western modern law.
The origins of the Eight-Nation Alliance
can be traced back to the
Ming and Qing dynasties
published in 1906.
If you ask a student
of the Taiwan University Law Department
who is majoring in
Law,
he will use a classic textbook
written by Wang Zhejian.
Many of the citations in that textbook
are back to the Ming and Qing dynasties.
The Ming and Qing dynasties
were published in 1906.
At that time,
China had signed
an agreement with the United Kingdom
and the United States.
The agreement said
that China was about to
start legal and judicial reform,
and Western states
had to help it.
If you helped,
and later I succeeded in reforming,
you would be expelled from foreign law.
At that time,
the United States was faced
with a new legal system
that needed to be improved
in order to improve
Sino-US trade relations.
On the other hand,
China was about to start
legal and judicial reform.
What if China really became
a modern civilized,
three-powered court,
using the same laws
as the U.S. or Taiwan?
If the U.S. still uses
a three-powered,
one-of-a-kind system,
the U.S. established
the United States Court for China
in Shanghai in 1906.
The U.S. sent
a graduate of Yale University
who was once the director
of the Philippine Procuratorate
to serve as a judge
and establish a modern court.
The judge
did three things.
The first thing he did
was to declare that
the U.S. did not do anything
related to civil and commercial affairs.
This was strange,
because the U.S. business community
wanted him to deal with
some business cases and disputes.
Instead, he had to deal
with brothels and casinos.
He felt that
many U.S. lawyers
had a bad image of the Chinese.
So he called all the U.S. lawyers
in Shanghai
for a legal exam.
80% of the U.S. lawyers
failed the exam,
which caused a great uproar.
The U.S. lawyers
were not allowed to come
to the U.S. court.
The next thing he did
was to sue the boss
of eight brothels
and four casinos.
In the past,
the U.S. lawyers used
the original defense technique
to say that they were not U.S. citizens
and that they were U.S. citizens.
For example, he called
U.S. Consulates in Shanghai
and asked them
if they had ever used
U.S. Consulates.
He even asked
U.S. Consulates
to show their diplomatic documents
and ask them
if they had ever
filed a passport in the U.S. Consulate.
Some of them
even said
that the U.S. Consulate
was a legal vacuum
caused by U.S. law.
This caused
a fierce uproar
among the U.S. community
in Shanghai.
The U.S. lawyer
was impeached
and resigned a year later.
The next U.S. lawyer
was not in charge anymore.
In the future,
I think there are several
different types of
jurisdiction.
This is common in the modern world.
For example,
if a Japanese
and a Singaporean
sign a business contract,
the law can be the law of New York.
When there is a dispute,
the law can be used in Paris
to solve the dispute.
I think the situation in the world
is similar to the past.
There are many different types
of jurisdiction.
I think China in the 19th century
is a good place to develop theory.
China has pushed the situation
to the extreme.
For example,
there are nine states in Tianjin.
In Tianjin,
there are ten laws
in the same city.
There must be some
place to develop
theory and research.
Next,
I will talk about competition.
We know that
in the age of globalization,
manufacturers will look for
the place with the lowest cost
of the system.
For example,
the labor law is relatively loose,
the salary is relatively low,
or the environmental law is relatively loose.
At that time,
in China,
there were more than 20 countries
with foreign jurisdiction.
For example,
there are nine states in Tianjin.
Is there any more theory
that can be developed?
Next,
there are some foreign law in the modern world.
For example,
there is foreign law in Chongqing.
Is there any way
to push or deny
the existence
of foreign law
from the implementation
of the actual system
The last point is
who benefits from foreign law?
At that time,
the United States had a very
intense backlash,
which made it believe that
the United States should not
throw taxpayers' money
overseas for foreign law.
In fact, the Americans have been
faced with the fact that
they can not manage
the situation of their citizens
in other countries.
So they were impeached
and resigned.
Later, the judges also
continued to ignore these things.
Is there really benefit?
For example, if the image of the United States
is so bad,
if the court is not fair,
the Chinese will resist your goods.
So it seems that foreign law
is not something that can be
implemented indefinitely.
In addition to the law itself,
there are many other factors to consider.
In the first part,
the teacher will ask you
to understand the content of the system
and then think about
more theoretical and abstract
things with your eyes.
So today I will briefly
report to you.
Please give me your advice.
Thank you.
I think today's lecture is really wonderful.
I really learned a lot.
It's like a book.
I think it's pretty exciting.
Do you have any questions?
Please feel free to ask.
If you can,
please briefly introduce yourself
before asking questions.
Can I ask another question?
Welcome.
Sorry, the question just ended.
I'm afraid it will delay your time.
If I ask you now,
if we want
contemporary foreign law
to continue to exist,
what do you think
is the best way
to defend it?
What is the direction?
Why does contemporary foreign law
still need to exist?
If I ask you to make
the strongest defense,
what should it be?
Thank you.
I think it depends on
who you are talking to.
For example,
there are a lot of things
that are close to foreign law.
For example,
investment in heavy industry.
What is investment in heavy industry?
For example,
a Singaporean came to Taiwan
to invest.
He bought a piece of land.
As a result,
today our government
does not support
the acquisition of land.
At this time,
according to our domestic law,
if he does not support
the acquisition,
he thinks it is illegal.
Then he should be sued
by our administrative court.
However,
because we have an investment
guarantee agreement with Singapore,
at this time,
this Singaporean
did not support
Taiwan's domestic law.
Instead, he sued
the World Bank's
Investment Heavy Industry Center.
This is a bit like
not being governed by the domestic court.
We entrust him to a third party.
In fact, foreign law
is entrusted to his motherland.
Of course,
in Africa or some countries
where the law is not so stable,
or you do not trust
the law or the court,
you have to entrust
the solution of this dispute
to a fair institution
that you believe in.
Then this foreign law
will be meaningful.
So some people ask,
because there used to be a theory
called the law and development theory.
He believes that in the process
of capitalist development,
good courts must be coordinated
to help each other.
Otherwise, there will be a lot of
commercial disputes in capitalism,
and you need a good court to solve them.
Some people ask,
why is the Chinese court
so biased?
Xi Jinping said that the court
should trust the party.
Everyone knows that
Google sued Baidu,
and Baidu won.
Why is the development of
Chinese capitalism so good?
Many people think that
the problem of foreign law
is not solved by the people's court,
but you can entrust it to another
third party institution
that you believe in.
So I think that foreign law
can replace certain legal developments
at least in the commercial part,
or the court is not so
healthy and credible.
It can help attract investment
and people outside
can go to the court
with confidence.
It can help attract investment
and people outside
can go to the court
with confidence.
In terms of the form,
I don't think that
some countries
still have meat
or planets.
In order to protect foreigners,
in order to make foreigners
willing to invest in your country,
willing to travel to your country,
in order to make foreigners
you have to give them
some kind of protection of foreign law.
You can understand that.
In fact, the most common foreign law
is applied to diplomats.
If a diplomat breaks the law locally,
he is not subject to the local laws
and courts.
This is part of the diplomatic privilege.
Of course, we believe that
there is still some foreign law
in respect of foreign history.
But to me,
it sounds like the reason
why foreign law should disappear.
If in the ideal reality,
we have a very fair third party,
let's say it's a certain court
made up of 200 countries.
If you want to deal with criminal matters,
you can throw it to the criminal court.
If you want to deal with civil matters,
you can throw it to the civil court.
This court can judge a person
fairly.
For example,
if a Singaporean comes to Taiwan
and does something similar,
we don't need
Singapore's foreign law
or Taiwan's foreign law in Taiwan,
right?
I understand
why
the two questions are not interrelated.
Let's go back to
the definition of foreign law.
In fact,
when we talk about
foreign law,
it means that foreigners are not
privileged by the local
legal courts.
But it is not necessarily
in accordance with
the law of his motherland
or the law of the third party
or the jurisdiction of the third party.
So when I just answered,
I went back to the original definition
of foreign law.
But what you just discussed
should be said
that today a person
is not privileged by the local
legal courts.
But I don't think
all cases
can find
a fair third party.
I understand.
For example,
in the case of criminal law,
I have not received any
legal or historical training.
In my imagination,
for example,
if the British
come to Taiwan to commit a crime,
and then you want to say that
we British should have foreign law,
we want to introduce it back to
the British trial,
it seems to prove
why the British return to
the British trial
is better than
the trial in Taiwan.
One of the cases is
that the legal system
of some African countries
has been changed.
It is not easy to prove
that your national
legal system is worse than mine,
so it should be introduced
back to my own country.
Yes.
There are some standards.
For example,
because European countries
have abolished the death penalty,
it will not be introduced
into a country that will be sentenced
to death in Taiwan.
It is quite obvious
in some extreme examples.
For example,
if Lin Keying is a murderer in Taiwan today,
because murderers in Taiwan
will be sentenced to death,
so when she returns to the UK,
the UK will not introduce her
back to Taiwan.
But this means that
the British have an assumption
that a country with a death penalty
or a death penalty
is a country with a death penalty.
But I think this matter
also requires a process.
If you want to have an extramarital law,
you have to prove that
my legal system is better than yours.
In some cases,
this process may be easier,
but in some cases
it may not be so easy.
Of course,
now it happens
whether it is easy or not.
If I don't want to give you a death penalty,
you have to ask yourself
how strong or how weak
your country is.
You have to ask yourself
whether you are strong
in international negotiations.
I used to think
that I could not prove
that extramarital law
is inefficient
in the way of economics.
This is one of the things
I might want to do in the future.
I think there are several levels of problems.
The first one is whether
extramarital law is inefficient.
Extramarital law will cause
legal vacuum.
Legal vacuum is like
Shanghai in the early 20th century.
No one can do anything.
This is what we don't want to see.
From this perspective,
extramarital law is inefficient.
On the other hand,
many extramarital laws
are competing in good systems.
For example,
Tianjin is divided into
ten land laws.
Is it because everyone
wants to create a better land law,
so Tianjin's land
is better or worse now?
Extramarital law may be efficient,
but it may also
have other social norms
or social norms.
For example,
if you are too good
to your own country,
you will be restricted.
In the future,
I want to build a theory
that extramarital law
is inefficient or
has some advantages
and some disadvantages.
Or it has some
more important social norms
behind it.
I can also
make a point about this.
For example,
a country like the United States
sometimes
doesn't care
how much money
is worth.
For example,
if it happens between
China and the United States,
the Americans think
this person must be extradited
or he may be treated
unfairly in China.
In this case,
the economic calculation
becomes very complicated.
But the Americans think
this $10 million is to
buy our face,
so even if it is $100 million
or $100 million,
I should do it.
Of course,
each case has its own considerations.
However,
I think the extramarital law
in the end of the 19th century
or the beginning of the 20th century
is a more transparent case.
Of course,
Wang Dan was taken to the United States
from Qinchen Prison to Harvard to study PhD.
I believe this must have
his diplomatic image
or American idealistic
diplomatic policy considerations.
However,
I think that
the extramarital law
in the end of the 19th century
is a good example
to respond to the issue
of institutional competition
or institutional competition
in the United States.
For example,
most American companies
are located in Delaware,
which has the best
company law.
However,
is it really efficient
for each state
to adopt different
legal systems?
To me,
this is still
a question
that needs to be answered.
Thank you for your answer.
Thank you.
I have a question.
I'm not sure
if it's too early
or not.
If
the audience
at the scene
can leave
if there is a problem,
the recording will continue
if the audience
can leave
if there is a problem.
If you want to follow
the Q&A,
you can watch the video later.
If you can leave
now,
you can continue
the Q&A.
I have two questions.
The first one
is probably answered.
Let me ask you
one more time.
The second question is
basically
a legal study.
Since it's a legal study,
my understanding is
that it's a principle.
We start from the principle
and discuss it.
However,
from another perspective,
it's a very political
and valuable act.
It's a diplomatic act.
I can give credit to others
to strengthen my control
or dominance over others.
What do you think
about the economic
and diplomatic aspects
of extramarital law?
You've answered a part of the question.
This is my first question.
My second question
is about
extramarital law.
There is a word called
external.
There are internal and external.
How do you define
extramarital law?
Who is my citizen?
Who is not my citizen?
Who is my country?
Who is not my country?
Do you think
extramarital law
is enforced
or dilutes
the definition of a country?
Thank you.
My first question
is
about extramarital law.
You said that
extramarital law
is based on principles.
For me,
this is a more traditional
study of legal ethics.
For example,
I have a theory
about what is justice
and what is fairness.
I have some principles
and I apply them
in a logical way.
This is a more empirical
study.
I hope to draw
some theories
or calculations
from the past
so that we can
have some new directions in the future.
It is a more
social science method.
There is a word
in mainland China
called social science law.
In Taiwan,
I used to be an assistant
of Mr. Zhang Yong-cheng.
He also published a book
called Social Science Law.
I think
from my point of view,
any law
has politics in it.
We cannot say
that the study of law
can be completely
excluded from
the diplomatic context.
For me,
the big question
in my study
is how the international law
can change the domestic politics.
This is what I wrote
in my thesis.
In 1945,
the international law changed
the legal operation
and the domestic politics of the Republic of China.
I think
under the example of an
international law,
we should consider
the level of economics,
politics,
and social science.
Under such conditions,
how will it affect
the reasoning,
logic,
and interpretation of the law?
What should we pay attention to
in the future
when there are
relevant systems
of international law?
I will try to convince him
that these are important backgrounds.
Your second question
is that
I think in the near future,
the international law
will certainly strengthen
the national boundary.
It is like
decoupling.
For example,
when foreigners enter Taiwan,
they need to have
a negative vaccination certificate.
I do not need it
because I have a passport from the Republic of China.
At this time,
there is a difference
between you and me.
If I see someone
who owes money like me
but he is subject to legal jurisdiction
and the law he uses is different,
this kind of
internal and external distinction
will strengthen
our imagination
and views.
I think the international law
plays an important role
in the modernization
of China.
Thank you.
Do you have any questions?
I think
both the speech
and the Q&A are wonderful.
Thank you.
Excuse me,
can I ask a question?
Go ahead.
I am from Indiana.
I am studying information science,
which is the term used in Taiwan.
I have studied history,
so I know a little bit about history.
I am curious about
legal pluralism and
international law.
Although there are
different contexts,
for example,
in the past,
the rule of law
of the colonial motherland
was different but equal.
In fact,
it is not equal.
Is there any possibility
that the same concept
exists in the dispute
of international law?
Is it the same
as the rule of law?
If I remember correctly,
it is the same as the rule of law.
There are many questions.
The first one is
the dispute between the rule of law
and the national security law.
In fact,
not only China implemented
the national security law in Hong Kong,
Taiwan also discussed
whether to implement a national security law.
It may already exist,
but I wonder
if there is a common origin
or a common core
in the dispute.
The last one is
if you know that
you have to study history for seven years,
do you still want to study
a doctor of law?
After you finish studying history,
you can teach me in the history department.
Do you think that
the law history of the U.S.
is a more
inclusive direction
under the system
of the U.S. Law School?
There are many questions.
You can pick the key answer.
Thank you.
The first one is
the issue of multilateralism
and colonization
of the United States.
The term
multilateralism
originated
from the study
of the Great British Empire.
The Great British Empire
was famous
for its
high regard
for local officials
in every colony.
In 1895,
when the Japanese ruled Taiwan,
they did not use the Japanese Civil Code
or the Civil Code.
Taiwanese used old customs.
It was not until 1900
that it became a local colonization.
The recent study of the empire
in the history department
is very popular.
It re-evaluates
the methods of governance
of the previous empires,
such as Rome and China,
to see whether
the British Empire
did the same thing.
The British Empire
was well-known
for its multilateralism.
In Hong Kong,
it used the old customs
as a part of the United States' law.
My main question is
whether there is
such a situation
in the history department.
I think
foreign law
gives people
an impression that
foreign law is biased.
However,
foreign law
seems to cause
people to use
different laws
to achieve
unequal results.
Yes,
this is our impression
of foreign law.
However,
I am not sure
about this.
Last December,
I went to
the Second National Archives
in Maryland.
There were 10 boxes
of documents.
One of the things
I want to do
is to look through
these documents
and do some coding
and quantification analysis
to see whether
foreign law
is biased against Americans.
I don't think
there is such a situation
in Shanghai.
I think
this is a matter
of fact.
We need more evidence.
The second question is
why it was in 1868.
I think
the Tongchi Restoration
was established
by the
Tongchi Center.
After the Fourth War,
it sent more students
to Europe and America.
They began to
learn more about
the concept of
sovereignty and
modern international law.
They realized that
Europeans used
the label
of an uncivilized country
to label China.
The first person
who opposed it was
Guo Songtao.
He went to Europe
and became
a member of the
Tongchi Restoration.
There were many
religious crimes.
One of the crimes
was that Chinese people
destroyed churches
and killed missionaries.
Why did this happen?
In many cases,
it was because
a Chinese person
believed in Christianity.
The missionaries
applied for foreign passports.
For example,
British and French passports.
Later,
many Chinese people
enjoyed foreign law
and committed crimes.
This led to dissatisfaction
among the local people.
The grassroots people
began to think that
there was a lot of
injustice in it.
If you look at the documents
of the Xiamen Consulate,
you can see that
Taiwanese also enjoyed
foreign law in China in 1895.
Many people
from Chaozhou
went to Singapore
and obtained passports
from the British Empire.
When they came back to China
to do business,
they advocated foreign law.
Many defendants
are still being investigated.
What is their intention?
Isn't it normal for a person
to have two passports?
I don't understand
why so many Taiwanese
have two passports.
If everyone in Taiwan
has foreign law,
how can he have foreign law?
Next,
the issue of national security law
and foreign law.
As I mentioned earlier,
I think Hong Kong
is like a
legal multidimensional state
to the People's Republic of China.
However,
it is a problem
whether a modern country
can tolerate
legal multidimensionality.
I think the common cause
is to expand
the judicial sovereignty
at the core of a sovereign state.
Therefore,
there are many exceptions
in the national security law.
For example,
Taiwan's jurisdiction
and so on.
This is an interesting question.
I haven't figured it out yet.
I will share the results
with you later.
I'm looking forward to it.
The last one is
about teaching.
This is an interesting question.
I'm studying
the history of Sino-US relations,
but it doesn't mean
I'm going to teach Sino-US relations
in law school.
For example,
a well-known American
tax law teacher
teaches law school
in Michigan.
He is a Harvard History PhD
and a Harvard JD.
PhDs need to have
academic training,
such as writing papers
and publishing papers,
and have a good background in knowledge.
In the end,
what you teach in law school
actually depends on
the field of representation
when you apply for a job.
Of course, it is difficult
to find a good teacher
in law school.
In fact,
American law schools
are very special.
In history,
I know that
a law school
rents a whole hotel
in Washington DC
every December,
and 200 law schools
in the United States
recruit new teachers.
So every year,
there is a shortage of
law school teachers.
I heard that
there is a teacher
who has never been
fully recruited
in the United States.
I read a lot of
tax law books
because I thought
it would be easier to find a job
in law school.
In fact,
law school teachers
are very realistic.
If you want to be fully recruited,
your CV must be
in a fixed format.
In the Northwest,
a law school teacher
told me that
I should print out
the blank form of my CV
and put it under my desk.
Every year,
I should reflect on
which part of my CV
that I should print out.
So,
after reading for so long,
should I continue to read?
In fact,
most people suggest
that I should finish
my 5-year history course
and finish my PhD
by the fifth year.
I should finish my PhD
by the seventh year
and finish my PhD
by the eighth year
and finish my PhD.
In the U.S.,
if you want to teach
in a law school,
you need two years of experience.
So, I should graduate from J.D.
and become a lawyer in the U.S.
and then apply for a job
in a law school.
Law school teachers
apply for a job
before 40 years old.
So, I should finish my PhD
and become a lawyer
so that I can apply for a job in a law school.
That's all.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
But,
there is an interesting point.
Why are tax lawyers always dissatisfied?
Because
tax lawyers in the U.S. make a lot of money.
After being a tax lawyer for two years,
many people don't want to come back
to apply for a job.
They make a lot of money.
After all,
a tax lawyer needs two years of experience.
So,
the more money you make, the less people want to apply for a job.
That's true.
Just like C.S. is always looking for a teacher.
That's right.
And,
C.S. doesn't force you to have a lot of experience.
In law school,
you need to be a lawyer for two years before applying for a job.
So, some people are very happy
and apply for a job right away.
It's like your love for law school.
Law school is your true love.
That's right.
Because of time constraints,
as a host,
I'd like to ask C.S.
for a final answer.
Because this is a projectile speech,
whether it's
the audience
here today or
in the future,
I guess most of the people watching this video
are Taiwanese.
I'd like to ask C.S.
to tell us
about your research
and how you connect with people
from different backgrounds
and fields.
Okay.
I think
Taiwan is Taiwan,
but it's different
from China.
I think
the legacy of the Republic of China
has a great impact,
especially on the law.
Our Civil Law and Criminal Law
were established during the administration period.
The main purpose of the Civil Law
and Criminal Law in Taiwan
at that time was to complete
the modernization of the law
and abolish foreign law.
So we still have a lot of legacy,
such as the LinkedIn case
or the Judiciary.
I always think
that we need to understand
the law of the Republic of China
in the mainland
in order to better understand
the law we use in Taiwan.
You need to understand
why the Republic of China
has such a law,
and its bigger background
is the contact
between the Qing and the West.
From a legal perspective,
the biggest problem
is that the Qing Empire,
the Beiyang Government,
Sun Yat-sen, Chiang Kai-shek,
and the Communist Party of China
all want to abolish
foreign law.
However,
because of this political context,
we have a lot of misunderstandings
about foreign law
and a lot of democracy.
So I think
this kind of research
can be done
and we can
reflect on
what it means to us,
develop more theories,
take off our democracy glasses,
and re-understand
the background of the law
we use in Taiwan.
I think
this is what I want to do.
I think it's super exciting.
As someone
who used to teach
at a law school,
now I'm a PhD student
in different fields
of law.
I'm looking forward
to your future
in history,
and your
PhD career.
I also hope that
you can overcome
your eight-year PhD life
and get two J.D. and Ph.D.
and become
the first person
at a law school.
Thank you for your time today.
I'm going to end
the meeting now.
After the recording,
you can share your thoughts
with your friends and family.
Welcome, Mingxi.
We look forward to your research.
Thank you, Yiyan.
Thank you.
Bye-bye.
I'm going to end the meeting now.
After the recording,
you can share your thoughts
with your friends and family.
Thank you, Yiyan.
Bye-bye.
Thank you for watching!
If you like my video,
please subscribe to my channel.
See you next time!
Thank you for watching!
If you like my video,
please subscribe to my channel.
See you next time!
If you like my video,
please subscribe to my channel.
See you next time!
If you like my video,
please subscribe to my channel.
See you next time!
If you like my video,
please subscribe to my channel.
See you next time!
If you like my video,
please subscribe to my channel.
See you next time!
If you like my video,
please subscribe to my channel.
See you next time!
If you like my video,
please subscribe to my channel.
See you next time!