Hello, everyone. Welcome to the Taira Talk on March 20th.
Today's speaker is Dr. Su Guanlin.
He was a doctorate student at UIUC, and then a post-doctoral researcher at UC Berkeley.
Today, he is going to talk about the direction of his research, which is collective light path, continuous light study, integrated process, and wavelength-adjustable semiconductor laser.
The topic he is going to talk about today is his work at UC Berkeley.
I think it has a lot to do with semiconductor laser and its integration.
Let's give him a round of applause.
Let's start with Dr. Guanlin.
Thank you, Jason. Thank you, everyone, for coming to my talk.
I want to thank Taira for providing this platform so that we can talk about this topic today.
My topic today is high-performance and high-performance wavelength-adjustable semiconductor laser.
As Jason just mentioned, this is something I studied at UC Berkeley as a post-doctoral researcher.
The unit I am currently affiliated with is Intel Labs Research Scientist.
Why do I want to mention this field in particular?
In fact, you may not be familiar with this picture.
This is a Wi-Fi input test web page.
The Wi-Fi on the screen that I will connect to you today is actually built up by light integration technology.
This is called optical transceiver.
This green row is all optical transceiver.
It's all equipped with light integration technology components.
This is also the most competitive field in light integration technology.
Even though it's very competitive, it's just the beginning.
Light integration technology has actually developed a lot of opportunities.
I personally think this technology is a very balanced combination of laser physics, light, and semiconductor manufacturing.
I think it's quite aesthetic.
So I hope to invest a lot.
As Jason just said, if we can make good use of Terra Journal Club,
I believe we can find a lot of people in this field who have the same morality and then further promote it.
My talk today is mainly divided into three parts.
The first part is the introduction.
I will introduce to you what is light integration technology.
And some of its basics.
Then there are two examples.
I have done two examples in Berkeley.
It's probably a very wide, widely tunable.
It can be tuned to a few nanometers.
And the second one is a system-level work.
It's a laser power guiding system.
It's kind of like we want to demo a data center.
A very energy-saving network resource distribution system.
This is also done by using light integration.
The rest is my summary.
I'm sorry to give you a disclaimer.
Because I am now working on light integration technology.
One of the benefits is Intel.
My opinion today, my discovery, and my summary.
In fact, it does not represent the company's position.
You can think of me as a postdoc.
What is light integration technology?
In fact, we all know that there is nothing too fresh under the sun.
Light integration technology allows light resources to go back to the microwave resources.
We are going to go from the table to the source.
We are going to go from the table to the source today.
This is what light integration technology represents.
The essence of technology is like this.
This technology was proposed by Stuart Miller in 1969.
This article was a very important article.
He mentioned three very important points.
The first is how we get the light from the optical table to the chip.
We have to create a certain optical distortion rate on this chip.
It can also form a web-guided structure.
After this thing is realized, he said.
After this thing is realized, we can improve the stability of the whole system.
Its reliability will increase.
Unlike doing free space, we often need to adjust some components.
When everything is on the same chip, this thing can be omitted.
You can ignore this step.
After this step is completed, he made the boldest prediction.
He thinks this thing will have a certain market scale.
Today, 50 years later, we can see that the light receiver is a very novel market.
This is basically in line with his prediction.
What he didn't predict is that humans have broken through the synthesis process of a single chip.
We can now synthesize more materials on a single chip.
Or we can synthesize two chips of different materials together.
It can break the physical limit set by a single material.
This is our hybridization material.
At the same time, if you combine a lot of materials of different optical properties,
you can break the physical limit set by a single material.
This thing is also a powerful force that promotes the advancement of the industrial world and the academic world.
This is basically the most intense field at present.
The left side is the traditional light communication, sensing, and network systems.
For example, last year, two terabits per second were demonstrated.
It's not just a light receiver, it's also a PGA.
This is a very, very new result.
This was in March of last year.
Then, about ten years ago,
Onchip, which was made on a single-chip,
is the optical prime of a chip.
It has a bandwidth of 300 MHz.
This is the last year's 30 parallel channels light radar.
This is the most studied technology in LiDAR.
It's a 30-channel light radar.
This is a very large amount of transmission.
In Japan, AIST also showed 800 Gbps data transmission.
And it's a light-operated data transmission.
And it's Lossless.
Basically, it doesn't matter how much power goes in, how much power comes out.
No loss.
In the more cutting-edge field,
For example, machine learning, quantum, and NIST,
The American Academy of Science and Technology,
In 2018, they demonstrated a optical frequency transmitter.
Directly in C-band, the so-called 1550nm,
1.93kHz,
It directly generates an optical frequency.
And its frequency can be up to 1Hz.
That is to say, its error is only 10-14 to 10-15.
This is a very fine frequency generator.
A Spanish group also made an optical FPGA last year.
It is composed of multiple unit cells.
It can do all kinds of transfer functions.
If you want to program it, you can program it.
A few years ago, it also came out.
Use optical circuits to make convolutional neural networks.
It can do image vision.
Connecting these two most extreme fields,
In fact, what can't be separated from the industrial and academic fields is our so-called high-performance light source.
Based on optical integration technology,
The bandwidth of our current bioluminescence laser has been compressed to about 3Hz.
Turnability has also exceeded 100nm.
This is C-band, so it is about 1550nm.
So it can be adjusted from 14 to 1600nm.
And our optical amplifiers on the chip
It has now exceeded 27dB, which is 500 times the optical amplification.
It can bear 500 times the loss on the chip.
It can continue to recover your signal.
Then there is a frequency cone.
It can produce direct 4-cell.
So this is a very groundbreaking work.
In fact, these more amazing studies,
In fact, the following things are very basic, very fundamental things.
It's our so-called waveguiding.
What Miller mentioned just now,
What is the difference in the loss rate caused by a single chip?
The one on the left is a SEM, a optical chip.
The SEM of the light path inside
The light is transmitted in these so-called light path lines.
When we cut this straight waveguide,
In the cross-sectional area,
We see such a material distribution.
For example, in this paper,
The material of the light path is a single-chip.
Below it is a low-resolution,
That is, the two-chip is the material below it.
It's all air.
So if you cut a chip,
You can see its index.
Its resolution distribution is actually a step thing.
Under these boundary conditions,
Our Maxwell's equation will actually degenerate into an eigenvalue problem.
Its solution is Lissan.
Then this solution is our so-called waveguiding mode.
Its solution basically looks like this.
That's different from the plane wave.
Waveguiding mode,
It is defined by an equivalent resolution.
Its equivalent resolution is somewhere between the low-resolution and the high-resolution.
Then its field shape is basically a certain rule.
Its peak value is a semi-wavelength.
Can fit in this index.
Then its peak value is probably in the middle.
Then we can change this light path.
Our so-called waveguiding.
Its light path, its interface,
We can engineer its mode.
For example, we can have this.
A little wider,
We can now fit in three modes.
For example, there are several more than just now.
So we just need to be able to master this light path.
Its basic design,
For example, its material,
Its index gap,
The gap between light and snow,
And its size.
We can design different photonic devices,
Photonic components.
In this talk,
I want to introduce a few photonic components.
First of all, this is what I just said.
If we use a single mode,
A single light path that can only support one mode.
We trigger a light path that can support multiple modes.
This light path is relatively fat.
Then I can trigger many waveguiding modes at the same time.
Then they will interfere.
This interference pattern can be accurately predicted.
For example, this is a very standard light path.
If we cut off this relatively thick wave at the right length,
We can make a light path.
This is a light path.
Then,
Then we are a 1x3 light path.
Then we have a single mode,
We set up two mirrors.
Partially mirrored, or 100%.
It can form a cavity.
This is a cavity.
If we add some photonic components to this cavity,
That is to say, it provides gain.
Then you can compensate for the loss of the entire cavity.
Under the right conditions,
It will form our so-called photoreceptor.
This is our laser.
What about this curve?
One by one,
It actually reflects that
All that can be seen in this photoreceptor
It forms a whole number of waves.
The wave field.
This is our so-called magnet.
Longitudinal mode.
This is the magnet.
It mainly emits light.
These wave fields.
Of course, we can also put a single-core
Single-core single-mode waveguide.
We use a more complicated loop to make it into a filter.
The first filter is our so-called Mach-Zehnder interferometer.
In addition,
You can also make it into a circular photoreceptor.
That is to say, the light hit in here.
The light coming out of here can also have a filter effect.
Mach-Zehnder interferometer.
Its transfer function is a very classic sine wave.
It is a sine wave.
From 0% to 8%.
That environment.
Its transfer function is a sharp thing.
Because it needs to achieve a resonance in the middle.
So its frequency selection is very large.
It is very fine.
But at the same time, it is also difficult to reach 100%.
In these devices that are used to form resonance in the future.
Whether it's a cavity or a filter.
The distance between our resonance points.
Basically, it depends on the size of our feature layer.
For example, in this cavity.
Laser cavity.
The distance between these grids.
It's actually very different from the resonance field.
And in Mach-Zehnder's interferometer.
In the middle of these resonance points.
It's the length that comes out of this.
It's also inverted.
In the same way.
The distance between these two resonance points.
And the radius of this transverse resonator.
That is to say, its wavelength is inverted.
These devices with resonance features.
Of course, after we do it.
After we realize it.
It must be different from what we expected at the time.
Because there will be various errors in the process.
So we may have to add some.
Our so-called phase tuner.
We can use.
Substantially change this.
The detection coefficient on a certain waveguide.
For example, heating.
Substantial heating.
Or adding a power plant.
Or adding current.
Turn off the current.
To stimulate these electron hole pairs.
We can change its optical detection rate.
And then we can.
Put these.
We used to miss the resonance points.
Move it to where we want it to be.
So basically.
As long as you are familiar with these components.
You can build a more complex system.
If you have any ideas.
You can use some well-known components to build it.
I'm going to talk about it now.
The first example I want to introduce to you.
Is this.
Ah.
We are on the single-conductive material.
There is also a single-conductive.
Integrated platform.
They made it.
The platform.
I will do a demonstration with him later.
That.
Ah.
Is.
In fact.
It's a single-conductive material.
It's not a multi-conductive material.
This one.
You decide.
The idea is that the two juices are theoretically exactly the same.
And when they launch, they will have a very uniform shape.
It's just optical.
It's just the shape of the frequency of this optical controversy.
Ah.
So you see every line.
They actually don't have a lot of energy.
But if we listen to the laser, we are in this.
This one.
Every product is inserted into a optical filter.
Ah.
This optical filter can be controlled by external signals.
For example.
Ah.
This is our so-called light barrier.
Then he can.
He can only choose one laser model.
He suppresses other laser models.
So when he has a shock radiation, he is a single-mole laser.
And he has a very strong one.
Ah.
This is a well-defined mode.
Only his power is obviously a lot bigger than that.
So what kind of applications does he have?
He's the first one.
It can be used in gas.
Ah.
My class.
It's optical.
Optical.
It can be used to track a certain party.
Or in the sound optical field.
He can do it.
The part of the body.
Then his light transmission is also a more traditional application.
Ah.
For example.
Hong Kong communication.
Or the same tone communication.
It's all a main force.
That's a new one.
Hong Kong is introducing to you.
The frequency-continuous wave light radar.
This.
He still has.
The main force is.
He is.
The main light source of the frequency-continuous wave.
That.
And.
Color.
Military Wave.
The frequency generation.
It's also called Tunable Laser.
That.
Tunable Laser.
What is his main metric?
What are his main parameters?
For example.
The most classic one.
I just introduced to you.
It's a.
Ah.
One.
The back side is replaced by a light bomb.
That light bomb.
After you put the current in it.
His index will change.
That is, the light bomb.
His.
The black weapon in the middle.
His maximum reflectivity.
The wave field can be.
Because.
Add current.
And then control.
That he.
That laser.
After the shock radiation.
His laser spectrum.
It basically looks like this.
Ah.
Until that one.
He's a single mass.
My.
His laser.
Why doesn't look like this?
Top wind with this second wind.
Power in the middle.
The difference is a 40 bibi, which is our so-called Punk wants.
He's al.
The mainstream wind and the wind.
The igen they stand between each other.
10 to 10.
It's in the BB.
For the second.
The second.
Who the hell is the parameter?
What is the original parameter?
I'm going to say.
So much.
When he continues.
In the case of continuous power supply.
He can.
He has a total of his weapons that can be adjusted.
How much?
Of course, his output power is also a main measurement goal.
Milliwatt or dbm to show.
And his efficiency.
For example, his.
How much power do you put in?
How much power does it give you?
Such a conversion efficiency.
It's a line with.
This is our frequency.
Accuracy.
Then it's because of the client.
A little better.
If it's a little worse, it's basically this number.
What if it's like this example?
This traditional dbm laser.
He only has one.
Ah.
In the case of a filter.
The most we do is adjust 5 to 6 nanometers.
This is a material limit.
So how do we get tens of nanometers?
Or like the example I just did.
More than 100 nanometers of tuning.
We mainly have two means.
This can be achieved.
This is the so-called white ability.
The first one is to use.
Ah, but it's a pair.
That is to say, we are using a pair.
This is the structure.
For example, the circular oscillator or the light.
Ah, light.
This kind of explosion.
As long as you are a pair, you can do this.
What does that mean?
This example is that we have two circular oscillators.
His.
The environment is different.
What about when the environment is different?
He's this.
Between the two points of resonance.
We have the so-called Fritz.
Fsr.
It's different.
For example, the green ring.
He.
We can see the green ring and the orange ring.
It's a little different.
So it leads to the two of them.
When they are together.
Only in their ally.
This place.
130 nanometers.
His transmission is the highest.
Then when you.
Ah.
In the middle of this green ring.
Add an object.
After a three-dimensional movement.
He can move a little bit.
Just move a little bit.
But their.
The second overlapping place is directly from 130 to 1290 nanometers.
So he's just.
You just have to move about 1 to 2 nanometers.
The wind.
What about your overall score?
You can jump ten times.
This is what we call the so-called oil marker effect.
I've used oil markers.
They all know that there are two degrees above.
They are a little bit away.
This is what they are.
You move one of them a little bit.
The next time they come.
It's very far away.
Then this.
His.
Ah.
His second feature.
It's just that he's got a very small.
This.
Ah.
He can make a big one for you.
Frequency jump.
Another feature.
It's usually this kind of parallel structure.
His role is relatively sharp.
In other words, his filter works very well.
But he's another semi-permanent.
One of the more significant shortcomings is that he's more.
Because.
He is a result.
So he.
Two small things into one.
He's getting smaller and smaller.
When you connect more and more.
He's getting bigger and bigger.
For example, you can see him.
From 80% to 64%.
That's another way.
Just use light interference.
That's what we just said.
A single color.
That's under this architecture.
We're just going to cut the structure in half.
And then add the mirror directly.
We all know this.
This mirror image.
It can be used as a single color.
His.
His transfer function.
That's the classic.
Then as long as one of the.
100% reflection.
That.
He's a continuous tuning.
That's what he.
It's the type of thing that jumps.
He is.
He's moving as much as you add.
How much.
But it should.
He's not like this.
The more you wear, the more he loses.
Uh, but his shortcomings.
It's also obvious that his role is slower.
It's just that he's particularly close to this.
The top of the three-way.
So his.
Uh.
Frequency selection.
It's not as good as this one.
I don't know if it's so good.
Whether it's an effect.
That's the kind of resonance.
Whether it's a resonance or this interference.
This kind of component.
He.
We've seen it.
He can be used.
Uh.
It can be adjusted.
It's a price.
For example.
On the single-fingered.
He is.
It's already reached a commodity level.
A parameter.
It can be adjusted.
For example.
There's a front light.
Backlight.
There's a layer of light in the middle.
There's an external magnifier on the outside.
At the same time.
To magnify.
Uh.
It's used to magnify light.
His.
Range.
It can be adjusted.
About 40 nanometers.
His.
It's the wind.
If you press the wind.
About 50 db.
It's 100,000 times the pressure.
Uh.
It's already at 100.
But in the case of an external magnifier.
It can be up to 40.
Uh.
This is a commodity scale.
A parameter.
That.
Next is.
On the second.
The platform will be introduced to you later.
On the silicon.
We.
Already.
Humans have made countless nanometers.
More than 50.
Uh.
db.
SMSR.
And then.
It's less than 100.
Because he doesn't have an external magnifier.
In fact, he.
Uh.
Nine.
It's still relative.
A more.
Uh.
A power level.
That.
In this.
Light.
Light interference.
The method.
In.
Most of the time.
It's in the single-finger.
They make monolithic.
A little.
That's it.
It's three.
Really.
Stuck together.
That.
It can be up to 74 nanometers.
You.
Uh.
At the same time.
About 40 db.
Or more.
A little bit.
Uh.
Power is relatively low.
He only has one.
That's it.
This example.
He's this year.
He just came out last year.
He's eight.
Uh.
More.
More extreme.
A means.
He has eight.
Mzi.
8.
The interference.
He's a total of 45 nanometers.
Uh.
50 db.
SMSR.
His language.
It's also down to 160.
Uh.
Power is also better than the previous one.
50.
Uh.
About five.
But.
You can see that they are involved.
They use a lot of filters.
Compared to this.
This kind of use.
Uh.
They need more filters.
To reach this level.
40 or 50 db.
So we can see it very intuitively.
His control is how you want to go.
It's actually quite a challenge.
What about this filter design?
In this example, you can see this.
Light filter.
His design.
It directly affects your laser performance.
This is very obvious.
Then in 2011.
Ah.
Please say.
Oh.
This is the language here.
What is the laser language?
Uh.
What do you mean?
That is.
These languages are.
Uh.
He is.
Oh.
Intrinsic language.
Is it related to his laser.
Is it related to the gun?
Or with.
Oh.
Right.
He is.
Intrinsic.
That's right.
You remember very well.
He is.
It's related to the gun.
Uh.
If.
For.
Uh.
Laser.
He is more.
Just.
I have prepared a more.
Uh.
A more graphic slide.
What is his language?
He's actually laser.
His.
He's tired to death.
When he turned his body around.
He's actually.
Especially the semiconductor laser.
He's in his background.
In fact, there is a very weak.
It's his.
Uh.
Self-radiation.
It's just that he hasn't reached the water.
The thing that happened before.
It's the LED thing.
Uh.
When it reaches the water.
He's going to have a very clear one.
Uh.
The mechanism of radio radiation.
But.
And then this is my.
Put this.
The expression of that.
It's his.
Instantaneous.
The electric field inside the laser.
His face.
When the radiation occurs.
There will be a very large amount.
To show that he was the radiation field.
But on top of this.
It's because he's got a lot of background.
Uh.
Self-radiation.
So he's got this.
He has a very weak one.
A very small amount.
He has.
He.
It's riding on this.
This.
On top of the mobile radiation.
His lungs are random.
It should be said that he is.
So you can imagine.
He's a very big amount.
He's actually got a very small thing on top of it.
So he's actually shaking.
He's not.
It's not a very clear one.
He's got a distribution.
That's what we call the face.
The face is not accurate.
In fact, it is this.
His.
His performance.
They're only missing a factor in the middle.
That's right.
This.
Live with him.
The main thing is your gun.
The longer the laser is, the longer the gun is.
Your language can be lower.
But the longer the gun is.
It's also.
It's also equivalent to your laser.
Between the captain mode.
It's getting narrower.
If it's getting narrower.
If it's getting narrower, it's testing the design of your filter.
How to make this laser.
In.
Maintaining a single film.
Uh, it's harder to launch.
So, in order to normalize the gun, it's still.
This is a blow.
I understand.
Thank you.
Right.
That.
So we're in.
Uh, so.
We're in 2017.
When I was in the post office, we proposed a new architecture.
We call it the three X.
It's actually also part of this kind of light.
Light sensor system.
A filter effect.
So, he actually, we're talking about Bell Labs.
In 1990, he did the Y-Laser.
At the time, they had two branches.
That's the only one.
That's what we call the.
Uh, the sensor.
So his.
The SMSR is relatively low.
The top of his side wave is very smooth.
He only has 100 times the 20 dB.
Uh, his tuning range is also relatively small.
Only 8 nanometers.
But we.
Uh, based on theoretical calculations, we found that as long as you add the third R.
The third branch.
That's equivalent to the two of us.
It's equivalent to the shortest one.
This one.
We have two.
They each represent a very wide FSR and a very narrow FSR.
Uh, through this, uh, mechanism, we can introduce two.
The interference pattern of the front wave.
We can.
Max, we can design this tuning range separately.
With him.
Improve his SMSR.
To achieve a, uh.
Basically, it can decouple these two parameters.
I want to be on the Y-Laser.
These two parameters are always.
Uh, hand in hand.
You want SMSR high.
This is.
Intrinsic.
Mathematically, it's such a.
Uh, a reality.
What kind of structure does that 3X laser have?
This is a good explanation for everyone.
This is.
Uh, their transfer function.
If this is the Y-Laser.
It's the front wave we just saw.
But if there's a 3X, we add the second front wave.
We're naturally on the outside.
We're still the same as the Y-Laser.
But in essence.
In this.
We have the second.
Interference.
That is, we can.
We can.
We can take this.
It used to be very smooth.
The front wave has become very sharp.
Uh, further filter.
I don't want to.
I don't want to filter.
If we're going to calculate it.
If you don't, you'll find this Y-Laser.
It's actually very dense at the top.
That is to say.
These modes.
It's actually with the main model.
That's what we want.
150 nanometers.
They're very close.
So, uh.
But if you add.
Like, if we add the third branch.
We can filter out a lot.
I don't want to.
You see, we only have about four or five left.
And they're with the main model.
There's a certain gap between their hands.
So we can.
So, uh.
Uh.
Okay.
I'll tried.
One.
I back.
And I kicked.
My body.
Just.
Uh.
Okay, okay, thank you.
Oh, thank you.
Um.
Uh, I, I have a question here.
Uh.
So this is what we call a jump.
Uh, jump filter mode.
What I just said is a jump.
Uh.
Of course, he's testing.
It's very obvious that you can see it when you're testing.
For example, we can see that he has a middle jump here.
He jumped again.
Jumped again.
This is basically a jump.
Jump.
Uh, that's it.
You can also see this.
Every step.
That if it is.
If it's a laser, he'll jump this.
Uh, filter mode.
Yeah, that's it.
Is there any application of this?
At present.
Uh, I haven't used it yet.
And.
In fact, people hate this thing.
It's because of the time.
That represents him.
Physically, he represents two.
He competes with the carrier.
When it's the most intense, it's the same input current.
There are these two.
He's giving you at the same time.
Grab this resource.
That is, he was at that time.
Uh, noise is the biggest.
So everyone hates this thing happening.
Well, there's no way.
This is physics.
There's no way.
Uh huh.
But all of them.
With that kind of micro ring.
Will there be this problem?
Yes, all of them.
As long as there is a filter.
He will have this problem.
Uh, the most frequent.
Uh, if the L I is.
Uh, there is no filter.
As long as there is a filter, he will be like this.
Of course, he can play very high power.
But he is always multi mode.
There is no way.
Yes.
Don't worry.
Um.
Or use DFV.
DFV is a single product.
Then he.
Uh, there won't be.
This problem of motor.
Uh huh.
Hey, ask him.
His mother.
His.
Hey, can you give me some numbers?
I can't see it here.
He's probably.
How much frequency is this?
Uh, I think.
OK.
Oh, it's okay.
Hey, I want to ask another question.
Hey, a little bit.
His.
You have a character.
What is his?
Uh, relaxation.
Is the frequency of the selection?
Oh, we don't have it.
Because of this platform.
We are.
Uh, more.
We are a foreign package.
This is the Netherlands.
Uh.
But you can guess very well.
He is in the middle of 1 gigahertz to 3 gigahertz.
He is not.
So, of course, this level.
OK.
Thank you.
Correct.
But he has something to do with his resonance gun length.
The longer your resonance gun is, the slower it is.
Correct.
OK.
Well, if not.
Then I will end this recording here first.
Thank you all.
Thank you.