Let me start by introducing Annie.
Annie completed her Ph.D. in Geography at the University of Sydney, Australia last year.
She is currently a Senior Research Officer at the University of Technology Sydney,
working closely with the Associate Dean of Indigenous Land and Justice Research Hub.
Before completing her Ph.D., Annie was awarded a Master by Research and a Master of Cultural Studies
with Gender and Cultural Studies, also at the University of Sydney.
Her research interests include human geography, labor and spouse immigration, urban planning,
circular migration in the South Pacific, resource and livelihood,
Southern Asian studies, rural economics, Australian aid, the end of the user experiences,
remittances, and substantial development.
Annie is fluent in English, Mandarin, Tartoon, and Taiwanese.
Let's start with Annie.
Thank you.
Thank you, everyone.
I'd like to go over my topic for today.
My topic is Life After Migration, Migration, Urbanization, and Mobility in Geography.
Geography is the capital of a country called Timor-Leste.
You can see a cute little house on my PowerPoint.
According to Taiwanese, it's a traditional sacred house.
When I was still doing my Ph.D.
I lived in the Far East for about seven months.
I worked there from the end of 2018 to the beginning of 2019.
As the host mentioned, I speak Tartoon.
Many of my interviews were done in English plus Tartoon.
After I returned to Australia, I completed my Ph.D. at the University of Sydney.
I went to UTS, the University of Sydney Technology, as a Senior Research Officer.
In the U.S., I would be considered an Assistant Researcher or Assistant Professor.
But in Australia, we have a clear distinction.
So I only do research.
I didn't teach this semester.
So I don't call myself a professor.
In Australia, we have professors, assistant professors, and professors.
We don't have an assistant professor.
So we have lecturers, senior lecturers, and associate professors.
As you can see from my PowerPoint,
I'm going to talk about East Taiwan and Australia.
I know that most of our listeners are in Taiwan or the U.S.
So you may not know much about the South Pacific.
I think this is what makes lecturing valuable.
It shows us that there are different possibilities in life.
Of course, it's still a research topic.
So I'm still going to talk about what I'm studying.
What is my method?
From a geographical perspective,
what's the point of living there for seven months?
What else did I discover?
So the first point I'm talking about is resource management.
So why is it useful to do research in this small country?
Is it useful for Australia or Taiwan?
Or is it useful for them?
My Ph.D. was covered by an Australian aid program.
Australian aid is the same as U.S. aid.
Australian aid was used to assist the Pacific Islands and Southeast Asia.
Taiwan used to receive aid.
We used to have U.S. aid.
So it's a miracle for Taiwan's economy.
But we can think about whether we can replicate this in other countries.
Or what direction can Taiwan's aid be in the future on the South Pacific?
So I'm going to talk about its resources.
My PowerPoint has oil.
And it's very young.
And you can't find a job in the local area.
That's the point of today.
Remittances is right.
As long as it's a private loan, it's called remittances.
It's different from A.
A is government-to-government agreement.
But remittances can be sent from Australia to Boxuan for $100.
This is remittances.
So a lot of people would like to send people abroad to work or study.
And there are a lot of natural resources in the local area.
So there's coconut, palm oil, and coffee.
So my first point is that there are a lot of Australian aid projects.
One of them is the Australian Seasonal Workers Program that I did.
It's very similar to the plan for Taiwanese to go to Australia for holiday work.
But the biggest difference is that Taiwanese or Australians are free to go to Australia for holiday work.
Because they're holiday workers.
But this is a South Pacific island.
Only workers from countries supported by Australia can come.
They're government-to-government agreements.
So it's a bit like our diplomatic model plan.
So workers are actually treated very well in Australia.
Because this is the face of the country.
And it's government-to-government agreements.
So if Taiwanese go to Australia for holiday work,
you have to find a job, find a house, apply for a visa, and do everything yourself.
But if it's a Pacific islander, like Fiji, Samoa, Tonga, and my Timorese workers,
they're already set up.
Everything's set up for you.
All you have to do is fly over.
So that's a very different thing.
And they often have ambassadors from Pacific islands to see the workers.
Make sure they are treated very well.
This is a big difference.
So a lot of people, because of the support of this plan,
they can buy land or build a house when they return to their home country.
Or a lot of islanders like to party.
So a lot of it is spent on the maintenance of social networks.
The third and final point I want to talk about is
what I find challenging.
As a woman, and as you can see, I'm not white.
But I'm from Australia.
I'm Australian, I'm Taiwanese, I'm Hakka.
So this is how I negotiated my positionality.
Of course, sometimes it's boring when you first go.
And basically, as long as they see you as a woman,
they'll think you're a high-ranking wife or something.
They won't respect me as a professor.
Sexism and xenophobia.
This is what I'm talking about.
In fact, a lot of Pacific islanders have Chinese roots.
But how do Chinese people get along with them locally?
That will actually affect how they see my role.
Or I'll talk about how I often walk on the road and get touched by children.
Or pull my hair or something.
But I can speak local dialect.
So when I use local dialect to scare them, they'll be surprised.
Oh, this foreigner can speak local dialect.
And he seems to be from Australia.
They're scared when they see someone from Australia.
Because the role of Don Lee-Woon is very ambiguous.
He's a bit of an Australian colonial enemy.
So I'll talk a little bit about the history of Don Lee-Woon and Australian roles.
So we need to know where T-Mall is.
Where is Australia?
So you may have no problem with geography in this regard.
This is a map of the United States.
So the size of Australia is actually about the same size as that of the United States and Canada.
Don Lee-Woon is on this small island in the north.
It's a very small island.
It's between Indonesia and Papua New Guinea.
It's actually very small.
It's smaller than Taiwan.
But the complexity of its population is actually similar to that of Taiwan.
Because it has a mountainous terrain.
It's quite similar to Taiwan.
Mountainous.
And there are only two seasons, dry season and rainy season.
I was so happy when I went there in August.
It's about 40 degrees every day.
By November or December, like now, it's rainy season.
You go out every day like this to pick water.
In such a situation, it also has a lot of products.
Because there is a lot of rainwater, you can grow anything you want to live.
So there are a lot of things.
I'll pick a few first.
The first one is why I did this PhD.
Because Australians think it's important.
Because there is oil in the back garden of Australia.
So you can see it on this map.
Australia is here.
And then there's a small island on top of it.
It's Papua New Guinea.
Next to it is Indonesia.
So it's about the 17th century.
The Portuguese came and took over Papua New Guinea.
And then it's been there for over 300 years.
Basically, the number of buildings is not very large.
If I want to be more diplomatic.
The Portuguese brought them nothing but singing, dancing, Latin names and Catholicism.
There's not even a railway.
And they didn't build a university.
So in fact, the Portuguese are the characters over there.
I want your sandals.
I'm the sandalwood.
The locals used to talk about sandalwood, but now they don't.
I don't want to do a lot more construction.
But in the post-Papua New Guinea colonial era.
It was from the 1960s to the 1970s.
Natural gas was discovered in the East.
It's the kind of natural gas that you can light up in your backyard.
Natural gas floats up from the ground like this.
Of course, the Portuguese didn't have the Renaissance Revolution.
So I don't want to be able to pick it up.
But they found a lot of Indonesian businessmen who were actually very interested.
Australia is also very interested.
The United States is also very interested.
In the end, Indonesia's stronghold next to it was occupied by Dongding in 1975.
And then Australia signed a contract with Indonesia and said,
Hey, let's open the Timo Sea Oil below you, okay?
That's their cooperation.
But because Indonesia was independent in 1975 to 2002.
There's construction between 25 years.
There's a university and there's a lot of scholarships.
And then there's actually a little bit of the whole domestic economy of Dongding.
There's a construction infrastructure.
But he killed a lot of people after all.
In the 1992 massacre in Santa Mascara.
The issue of human rights in Dongding caused strong interest in the international community.
Yes, of course, in the end, Indonesia was there.
Ah, there's no way to go on.
And then the United Nations sent troops.
So, in 1999, they had the world's first record.
It's an independent referendum.
And then it was decided that a lot of people who were close to 99% decided to be independent.
We want our own country.
We don't want to be a province in Indonesia.
So they're independent.
So, from 1999 to 2000, the UN sent troops.
Most of the people in the UN are American or Australian.
So Australia and his ambiguous relationship has been going on for a long time.
But now it's officially the UN sent troops.
So what about the oil treaty between Indonesia and Australia?
So they're renegotiating the bond.
And then it becomes the oil of Dongding and all kinds of natural resources start to be exploited.
And maybe there's a bigger chance that they're going to let their own people manage their own resources.
So then they set up a team.
Petroleum fund.
It's about putting the oil revenue into the country's reserve fund.
In Taiwan, it's called redistribution fund.
And then we're going to talk about whether or not the money has been used properly.
And then there's the whole situation of the people's livelihood.
But in addition to oil, they have pretty good coffee.
Yes, I put a picture of Fairtrade's Timor-Leste coffee.
And a lot of coconut.
There's a province in the east called Los Barros.
They produce a lot of good quality coconut.
And I put the Dongding sea water I shot there.
Their sea water is really clear.
I haven't been to Palau.
But I heard from some of my friends who have been to Palau.
He said that the feeling of looking under the Dongding sea water is similar to that of Palau.
It's very beautiful and pollution-free.
So it's actually very rich in marine resources.
And then there's the most important resource.
I think it's also about determining whether or not this country can develop the most important resource, which is people.
Let's take a look at the demography of Timor-Leste.
Look at the population.
It looks very young.
Most people are under the age of 25.
When I was in the Dongding sea water, I was over 30 years old.
But young people over the age of 10 are at a loss.
But if someone looks very old, like over 50 years old.
It will be respected by the local community.
Because we can see that there is a gap between the population pyramid 35 to 39.
Then we can push it back a little bit.
They had a war more than 20 years ago.
At that time, it was those 18-year-old men who were going to serve in the military.
Usually quite a lot of people died on the battlefield.
So now they are about 40 years old.
Then there is the population pyramid.
It is in the age bracket of 35 to 45 years old.
There will be a shortage.
So because there was a civil war before.
So a lot of people just can't do it.
In this situation, develop their own personal economy.
Or the development of life.
Basically caused a lot of problems.
Then we are going to talk about the role of Australia in the development of the East China Sea.
Because I just said that there are Chinese people in the East China Sea.
So basically 75 years ago.
Many Chinese people in the East China Sea came to Taiwan to study.
Because at that time they were members of the Republic of China.
And there is a consulate in Dili.
Because they are part of Portugal.
At that time, Portugal had diplomatic relations with Taiwan.
So from the founding of the Republic of China to 1975.
In fact, the relationship between Taiwan and East China Sea has always been very good.
A lot of people came to Australia because of the war.
Most of them are Chinese.
50%.
Most Chinese people in East China Sea are very good.
And rich.
So at that time, they could either choose to go to Taiwan to study.
Then a lot of people went to Taiwan to study.
Then apply for a refugee visa to Australia.
Or some people settled directly in Taiwan.
Not necessarily.
So now there is a census in Australia.
I mean they are Australian.
They are Australian citizens.
Or permanent residents.
Just like there are green cards in the United States.
There are about 10,000 people.
Of course, there are a few workers.
Or people who study abroad.
These may not be included in the census.
But Australia has always had a very close relationship with the East China Sea.
So when we talk about immigration theory.
Excuse me.
You just said 10,000 people.
Is this a high proportion of the population of East China Sea?
Yes, because the population of East China Sea is only 1.3 million.
Oh, OK.
Almost 1% of the population.
Yes, almost 1% of the population are in Australia.
So Australia is very important to them.
Like me and the East China Sea Embassy in Sydney.
It's a very good relationship.
The Embassy may come to me for a cup of coffee.
So they will say.
They usually send people to Australia.
Must be looking for the best, the highest level.
Just like Taiwan sent to Washington.
Is a peak of your diplomatic career.
So what we are talking about in immigration theory.
Migration has a push and pull factor.
Is that push and pull.
What is your birthplace?
How bad is it to let you send you out?
Or the place you moved to.
Like the United States or Australia.
How good is it to let you stay?
So what I'm talking about in this PowerPoint.
Is it the push and pull factor of the East China Sea?
We can take a look.
Because it's not very urbanized.
31%
And this is last year's data.
So 31% means.
70% of people actually live in rural areas.
So think about it.
If you are Taiwanese.
What was Taiwan like more than 40 years ago?
That feeling.
Maybe more than 40 years ago.
Taiwan's literacy level may be a little higher.
A little bit.
I don't have that data.
Then they have a very important reason.
Is the young unemployed population.
Because there are really not too many buildings on the island.
So if you go to college.
They now have about 7 specializations.
Plus college.
But after going to college.
Do you want to find a job?
The unemployment rate is 12.3.
The unemployment rate in Australia.
The overall unemployment rate.
It's very high after COVID.
Our very high is only 6%.
Then this country.
The unemployment rate on the island is 12.3%.
Then his population is only.
1.3 million.
And most of it is a very young population.
It's the middle of the year.
Because of the war.
There is no.
Their minimum wage.
$150 a month.
Is to do labor work.
I can only make about $5,000 a month.
But their official currency.
It's in US dollars again.
Because there is no ability to.
There is no central bank to issue their own currency.
So it's in US dollars.
Then a dollar or less.
There's that little coin.
It's called Saint.
It's Portuguese.
Saint.
They were in 2002.
After independence.
And then there's something like that.
The civil war.
It's a little bit of an Indian.
With that one.
A little bit of a local.
And there may be people from Australia.
There's a little bit of a conflict.
So that's in 2006.
Plus they're actually.
In 2014.
With Australia.
Because of the oil.
And there's a hearing.
That's right.
Because I'm not a political expert.
So I'm not going to go into detail.
But we can find out.
It's a big problem.
So I'm going to repost.
So we.
So many resources.
How does it help the development of this country?
Or is it just a resource curse?
There's oil, but.
It's like oil revenue.
It's not owned by the people.
Economic development is not up.
So then later.
The Australian government did something.
Just like I just said today.
Australian seasonal workers program.
To put this.
The diplomatic.
It should be said that the diplomatic.
Political ambition.
With the purpose of economic development.
Wrap it up into one.
Is that it can make both sides.
Can accept the immigration plan.
So what about this plan?
I have a net.
And this one on top is mine.
He's in one.
He's probably.
Because because the islanders.
They don't have that many people.
Can go to college.
So as long as this plan has.
You can join when you're in high school.
That might be 18 to 45 years old.
That's going to be very capable.
So they're going to have some physical tests.
It's like Kang.
It's not Kang Sabao.
But it's a little bit like jumping.
Something like that.
Can be that.
And then there's the hospital.
I just realized.
I'm going to Australia.
Is to the farm or.
Because it's a diplomatic plan.
So it's not the same as the resort.
They can go to some.
Places on the Australian coast.
There's a place in the northwest of Australia.
You can have that.
The industry.
So it's like that.
Remote hospitality.
They can actually do it too.
There's a pretty big one.
The focus is on me.
Talking about it.
Australia is the first world.
So if it's a job search.
Like me.
I can only have my name.
But if today.
Assuming my last name is changed.
I might be Chinese.
And then your application.
I'm not going to put up a picture.
Yeah.
You can only have your academic experience.
In order to avoid that.
Right.
The discrimination of competitors.
But if this plan.
It allows you to do overseas recruitment.
That's a big deal.
It's a big deal.
So they can do it.
Any kind of test.
What kind of people do they want to pick?
Go to Australia to work.
Those who want to use.
Want to join this government.
Plan.
Approve employer.
They have to pay.
Those migrant workers' visas.
Residence.
And air tickets.
Although it's still deducted from their salary.
We call it deduction.
But this is basically.
There will be a lot of convenience.
You can actually.
If I'm the owner.
I can pick anyone I want.
And those in Australia.
The law may be very unauthorized.
Like this.
You can't have pregnant people.
Or.
People who used to do business.
It's in there.
But this is in Australia.
Local laws are not allowed.
If someone is pregnant or married.
If you resign.
The government will shut down.
But this is basically.
You can do a lot of tricks.
So.
In this situation.
This plan.
A lot of migrant workers.
The islanders.
They are all very.
I should say it's a local business.
So.
There is also an implication.
The Australian government also hopes.
We are the best on the island.
They should be able to contribute to the local community.
Help this country.
Can develop.
So I made a picture here.
These workers may be.
In.
Regional Australia in the Australian countryside.
What do you do?
And then the money.
He might just send it back.
To his wife and children.
They will build a house there.
And then raise some pigs.
Or buy some farmland.
The so-called economic effect.
From just a family.
Expand to a whole community.
With a whole country.
This is their original expectation.
But we can look at this thing.
Is it feasible?
Because people.
You can't put the money.
Give the money to others.
It has nothing to do with you.
So this project must be big enough.
Its impact will be big enough.
Because I won't just send money to me.
A stranger.
I might just give it to my brothers and sisters.
To my family.
So this thing.
We will talk about the so-called academic.
We will say it is a.
Bottom-up approach.
Not that top-down.
But also these two.
Approach.
At the same time there is that power.
So the development of this country.
It may only rise.
But we can see that his current ratio is still.
31% still in Petroleum.
With oil.
Then 26% in natural gas.
22% in coffee.
Is raw coffee.
Then there are some other things.
Basically it is very small.
Then I said.
I was doing research at the beginning.
I do household survey.
Then a local family.
There are probably 11 or 12 people.
Imagine 45 years ago in Taiwan.
Because they are every.
Because women will be born.
Seven children in a lifetime.
If you see three or four.
That may be a senior official.
Pressure or something.
Maybe three or four are very few.
So I was.
A total of 52 families interviewed.
Then there are about 11 or 12 people in each.
If the child does not count.
I just do one.
Similar to the focus group.
The nationality.
Then ask them.
Asked some questions.
May be.
Because I mainly want to know.
How do they spend money?
What did you buy?
Something like that.
I also chased those workers.
From the countryside of Australia.
This is me.
Field map.
In Kunshan in the north.
Because Australia is a basketball.
So our north is a tropical.
I remember that time.
I drove for a long time.
Maybe half an hour.
I did not see anything.
Australia is very big.
After 25 minutes.
I only see nothing.
In the middle of nowhere.
They may live next door.
Accommodation.
That's it.
That kind of house.
Six months back once.
Six months back to the east.
So I was.
I was studying for a PhD.
Second year or third year.
I just followed them.
About six or seven months.
Then use WhatsApp and Facebook.
Contact them.
When they are ready to go home.
Very simple.
I just followed them home.
So I can know.
What do they use money for?
So the result I got later.
Where did they spend the money?
I came to a conclusion.
Basically.
36% of people.
Spend the money on.
Build a house.
This is easy to understand.
Because.
Their traditional house.
It's a straw house.
I really think the straw house is great.
It's very cool to live there.
It's a bit like Taiwan.
The traditional house.
You are the kind of tropical area.
Of course it's a straw house.
But if it rains.
Make a big water.
The straw house is washed away.
So they still basically.
Want to build that kind of western style.
Big house.
Then there are tropical colors.
Maybe the most is orange.
Red and green.
Then there will be 27% of people.
Want to do business.
Then I basically.
Three or four days ago at the National University of Australia.
There is another online conference.
Then there are many.
Development practitioners will say.
How do they use western ideas.
Think about it.
These islanders should take the money.
Then we should teach them how.
Financial literacy.
This is very.
Western colonialist view.
I teach you how to use money.
Then I said at that time.
Say.
No one is going to work for someone else.
Once they come back from Australia.
That's it.
You have been working so hard in Australia.
And there are white people.
Not necessarily white people.
Is the boss.
Then why do you come back?
Still continue to work for white people.
Or what kind of person is Australian?
Many people want to come back.
I just want to be my own boss.
So this is basically.
I think it's a great market.
They will be.
Can take this money.
Some people are from Indonesia.
There are many small and medium-sized businesses in Southeast Asia.
There are some people who are because of war.
May be young.
Their younger sibling.
There is no way to complete education.
So many of them.
Also invest in education.
Will send.
Will send their younger brothers and sisters.
Go to Indonesia to study.
Because actually.
As you know.
The nearest western country there.
It is Australia, New Zealand.
But the tuition is really expensive.
That is a year.
It is also 40,000 to 50,000 US dollars.
That.
Go to other places.
Asian countries like Singapore.
The competition is too big.
Taiwan did not provide scholarships.
The most convenient is Indonesia.
So many people have mentioned.
They want to go back to college.
May be going to Indonesia.
We may feel in Taiwan.
It is a very advanced country.
But after all.
That is also the Northeast.
So Indonesia for them.
In fact, the level of development is also very high.
And it is a very good choice.
So many people.
In addition to these three.
Build a house and do business.
Also invest in education.
Many people also bought it.
I bought some pigs in the countryside.
Domestic animals.
Basically more pigs.
Or chicken.
Or cash crops.
Mango trees.
Many people buy banana trees.
And coconut.
Some are quite a lot.
Sorry.
Can you go back to the top?
I have two questions.
The first one is.
These are all interviews, right?
I saw the data.
All interviews.
In fact, I also double verify.
Because many times.
What they want to do with him.
Not the same.
Because of me.
Only through Western Union.
It's Australia.
I actually have an Australian.
The office asked for the approximate value.
Then I asked again.
Then I went to the interviewer.
Can you show me what you bought?
What did you buy?
Because I still have a point.
Many people tell me.
He bought a chicken.
Do business.
In fact, he went to sell chickens.
Because they fight chickens.
There is a girl who told me.
How much did he spend?
When I went home to count.
6,000 less.
So where did he spend 6,000?
You ask him directly.
Where is the missing 6,000?
It's embarrassing.
The next day, his friend invited me to drink coffee.
When I was working.
With a special man.
Come back to have a baby.
Not his husband.
So the 6,000 dollars.
In fact, it was a baby born in Australia.
It's too embarrassing.
He didn't want to tell me.
I said OK.
So I spent about 3,000.
Understand.
Another question.
Because this is like.
Is it back from Australia?
So it's a bit like.
I don't know if this question is right.
For those who are already.
For these local families.
It's like this.
So it's like this.
The ratio of income.
Is it also applicable to the general.
The ratio of income they originally had.
It should be said that.
The way they use this money.
It's different from the way they usually use money.
Or are they using the same.
Almost the same ratio.
This question.
You really know how to ask questions.
I think this is worth it.
1 million questions.
Because basically the islanders.
Do you know that their salary is very low?
So 150 dollars.
Basically, this money is for them.
Windfall fell from the sky.
Sit down money.
And a lot of people in the countryside.
They don't need money.
You have to imagine that Taiwan.
Even in the 50s and 60s.
They actually don't need money.
Because they are obligated.
It's said that there is often that.
We drove by.
My colleague is a documentary director.
He will talk a lot.
Hey, that sister.
I use candles to exchange corn with you, OK?
So they are basically still.
A lot of rural people are in the original economy.
So this money is for them.
Some of my workers.
They are.
Sent 6,000 yuan.
6,000 dollars back.
That's very big for them.
It's completely zero money.
The gift that fell from the sky.
Because they used to be.
What do you eat?
Maybe 100 times a month.
There is no such system.
So this is extra.
In addition to their livelihood system.
Can you answer this?
Because I will ask these two questions.
In fact, there is one in economics.
A very important theory.
If you say today.
Maybe your income today.
You may use this ratio to spend.
Then if you say today.
Give you 100 more.
It's like a hundred dollars that fell from the sky.
How do you make a choice?
It is very possible that you will spend a sum of money.
To invest or a sum of money.
When you get it.
Just spend it all.
You may want to save it.
Let you in the future.
Have a certain consumption.
So that your consumption can be smooth.
Let your overall life level go up.
But this thing is not always.
There should be some information.
But not like this.
A very good piece of information.
Because this state.
For us, it may be okay.
But for the locals.
This may be a big state.
How do you use it?
If the quality of the information is very good.
In fact, it is quite suitable.
So I will ask like this.
So I feel very curious.
Really.
So we see this pie chart.
In fact, I asked.
They did not mention buying food or what.
Because you usually want to buy food.
You go to kill your backyard chicken.
Or you go.
Use candles to exchange for corn.
All they talk about is.
I took this.
Is to build a house.
I bought a car.
Or what.
Then they did not even talk about buying a mobile phone.
At that time I was.
Fortunately, you asked.
I asked.
Don't a lot of people buy iphone?
Or what.
Then I found out.
I really live in the local area.
I found out.
I really ask.
You are too naive.
You know their network is super bad.
And everyone wants to buy that phone card and network.
Then they bought a mobile phone.
So a lot of people say.
He may be working here.
He wants to talk to his girlfriend.
He wants to buy a mobile phone for him.
A smart phone for his girlfriend.
But this is not a remittance.
It's because they've been working in Australia for a long time.
I bought it.
So those are gifts.
They brought it all back.
What rice cooker.
I was wondering why.
No electronic device.
But they actually bought it first.
So these are the ones.
Because these are the ones that can only be used locally.
So yeah.
This is probably.
And then later.
I've been living there for a long time.
I'll find out.
They're actually in the process of urbanization.
There are quietly going on.
Although they are urbanized.
About 30 percent.
About 70 percent.
Most of them still live in the countryside.
But in fact.
This transition is also happening.
From that general.
They actually have one.
The only shopping center in the country.
It's called Timo Plaza.
It's a bit like when I was still in Taiwan.
When I was in fifth or sixth grade.
My hometown is Taichung.
I go to the first square.
It was about 20 years ago.
The level of Taichung's first square.
I don't know what other areas are.
There are some.
Chinese businessmen from other places.
Come over there to sell some small things.
Or goods or something.
So basically a lot.
But most of them are.
Because of the war.
So a lot of that.
The road is the whole.
It was when the UN army came.
Get rid of it.
So a lot of countries like Japan.
JICA.
What exchange association.
I helped them in.
There are also Koka in Korea.
China's Belt and Road.
Also fixed a lot.
Of course there is.
USA in the United States of America.
Also have this.
So there are gradually roads in the countryside.
But this is a very sticky situation.
They have a road but no streetlights.
So I really.
It was a long adventure for me at the time.
If I go out at night.
I have to have a flashlight.
Otherwise it's pretty dangerous.
That's another one.
I think it makes me feel even more.
A big change is because.
According to Marx's theory.
Capital transfer.
Also.
How do you get the capital.
To support you.
Your own activity.
The change.
To see the change of this era.
So they also started from.
The.
Sell small things in the market.
Also advanced.
That is to say.
Maybe it's like a sales service.
Like the one on my right.
There are buses.
So their buses.
This service is only available in the capital.
If I was going to the countryside.
I have to take a truck.
It's really a truck.
Then.
Because I'm a foreigner.
There will be some goods on the truck.
Like this.
If you want to take a truck.
You have to do it with the chicken and the sheep.
So I will.
If you use the power of money.
Then give me two more dollars.
I can sit next to him.
I don't have to.
Travel with animals.
Of course.
These workers.
A lot of money.
$6,000, $7,000, $10,000.
A lot in the local area.
I asked the least.
It's the kind.
He's not quite used to Australian life.
It's the first season.
He might only have 3,000.
But if it's the kind.
I've been to Australia four or five times.
They're very good.
They can save a year.
One season is six or seven months.
It's close to $20,000.
I want to say I'm a university professor.
I can't save that much.
I'm a moonlight group.
If you go back, you're basically considered.
It's a new father's class.
So this.
This is actually in.
In fact, in terms of local people.
This will break.
Break some.
Maybe that person.
He's usually in.
Uh, in the local society.
His original class.
It's not that.
And then he might go back.
With a lot of money.
Like Taiwan said.
Explosive or greedy.
It's just that feeling.
It's also a lot.
Uh, in the local area.
It's a hot topic.
Like I went to the countryside for an interview.
They want to say.
So that means I'm here to ask you.
Can I get into that?
They'll be right.
This thing is really going abroad to work.
Create an Australian dream.
This thing can be.
It's a way to make me rich in an instant.
But in fact.
When I was doing the interview.
I'll find out.
A lot of people.
I want to pursue this Australian dream.
But in the end, you're done.
We can see him build a house.
Progress.
Some people may be more.
So he might have gone.
Two seasons.
About 10,000.
And then the house on the left.
Just build a small house.
But some people may be ambitious.
Or what?
Like this house.
That's the backyard of our house.
He also went to Australia.
But because it seems like only one season.
Or what?
It's just that the money hasn't been sent back.
The whole house is embarrassing.
So his house has no roof.
He can only live on the first floor.
The second floor has not been returned because of the money.
And then maybe my wife is.
The second floor has no roof.
The whole house can't be built.
So this is actually.
There is the so-called.
That kind of meeting effect.
But the meeting effect.
Is there really that much?
Or can it always be a continuous thing?
It is also necessary to see.
Or there is.
In Taiwan, we are in the Japanese era.
There is self-love.
But not in Tokyo until now.
To my picture below.
The picture is standing next to the Tokyo girl.
It's Australia and the Tokyo flag.
This word is called Beirun.
Beirun means water well.
So the Australians donated a well here.
That's in the urban area.
What are they doing in line?
They are queuing for water.
Because only foreigners live.
Or high-ranking families.
There is tap water.
That's usually.
A group of people is going to.
Water station.
Or the water tower to get water.
What do they usually drink?
They are the main water.
Or buy that kind of imported water.
I remember when I was there.
The first thing I wake up every morning.
I opened my faucet.
Because I was sitting.
In the house of the British consul.
Then I opened the faucet.
There is water.
I just put that pool of water.
I just.
There is something like a piece of water.
Then I use that water all day.
To brush your teeth.
Wash your face.
Then I go to the supermarket.
Buy water.
So basically a lot of people.
After working home.
The first thing they see when they buy a house.
Like Taiwanese people look at the location.
Did you enter the train station?
What is the bus station?
Their first preference.
Enter the water tower.
There must be a well and a water tower next to it.
Because there is no tap water.
This is also a very different thing.
Then I have this picture below.
There is a German-Austrian geography.
Annual photography award.
That is.
They.
I was in the market at that time.
Take a truck to the side.
When I was doing a rural interview.
I took a sneak shot.
Their truck is usually a bit like.
Thai song.
Or the Philippine tattoo.
Everyone will sit in the back.
Then the driver sits in front.
Then there is no sign or anything.
So you just follow the water.
But my interviewee.
When he came back.
Bought a truck.
He said he wanted to do this business.
Because in a public transportation.
A very underdeveloped place.
You can move.
In fact, to some extent.
There is a way.
Generate more wealth.
Is to be able to let your.
Economic capital continues.
A very important element.
Then here again.
Back to what I just said.
In fact, some people may want to.
Come back and do business.
What.
Some people do it.
Tourism industry.
But their tourism industry is.
There is an empty environment.
It's very underdeveloped.
It's not easy to go to Tokyo.
There are only three places to fly.
One is from Australia.
Darwin.
Darwin is a base.
It was a military base before.
That place.
And only Australia Airlines.
Qantas Air North.
Next is from Singapore.
The last one is from Bali.
Bali is actually the most.
Most people fly.
Then I flew directly from Australia.
Then come back to Bali.
So the plane.
It's not easy to fly.
Very few tourists come.
That is.
Domestic tourists.
It's not enough to support this.
So they.
The official has been telling me.
Can you write an article about tourism?
Let more people come.
I just want to say.
But it's not like that.
The West will want to go to Tokyo.
The feeling of spending money.
It's a big adventure.
That kind of feeling.
Because they are actually like.
Many areas in Southeast Asia.
Fighters are banned.
We know that Indonesia is actually a.
Go home country.
In addition to the fighters in Bali.
Other places will call the mayor.
But the fighters in Tokyo.
Basically every day.
That's their rule.
The rule is.
I'll have a video later.
The chicken will become.
Dinner that day.
If you win the chicken.
Because they're in the chicken's leg.
Remember the chicken's leg.
A knife.
So if you lose, it becomes dinner.
Then if you win, you can.
Survive and then tomorrow.
Continue the next round tomorrow.
So a lot of people are actually.
In.
Get those things back.
In addition to doing these meaningful things.
A lot of people actually use it to gamble.
Or do something.
Make you happy.
Spend.
But every time I'm with the West.
I'll say this.
This is like our Melbourne car.
Go to SEMA.
You go to a bar or something.
But this is the local version.
Let's take a look.
Fighters.
Wait a minute.
So let's take a look at the Fighters.
That's what I put on the left.
It's a bucket shower.
I was in the east.
Ask how to take a shower.
This is a bucket shower.
Fighters.
Wait a minute.
Let's talk about it.
Yes.
There was a chicken.
A little accidentally picked.
And then the chicken was left to the side for dinner.
I was on the left picture.
I am our sponsor.
Come back he opened the ghost.
Really like Taiwan 450 years ago.
You are just in that window that man.
And tell the old lady.
Hey, what I want?
Hey, I asked my woman that person bought something.
She said she bought a bottle of gutebebe chili sauce and a envelope.
So they are basically that kind of small particlularly.
It's like this.
The whole thing on the top is the shampoo.
Because they actually only have to go on a date.
When is it?
When do you wash your hair with shampoo?
That's why they usually take a shower.
I just use cold water.
So when you wash your hair, you use a small bag.
And then because I'm a foreigner.
So sometimes I go to visit our OZ corner.
We have an Australian supermarket.
See if we can buy Australian milk.
Then we'll see.
These are our little friends.
This is their daily game.
And then I just put some.
I wrote some articles myself.
If you are interested.
And the Australian ABC has interviewed me.
Chinese experience.
If you are interested, you can take a look.
Wow!
The black one next to it is a pig.
Their pigs are pretty thin.
Because people can't eat enough.
So the pigs are also very thin.
Yeah.
So that's about what I wanted to share today.
If you have any questions.
You are welcome to discuss it together.
Thank you everyone.
Thank you.
Annie's speech was really, really exciting.
I really think it's very, very interesting.
Then I want to ask.
If the audience has any questions.
You can ask them at this time.
Then.
Or this is good.
Because our speech is almost.
I can stop recording first.
Then everyone can be more free.
If you want to ask questions, you can.
If you are here, thank you again.
Annie's speech today.
Thank you.