subs by bubucaca
Okay, I believe everyone can see my screen now
Sorry, let me see if I can play it
I think it's fine
subs by bubucaca
Okay, I'll just...
I'll just use this mode
Hello everyone
Today we have
Project Tyra
two professors
One is from
Houston University
Professor Chen Tai-yan
Professor Chen Tai-yan from Chemistry
The other one is
Professor Yang Shumin from George Mason University
He's a Professor of Criminology
Today is July 17th
It's one of the summer special activities
that Project Tyra is holding this summer
In this year's summer special
we are planning to hold
a few more
different topics
About the PhD application
Mentor Mentee
In addition to today's speech
on August 28th
there will be another
study abroad application
written workshop
I want to remind everyone
if you are interested
in joining our
study abroad application
on July 17th
which is today
and August 28th
you must attend
We will record
this as a basis
for future Mentor Mentee
application
So please
remember to attend
the lecture on August 28th
The lecture on August 28th
we will send you
the link
of the lecture
In addition to these two lectures
Project Tyra will also hold
a scientific drawing
including using Illustrator
or Latex
to make a scientific drawing
and the topic of COVID-19
and scientific collaboration
and mass-media
If you are interested
in Project Tyra
if you are interested in
becoming one of our staff
to promote
Taiwan's young scholars
weekly lectures
or other academic activities
you are also welcome
to join us this year
Next week
on July 24th
we will hold
an annual member meeting
and a staff recruitment meeting
If you are interested
I will now
hand over
the mic to
the other two professors
to share
their thoughts
on the
requirements of
applying for
a PhD program
Thank you
to the two professors
for coming
and sharing
their experiences
with us
Thank you
Okay
So
today's topic
will be discussed
by me and Professor Chen
Before you apply
for a PhD
what can you
consider
and what information
can you use
to help you
decide
whether to
apply for
a PhD program
So
let's start
with the first part
and then
the second part
Professor Chen
Okay
So
all the
audience
are interested
in applying for
a PhD program
If you are
applying for a
master's program
or a
MBA
or any other
major
it may be
a little
different
So
let me
introduce myself
My name is
Chen
I am a
PhD student
and I am
currently studying
at the
University of
San Francisco
and I am
currently studying
at the
University of San Francisco
In the
US, there is
no salary cap
In the academic world
In Canada,
it is more like
the US
but in many
European and American
countries
there is no
fixed salary
This is a
very important
part of
your career
For example,
the vaccine against
COVID-19
is a very important
part of your
career
I hope that
you can find
a better training
and a better
way of teaching
I hope that
you can
learn about leadership
In addition to teaching
and research, you can
develop your own
career
I hope that
you can
develop your own
career
I hope that
you can
develop your own
career
Thank you
I'm going to let them know
We're about to start
Is it this one?
Yes
Okay, so tell me if you still have a problem
Anyway, I hope I made myself clear
The point is, this is a soft voice
But
Can you follow me?
Yes
Okay
Another one
Future direction
Let's start with this
What can you do in the future?
I'm talking about social science
In social science, of course, you can go a long way
Social science is, of course
Except for academic position
For example, research university
Research type R1, R2
Teaching type university
The so-called Boya College
Or community college
Some people even do tenure track
Non-tenure track job
Or even in college
Some are research jobs
Not so-called teaching
But it's a pure research job
Some term faculty
Not tenure track
In Taiwan
The concept of so-called professional assistant
Or there is a visiting professor
Visiting students
This teacher is also relatively
Temporary
Actual position
It's more like Taiwan's part-time
Teaching one or two classes
There is a part-time job in the academic world
Of course there are more
But I'm roughly like this
There are also other people who want to say
I don't want to do academic work
Some of my students say
I'm not interested in pure academic work
But I hope to change the world
Or I hope to be able to
They may go to the library
Some students or friends
Work in government agencies
Whether it's the local government or the federal government
Like me
National Institute of Justice
FBI
Or local police
Of course this part
It depends on your identity
Especially in the United States
For government work
A lot of people ask
You are at least a green card or a citizen
This is a way out
Of course there are some non-research institutions
Or some organizations
For example, some people want to go
For example, criminal protection
Related organizations
Or even anti-human trafficking
Anti-population transmission
Like I have a lot of students
In some different agencies
But there is one thing
I want to talk about
So much good
But also consider
Sometimes looking for a job after graduation
Get a doctor's degree
Does it help you find a job?
This thing
It's not necessarily
Why do you say that
You may have to look at your future work
Standards for the degree you need
Sometimes people work
Especially if you are not in the academic world
If you work in the industry
They are also worried about one thing
Overqualification
You have a doctor's degree
But they only need a master's degree
At least in Europe and the United States
Sometimes they don't want you to have a master's degree
To find a job
Because on the one hand
It's a part of the salary
On the other hand
I think it's a waste of money
So maybe you can think about it first
What is your future career outlook
And then think about it
This is the way to go
Is it the most suitable way for you
So now
Is Powerpoint moving?
I have it here
OK
This is what I said before
When I was talking to Professor Chen
We are all curious about this
I want to share something with you
Sometimes you come to the doctoral class
Before you need to think about it
Why do you want to come to this doctoral class
Why is this question important
Because it's the doctoral class
It's not like the master's class
One or two years
But when it comes to a doctor
You're looking for a job
People will worry about whether you will be highly educated
And then you read the doctor
For you
Some parts of the field become more open
But the work part
Or some parts
Sometimes it becomes narrower
So you might want to think about it
And the time and money you invest
You can think about it
Why do you want to read this doctoral class
It's because of your family's expectations
Your important others' expectations
People around you keep telling you
You're so smart not to read
It's a pity
It's because of other people's expectations
Even the neighbors
Who is so smart
Why don't you read a doctor
Is it because of this
Or because you want to pursue self-fulfillment
I just like to do research
I think this is my mission
Or you are very enthusiastic about a certain topic
Like I might be a student
Tell me when I was very young
I think this is very important
This is his passion
Then it is very clear
Know which way you want to go
Then this may be a
Your internal motivation may be very important
Or is it possible to read this
I feel like I can do some work after reading the doctor
It seems to be a social status
It seems to feel like
The income will be very stable and high
But it's not like that
Just like we said
Although at least in the United States
But at the same time
That is to say
The distribution is not very uniform
For example, it's not the same job
Your payout will be the same
So you may have to think about this
If you come to read
It's to feel like I'm a few years later
Guaranteed to have a job
Guaranteed to have a good salary
There is no way
So if it's so direct
Or so practical
You may consider
Go to the way
Go to the way you want
Because especially now
Everyone knows that Kobe is more serious
In Taiwan
The same job
A lot of people are fighting
This is more serious in the United States
Like last year, we hired two people
Then we hired two people
I seem to have received about 160 applications
This is for two jobs
So this is actually very competitive now
So you got a doctorate
Guaranteed that you will definitely get a job
So this thing is what you have to think about
What is your motivation
Why did you come to read this thing
Some people say I don't know what to read
Especially Taiwan
I have read
I don't know what to do
Just keep reading
This is also an idea
But maybe at some point
Think about where your enthusiasm for the future is
Like I said here
There is nothing right or wrong
But maybe you have to ask yourself first
What is your goal
What kind of self-achievement do you want to achieve
Another very important thing is
Can you accept
If this
Walking back and forth
The result is not what you imagined
Can you bear such a result
Then these are all
I think these can be thought of first
Not to hit you
Not to make everyone feel that life is very pessimistic
But I think you can think about it first
If there is such a thing
More able to face
When it comes to life
Know that this is just a process
This is a process
You may always kick a little stone on the road
That doesn't mean
What will it be
But maybe think about it first
I know
If you are more determined
I think I can overcome this
But if you don't have a very firm idea
I think I want to retreat
Of course, the other part is
It's more practical to consider
What is the price you need to pay
Time to work hard
Your money can face the future
Uncertainty
After all, there is a lot of pressure
Can you do something good
Can you finish reading within a certain period of time
Then usually this test is
There are often some low self-esteem
The concept of low self-esteem
Why do you feel
I don't seem to read fast
My presentation is not good
My grades are not good
It's easy to become
Such a lost comparison
And often there are setbacks
Your first draft is accepted immediately
Then everyone goes to celebrate
This time is too little
If you get R and R
If you can modify it
You should put it aside
You get the first draft
You can see right away
Is to face
As we said at the beginning
Of course there are benefits
You can learn some knowledge
You have a lot of different life experiences
Research experience
Then you have some different skills
Then your field of vision will be more open
You will have some ideas of cross-cultural
Even say you can meet some very cool people
Great master
You used to read in textbooks
Maybe next to your office
You can talk to him about some research questions
But we can't just talk about the good side
Then don't talk about that
Don't talk about some negative parts
Jump to the next part
I want to ask
Do you want to add here?
For students
That is to come
Some of the parts I want to add
No, I think the teacher said very well
Please continue
Then I will continue to finish
I will leave it to you
That is
If you want to play this thing
Still feel very firm
I want to go to the institute
Of course the first part is
You have to find a school
Which school is suitable for you
Or I said which school
In the institute
Doctoral class is more specific
It's not the part of the school
Which is
Which department
Is suitable for you
So we will put that program
At the front
I think the program should be compared to the school
Is
The rank is more priority
Because after all
No matter how good the school
For example, some schools like Harvard
Maybe some departments are very good
Some departments are not so good
So it's not that the better the school, the better the department
Then I myself
I will put the program
Is able to provide
Even the ranking program content
At the top
Then you have to see if this department is suitable for your field of study
Is it possible to provide the necessary resources
For example
Is there a teacher in the department
Or the lab is special
In the part you want to study
Because you have to read the doctor
Basically there should be some
The field you want to understand
But that doesn't mean you can't change it in the future
Cross-field or transfer field
Because I have transferred to the field
But this part needs to be understood first
If you are very interested
That is to find the program
It's important to have a professor you want to work with
How to choose a good school
Of course
Carnegie is the
Commission of Higher Education
There are R1, R2 and D
There are many kinds
I only list those who can get a doctorate
Of course the first one is
R1 is very high
Respect
Focus
On the research part
Usually the teacher's teaching burden is relatively low
Usually 1,2 or 2,2
One semester, one door, one semester, two doors
R2
Also focus on research
But also focus on teaching
The teacher's teaching burden here is usually bigger
But I still hope
The teacher can do a good job
But this part becomes
Because the teacher's teaching burden is slightly higher
So usually it can be divided into research time
Not necessarily so much
D and P
Some professional schools
For example
For example, the Department of Physical Medicine
Or
Not reading PhD
Psychology
That's different
This is a more professional degree
But be careful
If you want to get a professional degree
A lot of times
They will ask you to get a PhD
Not a professional doctor
There will be some differences
Because the requirements are different
The evaluation method is not the same
When it comes to choosing a program
If the program is similar
Still have to look back at the school
Because the better the school's ranking
The better its resources
It usually attracts more
Different good students
Overall reputation
It still helps you in the future
So when the program is similar
Also consider the school's ranking
Then there are some
When you are considering
Like for me
There was a very northern school in New York
A very southern school in Florida
I thought it was too cold and too hot
So I went to Maryland to study
This is for you
Geographic location is important
If you think about going back to Taiwan
It's convenient
University is also an advantage
Not only can you fly directly to Taiwan
Another point is
Do you need to work
Easy to travel
The convenience of travel
Is also a consideration for you
Cost of living
Is your living expenses
You have to consider
Usually there will be scholarship
But in a big city
General graduate scholarship
You can't afford your life
Maybe you have to make up for some
But if you are in some
Lower living expenses
Many students I heard
You can still save some money
So cost of living is also a consideration
Opportunity
For example, my students
In DC
We often have some opportunities
We will do a state report
Report to the members of the state
We are in crime prevention policy
Research results
We have a better chance of getting along with them
Or even to be an intern
There will be more federal agencies
Can do internship
Or something
Or after graduation
Like I have a student
Before graduation
Because it's close
So this opportunity is also the future
You may want to consider
For example, whether it is a long-term job
Or some work experience
Opportunity is also important
Then there is the climate
If the climate is for you
Your comfort zone is not so big
Or you want to experience a very different life
Maybe you will choose
Some regions have different climates
The other one I want to tell you
Usually
You are in the doctor's class
If you want to find a school
Maybe you have to do a little more homework
Because if you only look at
Some of the schools you know
Sometimes you may have a sweat
Many good schools
Taiwanese may not know
Like Vanderbilt, Emory Rice
Maybe a lot of people know this school
But relative to the so-called
Some schools that everyone is familiar with
They may not be so famous
But they are in the professional field
Or even in the United States
Very distinguished
So just do more homework
To understand your own field
Instead of being influenced by the ranking of schools
Known by Taiwanese
Because this may lose
Some good opportunities
Then the other one is
So if you are not familiar with the school
How do you know
The teachers here are good
How to do homework
Look at every teacher
Research experience
Do they have a research plan
Or their field of research
These are all very important
I hope everyone is in
These parts have to be considered
Which ones do you need
To do the assessment
OK
I'll put this part first
Professor Chen
Professor Chen, I can help you
Let's ask Professor Chen
When you have considered all these things
When you are ready to apply for a school
How do you do this preparation
And what needs
Professor Chen can also add
OK
Can you hear me
All right
So now on the slide
Basically you are preparing
During the application
Will experience several
Specific process
When everyone was preparing at the beginning
First prepare some
English test
Then when you are ready
After the English test
It's not bad
The second thing is to prepare
To find the program you want to apply for
Or the school you want to apply for
Basically I suggest
Don't look too much at once
Use 5 plus
As a target
Find the corresponding information
I will give you an example later
Can let you see
How to go through these processes
In the application process
You also have to prepare a lot
Your
Track record document
For example, your results
For example, your CV preparation
At this time
I suggest everyone
The earlier the better
Then there will be a very important
Two documents
My personal feeling is
After being
Graduate Search Committee
I think
When reviewing abroad
Review in the United States
When studying abroad
Your Statement of Purpose
With Recognition Letter
Are the two most important
And the most decisive
Document
To decide if you will be admitted
When you prepare all these documents
You can go online
Then go online application
Basically this process
No matter which field you are
Will not change much
Time
The earlier the better
If you can come today
Project Tara Webinar
I believe to some extent
You are more
You prepare early enough
You know where to find some useful information
Next slide
Step by step
How to prepare
Be careful
Next slide
Because I am a chemistry teacher
I am in
Houston
Use our application
To make an example
Let everyone know
When you want to do this
Where to look for information
When you identify
When you want to apply for a school
First to the school
Top of the department
Basically
You will see a
PhD Program
Then you can click in
Now in our department
There is a Apply Now
If you click in
It will tell you
All kinds of application information
With basic requirements
you need
Next page
After going in
Usually some documents
You can't do much
Modification
How are you before
Now is the time to arrange
The most basic document
Includes your
University or master's degree
Certificate
Next is your result sheet
Next is your CV
These three documents
Basically you can't think too much
Especially your certificate
And the result sheet
You only need
To go to the school
Department
Apply for these things
After applying
You have to spend
Some time
With the school
I believe there are some
Help college students write their CV
Some institutions
At this time
I would suggest everyone to look for it
And use these resources
To write your CV
To attract people
Basically this thing
You can't think too much
About your CV
If you can make it clear
Simple is the best
But basically
There are not many things you can do
Next is your English test
English test
Basically what everyone sees
If you are in the United States
Basically
One is TOEFL
One is GRE
More and more schools
Especially
Research Institute
I think
People don't look at GRE
Many schools include
UH
Medical Center
RISE
Basically in the next year
They didn't ask for GRE
Graduation
So I think
At this stage
I guess more and more schools
Provide
This kind of convenience
This is because
Everyone wants to recruit good international students
Many international students
They look very outstanding in all aspects
But on GRE
They can't pass the threshold
That will cause a lot of sweat
In foreign schools
If you look at the results of GRE
And the performance of students in the course
Basically
There is no connection
So more and more schools are pushing
Abolish GRE
So
If you don't know
Do you want to apply for a school
GRE is necessary
Then I would suggest
Go to their website
Look at their latest
Certificate
On the other hand
I think GRE is a
Very important
English test
Because
If you go to
Tier 1 school
Basically
There will be enough support
For students' salary
They provide you
Financial support
Basically ask you to be a TA
TA is the so-called
Your main job is
You must
Communicate with
Undergraduate students
You are a TA
You must have good enough
English expression ability
To help
University students study
So GRE is usually
There is no way
Every school
Requirements for GRE
I think there has been a gradual rise in trends in recent years
So when you are preparing
I would suggest
Put more effort on TOEFL
GRE, I think
As expected
Maybe in the future
There will be fewer and fewer schools requiring GRE
Next slide
OK
This is
When you enter
After entering our website
Every school
There will be a
Frequently asked question
The students will
Always provide questions
Usually in that part
You will see
The department will provide
Very specific standards
This is before
Revealed on our department website
GRE is still a
Required document
On their
On our website
It will provide
Basically we must meet these requirements
For example, how many points do you need for TOEFL
How many points do you need for GRE
You are qualified
Enter
Graduate Search Committee to review
Otherwise the school will directly
Block your file
You don't even have the right to be reviewed
So
Everyone must know when applying
Are you in line with these
Requirements
Otherwise your application will be a mess
There is no way to be reviewed
Alright
Next slide please
OK
Next we are going to talk about
The most important document
It's called Statement of Purpose
When I was young
When applying for school
When I was writing the Statement of Purpose
I didn't know what to write
So I just wrote it
When I
After so many years
As a committee member
I summarized
A good Statement of Purpose
Should include
Several elements
The first element
I think it's motivation
Basically it means
Why do you want to apply
Your Statement of Purpose
The second element
You have to
Honestly discuss
Your GPA
The third element
You have to discuss
Do you have any research experience
You can see
I wrote leadership
Leadership basically means
Have you ever
Worked with others
OK
The last one is research interest
When you apply for school
I think research interest
Very important
Because you have to
Log into their website
Find your own interesting teacher
So every school will be different
You can't use the same
Statement of Purpose
To vote for all schools
OK
If that's what you plan to do
Basically
I personally feel
It will be lower
OK
Let's go back to the beginning
Let's talk about
In these five elements
What should you write
Like the first one
Motivation
I think it goes back to what Professor Yang said
You have to think carefully
Why do you want to take a PhD
OK
Of course you can't write
I just have nothing to do
Not a strong
Reasoning
So everyone
Why at the beginning
Professor Yang
I hope everyone can think about it
Why do I want to apply for a PhD
OK
Because in your Statement of Purpose
Basically your beginning
Will be a very important element
OK
The second one I wrote
The main reason I wrote this is because
When you are in elementary school
OK
Very few students can be in
Keep a good GPA for eight semesters
OK
I take myself as an example
When I was young
Especially when I was in freshman year
OK
I'm not a student who likes to study
My GPA is very, very bad
OK
Then
It's so bad that I feel
If I really wrote it casually at that time
I must not apply for school
OK
If you say
If you have a similar situation
Maybe in your student life
In college life
You may have one or two semesters
The GPA is very bad
Then you have to think carefully
To make an explanation
Because if you don't make an explanation
When the reviewer looks at your CV
Look at your SOP
I will start to think about it
OK, why didn't this student explain
Why your grades were not good at that time
OK
I take myself as an example
When I was in college
My grades in freshman year
In our class is very bad
The last class
There may be 60 students in our class
I may rank around 50
My GPA may only be more than 2
Yes
But when I
When I was in senior year
And when I was in freshman year
I may be the first or second in our class
So
At that time you will find
My case has become a relatively vague case
Because when I was discussing my GPA
I can say that when I was in freshman year
I actually don't know what I want to do
OK
So I just
Find myself to relax
OK
When I realized that
Chemistry is my passion
And I decided to be a chemistry teacher
Things get wrong
Right
This situation will be a very positive lead
OK
When you are discussing your GPA
When the reviewer
Look at your
SOP
This is a big plus
OK
The best idea is that you always
If you don't have anything to say
That is very excellent
In that case, you just need to list
What you have won
OK
But I think GPA is a
Everyone must think about it
Explain why your GPA looks like this
Everyone
Put your GPA with what you want to do now
That is to apply for Ph.D.
To make a link
OK
What else can help you add points
This is the so-called research experience
OK
Like me
I went abroad to study after finishing my master's degree
So when I was studying for my master's degree
In fact, I have already
For many
Common scientific instruments
Quite familiar
There is such a research experience
This is a big plus
The reason is that the students who apply in the United States
They basically
Apply for Ph.D. directly from the university
Ph.D.
This is not popular in foreign countries
OK
Because they apply for Ph.D. directly from the university
So many students actually don't have
Enough
Scientific training
If you say
You have done a lot of research
Then this time
Will be a big plus
Then you have to explain
What you know
To prove
That this thing is
On scientific training
Already have
Enough maturity
OK
So if you have these
You have won some awards
You do some presentations
Or you publish some papers
These will be big plus
Another point is
Leadership
This thing is actually
Although the United States emphasizes heroism
But when we review
A Ph.D. student
We actually value more
Is this student
Culturable
Is it a talent
OK
Can he be a team member
Can he
Cooperate with others
Complete a project
OK
But at the same time have their own unique insights
It sounds very
Contradictory
But in the end
When you become a Ph.D.
You must have so many different characteristics
How to write
To prove
Demonstrate you are a leader
The best
Example
If you say
Volunteer experience
OK
For example, you may go to the hospital
Be an intern
Interact with people
OK
What did you do
For example
Because
You care about someone
You provide some advice
Solve something
This will be a good example
OK
You can think about it
Is there a similar example in everyday life
If not
If your application time is still long
Try to find these opportunities
So you can write it in your SOP
OK
The last one
I think it is also
Very important but also very time-consuming
A component
You identify
Which lab
You are interested in
Obviously this thing
Must be done by every school
It will be very tiring
So if you do five schools
Must look at
At least identify 15 faculties
But this thing will make your
SOP
Very attractive
OK
Especially when
The teacher you like
Is their department
Decide who can
Admit
Can decide
This time
It will be very very powerful
OK
So I would suggest
Don't be lazy
Don't feel tired
Really just put
The teacher in the department
Find three
Now basically every teacher
Have their own website
So everyone just go in and take a look
I suggest you take a look at their latest paper
Don't find a paper
If you are going to do
One of these things
I would suggest not to do this
Because the research ten years ago
It will be very different now
So just read
What they wrote on the website
Plus this one or two years of paper
That's it
In this case you will have enough
And profound understanding
OK
And in this case
Even that
The teacher in the paper is not the teacher you are interested in
They are very likely to refer to
Those teachers you are interested in
If those teachers think you qualify
Then you get the admission chance
Will be a big expert
OK
So I think this is the summary
These key elements
For the study purpose
Next slide please
OK
The last one is the so-called
Recommendation letter
This thing
I think in Taiwan
With what I saw in the United States
The difference is very, very big
OK
I think the big reason is because
People don't usually talk to teachers
Relationship
OK
So when you are a student
Or when I was a student
I'm actually very afraid of talking to teachers
OK
But when you go abroad
I think it's a very important document
OK
In Taiwan, my feeling now is
Teachers will teach students to write the draft of the recommendation letter first
And then they do some minor modifications
OK
Usually when students do this
Basically
May be very close to your deadline
OK
The teacher basically doesn't know you
You may be his student
You may perform very well
He knows you
He doesn't know who you are
He doesn't really know who you are
He doesn't know what you want to do
He doesn't know what is your dream
OK
In this case
You draft the letter yourself
And then sign it to the teacher
And then the teacher sends it to us for review
The most common case is that we see this letter
OK
This letter
Very plain
OK
And this letter
This application document
Basically will be put into
Secondary pool
OK
So when you want a recommendation letter
You don't want a plain letter
That doesn't help you
OK
Sometimes it actually hurts you
When we see a letter that says everything
But it seems like nothing is said
Then we will try to
Try to
Read between the lines
OK
When you see a lot
When you save about one or two hundred minutes
You will know
The teacher doesn't really want to recommend you
If the teacher doesn't really want to recommend you
Then we have to follow the teacher's advice
Put you in
The category we don't like
OK
So how do you prepare your recommendation letter?
The first is that you have to prepare early
How early is early
Early until the teacher really knows you
OK
There are a lot of my students
When they are in the second year
They start to talk to me
Start to discuss with me
What they want to do
OK
When they are in the third or fourth year
When they come to ask me for a letter
I totally know
What are the characteristics of this student
OK
But there are students
Like this
I don't know this process
What kind of student
He may be a month before the application
Come to ask me for a letter
OK
The first one I don't know this student
Then the second
A month for me
For the teacher
Generally speaking
For the professor
A month is a very short time
OK
For the teacher
Because it doesn't match
OK
So I would suggest you
Once you decide to go abroad
You can start talking to the teacher
OK
You need at least three teachers
Let them really know you
Let them know
What kind of student you are
What are your strengths
When you go to ask for a recommendation letter
OK
Don't just say
Can you help me write a recommendation letter
This is actually a very irresponsible approach
The more appropriate approach is
OK
You have prepared your results
Prepare your CV
Prepare your SOP
OK
When you prepare all these documents
And then talk to the teacher
Believe me
The teacher will be moved by your sincerity
OK
Then I would suggest
When you really want to start
When I want you to help me write a recommendation letter
It's best to do it two months in advance
OK
Basically, these documents must be prepared for the teacher
It's possible that your SOP is not fully prepared
It doesn't matter
Just put a draft
OK
Let the teacher know
What do you think is the highlight of your life
When the teacher sees it
Once the teacher knows what you are doing
Once the teacher knows you
The teacher can play freely
OK
So you have to provide enough information to the teacher
Give the teacher enough time
OK
Of course, the sooner the better
The other thing is
When the teacher agrees to help you write a recommendation letter
I would suggest everyone
One week before due date
If you find that the teacher has not sent out the recommendation letter
Give the teacher a reminder
OK
This is definitely a very appropriate action
So don't be shy
Think OK
I remind the teacher is a disrespectful behavior
No, this is a responsible behavior
Because the teacher is sometimes too busy
He will forget a lot of things
OK
So don't be shy to remind the teacher
I would suggest everyone
One week before due date
Send a reminder to the teacher
OK
Next please
So we just talked about a lot of things
Right
What makes you stand out
OK
Usually everyone thinks
GPA
GRE
Of course these things are important
OK
But I would say the importance of the English test
For science students
I think the importance is relatively low
GPA is important
Because GPA is our
The first criteria we use
To cut off
Those not so great students
OK
So if your GPA is not very good
Then you can
The only chance you can get
Admission
It comes from your SOP and your recommendation letters
OK
If those two are very strong
They will compete
Your GPA
OK
SOP is a very very very
Important document
OK
It takes a lot of time to prepare
Recommendation letter
You have to let the teacher know you
OK
Taiwan's current
Taiwan's current atmosphere
I don't think it's a very healthy atmosphere
Still a lot of
Teachers ask students to write
Draft
This is actually not very good
OK
I found that very few teachers do this
All right
So I guess
OK
Spend time
May be much longer than you think
Because a lot of preparation
In fact, it's not just you
OK
You need the teacher's support
You need time
Put some key elements
Make it
For example, you do research
For example, you are an intern
These things take time
So if you are now
If you want to go abroad
Now you can probably start slowly
Be prepared
You won't feel so stressed
OK, next
OK, this is another
I think I agree with Mr. Yang
Is also a very
Effective way
When you find a teacher
You really like it
Like it so much
If you don't go
Then I will suggest you
Try to contact the professor
OK
Abroad
From time to time
There will be students actively
Come to contact us
This thing is actually very common
So when you do this
Don't think it's a
Very rare
Then you shouldn't do it
You should think about it
This is a
Can fully show that you are
Actively looking for the right teacher
A mode
OK
When you contact the teacher
Pay attention to
Make sure
Your tone is appropriate
OK
Then
When you
When you write to the teacher
In your
Email
Just introduce yourself
But remember to attach your SOP
Your CV and transcript
This way the teacher will know
What is the level of this student
He will decide
Do you want to continue to contact you
OK
Of course doing this
It may be a useful way
But it doesn't necessarily guarantee
You will get admission
OK
But I think it's worth a try
Next
OK
Financial support
This is a very important thing
If you want to apply
School
Belongs to R1
If you are a student
You don't have to worry about this
OK
In R1
Teachers usually
Will ask you to do TA or RA
OK
I believe this part
For R1
Not a problem
But
Social science
I believe you have to think about it
OK
I want to ask Professor Yang
To add
His thoughts
Thank you
Professor Chen
This thing is basically
Like what Professor Chen said
The students of the science department
Because their resources are more abundant
Then the funding is more abundant
So in my experience
The science department
If you are admitted to the doctor's class, you will definitely be paid
But social humanities
It's not necessarily like this
In the economy
Especially in the past few years
Because of the epidemic
In fact, many schools
Funds are tight
Some schools
Will insist
For example, a fixed fee
In this case
Some schools
If the number of people does not decrease
Or some schools do not have enough funding
He might say
We will accept you
But we do not guarantee your funding
Do you want to come
Unfortunately, our social humanities
Sometimes the funding is not so abundant
As I remember a few years ago
Our department is now
We are in an interesting situation
Many teachers in our department are very successful
Get all kinds of research funding
This is a permanent
So permanent
If it is a school or department
Long-term spending
We can write it on the offer letter
Tell the student
We provide you a few years of funding
But we have a plan
For example, the three-year plan, the four-year plan
Because that plan is so-called non-permanent
So we can't write it on the letter
We can also contact the student
We have this opportunity
But we can't write it on the letter
For example, our student
Older
Because he is married and has children
I remember he wrote a letter
He said
You did not guarantee that we have funding
Do you know that I have a family and children
Don't you make it difficult for me
Although you are right
It's also very sad
Sometimes there is this sad part
So I have to say
If it's my own student
I give my own student advice
I think this is very important
Even I think this is the most important
If there are two or three schools
The ranking is almost the same
If the other conditions are almost the same
Definitely consider going to a school that gives you funding
It's not just about money
Of course there is funding
For you
It's been so long
Your economic pressure will be much smaller
But it's not just about the economy
Another one is when you have funding
Especially you may have GRA
Or fellowship
Especially a graduate research assistant
It means you will be assigned to a teacher
To help the teacher plan
Or even do research with the teacher
Relatively speaking, it means that there is a teacher
Will pay special attention to your progress
For you
This is an opportunity to get along with the teacher
You can learn from the teacher
Usually you don't have funding
It's not that you can't find a teacher to work with
But that one
If you have this job opportunity
The level you can understand
Will be much weaker
Even if it's a GTA
You can also
It should be to help my teacher
Teaching assistant
For example, you can follow the class
Then see how the teacher teaches
You can also have a deep connection with the teacher
So no matter what I think
Financial support
I will put it with the student
I will put it in a very high priority
Unless for example
You don't need to think about it
This is of course
You may still choose your dream school
But of course
All the conditions are the same
I still recommend
Financial support school
If it's the school's budget
Some schools give GRA
Some schools give fellowship
GRA
I think it's best for students
Why is it best for students
Some school fellowships
No compulsory
Of course it's a good thing
When students have a high degree of autonomy
Or when students know what to do
You have the autonomy to follow the teacher
Who do I want to follow
You bring the research you want to do
Of course there is a gap in each department
But GRA
It's basically you
If you don't have a very clear direction
In fact, it is a better start for students
Let you have some opportunities
Contact research work
GRA is for
Language will be more demanding
Because you have to face the students directly
Then for example, take homework
Some courses you may have to bring
Or some parts you may need
There is a group discussion time
In terms of language
It becomes a very important thing
You have to be able to get in touch with students directly
That part is
I think it's good
There are a lot of English students in Taiwan
It's not bad
After five years of teaching
The experience of teaching again in the United States
Now Taiwanese students
English is generally much better than when we were in college
So in terms of language
But this is still a
Adapting process
So I mean if there is a choice
I will encourage students to choose GRA
If there is no choice, of course
It's really like this
Then of course
But this is your dream school
I have seen other students
For example
Libraries also provide jobs
Even I have seen students
Work in the school's gym
Administrative office
Of course it's all for me
If you want to study English
Or maybe it's a process
It's too much
Just waiting for you to find a chance
But if you really didn't
If not
This is also a
Out-of-the-box thinking
And of course
In addition to the school
Since everyone is studying in Taiwan
I just want to go abroad
The Ministry of Science and Technology also provides scholarships abroad
The Ministry of Education also has the Ministry of Education
A lot of scholarships
Like Fulbright
Or even if you are already studying in the United States
Then the school funding may be
Especially our social science
It's often read to the end of the world
Even if the school guarantees you four or five years of funding
Maybe I'm still not enough
The school also provides dissertation fellowship
Or some institutions like
The Ministry of Justice
Or NIH or something
There will be a dissertation fellowship
This can all be discussed with the teacher
You need the teacher to support you to apply
Then the teacher will usually be happy
If you have a good idea
Then this will usually provide you
Not only your stipend
It will also provide you some research funding
So you can go
If you can do your research well
If you have such a dissertation fellowship
In fact, it is also a bonus for you
It means you have a good experience
Your process
In fact, your research has been
The evaluation is recognized
I think your achievements are good
So this is also a very good experience
There are many other funding sources
I have suggested my students to apply
Like what female scientists
Some scholarship
That's not a lot
But in the process
You can put it on your CV
Some experience
It's a good thing to have this experience
What you need to pay attention to
The eligibility requirements for each scholarship
Different
Like Fulbright, Monster
Education
They all have requirements
For example, two years of residency
For example, especially Fulbright is quite strict
When you get your degree
You need to go back to your motherland
Then do two years of service
Some of these things you need to understand
If it's like the United States
Government agencies
Some fellowships will require you to have a green card
These things need to be read clearly
What are the requirements for you
I hope the information you send
Do you meet
Even if you have GREGT
Sometimes you can also
See if there are other funds
Can apply to help you
In the process of learning
For example, to supplement your research funding
Some of the costs of attending international conferences
This is also a way to consider
Of course, the most important thing
If you want to study for a doctorate
Usually when you apply for a fellowship
Because again, all humanities
It's not so abundant
If you get admission, it means you have money
That's not the case
You have to hook
Do you want to be considered for funding
This is very important
This goes with what Professor Chen just said
Contact the teacher if the teacher has funding
If the teacher thinks the research is suitable
In addition to the teacher
I want to talk to the department
I think this student is good
We can support him
If the teacher has funding
The first thing that comes to mind is
This student, I have this plan now
Is it possible to find him to take this plan
Like before
We received a student
In fact, he did not get our department's funding
He was very proactive
He wrote very specific
Not a letter
Then he received a response
And very active
Can I schedule a virtual meeting with you
Now everyone is used to virtual meetings
It doesn't take a lot of time
I know there are several colleagues
Including me, I talked to him for half an hour
I know his experience is quite special
Sometimes I feel so active
You also hope that if there is a chance
Give him a chance to try
This Taiwanese student
I want to tell the students
In fact, especially in the United States
In this cultural environment
If you take the initiative
In fact, there is a benefit
Give you a chance to show yourself
Even give you a chance
Let others know you
This is not a bad thing
Of course, it's not just writing an email
Talk to everyone casually
Of course you have to do this
Of course, be fully prepared
Practice well
To do this kind of contact work
Then
So what should I say
Of course, I emphasize that I think
Financial support is very important
But it doesn't mean
You didn't hear it at the beginning
There will be no chance
Speaking of this, I think
It's a very inspirational case
Just now
Mr. Chen said that his university hospital GPA is not very good
It doesn't matter
My first, second, third, fourth GPA is not very good
So I had to study in a research institute
Study a master's degree
That master's degree, of course, is not bad
Turned to the field
I was a psychology major
Turned to criminal studies
You can say a lot
Why do I study this
I have my own internship experience
So it's not that
Master's degree is not an advantage
But that gives you a chance
Demonstrate your academic research
Because college students are usually
But you have a master's degree
You will have more food experience
Even research experience
There may even be a master's thesis
To support
You are not only potential
But you already have some performance
So this is also an idea
Then
OK, wait a minute, I seem to jump
I don't like to jump to the front page
That's probably
A situation like this
Mr. Chen, are we
If you have any questions
If you want to discuss with us
Thank you for the two professors
The sharing is very
A lot of details
Then we want to say
Wei Zhe has put it before
The registration form
If Wei Zhe has given us before
We should all write
I have seen Wei Zhe before
Give me the list
We should all write
In our PowerPoint
Or is there anything we didn't mention
Or did you say that
I didn't notice
I think you've covered a lot of questions
It's very detailed
Thank you
I think I've probably done it
So now
Is there anyone at the scene who has any questions?
If you feel embarrassed to ask
You are also welcome to
I or Yixuan
Or other staff you know
We will help you
Ask the professor
Ok, wait
Mr. Chen
I have a question for you
How do I
How do I get to know you
Ok, Tsingtao Materials
Ok
I'm from Tsingtao, so I'm good
So the first one is
From a review point of view
Is it positive to have an internship at a company?
Yes
But the point is
If you have an internship somewhere
It's useless
The point is
Is there any story in your internship
You can tell
In your SOP
To reinforce
Reviewer's impression
You know you are a
A person who can be a team worker
When you are a team worker
You can also show your leader's talent
If there is such an article
That's definitely a big plus
Is it constructive to let the teacher know you early?
Yes
Usually I think
More approachable
Step would be
You find some
Classes that you think you are better at
Try to
Talk to the teacher
In Taiwan
I don't know if everyone is used to
When you are in class
Encounter some problems
Have you taken the initiative to find a teacher
The habit of asking questions
If not
To
Start to develop this habit
Because I think this habit will let you
Improve very quickly in all aspects
Because when you have a chance
Talk to the teacher
At the time
You will know
The teacher's idea
There is actually a very big difference
The main reason is because
The teacher is actually
On the other side
The side you see
The person who does the operation
You have to talk to the teacher
You have to say
What are the attitudes of these reviewers
What are their focus
Once you have
After this information
You are preparing your materials
Will be more efficient
You don't have to think about it
The materials you prepared
Will be more
Really able to address
What these reviewers want to see
OK
If you say this
If you start doing it in the second or third year
OK
If you say you are off duty
After a year
If you want to go abroad
I think you have to do it now
Another
The method is
If you have a partner
If you have a co-director
There are basically only two recommendations
Let the teachers
Have a good impression of you
Get things done
Give the teacher enough time
I think
The teacher's letter is usually good
OK
I hope this answers
The question of the student
There is a second question
I think it should be
For the recommended choice
Will choose
The same field but not the most familiar
Or two different fields
But a teacher who is familiar with himself
Professor Yang answered that he was more inclined to be two
Can you give me a reason
What do you think
Because like we said
Now apply for a doctorate
Your field
It's impossible for you to be in the same field as now
You usually have to read the doctorate
You will read more professionally
You have to do some changes in the teacher's field
It's more important
You are in college or doing something
What kind of experience do you have
Your performance
Whether it's your class performance
Or your performance with the teacher
Of course, find a teacher who is familiar with you
To be able to recommend you more deeply
Where is your strength
Where is your performance
You find the same field
It's like what Mr. Chen just said
It's better not to write
I don't know how to recommend
You have to be in the same field
But you are not familiar with me
What am I going to write
It's not good for you
It's better to find
What we mean by familiar
It's not that you have a good relationship with the teacher
It's not useful
I often go to the bathroom with the teacher
It's not like that
The teacher may be able to evaluate your personality
But not only personality
Familiar is that you take the teacher's class
I think it's very impressive
For example, you often take the initiative to ask the teacher
For example, after class, go to the teacher to discuss
Or the teacher has a very good impression of your research plan
Or something
It's like this
I don't know if this answer
Mr. Chen, do you want to add
I think Mr. Yang said very well
I think it's the field
Everyone will find it when they get older
Not so important
I use my own example
My university is doing 5G material synthesis
I went abroad to study
When I went abroad to study
Physics and chemistry
When I was a doctor
It's biophysics
And now it's neuroscience
Biophysics
I've been turning my field
So I think the field is actually in
When you do high-level education
It's not that important
Because in the end everyone is together
You need knowledge in all aspects
To do integration
The teacher must really know you
When the teacher is writing a recommendation
Don't let everyone think
The teacher's recommendation is
I'm familiar with you, I'll write you well
Not like this
A strong recommendation must be a
Fact-based recommendation
OK
The teacher will do what you do
Then comment on that thing
From his point of view
OK, the student did this thing
From my point of view
What are the advantages
What is it that I think
It's very suitable for a PhD student
OK, so if you're just
I'm familiar with the teacher
OK, but you don't have any specific evidence
Please write the teacher
It's also difficult for the teacher to write
A strong and powerful recommendation
So don't forget your root
You are actually
The performance is very strong
The teacher knows you
The teacher can follow you
Do further comment
This will be a strong recommendation
OK, you have to let the teacher know
You know so much
What did you do
Then let the teacher extend from this thing
His unique idea of you
These all take time
OK, I hope this answers
The student's question
I believe
For the recommendation
Is to give more detailed information
The next question is from
I want to ask
I'm sorry
I just found out
On the way to the speech
Someone asked two questions
So I want to say because that student
Asked me early
Ask the student first
OK, no problem
Thank you
The first question of this student is
I want to ask the teacher GPA
Every semester in college
About 3.8 to 4
Do you still need to spend the score sheet to write
Or can you not mention it at all in the architecture
See the score sheet or CV is enough
I can mention
If you are 3.8 to 4
Then you must have won a lot of awards
Right
Then you have to write what you have won
Or like this
Then my other one is
If you only have a good GPA
Then there is nothing else to mention in life
Then only mention GPA
Am I talking too much
But of course I hope
In addition to GPA
There are more in-depth questions
Why do I want to do this research
That thing your motivation
It's definitely not because I have a GPA of 3.8
It's definitely not like this
So I think SOP is for you
Do some more in-depth
Introduction
Your own process
How your research experience
How did you get to this step
You can also say because of me
Very enthusiastic
So my grades are very good
Of course you won't take the initiative
My grades are all 3.8 4.0
Everyone will say so
So that's not the point
Then because you introduce you
You can write it clearly on your CV
You will also write it clearly on your CV
But you will mention that there must be a purpose
I want to say because of me
I am very enthusiastic about these lessons
Although I work in full time
I still maintain my grades very well
Bring this thing into a situation like this
Instead of the main thing
My grades are very good
Otherwise, life is a bit sad
I finished writing your SOP in one paragraph
I think I want to add
If GPA
Then
You should be able to
Use GPA as an example
To say that GPA is so good
No one is
Just for the sake of GPA
The reason why your GPA is good
There must be a reason in your heart
Why should I make my GPA so good
The most direct way to think about it
You are really enthusiastic about this science
You can use your GPA as a proof
You can say
What am I particularly interested in
So I spent a lot of time
On this special project
Inventor's Outcome
My GPA is very good
This is also OK
When you are drafting these things
GPA can be used as a fact
You have to explain
Why in this
How to connect this fact
I want to apply for a Ph.D.
Why am I suitable for a Ph.D.
OK
Word is a very
Strong and meaningful fact
If a person
Has been winning the Nobel Prize for so many years
He immediately
Brought out the message
This student is very
Knowledgeable
And very
Persistent
If there are these records
Reviewers will also explain
Why can this student
Continue to perform so well for so long
Right?
What are his characteristics?
It looks very clear
The results of this thing
For students with good grades
That section
Not so critical
It is important
But it won't be a
Breaking point
But when your GPA is not so outstanding
You still hope to be accepted
The story behind
You have to make it clear
I hope I can answer
The question of that student
Wei Zhe
He has another question
The other question of the same student
He is currently with his former intern
Want to let the other person know more
His question is
When talking to the former intern
What do you think about forms?
You have not prepared the terms of the forms
Still want to ask this famous student
This famous student
Maybe 1 month later
Start again
Do you talk about school application?
16 months
Suddenly contacted
suddenly contacted
Go to chat with the teacher later
Should not chat
Should not chat with the teacher later
If the teacher's response is also good, then tell the teacher directly
Of course you can tell the teacher
Something is still being prepared
What is the result
I have to give it to the teacher first
The remaining thing I prepared and sent it to the teacher
It's very clear to tell the teacher
I want to add
My experience
Like talking to me
want
Recommended students
I agree with the recommended students
At the beginning
Will ask the teacher
What is the opinion of the class
OK
I think this is a good point
Just
Demonstrate
You are interested in applying for the class
But you are not so sure
If you ask the teacher about this
You will let the teacher know
This student is likely to apply for the class
Then I can put
You don't have to prepare anything at this stage
Right
But when you do this
Tell the teacher
I think I will
Interested in research
But my knowledge of the doctoral class is very limited
Can you share with me
Do you know the doctoral class
I believe it will be for me
Decide my future life
Has a great help
In this case
You don't have to worry about whether you have prepared your file
You can start from the teacher
Let you know
What do you think about the other side
The teacher will know
This student is likely to apply for the doctoral class
After several talks
Actually
When you ask the teacher for a recommendation letter
The teacher already has enough knowledge
When you really want to apply
Give the teacher enough time to write
Then put your
Grades
CV and SOP to the teacher
OK
Is this OK
Should be OK
If we follow the chat
Answer directly
For example, Carrie asked
Can you ask the teacher directly
Of course
Because sometimes you tell the teacher
I want to apply for the doctoral class
When the teacher is interested in the teacher's work
Usually the teacher will tell you directly
The teacher won't say he's not here
And he won't tell you in the past few years
The teacher won't do this
If you know that the teacher is interested in your work
The teacher will tell you directly
Of course you can ask
In fact, the teacher will answer directly
Teacher Chen asked a lot of questions
I will read it
Some may be answered by Teacher Chen
OK
Let you answer this part
He said
Is leadership important for all fields?
Or is it more emphasis on some fields?
Leadership
I think there is a bonus
If not, it won't matter
Some schools will become very important
I see
I think the most important thing now
If you want to go to medical school
Medical school
Leadership
Everyone has to have
If you apply for a foreign school in Taiwan
I think if it's a general R1 school
Not so much
But if you have
It will be a bonus
I will add one more thing
I think leadership is more important
When you apply for a teaching job
When applying for a teaching job
Leadership will be more important than graduate students
More important
Yes
I agree
Then
He said that if he had known
Can you mention the graduation age first?
How many years can you consider taking the exam?
How many years to intern outside?
I can only say that dreams are sweet
Reality is bitter
Does Teacher Chen want to add anything?
Of course you can mention
But do you want to ask the teacher to write the contract?
The teacher has to sign
How many years do I have to take the exam?
And how many years can I intern?
I think of course you can mention
But sometimes the teacher has to work with you
To know your situation
Or look at your questions
Then you may have to
Or I have a good class
The teacher told me
Don't take classes anymore
You have more credits than college students
Okay, I should be ready to graduate
Everyone has a different
But this thing
At least in our society
I don't know if natural science can sign a contract
I guess there is no way
I think this question
The topic we talked about today
It's a bit irrelevant
Now we focus more on how to apply
This is more like you have already got the admission
You have to find a teacher
Can you ask these questions?
For this question
I think
If you want to find the real answer
In fact, it is not to ask the instructor
But to ask the student of the instructor
You are quite reasonable
Will be closer to
Your actual expectations
Because
To be honest
Usually
You won't get any useful information
If you get the answer
You will say it depends
Because too many things will decide
The timeline of graduation
If the teacher says you have to submit three papers
To graduate
If you find the experiment is stuck
What should you do?
You don't want the teacher to use
Specific papers to limit your graduation time
Right?
So I think this is very professor-dependent
So when you are a non-admission
There are still a lot of questions
How do you choose a teacher?
What should you focus on?
Of course, we didn't talk about it today
I think
If you think
This is really a problem
I think you can participate
Maybe Tara has some other
Webinars
Talk about
How to choose
Advisor
How to have a successful PhD
I think that's a good topic
If you just want
First-layer information
I think
You don't need to ask the teacher
Because you won't get any useful answer
Maybe it's better to ask the students
If it's the same
We skip the advisor part
Because it's also
How to have a successful experience
Guanjing
She said
Not good enough
But you have the paper experience
That's good
But you have the research experience
That's also good
And then outstanding
That's beneficial
And outstanding
I think
Well, I don't think
Everyone is outstanding
If everyone is outstanding
Then no one is outstanding
So I think
What I should do is
How to present my best side
To the reviewer in the best way
I think that's enough
The word outstanding is too heavy
Yeah
You say
You say we receive the best students
Is it outstanding?
I said most of the time it's not outstanding
Right?
But are we looking for outstanding students?
No, we don't actually need outstanding students
OK
We just need a coachable
Then we can
We think he can grow and become a Ph.D.
Under our education system
Then my definition of Ph.D.
Of course
When this student encounters a problem
He can come up with solutions
He can find available resources
OK
Come up with proper hypothesis
Design a proper experiment
OK
Then we can figure out what's going on
That's my definition of Ph.D.
Right?
Do we need to be outstanding?
No, we don't
As long as we are coachable
And know how to do things
Right?
And have basic scientific sense
That's enough
So don't put so much pressure on yourself
To make yourself outstanding
If you want to make yourself outstanding
I'm sorry
We are done with the discussion
Recommendation to find a non-Ph.D.
I think it's OK
Chinese Academy of Sciences is also a research position
If you have any real research experience
And some cooperation
That's definitely fine
I believe we both agree
The point is
Whether you can really evaluate your ability
Your potential
Or your research experience
I think it's this
I think this is what we were talking about
In the presentation
Do you have any other potential you would like to see
Other than your academic achievement
I think this is area-dependent
I guess
In the field of natural science
Do you have any lab experience
What skills do you have
That's important
In the field of social humanities
Maybe
Your social participation
Your social care
Or something like this
Maybe it's important to us
That's a motivation
Especially if I study criminal studies
Some of our students
They are very concerned about social justice
They have some
What kind of group or what kind of leadership
What kind of library
Those things become important
So what I think is
Maybe you can look at different areas
I think this thing is actually quite area-dependent
So I don't think we can deal with it
External funding
You said public funding
There's Director Huang up there
I'd like to thank you
Director Huang
But the question he asked
If he had his own
Department of Education
My last name is Lan
But Professor Yang
I think his question is
If he had his own
Department of Education
I think he's asking
If he brought his own funding
Does it increase
For example, the chance of being accepted by the school
There are two points
That is
The basic answer is yes
Because that means
It's your external recognition
Like we just mentioned
This is your recognition of you
You've been evaluated
You can say I'm the only winner
That means you have potential in this place
But the other part
I saw an experience last year
A student in Taiwan
He applied for a B.S.
And then he applied
Of course, many students want it
But when the economy is more
I know
Some schools say
Since you have money, we won't give you money
So the students feel very depressed
Why should I lie to the school
I didn't bring any money
The school will give me the money
Because the student is quite good
My answer is
I don't think it's necessary
Because he still found
He brought the money
He is still willing to give him the money
It's just that it may not be his first or second choice
My idea is
Of course, when the school's budget is tight
There will be such considerations
How to divide some of the money
To the most students
He would like to say that you have money
To what extent
And what kind of help
The student told me
If I don't bring the school's budget
I still have the school's budget
The school's budget may only be given to you for three years
You may have to measure this yourself
Basically, yes, you are
I think so
Age will not
Age will never be deducted
If the United States asks the age
Age will not be the deduction point
I believe me and Mr. Chen
We are basically like this
Age will not be deducted
If you have work experience
In fact, it is usually a bonus
I want to add
Basically, I agree with Mr. Yang
But if you are
Maybe 40 or 50
If you come out to read PhD
The reviewer may have some concerns
We actually had a lot before
I've been working in the industry for a long time
Because everyone knows
But it turns out that what you bring is different
Like they are actually in the government
After working for more than ten years
He will bring in a lot of food experience
So that means
Usually I guess the research institute
No school will be all
These students came in
But there will be some students like this
Is to increase its diversity
But you will never
But definitely not because of age
He won't see how old you are
Basically this will not happen
When everyone is reviewing your information
Will feel that this person is very interesting
So they will do more discussion
I think it will
At least in
I think there may be this kind of situation in science and engineering
Because everyone expects students
Everyone hopes
Promote young students
Education
In this case, let's say you are very old
I don't know how old I am
Maybe 60 or 70 years old
Some are too old
It's very difficult to move a steel bottle
There may be some problems in actual operation
They may
There will be a more in-depth discussion about this case
I should say this
But basically
The age should not be a problem
The student asked
Your statement of purpose
Do you want to write it very carefully
Like a proposal or a summary
I think this thing
Is
Proposal
Because he has some
If you look at the teacher for too long
There will be no way to endure
To be honest
But if you write too rough
I'm just interested in this
There is no evidence to prove
I think it's too weak
So I think
What are you interested in
If you can support
Why are you interested in this
Instead of just saying that I am interested in this
I think this is a stronger case
Of course, I don't know how to write it like a proposal
Unless the school specifically requires you to write a proposal
I think it's in the middle
I think this is a good practice
Let everyone be able to use two or three
Two or three sentences
Summarize what you have learned
I think it takes time to practice
Like Mr. Yang said
I don't think you can write it too fine
You can't write it too broad
It must be right
We were reminded
That we are already entering the breakout section
And we are over time
It turned out to be 9.30
We are already over time
Let's go to the breakout room first
I'm sorry to bother you
Please help us get to the breakout room
OK
I would like to remind you
Let me remind everyone
We are now divided into two breakout room
If you have any questions
For professors in different fields
You are welcome to
Ask questions in the corresponding field
If there is a question
In the general Q&A session
If it is not answered
You are also welcome to
Ask the professor
In the general breakout room
Ideally, you should be able to
Choose the breakout room
We will leave one or two people
In the main session
To answer some technical questions
If you have any technical questions
You are welcome to let me know
Thank you Wei Zhe
Thanks Wei Zhe
Wei Zhe and Terry were talking about writing sample.
How important is writing sample?
Sociology students want to know how good your English writing ability is.
Sociology students focus on your English ability.
You need to be able to communicate, even write.
It's similar to SOP.
You need to be able to convince people that you have an important goal.
Writing sample wants to know how good your academic ability is,
and how good your English ability is.
The recommended direction is what you have written before.
Of course, writing an essay or diary will be a little awkward.
Of course, it is more focused on academic papers.
Unless you are applying to the Department of Humanities and Sciences,
for example, you are applying for a master's degree in literature.
Of course, it is more related to the field of writing.
Let me explain.
Professor Yang is assigned to the first breakout session.
Professor Chen is assigned to the second breakout session.
Everyone else is assigned to the second breakout session.
You can choose to accept or not accept.
If you choose not to accept, you can go to another session.
Thank you, Professor Chen.
Thank you, both professors.
There is no follow-up after the breakout session today.
You can leave the meeting now.
Please remember that a postgraduate lecture is scheduled on August 28th.
CVSOP will have a free review soon.
Please refer to Sandbox's event.
Thank you.