Hello everyone, welcome to today's lecture on July 31st, Project HIRA. Today is a special event in the summer, and we would like to invite Professor Tu-Ming Feng, who is now at the University of Westlake.
His main research focuses on the theory of quantum physics. He is interested in low-dimensional materials, transport phenomena, and the topological phase of matter.
Although he is a theorist, he also likes to cooperate with experimentalists to realize his theories.
Another important thing is that he is also very interested in scientific education, so he hopes that today's lecture can bring us some gains.
Today's lecture is mainly about the teaching of the scientific diagram and Illustrator.
I hope that in this lecture, we can learn the importance of the scientific diagram, the thinking process, and how to use Illustrator.
Let's give Professor Tu-Ming Feng the floor.
Hello everyone, this is my first time to give a lecture on Project HIRA, so please bear with me if there are any lags.
Today, I will talk about the scientific diagram and how to use Illustrator to realize the scientific diagram.
The scientific diagram is a very big topic, so I will talk about it in detail, but I will try to make it easy for you to understand.
Illustrator is a bigger topic.
At that time, I studied Illustrator for about two months, and I studied two nights a week and three hours a night.
At that time, I studied Illustrator in a classroom opposite Taiwan University, which is a very professional class for advertising students.
At that time, I studied Illustrator in a very professional classroom opposite Taiwan University, which is a very professional classroom opposite Taiwan University.
Basically, you take a picture and use Illustrator to copy it completely.
So we do this kind of practice every week.
We will practice from a small lamp to an apple.
But when I was studying for my Ph.D., I had to draw a lot of pictures.
Especially when I did a lot of scientific education, I had to talk to the general public about some difficult quantum problems or some difficult physics problems.
At this time, you have to draw a good picture to help them.
But this kind of picture only needs some basic functions of Illustrator.
You don't need advanced functions.
So today I will introduce these basic functions and help you get started.
At the end, I will give you some videos.
If you practice according to these videos, you will probably understand how to use Illustrator by drawing five to ten pictures.
Then you can move on from there.
If you have any questions later, you can leave a message in the chat.
So this is my routine today.
I want to tell you first that the science team is very subjective.
Some people think this picture is beautiful, some people think that picture is beautiful.
What I'm talking about today is mainly my subjective opinion and experience.
It's also my experience of helping people change articles for so many years.
So if you have a different idea, you are welcome to leave it in the comments.
I'm sure a lot of people have the same opinion as you.
Okay, the concept of scientific drawing.
When we start talking about the concept of scientific drawing, I need you to start imagining.
How do you draw a picture based on your recent article or article you just wrote?
Usually, as a scientist, you start with a PhD.
First, you will do a lot of research.
After the research, you may write a paper.
After writing the paper, you have to give a speech everywhere.
So when you want to present to others, you mainly write articles and give speeches.
The purpose of these two parts is also very different.
But whether it's an article or a speech, it basically has some components.
That is, there are words, pictures, and charts.
But every article has words, pictures, and charts.
But what kind of scientific article do you think is good to read?
I believe when you read other people's literature, you read other people's papers.
So sometimes you think, why is this article so difficult to read?
Why did I read this paragraph 10 times and still not understand it?
Or why when I went to listen to the slideshow,
there were people who did experiments for 20 minutes and showed you 100 slides.
Then you don't understand what the slides are talking about.
So sometimes you think a certain article is particularly difficult to read, particularly difficult to understand.
Or some slideshows, some presentations, you may fall asleep after 10 minutes.
This kind of thing means that this article or this is not necessarily your problem.
But a lot of times, this presenter or this author,
his article or his slideshow is a bit problematic.
So his slideshow or this article is not so easy to read.
So what is a good scientific article?
There are basically four concepts.
I'll give you a lot of examples of these four concepts later.
Let you understand what these four concepts mean.
Because I've been talking about this for a long time.
Okay, first of all, this article has to be very clear.
You're writing a scientific article.
What is my experiment?
What is my method?
And how did I do it?
What is my final result?
What does this result mean?
And what does that mean?
And how do I get from this meaning?
Go down and do more discussion.
It should be a very clear, very clear thing.
What about your English sentence?
We usually hope it's a simple sentence.
You don't want to use too many complicated sentences.
And then there's a lot, a lot of words.
That's not good.
The simplest thing is that you have to be very clear.
Write down the whole story of the fact you're doing research.
What about this story?
In addition to writing it down very clearly,
You have to have a very, very strict logic between each component.
That's why this one is going to take this paragraph.
There should be a reason for this.
So when you write an article,
It's not going to make people think, oh, I said A, and then I said B.
But there's a jump between A and B.
I don't know why I'm talking about B.
I don't know what A is.
Transition to B.
I'll just say A and B.
That's not good.
This is what you see a lot in a lot of presentations.
The third one is precise.
What kind of experiment are you telling people?
If it's a paper, if it's a presentation,
You can talk very long and wait for people to ask questions.
But if you're a paper, you have to make it very clear.
For example, what are some of your control variables?
What temperature are you doing?
You just have to find a corner in the paper.
It's all about the narrative.
It's all very precise.
What about your inference?
You have to be very, very precise with your words, especially your verbs.
For example, this thing is what I guess.
Or is this thing going to be like this?
Is this cause and effect relationship very absolute?
Or is it 80%?
Is it possible to have a relationship?
Maybe it doesn't matter.
Or is this completely my guess?
This kind of verb theory,
You have to be very precise with your words.
Okay, and then the fourth one.
The important thing is that this article is easy to read.
You can write it very clearly, very precise.
But sometimes it's just not that easy to read.
Or people don't want to read the first time they see it.
For example, some articles are very well written,
Then people don't want to read it.
So you still have to readability.
The first three are basically the skills you have to tell the story.
This is another topic.
What about the picture?
The main thing is to strengthen the readability.
It's beautiful and easy to read.
This is the biggest use of the picture.
So every time you draw a picture,
This picture must add points to your article.
The bonus part is that it makes people feel attractive and want to read it.
Then you can use very clear materials.
What are you studying?
So let's take a look.
A good scientific article or video.
What kind of pictures do you think will be helpful to the audience?
Then I'll try it.
You can all use the speech function, right?
I want you to give me some examples.
What kind of pictures do you choose to put on your paper?
Any ideas?
Let's ask for three volunteers.
Let's check if everyone is listening.
Do you want to talk about it first?
Me?
I think it's important to have a process.
There's a process, right?
Or push down the process.
Like a process diagram.
I think my first picture will be
In my experiment,
It's a more innovative part.
Enlarge it and put it there.
Then the second one is the entire experimental framework.
It's innovative, right?
And then put an experimental framework or process diagram.
And then the last one is the data.
The last one is the data.
Anyone else want to add?
We already have three.
Okay.
Today we're talking about these three pictures, right?
I'm going to talk about exactly these three pictures today.
It's a process diagram.
Because we just talked about simple and easy to understand.
Or beautiful and easy to understand.
What is readability?
Readability is that you want people to want to read.
So we're going to have an innovative picture.
What's the most innovative and different idea in your experiment?
This picture is usually very beautiful.
And then put it on the first page.
Because if you make this picture beautiful and put it on the first page,
It's easy to be selected as the cover of the magazine.
Okay.
So this innovative picture is not the same as your other data pictures.
I'll show you later.
What is an innovative picture?
And then the second one is.
Almost doing experiments or doing a lot of social studies.
Or the theory will have a process diagram.
How do you do this experiment?
How is your instrument exactly layered?
So this is how we have a process diagram.
The process diagram will make it easy for people to understand.
Because if you want to describe your instrument,
But if you use all the text, you'll say,
Okay, I'm going to put A material on top of this material.
C material, B material, C material, 9 cm, D material, 10 cm.
If you're using text, you might have to be naked.
I just said that for a whole page.
You can't describe an instrument well.
But you just need to put a little picture.
He can put everything you just said on top of it.
This is the most powerful part of the picture.
So you think if you talk about a page of things, you can use a picture to replace it.
You have to change that picture.
Even if there's no data in that picture.
But he can replace so many words.
It's worth being put on.
So this is the process diagram.
Okay.
But if you can finish your process in one sentence,
You don't need to put this picture on.
Because it's a waste of space.
And then the last one is the data picture.
You may have been doing experiments for several years.
The most important thing is the data, right?
So we're going to put the data picture in there, too.
So the data picture should be more straightforward.
Okay, so we're going to talk about these three.
So let's take a look at the scientific picture.
Of course, I can tell you what kind of picture it is.
Basically, it's a good picture.
So what kind of picture is a good picture?
What kind of picture is a bad picture?
Let's take a look at it first.
What do you think of this picture?
Let's say this is the current situation of Kobe.
And then some people are not infected.
There are so many people who are not infected.
And then some people are infected with no symptoms.
Some people are infected with symptoms.
Let's criticize this picture.
From the criticism, you can slowly increase your beauty.
What do you think is the biggest problem with this picture?
There are too few people who are infected.
There are too few people who are infected with symptoms.
You can't see it on the picture.
Yeah, you can barely see this, right?
So you can barely see this picture.
What's the purpose of this picture?
I want people to compare and see how much this is.
But this is so little.
This original picture is a failure.
You just can't see it.
Let me talk about some suggestions in the chat.
He said there is no main title.
Does that mean there is no title?
No title.
And Ray said there is no value.
No value, that's right.
And Chi-Chi said...
I'm sorry.
It's ugly. Why do you want an original picture?
You can just use this one.
Okay.
So everyone can see the point, right?
This picture doesn't have any bonus points.
This picture only contains three pieces of information.
Basically, I don't know how many people are infected.
And we don't know their numbers.
So basically, this picture tells us only one piece of information.
There are a lot of people who are not infected.
That's it.
And the sentence I just said can literally be used in one sentence.
One sentence is the end.
Why do I have to spend so much time to say one sentence to end it?
So it's not necessary.
This picture can be removed.
I can just write one sentence.
80% of people are not infected.
15% of people are not infected.
I can just finish this sentence.
So the biggest problem with this picture is that
in addition to not precise and no bonus points,
it shouldn't exist at all.
This is a picture I made up.
But the biggest problem with this picture is that
it shouldn't exist at all.
It doesn't make sense at all.
OK.
So everyone actually has some aesthetics.
Let's take a look at this picture.
What do you think is wrong with this picture?
You can also write it in the chat.
OK.
William said the font is too small.
The font is too small.
That's right.
Usually, very experienced scientists
will know the font size
as soon as they see the article.
Then they will know that the font is too small.
It doesn't mark what each line is.
What is the line of different shapes?
What is it?
That's right.
It doesn't have a legend at all, does it?
OK.
Did you find that the picture below looks empty?
But there is actually data below.
This data is just very close to zero.
Oh.
Did you find that?
Yes, like this picture,
you either make it log,
that is, semi-log 2,
or you have to zoom out as much as possible.
If it's all zero,
you don't have to draw at all.
Just write it all as zero.
That's it.
Yes, everyone has started to catch a point.
Of course, we will...
I usually...
You'll know later.
I'll tell you more in detail later.
For example, this triangle is too small.
It's too small compared to this one.
And then this title.
This is the X, Y axis.
We usually use text.
Try to avoid using delta P or T.
Try not to use symbols.
Try to use good things.
OK.
This picture...
Every picture I'm showing now
can be found on paper.
These are all already published papers.
This is also a paper that has already been published.
What do you think of this picture?
Is it not necessary to be three-dimensional?
Does it want to be three-dimensional?
That's right.
Once upon a time,
when people just started to draw three-dimensional pictures,
they thought it was cool.
So they wanted to draw three-dimensional pictures of everything.
Especially the round cake picture.
Everyone likes to draw three-dimensional pictures.
Then the tree-shaped picture.
Then this kind of picture.
Everyone likes to draw three-dimensional pictures.
But you see, this three-dimensional picture
has no extra points at all.
And it's very ugly.
So everyone must master a trick when drawing pictures.
You have to draw a picture in a simple way.
This is the best way for everyone to understand.
If you draw a 3D picture,
it often has no extra points.
Even if it's a round cake picture,
we also want it to be a two-dimensional round cake picture.
We don't want it to be a three-dimensional round cake picture.
You can be a very beautiful two-dimensional picture.
That's better than a three-dimensional picture.
Because the three-dimensional picture will be a bit oblique.
So it's hard to compare the size of each sector.
Then this three-dimensional picture is even more exaggerated.
It's uglier.
This picture, as you can see, is very strange.
This picture has no data points at all.
And it's empty.
This picture is very, very empty.
Then there is no data point.
It looks like a picture with very little information.
This picture either needs to be removed.
Otherwise, you have to add more data.
Or add more information.
This picture is too empty.
What about this picture?
Let's see if you can see it.
Where is the problem with this picture?
This is also a picture that I often see in my students' reports.
I can't see where the problem is.
But I don't know what this picture is talking about.
This picture is more professional.
The biggest problem with this picture is the error bar.
The error bar should be visible from top to bottom.
Especially the black one.
Can you see these two sides?
You can hardly see these four black errors.
Then William said the unit.
Yes, there is no unit.
They didn't tell you how high this is.
What does it mean to be high?
And what is the unit of this activity?
This is also a very good point.
So this error bar is a lot of experiments.
Especially social science.
It's a lot of experiments.
There was originally an error bar.
You shouldn't go up.
Because you want to talk about two things.
What does it have to do with?
Or you have to compare two things.
One is high, one is low.
You have to call the error bar.
You can make an effective comparison.
So the error bar is what people do most often.
The point where the tree map is forgotten.
Then the error bar must be very clear.
Be sure to come out.
Don't use it like this.
You can't even see it in black.
This is a similar problem we just talked about.
It's a tasteless 3D.
Look at this 3D.
There is no bonus.
There is no bonus at all.
Below this is even worse.
So we've seen a few pictures now.
Everyone has an opinion.
Everyone probably knows how ugly the scientific map is.
When you're drawing.
When you finish the picture.
You have to ask yourself.
Is your picture so ugly?
And then if you think it's ugly.
You have to improve it a little bit.
How can it be more beautiful?
Is there enough information?
OK.
There's another big problem.
Some pictures.
After it's done.
It's just that when you zoom in, it's a little bit of a blur.
So this kind of blurred picture.
We'll try to avoid it.
Because a lot of people now.
Some people may want to look at the details.
I want to zoom in as much as I can.
If you blur it.
It's hard for people to look at the details.
So we want all the pictures.
Try to use the amount of pictures.
But this is not absolute.
I can only say that 80 to 90 percent of the pictures.
It could be the amount of pictures.
But.
There are still a lot of pictures.
They can't make the amount of pictures.
For example, like this picture.
For example, you take your experiment.
Oh, that picture.
You can't make the amount of pictures.
You have to.
It is what it is.
You have to put it on like this.
So you put these pictures in.
It's okay, too.
You just have to make sure it's high enough.
It's more than 300 dpi.
OK.
That's the best thing about illustrator.
It can make all your ideas.
The amount of pictures.
So.
Go to the data visualization.
It's just that he has some of these.
It's basically.
You have a data.
You have to think about this data first.
What story do you want to tell?
And then how do you get this data to attract people?
It's you.
Um, I'm basically a little outlier.
But these are the ones we just talked about.
It's this data.
He must love it.
It looks beautiful and interesting.
Or a very amazing fact.
Or a very innovative idea.
Or this data.
To be able to tell you what the experiment I did is.
Show it to you very clearly.
OK.
Uh, or.
Some people will put some innovative pictures.
Or some.
Pictures that attract people's attention.
Right?
These pictures can reinforce some arguments or opinions.
For example, I'm going to talk about a point of view later.
Uh, that point of view.
I might need a picture to support it.
This picture is not necessarily my data picture.
It's not necessarily my intention.
But I can draw a process picture.
Or go and talk about my more.
More, uh, more profound.
A more powerful one.
A point of view.
OK.
So these are all things you might be able to put on the map.
It's just that you're going to put it on the map.
But this is a very good example.
It's just that NASA is making a beautiful picture.
It's still very good.
Look at how beautiful this picture is.
I'm not in this field at all.
But when I look at this picture, I know what it's talking about.
He's talking about the carbon dioxide level before us.
It's been fluctuating all the time.
But it's about less than 100 years from us.
He just rushed up like this.
So what's the conclusion of this picture?
It's about the million years.
It's about the carbon dioxide of our atmosphere that's never been above this line.
Boom.
This picture.
Just how clear it is.
He has data.
And then.
It just tells you.
It's just that you don't need to read a single article after you've read it.
You know what it's about.
This is a great picture.
It's a picture that's perfect for the presentation.
Or if your article is to be published in a magazine or in a school.
This is a picture of what you're going to put in those places.
And you just need to put this picture in.
Yeah, well, look at the background. It's beautiful, too.
It's the background of the earth and the outer space.
The background of the atmosphere.
It's just that it makes you think.
OK.
So, like this picture, it's a very good, very good picture.
This picture is also very good.
This is the year.
And then the center axis is the solar radiation on the left.
The temperature is on the right.
And then you look at it and it's got an average value.
The average value of 11 years.
It's got this one in the hospital.
It's very clear at a glance.
Right?
And then he's got, uh, he's got his, uh, uh, unit, like this.
And then this picture, uh, there's one more thing that's worth it.
What everyone likes is his, uh, the temperature is red.
And then this solar radiation is yellow.
It's the temperature. You'll feel hot.
So you'll instinctively use red.
And then the solar radiation is yellow because it's like the sun.
So I'm going to use yellow.
So, you know, when you're choosing colors, you're going to be able to choose colors.
The easier it is for the reader to think about it, the better it is.
And then you look at these two pictures.
These beautiful pictures are usually black background, right?
This kind of black background picture, you don't usually put it on paper.
But I like it very much.
Because it's just easy to catch.
It's just catching.
It's your audience's attention.
It's just that when you see black and then there's a bright one, you're going to want to pay attention to it.
It's just that it's psychological.
It's just that everyone will be like this.
So you're going to see this amazing picture.
It's usually black background.
And then you're going to think it's cool.
So this is a very good example.
This is also a very good memory picture.
Okay, so this picture looks like it's talking about global warming.
But it's just that this is a picture I picked up from the Internet.
So it's not that he's a little bit of a realist.
So we just talked about these things, right?
What I'm talking about above is more like a sense of beauty.
It's just that you have to keep writing articles.
And then when you're criticized or you criticize someone, you develop a sense of beauty.
So what do you actually do when you're writing a paper?
Basically, you want to use as little ink as possible.
So that the reader can get the most ideas in the shortest time.
So you have to try to make your articles as short as possible.
So at the beginning, you might be the first one to do it.
It's a lot of pictures, a lot of words, a lot of tables.
But you have to shorten it as much as you can.
So you have to shorten it as much as you can.
It's just two or three articles.
It's just that you have to shorten it slowly.
And then every time you review it, you have to look at it.
Can I use a picture as a substitute for this paragraph?
Is this paragraph really necessary?
Or can I move on to the next page?
So you have to keep reviewing this thing.
And then in the end, your very messy ideas will turn into a beautiful paper.
It just looks very clean.
And then every space, every space in your paper will be used in a huge way.
So what's the content?
What content do you use to present when you're writing an article?
You might start writing when you're writing an article.
There are some points.
Oh, what's the instrument?
You'll make a big bar first.
When you're making your big bar, you'll find that this part.
I want to make it clear in words, but it's very difficult.
I don't know how to make it clear.
If your instrument is like the instrument or the experiment, it's usually hard to make it clear, right?
That kind of thing that's hard to make clear.
You can choose to use a picture as a substitute.
For example, the first picture is like this.
Or the experiment's instrument picture is like this.
But if you have an instrument picture, your instrument is very simple.
It's just a layer of shit.
Then you don't have to.
You just say, oh, I've got a layer of shit.
You don't have to draw a shit over there.
so
It's got to be important, but it's hard to make it clear in words, and then you get a picture.
So this is the picture.
The second one is an effective and supportive point of view.
You have to write your argument when you're writing an article, right?
Someone says, I'm measuring this, this, this, and I found something, something.
So when you say that, you need something to support your argument.
What supports your argument, supporting your argument, is your data and your experiment.
How do you get your data and your experiment to support your argument?
Basically, you have to tell people your data, but there's a lot of data, a lot of numbers flying around.
At this time, you can also take a picture of the experiment.
That picture can clearly support your argument.
When you first started making the picture, you might have a bunch of different pictures.
You have to pick which pictures will be in the article.
You just put it up.
If you don't talk about it in the article, you don't put it up.
Or you don't put it up at all.
And then the third one is the third picture, which is what Jason just mentioned.
This is an innovative picture, which is what you usually find difficult to make clear.
It has your data arguments.
This is the only two in the general paper.
But when you want to get a better start, or when you want to face a wider audience.
And then when your article is very important.
You need to have a picture that can quickly make people understand what you're best at.
Where's your paper?
Is it a quick read of your conclusion or your logic?
Or is it your most innovative part?
This is an innovative picture.
Like the two NASA pictures I just showed you.
It's the third one, the innovative picture.
It's the innovative picture, or the second one.
But it's a library.
It has a lot of things and a background.
So it's basically a mix of two and three.
Like this picture.
Even if we're not in the same industry, we can see the conclusion right away.
This picture is amazing.
This kind of picture usually takes a long time to change.
Each font, font, even the color and width have to be changed back and forth.
This kind of picture is usually very important.
If you have any questions, you can leave them in the chat.
I'm talking a little fast.
If you want me to speak slower, you can talk to me.
These three pictures are also pictures on this Nature.
The first one is data.
The second one is the process.
The third one is the most important conclusion.
For example, what is a neuron cell?
Release to another neuron cell.
What are the receptors?
This is the conclusion picture.
Look at this picture.
It's not your process, it's not your data.
It's just a story.
But this story, you can actually replace it with a couple of words.
In the text.
But he still chose to draw it.
Because this idea is very important.
You want the audience to catch this idea.
So they draw this picture.
Then the whole piece of paper may only put this picture.
Or put this picture on the first page.
This data picture, Illustrator can help.
The second and third are the strengths of Illustrator.
Draw this beautiful picture.
This is the strength of Illustrator.
This is the drawing process.
We just talked about it a little bit.
Basically, you have to prepare a picture.
Prepare a good picture.
Ask yourself some questions.
I can put the slides up later.
Because the content I prepared today is actually more than an hour.
So I want to talk about something.
I think you might be more interested.
But if you want to slow down in some places.
If you talk a little more, you can write it in the chat.
Then we can go over.
Basically, you have to prepare a picture.
The idea of a picture is the most important.
You make sure what to do with this picture.
Then you use the draft draft first.
After you are sure to use this picture,
The second thing you should do is to study the journal you want to submit.
The style of this journal.
For example, how big is his file?
How big is the font?
What font?
He might have some regulations.
Then you use your data.
Because you are using MATLAB, Mathematica, or some data processing programs.
Or Excel.
When you use them to export, try to follow the standard output.
The better you export here.
The easier it will be to beautify it in the end.
If you export it badly.
It may take one or two hours to beautify it.
To handle a picture.
So when you export, it's best to try to follow the standard output.
Then the third is that you get it all done.
Then we start to draw.
Then we start to beautify.
This is the point of beautification.
For example, how much font do you want to use?
What kind of picture do you want to use?
I probably made a list here.
How to choose the color?
I just made a list here.
Does anyone want to go over?
Or we can start talking about Illustrator.
This table is what I prepared for everyone.
When you export this picture.
Try to use the same amount of pictures.
There's nothing you can do.
If it's too big, just use JP.
Just use a normal picture.
Try to use the same amount of pictures.
Do not mess with the picture.
Then the third is that I think the average person may have not noticed.
When do you use the line picture?
When do you use the column picture?
The line picture is used in.
When your X and Y are continuous.
Then you have to show people a trend.
If you don't want to show people a trend.
You just want to compare some of the paper.
Don't use the line picture.
Don't use a little bit of the line picture.
Don't connect it.
Don't use a little bit.
You have a line picture.
You must be able to tell people.
This thing grows up.
Grow down or have a pit.
You must have a thought like this.
Then you use the line picture.
You have to say.
There are so many people without infection.
There are so many people with infection.
You are a project, a project, a project.
This is the column picture.
Then the opposite is still.
If you want to tell people a trend.
You can say I measure this thing.
Get one measure.
The second one gets two.
The third one gets three.
I want to show a trend.
You may want to say I only measure three points.
Can I use the column picture?
The column picture will let people naturally.
These two things are related to X and Y.
But the column picture won't.
Then a picture is best to convey one to two concepts.
But you have to convey it very clearly.
Don't squeeze four or five in a picture.
Four or five pictures or four or five concepts.
There are too many lines.
I don't know what I'm reading.
Then the font size.
You can adjust it yourself.
Don't use less than 7pt.
You can't see the printout of the form.
Then I want to talk about the complete.
Some ideas are posed with images.
Don't burn this thing.
It is necessary to have a data.
But it's not important enough.
Usually we don't use the data to make another folder.
If you really want to show a folder,you can put this into the directory.
But you don't need to show this big database with a folder.
If you really want to show this big database with a folder.
Even if you have been programming better for a few years,
people want to give others a
Try to detoxify.
Humans don't use light yellow or yellow.
Don't use light yellow or yellow.
The simpler the color, the better.
Red, blue, green are simple colors.
If there is only one color to choose, choose blue.
After you finish this color,
It's best to print it out with a black and white printer.
After printing it out, you may find that
Oh, I might have three lines.
Then I use different colors.
This is not good.
You'd better choose three colors.
Then print it out.
You can see it clearly even if you print it out with a black and white printer.
Or you can just use different colors for data points.
Because some people are red and green blind.
So they can't tell the color.
So if you don't know the color before you die,
You have to use different shapes for data points.
So you see a lot of experimental schools
What circles, triangles, squares, to distinguish.
So if you basically make my outline,
The picture won't be too bad.
If you want to make it very beautiful,
The easiest way is to refer to the paper you like in the journal.
It follows its style.
For example, how much size it is, how much you use.
How thick the line is.
I'll share with you some of the sizes I use later.
If you like it, you can just take it away.
I have a question here.
Can I ask?
I see a lot of articles
And there will be insets in the picture.
There may be another example in one corner.
Is this picture good?
Or what is the situation?
This is a very good question.
Insets are very difficult to draw.
Because you like to squeeze your inset to show your face.
So the more inset you have, the more space you have.
So let me draw something simple.
Okay.
I can't go forward so much...
What?
Did you see it?
I didn't see what I was drawing.
No.
You didn't see it either.
I'll try again.
I have a picture like this, right?
For example, I want to put a picture on this empty space.
Then I can put a picture like this, and my line may look like this.
If my line looks like this,
if my line looks like this,
I have a blank space here.
I feel, you know,
I have something I want to explain.
That little thing may not be so important
I need to put a picture of myself.
I just want to mention it a little bit.
I can put it right here.
You can use this picture.
But if your picture
It's not very good, it might look like this.
But you still have a small insert,
You think it could be added points.
What can you do?
You can make this picture into a semi-log.
You can make it a log.
Then this will be squeezed over here.
Then you will have a little bit of space to do it.
But don't make it too exaggerated.
It's a balance.
This is a good little trick.
If you can't squeeze this picture in anyway,
If this picture is important to you,
You can consider combining this picture with other pictures.
I'm not going to box these two pictures.
I'll delete these two photos.
I don't need to box.
And then I'll use insert to take the picture out.
And then the next picture will be a little bit smaller.
But that's not a bad thing.
It's not 50-50, it's possible to be 60-40.
It's not too bad because they're 210mm blocks.
My teacher read it first.
The biggest problem with the inside picture is the size of the font.
You use 11 for the X and Y.
The convention is 11 for the X and Y.
It's your tick, 1, 2 ,3, 4.
Your tick is a smaller two font.
It will become 9.
3 is 11, so it's 9.
You use 9 for the X and Y.
The numbers 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7,
the numbers 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7,
become 7?
Because we follow them.
The smallest ones become 7.
So it becomes very crowded
because you have to use the smallest font size.
Sometimes you may want to explain
some things,
but you may find that
you can't fit in your words.
But don't be discouraged.
When you do Incept,
it's very crowded,
so you have to make some space.
But with Incept,
the numbers inside are already 7.
So you have to think about
how to make it
less crowded.
Sorry,
I just thought of another question.
Am I asking too many questions?
No, no.
When I write articles,
I often encounter a problem.
For example,
the editor may tell me
that the order of
reference to figure
in the article is wrong.
For example,
I may write
and reference figure 1,
and then reference figure 2B,
and then reference figure 2A,
and so on.
But sometimes
it's just a problem with the layout.
I think this layout is better.
It's better to show it on the layout.
But when you're writing,
it's better to show it in another direction.
Do you have any suggestions?
Okay.
This problem
is caused by the layout.
When you encounter this problem,
you may be very reluctant
and may not know
how to change the layout.
Or how to move it
to make it better.
This problem
is caused by the layout.
Basically,
you have to go back
to the first change.
Most of the time,
you can't make it better.
When you start writing,
you have to try to avoid this problem.
How do you avoid this problem?
When you write your article,
your logic should be one line.
Sometimes,
when we write articles,
when we write A,
we want to talk about B,
and we want to talk about C.
But if your article is one line,
for example,
I talk about A to B first,
B to C,
C to D.
Or when I do the experiment,
I talk about a point first.
I only talk about one material.
Then I may talk about another material later.
If you do this,
you can put all the pictures of this material
in a small box.
Then you won't have this cross-reference problem.
So your problem is
the logic of writing.
You need to change it at the beginning.
If you need to change it at the beginning,
you can avoid it later.
Thank you for your good question.
If you have any questions,
you can ask.
This is also informal.
I hope to help you
if you have any questions.
Next, I will talk about Illustrator.
How many people have used Illustrator?
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight.
Nine.
Ten.
Eleven.
Twelve.
Thirteen.
Fourteen.
Fifteen.
Sixteen.
Illustrator's philosophy
is a little different
from other software.
If you download Illustrator,
you will see the interface like this.
The middle is your drawing board.
On the right,
there are tools you often use on the left.
For example,
you can add text,
add a frame,
and so on.
On the top,
after you choose a tool,
for example,
I choose the first arrow.
After I choose the arrow,
there will be some tool details on it.
This detail will change
according to the tool you choose.
For example,
when I choose the arrow,
I will choose a frame.
When I choose a frame,
I will adjust the thickness of the frame,
the color of the frame,
the sharpness of the frame,
the roundness of the frame,
the style of the frame,
or the transparency of the frame.
You can basically find it here.
If you can't find it,
it may have this function.
But you have to go to the list
and look for it carefully.
On the right,
there are some advanced tools.
The tools on the right
are the tools I often use.
This one is personalized.
Usually, when you get it,
there may only be one or two.
As you use it for a long time,
you can drag the tools you often use
to this side.
For example,
I often use this one for building.
Or adjust the line.
There are also some colors for drawing.
I often put them here.
This is an advanced tool list.
Okay.
There is a question here.
Yan is asking
in the chat room.
Do you recommend any open source software
corresponding to Illustrator?
No.
Because I always use
school software.
I always use school software.
In the chat room,
someone mentioned Inkscape.
It seems to be an open source software.
Someone mentioned
that it seems to be
the open source of Illustrator.
Oh.
What is it called?
I can see it later.
Okay.
When you open
Illustrator,
I think you should talk about its logic first.
Then you will know.
The logic of Illustrator's drawing
is like this.
If you have never used this software,
you are drawing in
Illustrator or
Powerpoint.
For example,
I draw a star.
It is a star.
You can't do anything
to this star.
For example,
I want this star to have one less corner.
But I want this star to be a hexagon.
I can't do this.
And this star,
I might want it not to be so fat.
I might want it to be a little thinner.
What about this picture?
The star on the left
doesn't give you any wiggle room.
You can't do this.
But in Illustrator,
when it reads a star,
it reads a star like this on the right.
Have you ever seen this dot?
The square of this entity.
This dot is called an anchor.
This is a dot.
This protruding thing
will have a dot.
The dot is connected
by a straight line.
Illustrator reads this picture
and it reads a lot of dots.
These dots
will be connected by a straight line.
These dots will be connected by a straight line.
But you may not want these dots,
but want a curved line.
That's why you-
hm.
That's why you
have these dots.
This dot is basically
that line doesn't want a straight line.
I want it to curve.
So when you draw a circle,
for example, for a circle not a straight line
but a curved line,
you can pick up this dot
and draw a curve.
I'll show you later.
At this time,
there will be two handles.
These handles
will control the curve of the line.
So you can think about
how we usually draw.
Basically, it's all this idea.
You draw a dot,
connect the dots with the lines,
and then adjust the curve of the line.
Okay.
That's it.
Today,
we're running out of time.
I was going to-
There's a lot more, right?
Otherwise,
I-
This is-
I found this on the Internet.
Basically,
I'm going to draw a picture for you to see.
And then-
Okay.
I'm going to draw a picture
for you to see.
And then,
I can give you these tips
in PDF format.
You can understand it by looking at it directly.
For example, how thick the line should be.
You can look at it directly.
And how to start learning.
Okay, no problem.
I'll draw a picture for you to see first.
This way, you'll have more ideas.
Okay.
This picture is-
I found this picture on the Internet.
I drew this picture.
It took me about an hour
to reproduce this picture.
Okay, so look at this picture.
If you zoom in, it's a little blurry.
And then the next one,
I used Illustrator to draw the picture.
Look, it's very clear when you zoom in.
Okay.
So how do I draw these pictures?
Okay, let me-
Okay.
Let me-
Let me see how I can
zoom in.
Okay.
Let me-
This is what I drew yesterday.
Okay.
So, look at this picture.
I drew it one by one
the way I told you.
So,
in this picture,
do you have any-
For example,
I want to draw this tube.
Okay, I want to draw this tube.
Two circles plus a bar.
How do I draw this picture?
Okay, let me think about this picture.
This picture is basically two circles plus a bar.
So I'm going to draw two circles first.
First,
I'll- Okay.
This is my tool, right?
I'm going to choose something.
Okay, I'll choose this one.
This is a square, right?
Okay.
So this square,
I'm going to click on this square again.
Or there's a little triangle below.
I don't know if you can see it.
Okay, just click on it.
My computer is a little slow right now.
Okay.
And then this picture can-
This little tool can tell you,
okay, you want to draw a square,
but I don't have any other squares to choose from.
For example, I have a circle,
and then I have this kind of smooth
or a star, and so on.
Okay, I'm going to choose a circle now.
So I'm going to choose a circle now.
Is this how I draw it?
Okay, so it's hard for me to say
that I can draw a real circle, right?
I just want to draw a real circle.
So how do you draw a real circle?
You can press Shift.
And then pull.
This circle must be a real circle.
There are some shortcut keys in Illustrator.
These shortcut keys will suggest you to memorize
this circle.
Okay, so I have a circle now.
So I'm going to-
I want another circle below,
so I'm going to draw another circle.
So I drew a circle,
and then I want to use a square
to connect them together.
Right? Okay.
Basically, I have this picture.
But this picture looks ugly.
I want these colors to be right.
For example,
I want this to be black.
What if this is black?
What I'm drawing now is this object.
Okay, I'm going to choose this black.
And then I can choose-
You see,
this thing,
there are some things you can do.
The first one is the color inside.
I choose black inside.
Okay, and then there's no color outside.
What about this object?
I can also choose black inside.
And then there's no color outside.
What about this object?
I can also choose black inside.
There's no color outside.
I can also have three boxes
and do this thing together.
Now I've drawn
a tube like this.
I want them to be a little bit symmetrical.
Because I'm just drawing a circle
and then I'm drawing a bar inside.
It might not be very symmetrical.
We might want it to look better.
When you think about this thing,
Illustrator does a very intuitive job.
You just pick these three things up
and look at what you can do
with this object on top.
You'll see Align on top.
How do you align it?
You want to have two objects
aligned in the middle.
You can align it like this.
Now these three things are
beautifully aligned together.
I'm going to add text on top later,
so I want these three things
to be connected together.
I want these three objects
to be connected into one object.
If I want to do this,
I can come here and choose
Reshape Builder.
It reshapes your object.
I'm going to click on this.
I'm going to move the cursor
to the first one and then move it down.
Look, the first one and the second one
are merged together.
The third one is merged together.
The fourth one is merged together.
The fifth one is merged together.
When I let go,
this whole thing becomes an object.
I'm not going to draw a circle
and then the shape of the circle
becomes exactly the same.
I'm going to choose a color.
I'm going to choose this color.
This color is ugly.
Now I can choose this object.
Now I've created a shape.
After you've created a shape,
you want to fill it in.
You want to fill it in.
How do you fill it in?
You can draw another one,
but it's hard to make it
exactly the same.
So what we're going to do
is copy this thing.
If we can cut it off
and paste it on,
it'll be exactly the same.
How do I cut this thing off?
When I want to cut this thing off,
I'm going to do some cutting
on this whole object.
Do you remember
the Illustrator logic I just talked about?
There are two little dots here.
The first thing you need to learn
when you learn Illustrator
is to select an object
and then you can do some settings
on this object.
The second thing you need to learn
is to select the most basic element
in this object.
So when I click on this little dot,
look at my object.
I don't know if you can see it.
It's a little small.
There's a dot here.
If you can't see it,
you can tell me in the chat.
I've got a lot of dots.
These dots are the dots.
I don't need this dot anymore.
Because I only need the bottom.
I can delete it.
You see, my picture is gone.
So I can edit it directly.
So I've got an element.
I don't need the dots.
There's a trouble with this little dot.
If it's deleted, it's gone.
What do I do now?
I canamazit these dots.
The dots I need turn blue.
This allows
press down key.
Look, it becomes shorter.
Now I can Add a different color.
Now I move it.
When I move it...
Why is it not aligned?
Now I can move it.
When I move it...
When I was modifying it,
I accidentally made it smaller.
Now I can move it.
When I was modifying it,
I accidentally made it smaller.
When I move it...
Now it looks like this.
I can modify it a little bit more.
I want to make sure these two things are aligned.
Now I have a tube.
It's not perfect at the bottom.
You can modify it a few more times.
You can make it bigger and modify it a few more times.
Now I can copy this.
Now I have a tube.
If you need to,
I can show you how to make it.
If you want to learn how to do this,
you can use that.
Now I'm going to draw a star.
draw a star
There are five legs on this star.
I could just make it six legs.
I could just press the up and down buttons to make it have more legs.
Or I could press the down button to make it have less legs.
Illustrator has a lot of shortcut keys.
You basically have to practice to remember.
For example, I'm using this leg now.
And this is my new star, right?
I think this star is too sharp.
I don't want it to be so sharp.
I want it to be round.
How do I make it round?
I can choose this.
I'm going to use this to change the inner components of this star.
We just talked about the dots.
The dots tell you that there must be a dot on these dots.
I'm going to change the curve of this line.
I'm going to pull this circle.
See if my star is getting fat and round.
It's getting fatter and rounder.
For example, you don't want this star to be symmetrical.
You want this leg to stand out.
You can also use this to choose.
For example, I want these two dots to stand out.
I'm going to choose these two dots and pull them out.
I might want these two dots to be particularly sharp.
So I'm going to change the curve, right?
At this time, you can also use this to choose this dot.
I'm going to zoom in on this dot.
After you click on this dot, do you see this line up here?
This line is called the handle.
This handle is to control the curvature.
See if this is particularly sharp now.
Or you can make a big one like this.
I'm going to zoom in now.
So when you look at someone else's picture,
and you draw a picture,
you're thinking,
which basic shape can I start to transform?
Sir, we have a question here.
This is a question about
whether the picture will be set to the size of the picture you want first,
or do you draw it first and then set it?
Another audience member also said,
I'm also curious about how to integrate real photos into pictures.
OK.
Integrate real photos into pictures,
is it pulling a picture in?
I think that's what it means.
For example, if he has a picture of a lab device,
how do you integrate it in?
OK.
I'll talk about the first one first.
The first question is very, very good.
I think this is a trick that only those who are doing this will know.
I'll open one first.
I'll open another one.
This is a picture of my experiment.
I got this picture from something like Excel.
And then I dragged it over,
and then I beautified it like this.
OK.
In the process of beautifying,
you see,
will I make the painting board the size I want?
I won't.
There are a lot of reasons why I don't do this.
Because this painting board is white.
When you're painting,
if you need something to...
For example, when I'm painting now,
I might have done something first.
For example, I made a star.
I'm going to use it later.
But if my painting board is very small now,
then my star...
For example, I can change it now.
I can change the painting board directly.
OK.
For example, I can change the painting board.
If my painting board is very, very small at first,
You see, when my painting board is very small,
the problem is that my object will be squeezed onto the painting board.
Then it will be a little hard for me to see clearly.
Because the background is gray.
Usually white is easier to paint.
So what do I do?
I usually use a very large painting board.
And then?
For example, I want to deal with this data now.
Suppose I haven't finished this data.
I still want to deal with this data.
I want to add something.
OK.
I can put this...
I can put this thing next to it first.
And then I'll draw something first.
I'll draw...
I'll draw the last thing I need.
Where is it?
Here.
Suppose I want to put this last picture on a two-column paper.
So I'm going to put it on a...
Wait a minute.
Black. OK.
This is...
This is the last thing I'm going to put on the paper.
I'm going to put a picture in this space.
Usually, if the paper is a two-column...
Wait a minute. I'm going to make it bigger.
OK.
I'm going to choose this square now.
I'm just going to pull a square.
And then I'm going to adjust the width and length of this square.
That's the width and height of the square.
I usually use 3.75 inches for a two-column paper.
Let me see.
I wrote it all down below.
How do you draw it?
3.75 inches.
If it's a double column, it's 3.75 inches.
If it's a single column, it's 89 milliliters.
OK.
I'm going to use 3.75 inches for this thing.
That's it.
OK.
And then I'm going to draw a picture.
I'm going to put this picture...
I'm going to put my data picture in.
And then I can adjust this data picture.
OK.
For example, I want it to be smaller.
Because I want to put another picture next to it.
I want it to be smaller.
Like this.
OK.
Then I'll put a picture here.
And then...
And then I'll put another picture here.
You'll think it's a little crowded.
And then you might have to make each picture smaller.
Anyway...
You just put this grid...
I drew this grid as your final size.
And then you put your data in first.
And then you can start to adjust it inside.
For example, you can change this word.
I can add a text here.
I can re-enter the text.
And then I'm sure this text is 11PT.
For example, number.
I'm going to pull this over here.
Like this.
You know what I mean?
All your drafts are placed outside this box.
And then you put your final product in this box.
And then you just do it in there.
OK.
So when I'm done with this picture.
This picture is already very beautiful.
OK.
All done.
I'm going to export this picture.
At this time, you put the things outside.
For example, there may be some squares outside.
You delete all these things.
OK.
Delete all the objects outside.
After deleting it, keep this box.
This box can't be deleted.
Keep this box.
And then turn the outer frame of this box into a transparent one.
Transparent.
And then at this time, you export it again.
OK.
At this time, you can save as.
For example, I'll save it as an EPS.
Like this.
Example.
For example, test1.
And then when you export it, you have to choose a blank background.
Choose transparent.
OK.
And then I'll export it.
At this time, the picture I exported will be exactly.
Just right.
This frame.
This white frame.
It's just right.
It's the frame you want to put on the paper.
This width is just right.
3.75 inches.
This is the bottom of this piece of white.
When you put the whole picture on it.
You won't.
Because sometimes you use latex.
Or when you put the picture in the text.
You'll zoom in.
Because you want it to look pretty.
So when you zoom in.
The font of that text.
It's going to zoom in with you.
The shape of the picture is going to zoom in with you.
So maybe when you were drawing the picture.
What are these fonts?
11pt.
It looks very good.
But because you zoom in.
Maybe put it in the article.
Hey, this 11 font.
Zoom in.
Maybe it becomes 7.
Then you can't see it.
It's almost invisible.
Hey.
So when you use Illustrator.
I usually divide my page into two sides.
OK.
And then the first thing I do.
Is to put my last.
The size of this picture to be output.
Draw it out with a frame.
And then the width of this frame can't change.
But the length can change.
For example, I want to add two more pictures.
It might get longer.
Yeah.
And then I use the right side as my drawing board.
And then what am I going to draw?
What words do I write?
I'll take care of the right side.
And then I'll stick it up here.
And then slowly align.
Yeah.
And then after the alignment.
You just have to make sure there's nothing out there.
And then this frame at the end.
If you make it transparent.
Your output will be the whole one.
It's just like this.
You won't be.
There's more white on the side.
Or the size doesn't fit.
What you want is exactly.
What you draw is exactly what you want.
Does that answer your question?
Yes.
I was answered.
But I don't know if the actor was answered.
OK.
So you didn't know how to use the animation board at first.
The animation board is usually for people who do art.
They need to be.
When they're printing, there's a problem with the edge.
So they're usually the ones who understand the animation board.
But I think this is better.
And what's the harm in moving the board?
You know, like, let's say I'm going to put my board.
Make it the size I want.
This is a big disadvantage.
For example, I guess I will.
Well, I was going to say, okay, I'm just.
Yeah, you know, all right.
My eyes are good.
I can see black and white.
I'm going to use this direct.
Is there any problem with the board?
Suppose I just made a drawing on the board.
I've done it.
And I don't have this frame.
I just drew, drew, drew, drew, drew, drew it out.
Ok, I'm done.
I just want to say, all right.
This is a.
This is the animation board that I want to output.
At this time, I'm.
At this time, I'm going to save.
And you can see where the difference is.
Okay, have you seen the difference between this test and this test?
Look at this test.
Is this the case where the grid is wider?
Is the grid of this test 2 getting narrower?
And then you see if this grid is getting narrower.
This distance is also a little wider.
So why is that?
Why isn't it?
Look at how wide my panel is here.
How does it look different from my final output?
Why is this so wide? Why is this so narrow?
On the contrary, if I used this grid at the beginning,
You see, this is so wide, this is so wide.
Right?
So why is this?
This is because when we're saving,
Because this is an image.
So your program will use
Illustrator will use the simplest way to save your image.
That is to say, you see,
If I frame all these tools,
You see, my tool actually only takes up so much of the panel.
I didn't use the whole panel.
So your computer will be very smart.
It will choose this smallest frame.
The space you actually use.
And then you make it into a square and you output it directly.
And if you don't use this place, it won't output.
So what you're actually outputting is
It's a little bit wider than you want it to be.
There's a little bit of a gap.
So that's why I'm going to put a frame here.
To make sure that when you output it,
It's the whole frame that I want.
Got it.
Okay, Yan said she got it.
Okay, good, good.
What's the second question?
I think the audience has a lot of questions right now.
Otherwise, we'll just answer the audience's questions directly.
We'll take the rest of the time to answer the audience's questions, okay?
Okay, okay.
The second question is how to integrate the actual photo into the picture.
Okay.
And then this question is also a very good question.
This is very tricky.
I'm just sharing a screen.
I'm assuming I don't want these things now.
And then I'm going to put a picture in there.
For example, I have a picture here.
Okay, okay.
And then you see, I just took this picture from my desktop.
It's big now, isn't it?
So I'm going to shrink it a little bit now.
I'm using the shortcut to shrink it now.
But if you have a magnifier here, you can also use this magnifier to shrink it.
Okay, I'm going to shrink it now, and then I'm going to use the first one.
The first one.
This is a picture.
It can no longer be broken into components.
So when you choose, you always make the first choice.
If you choose the second one, this picture will be easily destroyed by you.
Okay, I've chosen this one now.
Okay, so I'm going to shrink it now, and I'm going to put it on my drawing board.
And then I'm going to zoom in and see what it looks like.
If I want to put this picture up, I can just put it up.
And then what's the advantage of Illustrator?
I'm on the left side of the picture, and I'm on the right side of the picture, right?
That's okay.
It's just a picture that's going to be a thing.
So when you export it, it's the same, both of them will export.
I'll save it.
So when you export it, both of them will export.
So when you export it, it's the same, both of them will export.
So you say, okay, this is an EPS, it's supposed to be a image.
So I'm not going to be a real one when I zoom in.
Okay, so the problem is, the left one is all really a real one.
It's not going to be real.
But the right one is.
I've been zooming in and out.
You see, this MF is starting to be real.
So you want to put a picture in and drag it in.
It's very simple.
But it's a little tricky.
You have to take this big picture.
Because when you take this picture, it's a big file.
It's a big size.
So I recommend all the pictures.
Even if he's not with anyone else.
If you want to put it on your own.
This picture is best handled by AI.
You just drag it in like this.
There's only one picture in the whole panel.
It's better to come in.
Because when you come in, you can take it from the original size.
Maybe 1.3 megabytes.
You just zoom in and out.
Now we have this panel.
It's the size we're going to export.
For example, you want this picture to be this big.
You can just look at it in this export size.
Is it still readable?
If I shrink it to this size, it's already blurred.
That's just asking you to remake a picture.
You need a high-resolution picture.
If you look at this picture, it's good.
This picture is after I took it down.
It's still very clear.
You see, I put it in a big way.
Normally, a paper wouldn't be that big.
Basically, it's still very clear.
This picture is OK.
This kind of photo doesn't usually require much.
As long as you can see it when you zoom in.
And the main feature is that you can see it.
That's OK.
So when you shrink this picture, make sure it's visible.
It's the first thing you have to do.
The second thing you have to do is export it.
Like I just exported it to TAS 2, right?
I can come over now and see how big this TAS 2 is.
It's 3.4 MB.
Compared to this one, my first one is a full-size picture.
It's only 1.1 MB.
As a result, after I added a picture, it became 3.4 MB.
So when you're taking pictures,
Sometimes you use a very fancy camera.
The picture you take is 4K.
The file is super big.
After you export it, it's 1 GB or 500 MB.
That's not going to work.
Because often, for example, if you add four pictures together,
It can only be, for example, 25 MB.
Then you put a high-resolution picture on it first.
Basically, it takes up all your space.
That's not going to work.
What do you do at this time?
You have to go back and take this picture of yours.
Use other software to lower its quality.
It's not that good resolution.
But it's visible.
So when you put the picture in,
You have to make sure the resolution is high enough.
It's high enough to be visible.
But you have to make sure it's not too high.
Because it takes up a lot of resources.
So this is the main problem.
And then some people might want to, for example,
For example, like this one, I just want to make a beautiful one.
I'm going to give you a talk.
I'm going to give you a beautiful picture like this.
I want this picture to be the background of my data.
Suppose I want it to be the background of my data.
I can do the same thing.
I'm going to pull it to the size I want.
And then I want it to be at the bottom, right?
So I'm going to put this thing at the bottom.
So my data will show up on top.
And then I can usually, if you do this kind of thing,
You're going to need opacity.
I just want it to be a little transparent.
Like this.
That's it.
It looks like this data is related to AI.
Something like that.
That's fine, too.
But it's the same thing.
Every time you want to put in a picture,
You have to pay attention to the resolution of this picture.
It doesn't have a set rule that says how much it has to be.
The guideline is that you can see it when you zoom in.
That's it.
I had a real problem before.
How do you cut it?
Do you want this?
Yeah.
Oh, you don't want it.
You're going to step on it, right?
Yeah.
Okay, let's get the opacity back first.
Pull it back.
Okay.
You just click on this.
You just click on what you want to do.
Basically, this bar up here.
It has almost everything you want.
If it's beyond your imagination,
If it's not on top of it,
You'll just have it on YouTube.
It's going to be at the top.
In this detail.
Yeah.
Do you want to crop?
Basically.
Then you press crop.
Then you just cut it.
Apply.
Okay, that's it.
Because it's an object now.
If you want to put a star on it.
I want to dig a star.
I can do this.
Dig like this.
Got it.
Let's go to the next question.
Okay.
The next question is,
Can Illustrator add dots or lines to the pattern?
Yeah, that's a question.
And then I just saw another one.
A similar question.
Let's talk about it together.
Okay.
The other question is,
In the example of the chemical measuring bottle,
Is there a concept of scissors in Illustrator?
So you don't have to delete the dots one by one.
Just cut out the parts we don't want.
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
Basically, it's delete.
Or backspace.
That's the one on your shoulder.
For example, we're back here now, right?
So what else can I do with this?
I just shortened that dot.
I'm going to use a way to add dots.
To make this picture.
This thing.
I just didn't say that.
If I just press this now.
I'm going to edit the dots now.
So I'm going to change the oil to direct selection.
Then I can start to change the component.
I'll click on this object first.
One, two, three, four, five.
I see that there are so many dots now.
I don't want these three on top of me.
I'll take it off first.
I'll press delete.
I'm going to press the keyboard to delete or backspace.
You can do this.
Or?
Sometimes your dots are very dense.
You might not be able to do that.
It's so good, it's framed to your liking.
At this time, you can.
Uh, for example, you have to choose.
You might be, uh.
Okay, you press this.
Then you choose this.
I'm going to choose a dot now, right?
I'm going to press shift.
Just don't put shift.
I can start to choose more dots.
But because this is an image.
It's not, uh.
It's not like a little painter or a photo.
Uh, that, that.
What's that? Photoshop.
Yeah, he didn't cut it.
It's like cutting it off from the middle.
He didn't.
But he can do that.
It's just that he has to go in.
Delete every dot and line of the image.
Or you can, you can delete it together.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to add a dot.
How do I add it?
Because I'm now the problem is the dot.
So I'm going to move the dot now.
You can see the left side of the toolbar.
There's one of these things in there.
Okay.
Usually you see this.
This is the pen tool.
The pen tool, you press the right button.
Or you, you just press this triangle.
He's going to have four options.
The first one is to draw a dot.
I don't draw a line.
I don't draw a picture.
I just draw a dot.
For example, like this.
Okay, I'll just draw a dot.
The second one is to add a dot.
The third one is to subtract a dot.
The fourth one is to pull the handle.
That's what I'm doing now, right?
But I want him to have a handle.
I can use the fourth one to pull the handle.
That's how you add a dot.
I'm going to add a dot here.
Okay, that's it.
So what am I doing now?
I'm going to use this shape to click on this.
Look at this.
I'm going to use this direct selection to see.
I see one, two, three, four, five, six, seven.
There are two more dots here, right?
I'm going to be happy now.
Pick it up and delete it.
That's it.
And then I can just put this over here.
I might want to cover this up.
Otherwise, it's a little weird.
I'm going to use this pen tool to cover this up.
I'm going to cover this up.
And then I'm going to put this over here.
Sometimes when you delete a dot, the shape will be a little bit of a walk.
This is the color scheme.
You might want to pay a little attention to it.
I used some of the tricks yesterday.
It's just that it's exactly the same.
If anyone wants to know later, we can share it.
But this is how you increase the number of dots.
You can also cut the dots.
And then I cut the dots.
I can also use this thing to pull the handle.
I don't like this dot.
I can press this.
I'm going to use this little thing.
And then I'm going to pull this handle.
Okay, look.
It's a little heart.
Okay.
And then the other question is,
Did you also adjust the dots for the Neuroscientist picture in the first video?
Which one is the Neuroscientist picture?
Are you talking about this one?
Yes, it should be.
It should be this one, right?
Okay.
This is a very good question.
This picture is actually a little complicated, right?
He can use that dot.
If I made this picture,
I might pull a star first.
And then let that star become, for example, an octagonal star.
And then I make each star round.
But because you know this line, you don't have to do it yourself.
I know it's going to take a lot of time to simulate this picture.
Because I want to make sure that the curvature is exactly the same.
But when you draw it yourself,
For example, I can draw a simple Neuroscientist for you now.
I'm like this.
Okay.
And then I want this one to be, for example, it's curved.
Right?
Then I can make it curved.
This one is curved.
This one is curved like this.
I drew it a little ugly.
I can make it curved.
And then here.
And then I might want it to be crooked.
Then I'll add two more dots.
For example, add a few more dots.
And then I'll pull this dot out.
And then the dots are also curved.
This one is also curved.
Wait a minute. I'm going to break this one.
This is also curved.
And then this one here is also curved.
Okay.
Basically, you're just doing this kind of thing.
You're just adjusting it slowly.
And then it's going to get better and better.
Okay.
It's easy to draw it up and then slowly draw it.
You just want to draw it all the time.
But anyway, this is it.
This is it.
You just add your own dots like this.
So what do we usually do?
There are two ways to do it.
One is that you draw on the paper first.
Draw a draft. It doesn't matter if it's ugly.
Put the paper down and stick it on.
And then when you're pulling the dots,
you stick it to the line you drew.
Pull it.
That way, it's going to be smooth.
It's not going to be that ugly.
The other way is if you have
an Adobe software.
There's another software in Adobe.
It's called Adobe Capture.
It's basically...
I think Google has this feature, too.
You type in NeuronCell.
And then it's going to have a vector neuron cell that someone else drew.
You can just pull in someone else's neuron cell.
And then modify it.
For example, you just need a few more touches.
And then you can do this, too.
For example, I don't know if this one has it.
You can see that I'm doing AI right now.
There's a neuron cell in the upper right corner, right?
You can search for someone else's neuron cell.
Look, I have so many neuron cells.
You might want to draw this one.
You might want to draw a simple two-dimensional picture.
Let's say you want to draw this one.
This is generally...
If you buy Adobe Stock, you can use it directly.
If you don't buy it,
you can screenshot it.
You can take a picture of it.
And then paste it in.
For example, like this.
I can screenshot it.
I'll take a picture, paste it in.
And then copy it and draw a similar one.
I have a lot of...
Here.
I can paste this picture in.
And then put it at the end.
And then I can start.
Just follow this picture.
I can...
Make this colorless.
And then start.
Just start copying it.
Okay.
Or I can even
add dots directly.
Okay.
Why is this panel so short?
Or I can
add dots directly.
For example,
I zoom in now, right?
And then I want...
You can see that I may need a dot here.
I may need a dot here.
I can draw a skeleton
one by one.
This may be easier than the stars.
Okay.
The more dots you have, the more you have to adjust.
But of course it will look more real.
Okay.
Oh, I drew this badly.
You probably know what I mean.
You can learn it one by one.
Okay.
This is a pretty good example.
And then we have some more questions.
Is it...
okay.
Okay.
I actually have a case today.
I'm going to talk about this.
So I can use this picture.
I'll delete this picture first.
Can you
Thank you
Let's make a final size box
This box
Let me adjust this box
The size of this box is
3.75 inches
Assuming this is 3.75 inches
This is my original picture
I'm going to put this original picture in
I'm going to put it in
But you see I put it in
Don't you think this line is particularly fat?
And the word might be very small
Not the font you want
This is a little bit of trouble
This is when I first told you
When you are sure to use the picture
The font you output directly to the software
It's best to be the last font you use
So you don't have to change it when you come in
Because for example, you output
For example, my picture
I'm from my Excel
After I output it from my Number
I didn't specify
my
The size of these letters
I didn't specify the size
So he might use something like 28, 32
Very big
And then when I put it on, it becomes very big
And when I shrink
It's just that it's a little bit deformed
It's a little weird
So when you output
For example, your tick
All your numbers are 11
Then
Or 9
This is the best
So you don't have to change it here
It's very troublesome
What about the thickness of this line
You'd better set it first
If you can't set it, you can come here and change it
I'll show you how to change it now
When you put the data in here
You don't want to make false data
So every time you shrink
There's a tool here
Take this
Free Transform
Free Transform is
After you pick up some objects
You can use Free Transform
To shrink
You can shrink like this
Or you can rotate
When you use Free Transform
You must press Shift
So I'm going to write it down
You have to press Shift when you shrink
If you press Shift
The proportion of your length and width will be fixed
So you don't make false
The whole data is suddenly deformed
So you have to do this
After I do this
I'm going to come in and change the thickness of this data
How to change
At this time, I'm going to talk about
How does the general software process the layout?
You see, we're processing the layout in the AI
All the things are dots
The lines are connected, right?
It's very simple
It's like our kids are drawing
But the general software is processing the layout
It's not like this
It's to make sure that every line or every layout
After the output
It's still the way it was
So every layout
Every line, every dot
Even every number, every icon
We're going to use a thing called clipping mask
It's the protector
What is clipping mask?
You must be doing powerpoint
There is
Let me see
You must be doing powerpoint
There's something about it
For example, I added a slide
OK
You see, I'm in this slide
Is there a picture on the left?
Is there a picture on the left of my slide?
If I want to change a picture
Do I pull in a picture?
You see, this picture is different from my original picture
I had so many neurons in my original picture
My neurons are now cut off
What should I do?
How did this happen?
The reason is because
All the software
It's to make sure
It's the same
It's going to add a clipping mask
I'm going to show you a clipping mask
Double this pattern
You see, there are two
The first one is your original picture
This one
The second one is your mask
Your mask
You see, I'm going to show you a clipping mask
The part that the mask frames
It's the last thing that's going to show up
OK
What about this idea?
This is our battle
Drawing is the biggest problem with modified timetable
Look at this
This picture is just
From
Just let it go
Let's just look at this line
This line
When I choose this line now
I can't just choose this line
Did you notice that I chose this whole thing
Because the mask of this line is so big
I'm going to move this out now
Did you see
When I choose this line
It's not these anchor points
It's not a line
But what does this mean
This doesn't mean that my data is so big
No, this means that my data is
It's just dots and lines
It's just data
This one outside is its mask
What can I do now?
I can double click now
I'm going to double click now
This thing is what I'm going to do
This is what we call Compound
OK
I'm using the first arrow now
I'm going to frame the whole big screen
Then you see
I framed this
Who is this
This is this line
Then you see this line
I moved it out of the clipping mask
It was cut off
I don't know if you have this idea
First of all, I'm going to move this over
OK
You see
I have this thing
This big mask
And then the data inside
When I'm changing
I'm going to change the data inside
So you usually have to point at the data you want to point at
And then dot dot dot dot
You see
I clicked a few more times
I finally clicked into this one
You see if I can see it now
I zoom in and see if I can see it now
Circle circle
This is the image
I finally got this data
I can choose this circle now
Then you can choose this line
Sometimes you have to click a few more times
Very troublesome
Then I can put this stroke now
Become more
Become thinner
For example, I use 1.75
I like to use 1.75 the most
Then these circles are the same
You are the same
You don't want it to be so thick
So you have to go in and choose
Click a few more times to choose this circle
Then become 1.75
Change one by one
You see this is actually very troublesome
How do I do this efficiently?
We may want to take this mask
I just choose this thing first
Then I'm going to pick up this object
Right click
Then press this
I'm going to take this mask off
Take it off
OK, now this thing
After I re-frame it
You see, it's completely
These groups of circles and lines
I want to change this thing
It's easier
I can do this
Then it will wash
I just moved it out
Don't do it when you are doing your own data
This is ugly
There is a risk of fake data
I just want to make it easy for you to see the mask
So I just moved it out
Actually, when you are operating
You usually do this
You just choose this
After choosing this thing
You just choose your object
Move a little bit first
Make sure you get it
Then press ctrl-z
Right click, release this mask
When I release the mask
I originally chose an object
You see, there are two boxes
One is my data line box
The other is the mask box
Now you can put this mask box
You can also choose this mask box
Delete it
I think I chose the wrong one
Wait a minute
These two
Then I choose this
Delete
Now this box is gone
I can choose the data I want
Change its appearance
Like this
The most annoying part of AI
Just look at each of these
Just this bar
Look at our bar
This bar
It's not like a text
When you enter the text
Choose the bottom line of the text
It means it's a text
But when you enter
That bar
It becomes an object
It doesn't have that line
And it doesn't have a lot of dots
So it means this thing
It's also protected by the mask
Just press the right button
Ok
Sorry
And then the same thing
Cut off the outline of this bar
So you can choose
So when all the software
Enter Illustrator to draw
The most annoying thing is
You have to put every little thing
The clipping mask is all released
And then delete those masks
Delete those masks
And then edit it
And then after this thing
There's something important
A lot of people didn't notice
I want to talk about
After you enter the number
You might have the size
And then you have to output
And then you have the font
And then you output
And then your picture
After using another computer
I found that the font
I can't find it
But the font is ugly
What should I do
This is a very common problem
Your computer font
Windows font
Mac font
There's a problem when you switch
So the best way at this time
You type all the words
For example, this bar
I have a number
After I type it
You circle all these words
Right click
Then click Create Outline
I'll zoom in for you
This bar is just a bar
It's a text
After I create it
It's not a text
I'm using this A
Look at this picture
It's not a text anymore
It's a lot of dots
Look at this picture
It's already a text
When you output it on a different computer
There will be no font
Unreadable problem
Understand
And then the audience
Someone said
That is
You can see more clearly
Masks and objects
Layer management
Yes, there is a layer management
There is a layer management
You can
You put everything on different layers
You can see the objects
But I rarely use this
I personally rarely use this feature
I don't remember
How to set up layers
But if you're interested
There are a lot of layers
I suggest you
Go to YouTube
Lastly
I'll end the meeting here
But we can continue
To ask questions
I'll bother the teacher
Until she can't
Because there are too many questions
If I can't, I'll
That's all
Bye