The recording has started.
We even discussed where to go to buy alcohol, masks, etc.
Many of my European friends and classmates laughed at these behaviors.
But to a certain extent, it also shows that Asians, or more specifically,
Taiwanese have a very different response mode to the epidemic than Westerners.
So at Project TIRA's summer event this year,
we specially planned a speech on the COVID-19 epidemic.
We are honored to have Professor Li Xiongwen as our guest speaker.
In 2016, Professor Li graduated from Beka University's School of Mathematics.
He is currently working as an assistant researcher at the Institute of Sociology.
Professor Li's interest spans many different fields.
He is interested in social network analysis,
social conflicts and cooperation in evolution,
and social science quantification.
We can see that Professor Li has a wide range of interests.
We look forward to Professor Li's approach to the COVID-19 issue.
Now I will hand over to Professor Li for his speech.
Thank you, Professor Li.
Thank you for the introduction.
I am very happy to be able to share my research on the TIRA platform.
Let me find my screen.
I don't know if you can see the video.
Can you see it, Professor Li?
Yes, I can see it.
Okay, let's get started.
First of all, I would like to thank Professor Li again for his invitation.
When Professor Li invited me,
he specifically mentioned that he wanted to find the topic of COVID-19 and invited me to give a speech.
Actually, I feel very ashamed.
Although I have done the topic of COVID-19,
I have also collected information related to COVID-19.
I will talk about another topic later.
Today I will talk about the first topic.
I will talk about the second topic later.
However, I am not a disease infectious scientist.
Although Professor Li mentioned that I work in other fields,
this field is not the field I am familiar with.
What we do is more like psychology, public policy, or public health related issues related to disease infection.
This is not the topic I am familiar with.
I am an expert in methodology.
However, this is the first time I have collected data.
This is the first time I have collected data for research since I was a child.
This is data from all over Taiwan.
Of course, the method used is the statistical method.
This is not the method I am familiar with.
This is not the field I am familiar with.
However, since I have collected data, I must have something to say.
I will try my best to present the data I have collected for research.
This is the data from my research team from March to May last year.
If you still have an impression,
At the end of January and February last year, the epidemic of COVID-19 began to break out in Taiwan.
In addition to China, epidemics began to occur around the world in February and March.
The most tense time in Taiwan was from March to May last year.
At that time, we rushed out to collect data.
Our supervisor told us that we should not be locked in our own room and do our own thing.
Because the students of natural science are already very busy.
We also need to go out and collect more data related to COVID-19.
Since the supervisor said, we want to do what our team can do.
We want to do what we can do in this epidemic.
I will introduce what data we rushed out to collect later.
This is the data we collected between March and May last year.
We found some research topics to do.
This is one of them.
What are we studying?
What we are studying is that when the epidemic began, the government of Taiwan will have some corresponding policies.
One of the very special policies is to ask some people who are at risk to stay at home for 14 days for quarantine.
He may not stay at home, but he may be quarantined in a medical institution or a quarantine center or at home for 14 days.
We want to know if he will have the idea of disobedience or resistance during these 14 days.
The idea of wanting to leave quarantine.
What are some of the reasons why these people want to leave quarantine?
This is noncompliance.
This is the focus of the research we want to focus on.
Because we want to say that if we know the reason why he wants to leave the quarantine, we can know which supporting measures the government can provide to make these people more willing to stay in quarantine to help us control the entire epidemic.
This research is done by me and my two assistants.
The first two authors are our two research assistants.
Let's start sharing.
Let's take a look at the latest COVID-19 numbers.
From January last year to August 6 this year, we went to the relevant website of WHO and saw that the number of confirmed cases of COVID-19 around the world has exceeded 200 million, and the death toll has exceeded more than 4 million.
The number of confirmed cases in Taiwan is 15,000 until August 6 this year, and the death toll is 809.
Taiwan's situation is of course different from other countries around the world.
Between March and May of 2020, the government just mentioned that it was a tense moment.
At that time, the global epidemic began to fever.
Many young people working and studying abroad returned to Taiwan.
At that time, the atmosphere in Taiwan was actually more tense.
At that time, if everyone came back from abroad, would there be a virus?
Because everyone did not do the test, they may come back and there may be some infected people who will explode.
At that time, if you still remember in Taiwan, we were worried about a lot of holidays, such as the annual holiday, and then all kinds of holidays.
I was worried that there would be a large-scale outbreak.
It was at this time last year.
After May, the performance of Taiwan's government began to be very good, and the epidemic was controlled and did not explode.
There have been no local epidemics for 253 consecutive days.
Next, let's look at this graph.
This is a graph of the cumulative confirmed cases and the cumulative death toll in Taiwan.
From January and February of last year to July of this year, the green line is the cumulative confirmed cases.
The cumulative death toll only goes up.
So we see a very small spike.
It was between March and April of last year, and there were still cumulative confirmed cases.
It has been flat since mid-April.
Local confirmed cases began in December of last year.
Taiwan has no local confirmed cases for 253 consecutive days.
There were no local confirmed cases from April of last year to December of last year.
Later, there were local confirmed cases from December of last year to May of this year.
Everyone knows that this is a new wave of epidemic in Taiwan.
However, the outbreak of the new wave of epidemic has also been gradually reduced.
It has now dropped from level 3 to level 2.
In fact, the peak of the outbreak is at the end of May and the beginning of June.
Later, we will also have a new collection of data to share with you.
Let's take a look at the situation in Taiwan.
Taiwan is a very special example that I just shared with you.
Taiwan was very well controlled in the early days.
We are a model god in these countries.
I also saw a lot of articles analyzing the reasons why Taiwan was able to succeed in the early days.
First of all, we have a central government agency that reacts quickly.
This is the Central Epidemic Control Center, CECC.
Of course, we hold press conferences every day to announce timely information.
Then do a lot of effective group distribution, such as mask maps and other materials.
In fact, there is a very fast and transparent information management.
The second is that we have good border control.
No matter who he is, he must be quarantined or quarantined for 14 days before entering Taiwan's borders.
After coming out, you have to track his temperature and see if there is a problem.
If there is no problem, you can go out and exercise freely, and you have to be self-isolated for 7 days.
In fact, this border control is very important.
Another one is to add his later isolation and quarantine.
What is the difference between isolation and quarantine?
Quarantine is if you have been infected, you will be quarantined.
Quarantine conditions are more strict.
If you have the risk of infection, such as your host and the infected person may have met in the same place.
Then you may have to be quarantined.
Quarantine is a lower standard, but it also has to be quarantined for 14 days.
Quarantine is quarantine, and quarantine is isolation.
We also do contact tracing, which is tracking control.
In fact, in many places, we will know how the host of the infected person is going.
You will see the GPS location of his mobile phone, which is to announce his host.
Now we all know that if we go to a public place in Taiwan, we have to send a heavy text message to the central control center to report that we have entered and left that place.
This is a very common example of contact tracing.
Other related measures include social distancing or wearing a mask.
These are all key elements of Taiwan's success.
In this study, we want to focus on two key points.
The first is that we want to look at quarantine and quarantine.
What role did quarantine and quarantine play in the process of controlling the epidemic in Taiwan?
What policy measures are effective?
The second is whether the person who is quarantined or quarantined has the idea of ​​leaving the quarantine area.
What factors make him want to leave this place?
Quarantine is that he has contact with the infected person.
Quarantine is that he may have some contact.
Another quarantine is that if he comes back from abroad, he must quarantine automatically.
As mentioned earlier, Taiwan has done very well in many areas.
The early part has done very well.
One of the things we want to pay attention to is Taiwan's quarantine and quarantine measures.
This measure is actually for those who are at risk.
We want them to stay at home or stay in their designated quarantine place, such as a quarantine hotel, a quarantine hospital, or some quarantine places.
Let him stay there for 14 days.
Of course, these people will have good supplies for 14 days.
The government will know that he is there, and there will be ways to know his location and provide him with sufficient supplies.
From last year, February and March, until now, until July, about 700,000 people have experienced quarantine or quarantine.
Of these, 2,000 cases violated these regulations.
If these regulations are violated, they may be fined up to NT$1 million.
So in fact, in most cases, we see that most Taiwanese people cooperate with this policy.
Of the 700,000 cases, only 2,000 were violated.
But there are still violations. We want to know the reasons for the violations.
Of course, we may not be able to find these violations, but we want to know why the people who have experienced these measures want to leave the quarantine place.
We want to know what role the government plays in this, whether the information it provides is transparent, and whether the supplies it provides to the people in the quarantine place are sufficient.
Will these affect the idea of ​​wanting to stay in the quarantine place or leave the quarantine place?
Next, in fact, all over the world, we face different measures from the government to do different things.
In fact, people in each place will have different levels of obedience and even resistance.
In fact, there are also a lot of large-scale protests abroad that may not obey some of the government's actions.
For example, many countries are protesting that the government should not require the people to wear a mask at any time, or wear a mask when entering the factory.
Or there are even people who think that the government's COVID policy is actually a conspiracy theory, and that the government is trying to suppress the people or restrict the freedom of the people.
So in fact, when the government is doing a lot of relevant measures, it is likely to receive some resistance or rebellion from the people.
We want to know what is the greatest dissatisfaction or greatest pressure on people with the quarantine or quarantine measures alone.
If we want to make these measures more effective, we should pay attention to which aspects.
Of course, this is not the first time that we have done research on isolation or quarantine-related disobedience.
In the past, scholars also did research on different situations.
For example, some different diseases will actually restrict the freedom of residence or action of these infected or at-risk people.
There are different levels. First of all, it is the level of the government. People are concerned about whether the information given by the government is open and transparent.
Since the government restricts me from moving today, the government should let me know whether the government's policy is correct or whether I have the necessity to stay here and whether I have received sufficient information.
Next is the level of the individual. What factors will affect the individual whether he wants to leave the quarantine zone?
In the past, scholars also found that he had financial difficulties. For example, if he can't go out to make money, he may feel difficult to go out after being locked up for 14 days.
Or he thinks he has no social responsibility. After being locked up, he has no benefits. He is only limited to freedom of action, but it is of no help to society.
He may have experienced strong negative emotions, which makes him unable to stay. He feels very bored and uneasy. He must go out and leave this place.
Or he lacks a lot of opportunities to get in touch with others. He has no interpersonal interaction. Because he may not be able to get in touch with others in the quarantine zone, he can only force others to give him food. He lacks interpersonal interaction and wants to leave.
These are the rules that have been found to make people want to stay in a place.
During the period of isolation, it will cause some negative emotions to these people. These negative emotions may also lead to him wanting to leave the quarantine zone.
Of course, there are many sources of negative emotions. Some of the sources we see in the document are related to leaving the quarantine zone.
He may lack some sunshine. Because he is locked up in a place, he may not be able to get sunlight in that place, which may have an impact on his mental health.
The next one is the financial difficulties that I just mentioned, which may also have an impact on his negative emotions.
Or he may be illiterate. There may be a lot of sources of illiteracy. It may be relatives or very good friends who take care of him.
He may think that he is causing trouble to his relatives and friends.
Or he may have a bad relationship with his neighbors. For example, if you are quarantined at home and others know that you have come back from abroad to work or study, you may have a different view of your family.
This may cause his own pressure.
Or a stranger may be illiterate to a group of people. For example, why do these people who work abroad and study abroad have to return to Taiwan within a few days?
Or why do these people who work abroad and study abroad have to return to Taiwan within a few days?
It may be the illiteracy of strangers that causes his negative emotions.
Or some self-evaluation of oneself. I may cause trouble to others. I shouldn't do this. This will also increase negative emotions.
Or some information given by the government is incomplete or inconsistent. This may also have an impact on negative emotions.
We will see if this negative emotion is an intermediary variable, that is, whether a person wants to leave the quarantine area.
Because it is related to other variables, the negative emotion itself is a big variable.
We want to analyze a set of systems to see if the negative emotion project is an intermediary variable for a person who wants to leave the quarantine area.
Of course, the intermediary variable is the statistics. You have to see that a lot of things are X that affect Y.
The negative emotion is an intermediary variable, let's call it M.
A lot of things are directly affected from X to Y, and then X will affect M to Y.
We want to see how much M, the intermediary variable of this negative emotion, accounts for.
Next, let's talk about how we collect information.
In March and May of last year, when the epidemic in Taiwan was relatively tense, when students and young people from overseas returned to Taiwan, we began to set up a website called epidemic prevention diary.
We collect several types of information from everyone.
The first one is that they want to tell us who they are in contact with every day.
This information lasts for more than a month, from March to May.
They want to tell us who they are in contact with every day.
Next, he will let us know how he feels every day.
We recruit people on the Internet. There are two types of people.
Here is the timetable.
There are two types.
The first one is quarantine or quarantine.
How do we know if he is in quarantine or quarantine?
The government will give him a home quarantine or home quarantine notice.
If you are a person who has been diagnosed or you are a person who has returned from abroad, the government will give you a home quarantine notice.
Participants have to take this notice and send it to us.
Then our people will check it manually and see if there is no problem.
It is not fake.
We will let him come in and join our quarantine group.
The quarantine group is the first day he is in quarantine or quarantine.
He is in quarantine or quarantine.
We will let him participate in our research as a quarantiner.
The other group is the people who have not experienced quarantine or quarantine.
When he participates, he does not have the identity of quarantine or quarantine.
He can also sign up for our survey.
The survey is very similar.
At the beginning, when he joined our research, he had a pre-survey.
He said that he was at this time, March 30 or April 2, his current state.
The person in quarantine is currently in quarantine.
This is where he is different.
The next 30 days, he will let us know who he contacted and who he contacted every day.
Then there are some moods in his daily life or how much time he spends doing what.
How is the time allocation of daily life?
You will see some related questions later.
We will give him a follow-up when the investigation is over.
When the quarantine is over, we will give him a questionnaire.
This is the questionnaire after the quarantine.
If he participated in this research on the 7th, he will fill out a questionnaire on the 14th.
This is a screenshot of our website.
This part is what I just said.
We want these participants to record who they interact with every day.
He has to establish the interaction between me and Zhang Yanping.
Our interaction is on the Internet.
I have to write down who initiated it and how long it took.
Did I get it?
How do I feel?
Did we get specific emotions?
Get information, etc.
We call this contact.
You can think of it as an interaction.
The daily interaction should be recorded on this platform.
The other part is the part of life that I just talked about.
Is there a cool body temperature?
Did you let the sun bask into the house?
Do you feel lonely?
How long does it take to work, study, have fun, socialize, etc.
Some daily life-related questions.
Of course, we also give some subsidies or rewards.
They can participate in this study.
If it meets our standards, we will send him a gift certificate.
Let them draw.
They are willing to participate in this activity.
It is worth noting that we are recruited on the Internet.
We are recruited on Facebook, LINE, and some websites.
We can see that the people we recruit are relatively young.
You can see that the group on the left who has not experienced isolation is on average 33 years old.
The group that is undergoing isolation is on average 28.3 years old.
It is a relatively young group.
But this is also the result we expect.
In fact, this group of people, especially those who are isolated, are mostly from abroad.
Like studying abroad or working abroad.
This group of people is relatively young.
We also expect this situation.
And young people use the Internet more.
So the people we recruit on the Internet are mostly young people.
This group of people are mostly women.
The women accounted for about 70%.
The men accounted for more than 20%.
Since they are young, most of them are unmarried.
And the group of people who are undergoing isolation.
Because they are younger and more unmarried.
Most of them live in big cities.
There are a total of 158 people who have not been isolated.
There are about 140 people who are undergoing isolation.
The information we are sharing now is the group of people who are undergoing isolation.
That is to say, the first day of his study, he is in isolation.
He may be isolated after 7 days or 5 days.
Then he has to do the remaining 25 days or the remaining 21 days of this questionnaire.
He will do another questionnaire after the end.
What we are discussing is the group of people who are undergoing isolation on the first day.
This is a total of 140 people.
What are some of the changes that we care about?
Is it related to his idea of ​​leaving the isolation area?
First of all, he thinks that his own isolation or isolation restrictions are helpful to society.
Does he think his social responsibility is high?
Does he think he is helpful?
Next is whether the government's relevant information is sufficient.
This is what we measure every day.
Repeat means measuring every day.
We will measure the number of contacts or interactions with him every day.
Of course, our interaction does not necessarily refer to face-to-face interaction.
It may be network interaction, it may be voice, it may be text.
He can record it all.
We record whether he blames himself.
We also investigate their quality of life.
Here we use the WHO's quality of life, which is a simplified version of the 26-point version.
It is divided into four aspects in total.
We put it all into physiology, psychology, society and the environment.
Next, we measure his negative emotions.
Ask if you are in a good mood today.
Did you feel negative emotions?
How strong?
Next, did you let the sun shine into your home?
Or ask him how many people are quarantined every day.
How many people want to leave the quarantine area every day?
We will see how to ask this question later.
It depends on the negative evaluation of oneself, the degree of anonymity, and the degree of financial difficulties he has experienced.
Next is some preliminary analysis.
We can see that among the 140 people who are quarantined, their quality of life is compared to the long-term model.
The long-term model is that we use the same questionnaire to measure other people in Taiwan.
This is called the long-term model.
Is there any difference between these people and those who are quarantined or quarantined when we found this group?
This group of people who are being quarantined or quarantined may be in a bad situation on the first day.
Maybe just got off the plane or just came back from abroad, everything is in a hurry.
His physiological quality is relatively low.
We see that he is prominent.
His P is very small, less than 10 to the negative 4.
He is negative.
He is lower than the long-term model.
The psychological aspect is also lower than the long-term model.
This is also prominent.
In terms of the quality of life in the environment, this is not prominent.
They are prominent in social relations.
Because his P is also less than 10 to the negative 4.
He is higher than the long-term model.
So this group of people, on the first day of the study, their physiology and psychology are worse than the long-term model.
But they have better social relations.
We have asked three questions.
The first day of the study, the end of the quarantine, and the end of the study.
The end of the study is the 31st day.
We want to see his changes.
What we are looking at now is the first day of the study and the day of the end of the study.
Which of his various changes is significantly different?
This group of people is the isolation group.
They believe that their isolation is helpful to society.
They are significantly reduced in social responsibility.
What we put here is significant.
He is significantly reduced.
This group of people believes that their isolation is not helpful to society.
The second group of people is significant.
They believe that the transparency of government information has increased.
This is significant.
They believe that the transparency of government information is high.
This group of people is significantly reduced from the beginning to the end.
The third group of people is significant.
The number of people in contact every day from the beginning to the end is relatively low.
Sorry.
It was relatively low at the beginning, but it was higher at the end.
At the beginning of the study, the number of people in contact with him was less.
At the end, after the 30th day, he was free to socialize outside.
So the number of people in contact at that time was significantly higher.
Let's look at some of the issues we are concerned about.
First of all, what variables will affect the behavior of these people who do not obey?
Next is the negative emotion.
Does it play a role as an intermediary variable?
Will it also affect the behavior of those who do not obey?
First of all, let's look at what our self-variable and one-variable are.
The dependent variable we want to look at is how much he wants to leave the isolation.
These people are asked every day.
He is asked every day during the isolation period that if you want to leave the isolation today.
If there is, how strong is the degree?
We ask every day.
So we have a total of 734 pieces of information.
Because not everyone has 14 days in our research.
He may be the 8th day to join the study.
He only has 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14 days of information.
We ask every day of isolation.
If it is the first day to join, there will be 14 days of information.
So we have a total of 734 pieces of information.
Of these 734 pieces of information, there are 278 pieces that say they don't want to leave the isolation at all.
278 is a little bit.
77 is normal.
Next is very strong.
Very strong is 18.
So we do different things for this.
We know that he is not very strong.
There is no majority at all.
Then we will analyze which reasons make him want to leave the isolation.
Then we use the Multi-Level Ordinal Logistic Regression Model.
In fact, it is Multi-Level.
Multi-Level is that our first layer is every day.
The second layer is everyone.
This is Multi-Level.
The variance of his normal model is 8.5.
Then we use the Random Intercept Model.
Ordinal is because his Y is a sequence.
It is from very small to very small.
We use this return model.
Ok, let's see which variables are for this.
Want to leave the isolation.
First of all, we see that the conclusion is that there is no male.
His attitude, his coefficient is negative.
Then he shows that we only put it today.
He is showing that he does not want to leave the isolation.
In this study, the male is more obedient.
That is, his idea of ​​leaving the isolation is smaller than that of women.
Next is Negative Emotion.
This is also a high value.
The higher the negative emotion he experiences, the more he wants to leave the isolation.
Next is how many days he is in isolation.
This is N-State, which is how many days.
The higher the number of days, the closer he leaves.
The closer he wants to leave, the more he wants to leave.
The 13th and 14th days are the most wanted to leave.
The more time he is in isolation, the more he wants to leave.
This is positive.
The higher the level of dehumanization he experiences, the more he wants to leave.
This dehumanization is positive.
Next is social responsibility decline.
He thinks that his isolation is more and more unhelpful to society.
The more he wants to leave.
Daily contact is negative.
The more the daily contact declines, the more he wants to leave the isolation.
This is where we put all the variables at the beginning of the model.
We got some information from the Multi-Level Ordinological Regression.
Next is Mediation Analysis.
We look at negative emotions.
How many variables will it absorb?
We put all these variables into the model to see how much negative emotions can be absorbed.
Of course, we use the Perl model.
We can see that it will divide the variables into several effects.
Direct Effect and Indirect Effect.
Which will pass directly from X to Y, not through the intermediate variable M.
The intermediate variable here is negative emotion M.
Indirect will pass through negative emotion from X to Y.
We did some analysis.
Here are some conclusions.
Let me give you an example.
Dehumanization.
Dehumanization can be divided into three groups.
Weak, medium and strong.
Let's look at one of them.
Strong.
Total effect is positive.
Positive 4.71.
The stronger the dehumanized emotion, the more it wants to leave the quarantine.
The intermediate variable is direct.
Direct is 83.9%.
From X to Y.
From strong dehumanization to Y wanting to leave the quarantine.
The direct effect is 83%.
The indirect effect is that these strong dehumanized emotions to negative emotions are about 13%.
So we can look at the path in this way.
How many variables will pass through the intermediate variable negative emotion?
Which will directly affect from X to Y?
We have discussed the following.
Let's summarize the discovery of this topic.
What factors will affect these people?
Want to leave the quarantine?
Like dehumanization or people you meet every day.
The fewer people you meet, the more you want to leave the quarantine.
The more people like this, the more you want to leave the quarantine.
As the number of quarantine days increases, the more you want to leave the quarantine.
Maybe it's because you can't stand it anymore.
I've been quarantined for too long.
The more you want to leave, the more you want to leave.
He feels that his own isolation has no effect on the community.
The more he wants to leave, the more negative emotions he experiences, the more he wants to leave.
What are the factors that cause negative emotions?
Self-accusation or negative evaluation
Dehumanization of the outside world
We found that the dehumanization from strangers is the most serious.
Or he experienced some financial difficulties.
It will cause more negative emotions.
Negative emotions indirectly affect this.
The idea of wanting to leave the quarantine
We also have some extended conclusions.
Some aspects that the government can consider
First of all, the government should pay more attention to these people.
He was quarantined or disinfected.
How is his psychological state?
We care about whether he is short of supplies.
Is there anyone who cares enough about him?
We want to let him know that his psychological state is something that the government should know and care about.
Public health personnel should know every day whether he has experienced a lot of pressure.
Try to eliminate the possibility of dehumanization in society.
Dehumanization from relatives, friends, and strangers
This is very serious for them.
They may want to leave the quarantine.
Therefore, there will be a lot of negative emotions.
Next, we should strengthen the social responsibility of these people.
He can protect more people from the harm of the disease.
The stronger the social responsibility, the easier it is for these people to stay in quarantine or quarantine.
The more he doesn't want to leave, the stronger the sense of social responsibility.
What are the restrictions on this study?
The first restriction is the way we recruit.
These people are recruited by social media, such as Facebook and LINE.
In fact, their information is relatively sufficient.
He is a relatively online user.
He is a young group.
They are also a very equal group.
They are young and about 90% of them came back from abroad.
They are a very equal group.
Most of the people they participate in are women.
This is a very special part of our sample.
The main topic we want to introduce just finished.
I want to spend a little time to introduce the other information we received.
This is an article I wrote on my website.
It's more like a science journal article.
He said that the social impact of COVID-19 is cross-national analysis and comparison.
This is a global cross-national survey we did from September 2020 to the end of May this year.
It is different from the Taiwan survey from March to May.
The Taiwan survey from March to May is a one-month research.
He is looking for two groups of people, people who are isolated and people who are not isolated.
We asked him to write a one-month journal separately.
This cross-national study is a global survey.
There are 12 languages ​​in this survey.
We want participants to be able to do three surveys.
One survey will take 90 days.
In other words, if a person wrote in September last year, he received an email in December last year.
In April this year, he received an email and filled out three surveys.
The questions we ask are very similar.
We also ask about contact, mood, and whether or not we have contacted the patient.
We also ask about their quality of life and their political attitude.
If you are interested, you can look at the science journal article on my website.
The organizer invited me to talk about some issues related to COVID-19.
I will share the latest research here.
However, we have not sorted it out yet, so we can only talk about it.
We were very lucky during the collection period.
From September last year to the end of May this year,
In fact, in Taiwan, there is a very good research topic.
From September last year to May this year, Taiwan did not have any local cases from September last year to December.
Local cases began in December.
However, in mid-May this year, the local epidemic began to break out.
As you can see in this picture, after Mother's Day in May, the national level 2 alert was issued.
On May 15, the level 3 alert was issued.
On May 19, the national level 3 alert was issued.
The peak was probably at the end of May.
That is, at the beginning of June at the end of May.
Our data in Taiwan is actually very satisfactory to the government.
There was no epidemic until the end of May.
At the end of May, everyone was actually very nervous.
We felt that the epidemic was about to break out, and we did not know how dangerous it was.
We only knew that there were hundreds of people every day, and the number of deaths was constantly increasing.
We have a question that can be shared today.
If you can get the vaccine, will you get the vaccine?
There are more than 1,700 people in Taiwan who answer this question.
There are three options for more than 1,700 people to answer.
The first is that I will not get the vaccine.
The second is that I may or may not.
The third is that I will definitely get the vaccine.
In fact, we asked this question from March to May.
We can see a very obvious change.
That is, before mid-May, before the level 3 alert began, everyone did not want to get the vaccine.
Even though the Delta virus was already very serious at that time, it was already very serious in India and other countries.
But in Taiwan, you can't see the will of people who want to get the vaccine.
In addition, this model also shows that Taiwan does not particularly want to get the vaccine, at least in Shuangbei.
We know that this virus spread from Shuangbei.
But people in Shuangbei don't want to get the vaccine.
What does it tell us?
It tells us that you are in the same island.
You are in Taidong and Taipei.
In fact, the will of people who want to get the vaccine is the same.
What factors will affect the will of people who want to get the vaccine?
We can take a look here.
For example, if you often go to crowded places, or if you are sick, you will let the public health personnel know your situation.
This means that people with a high awareness of public health will want to get the vaccine.
It is believed that the government can use information technology to track people's whereabouts.
The stronger the government's control, the more people will want to get the vaccine.
People who use information technology to track people's whereabouts because of the epidemic will not want to get the vaccine.
This may be more against the government.
The more people you think the government gives you enough support, the more you want to get the vaccine.
The more you believe the government will want to get the vaccine.
The more you worry that fake news related to vaccines will cause harm, the more you want to get the vaccine.
O is openness, which is the openness of the personality test in psychology.
The more open your personality is, the more you want to get the vaccine.
This is also related to quality of life.
The higher your physical health, the more you want to get the vaccine.
Social relationships are negative.
We observe that this is a repressive phenomenon.
It is not so related to Y.
So it may be a model performance.
The more you worry about the physiological effect of the vaccine, the less you want to get the vaccine.
The more you think the vaccine is troublesome, the less you want to get the vaccine.
These are what we think are more reasonable.
Another study related to literature is that men want to get the vaccine more.
This may be a study we did in March and May.
At that time, Taiwan had a lot of information.
Because most of the vaccine discussion at that time was AZ.
AZ may have more side effects on young women.
Our source is young people.
So I found that men want to get the vaccine more.
This may be one of the possible reasons.
People over the age of 30 will want to get the vaccine more.
This is also reasonable.
The more you want to get the vaccine, the more you want to get the vaccine.
This is what we found.
What factors make people want to get the vaccine?
This is the result we found in the past 1-2 weeks.
Because we have been collecting and organizing data until now.
Start doing some analysis.
This is a small conclusion I want to share with you.
A small result.
It has nothing to do with the topic of today's speech.
This is another COVID-19-related survey we did.
I will share it here for the time being.
Thank you all.
See if you have any further questions.
We can all discuss here.
Thank you.
Thank you for the wonderful speech.
Now we are in Q&A time.
I saw a question on the chat room.
William, can you turn on your microphone and ask a question?
If you are still here.
Okay, he may not be here for the time being.
Let me repeat his question.
William asked how to avoid survivorship virus in this way.
People who can resist the distance may avoid traveling at the beginning.
This may be a participant's question.
Can you repeat the second question?
What kind of people will avoid traveling?
He may be the first question.
He is just talking about whether this participant is possible.
Some people are more resistant to isolation.
It is easier for him to avoid traveling.
Thank you for your question.
Of course, we have a lot of limitations in this study.
He mentioned the survival bias.
Of course, I don't think we have a lot of evidence.
I don't think we can avoid it.
It depends on whether you can avoid it or not.
We recruited this group of people because they are interested in this.
He is willing to participate.
These people have also experienced traveling.
Because we are looking for Taiwanese people.
He must be Taiwanese.
He can't be a foreigner.
Some people are afraid of COVID-19.
If isolation or quarantine affects him, he will not return to Taiwan.
This group of people were not in the range of our survivors at the beginning.
He must return to Taiwan to participate in this survey.
If he returns to Taiwan, he will be quarantined or quarantined before he can participate in the survey.
So we don't have this information.
If he wants to avoid traveling, what will he do?
If he wants to avoid traveling, he will not enter our survey subjects.
Of course, he will not face 14 days of isolation or quarantine.
Because they wanted to avoid traveling at the beginning.
He will not experience 14 days of isolation or quarantine.
So this is a bit out of our scope.
We can't handle it, we can't know.
We can only know which factors will affect him.
Because he was quarantined and quarantined, he wanted to leave.
So those who want to avoid this matter are not in our research range.
Yes, I also think this question is actually quite difficult to answer.
I don't know if William's answer just now
is in line with the information William wants to get.
If you want to continue to explain, you can look at the microphone
and ask these questions in depth.
I don't know if there are any other audience members who want to ask questions.
Hello, I'm Yiting.
I'm doing a post-doctoral research at the University of Taiwan.
We are also doing research related to COVID-19.
Our source of data is a safe zone in Taiwan.
We also saw some people who were quarantined
and called this safe zone for psychological support.
But because our sample wanted to get a group of people who were at higher risk of suicide.
Later, we did not include too many people in the group of people at higher risk of suicide.
But this group of people often mentioned financial stress.
I just saw that in your presentation, you also mentioned that
one of the factors that will lead to negative emotions is financial difficulties.
I would like to ask about the details.
In this project, usually in quarantine,
because it sounds like they are a group of younger people who came back from abroad.
They may be students or workers.
What kind of financial difficulties are they facing?
Or how do you ask this question?
This is my question. Thank you.
Thank you for Yiting's question.
Our question is, do you feel any pressure on finance?
Will finance give you any pressure?
From very little to very much.
We usually ask for a five-point chart.
Of course, we did not go into the details of what financial pressure is.
We think that since financial pressure will affect negative emotions,
it may be that he is working overseas,
he may leave his job,
or he knows that he is coming to Taiwan,
it will be difficult for him to continue his original job.
This kind of pressure affects his negative emotions and makes him want to leave.
Because we found that negative emotions are a big influence,
it makes him want to leave the idea of quarantine.
This anxiety and uneasiness can directly contribute to this negative emotion,
and it will affect him to want to leave the idea of quarantine.
We did not ask,
but the situation you can imagine should be that it will affect his work.
Because it should be okay to stay as a student.
Of course, we did not cross-compare.
Because of the restrictions on information,
we are not sure if he is a student or not.
He is still a working person.
We do not know.
But we know that the people who came back at that time were these two kinds of people.
Working overseas or studying abroad.
We found that this is one of the factors.
It may be similar to your research.
We are sure that these people are in quarantine or quarantine when researching and investigating.
Because some of our samples are completely in line with what I just described.
He is working abroad.
Because we are the information that comes to the store,
so it is a more straightforward organization analysis.
There are more specific mentions in it.
For example, his original job development,
Or maybe he used to do business in China or other countries.
After he suddenly returned to Taiwan,
he said that his dental development seemed to be interrupted.
Or the business is really bad.
So it doesn't matter.
It sounds like he subjectively believes that he has some economic pressure.
But in this questionnaire,
there may not be a more detailed part to understand his deep situation.
I think this is a good comment.
In fact, this is also limited to the source of our information.
We know that many people who are quarantined or quarantined do not necessarily come back from abroad.
After that, many people have been in contact with the confirmed person or have been in contact with the confirmed person.
He went to some places.
He may be locally, but he did not go abroad.
He may be affected by his work.
He can't go out to work.
There are no such people in the information we receive.
This is a pity.
Most of these people came back from abroad in their 90s.
So it may not be the same as yours.
However, the common point is that financial pressure is a big reason for negative emotions.
Sorry, I'll share it at the end.
It's about stigmatization.
We also have a very specific view of those who are really quarantined from abroad.
He complained that his neighbor put a label on him.
His family did not support him.
This really caused him a lot of anxiety and anger.
Some sense of hopelessness.
So I think from what the teacher just shared,
I think there are a lot of things that we see in another research.
We can echo each other.
Thank you very much for your presentation today.
Thank you.
In fact, if this can be done,
In fact, we can also do some direct and quantitative research.
My colleagues are also doing related research.
For example, Mr. Zenfanzi on hand.
He does medical sociology.
He may visit some people who are quarantined or quarantined.
Will he experience some stigmatization?
Or do you need any related resources?
If we can identify on quantification,
What are the reasons for the negative emotions of these people?
Or the reason for wanting to leave the quarantine.
The interview on quantification will be able to ask questions about these reasons.
This can supplement a lot of aspects that we can't see in the data.
So I think it should be possible to do more complete research.
That is to look at the follow-up.
This may be just the beginning.
I just mentioned that we
Sorry, I don't need to look for that information.
From January and February last year to July this year,
There are already 700,000 people who have experienced quarantine or quarantine.
In fact, there are 23 million people in Taiwan.
In fact, 700,000 people are already a lot.
About 3% of people have experienced 14 days of quarantine or quarantine.
A lot of people have experienced this.
Our research also hopes to find out what kind of pressure these people experience.
What kind of help can the government give?
What kind of help can the society give?
Stigmatization is definitely a big one.
Because the stigmatization he experienced is significantly higher.
We also found that the most people came from strangers.
Compared to relatives and friends, compared to acquaintances,
The stigmatization of strangers is the highest.
Got it. Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you, teachers and audience.
I don't know if I can take 5 to 10 more minutes from you.
Because our voting time was originally around 11 o'clock.
But I don't know if I can take 5 to 10 more minutes from the teacher.
Because I see that the audience seems to have a problem with Pan Haoren and Yanping.
No problem. We don't have a time limit.
Thank you, teacher.
No problem.
Let me invite Pan Haoren to ask the question first.
Thank you.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
Thank you.
Thank you, teacher.
My question is this.
Because most of this research was conducted last year.
This year, after the outbreak of the epidemic in Taiwan,
Now, in terms of double-digit, it is about 1 to 2 digits per day.
After this outbreak, the public sentiment in Taiwan may be a little different from last year.
For example, last year, everyone thought that there could not be a single N5.
As long as there is a single N5, it is a very bad situation.
But this year, until today, there are still some new cases in double-digit.
But people may not feel that panic.
I would like to ask the teacher,
In this different time and space between last year and this year,
What impact will it have on the non-compliance behavior of home isolationists or their source of pressure?
Thank you.
Is this the question?
Yes, thank you.
I want to think about it.
In fact, what I am doing now is a prediction.
Because I don't have this information.
Thank you Haoren for your question.
We only have information from March to May of last year.
Then quarantine or quarantine people.
Because this information is from May of last year.
Then we did another wave of research is the world.
Then we may have this information, but we have not analyzed it yet.
Because in the second piece of information I just mentioned, we actually asked if he was in isolation.
He has some people in isolation, but very few.
At that time, we just found very few people.
We found very few people in isolation.
I remember only a few.
So can you analyze a good conclusion?
I don't know.
I don't know about my information.
Unless there is a relevant study.
Looking for people who are in isolation or quarantine from May to July this year.
His negative mood or he wants to leave the idea of isolation.
Otherwise, we actually can't know this thing.
Then I want to turn around and ask what you think will be different.
Because in fact, I also need to think about it.
Because I can only say that we don't have this information.
I only have information from March to May of last year.
I only have a few people in this year's information.
We haven't actually analyzed the data of these people.
And what conclusions can a few people come up with?
We are also very conservative.
Do you think there will be any different results?
Is it just for these people who want to leave the isolation or the negative emotions of these people?
My personal guess is because the teacher just mentioned that there was a lot of isolation in the survey last year.
The source of the isolation may come from relatives and friends around them.
Or even some unknown neighbors.
Some pressure.
For example, the situation in Shuangbei or some more serious situations before the epidemic.
From a situation that has broken out.
So far, it has been slowed down to a phenomenon that should be controlled.
I'm wondering if people are more afraid of being isolated at home.
If so, the pressure from external public opinion may be reduced.
But I'm not sure if there will be such a situation.
After all, from last year's situation, I feel that as long as there is any local case, everyone will put the alert to the highest level.
I don't think there will be such a strong reaction now.
Thank you for your comment.
I think it makes sense.
If it is July or August, the degree of isolation may be smaller.
For example, many department stores or public transportation may not be able to work or work together.
At that time, if there is a collective diagnosis, it should be said that the diagnosis in the workplace should be smaller.
Because it's not voluntary.
But another type may be at the beginning of May or the middle of May.
For example, those who were found in some entertainment venues in Wanhua District may be highly insensitive to isolation or quarantine.
It may be different now, but we also have to think about the impact of other factors.
For example, the degree of satisfaction with the government in other aspects.
For example, there is no way to get a vaccine.
Because at that time, the vaccine was not a topic.
Now we can say that the number of vaccines and the proportion of vaccines is the key to this disease.
The key to fighting this disease.
There may be another issue now.
The two data are very different.
Last year's government satisfaction was very high.
When we received this group of people from March to May last year, their government satisfaction was very high.
They think that the information given by the government is very transparent and they support the government.
But this year, in May, the government satisfaction was not so high because of the sudden outbreak.
I believe that the government satisfaction should have dropped from May to July.
At that time, we don't know how much it will affect their emotions.
But this is very complicated.
I hope there will be related research on the isolation or quarantine from May to July.
But I don't know if there is.
Thank you.
I will ask Yen-Ping to ask the last question.
After Yen-Ping asks the question, I will stop recording.
Then everyone can ask questions more freely.
So I will give it to Yen-Ping first.
My question is as short as the conversation window above.
I want to ask what kind of negative emotions do you distinguish when you talk about negative emotions?
Like depression, anxiety, anger, sadness.
These should be different emotions.
Thank you.
I know that Yen-Ping is studying emotions, so I can't talk nonsense.
We have given him a list of depression.
They made a list of depression at the end of the isolation.
We asked him why he wanted to leave the isolation.
There are two reasons.
One is anxiety.
The other is negative emotions.
We don't distinguish too much.
Anxiety is there.
We have a list of depression.
But the list of depression is not in this list.
Of course it's all negative emotions.
But the list of depression was made after the isolation.
So there is a distinction, but there is no depression in its variables.
So in summary, the negative emotions are not so detailed.
But we have the degree of depression, but it is not in this model.
We think of it as a negative emotion of the acute stress syndrome.
This result is there, but not in this model.
Since Yen-Ping has raised a question, he should thank Yen-Ping.
Because the question of sunshine was raised by Yen-Ping.
Did these people experience sunshine?
Of course, whether or not you have experienced sunshine may affect negative emotions.
We found this later.
In another survey, I also found that sunshine is a very important variable.
For the sense of time, do these people know the current situation?
It also has a lot of decisive impact.
Sorry, I can only say that negative emotions are not so different.
But we have information, but it is not used in this model.
When I asked this question, I wanted to answer it after Yen-Ping.
Because I think that without Yen-Ping,
Yen-Ping's data may have this part of the analysis.
I don't know if you can communicate.
Although Yen-Ping's data is closer to real-life data,
because it is a secure brick line,
but it can do some coding.
The reason why I ask this question is because
sometimes people who are depressed lose their energy.
So he doesn't want to run away.
He thinks he should just die in his room.
But he won't run away.
What kind of person will run away?
If you have been in contact with me before, don't be scared.
There was a person in our community who was supposed to be quarantined at home.
He shouted in the hall, saying,
why is it me? I can't run away.
He was very angry and wanted to go out.
The police came.
It seems that people who are angry are easier to run away.
But people who are depressed don't seem to be.
So there seems to be a little difference between negative emotions.
My feeling is like this.
Some people even feel that they are invisible.
Even positive emotions.
But this kind of person will run away.
But if you are a very peaceful person,
I don't feel like I'm quarantining at home.
Then this kind of person won't run away.
So it doesn't seem to be just positive and negative.
It seems to have a lot to do with what kind of emotion.
I don't know my intuition.
Okay, I think it's a very good suggestion.
Let's go back and analyze this more.
I totally agree.
Because we also asked
In fact, there are also these questions in the depression table.
Do you think existence is meaningless?
I believe most of those people
I don't think I want to do anything.
Leave this matter
I just want to end my life.
There are indeed many different negative emotions.
Then we will explain it again.
But if we only talk about negative emotions,
It seems a bit too big.
Maybe I need to explain more.
Sorry, I can add here.
Are you Yiting?
Yes, I am Yiting.
I am now
My current mentor is doing suicide research.
So all of our data analysis
He is all focused on
He may be informed by some suicide-related theories.
So we are indeed
Psychological response related to suicide
Even in the process of coding
Can find six
Especially it will trigger the idea of ​​suicide
For example, he wants to feel hopeless.
He wants to feel insolvent.
Then his low mood may be just one of them.
I think it's just that we don't particularly
Because the purpose of the time when we were fishing
It's not to become a quarantiner or a non-quarantiner.
But that is to say, we don't have
We don't have this kind of analysis at the moment.
But like what Yanping mentioned just now
I think
In fact, in the data we have obtained
In fact, it is possible to put a group of us
We mark it on the identity label
Is it a quarantine or a quarantiner?
Then go to understand that the content of their call
Usually ask some of that
Just treat it as a 1922 question
In addition to that kind of question
In fact, there will be quite a lot of emotional parts.
We have mentioned that we have
We have seen that it is
It's not a very systematic analysis now.
It's just that when I read these diaries
I will hear that kind of
He may not be satisfied with his health needs.
For example, he needs to see a doctor.
He needs to get the medicine.
Then he may think
Or I think I am pregnant.
Then I want to find my current doctor to check.
Then these things may cause them to want to
Make a call
Is to release their heart
This feeling of wanting to leave but not leaving
This feeling of being trapped
But we haven't done a very systematic analysis yet.
So maybe this thing is quite interesting.
I can go back and discuss it with my mentor.
I think maybe it's an interesting topic.
In the psychological health part of the quarantine interpreter
I also want to ask Yiting
Is this information of Anxin special line
Are you still collecting?
What we currently have
In fact, it is also a bit similar.
Is that we are
What we are analyzing now is last year.
Uh, from the end of January to the end of May
Because Taiwan's first confirmed case
It seems to be January 23rd or 22nd.
Then our information is from that day
After a day
Start
Uh, until the end of May
Because in May
In fact, Taiwan was almost
There is no confirmed case.
Then this year we have
Consider that this wave of this year
Do we want to get it again?
But this is not yet
There is no conclusion like this.
But we have this question now.
Indeed, it is limited to last year.
When the first wave of Taiwan broke out
understand
Did they mention that contact?
Because we found that the more people we contact
The more people we contact
The more people he wants to leave
I don't know this
Because the nature of the security line is
Yes, because it is a bit like a
Secondary data analysis
Because we can't take the initiative to ask
Hey, which of our anti-corruption
Take the initiative to understand what the problems are
He is more of a messenger
He is willing to follow this
Uh, counselor
What is the content of this volunteer?
What can we hear
So this is a use
A restriction on the security line
Of course it is
Uh, yes, so he can't
As long as this person did not take the initiative to mention
We can't ask
There are quite a few people in it
Uh, say
His
I think
Hey, his social support is reduced
Even if we now
Analyze these 60 people
They have a higher suicide rate
They are
Uh, no
None of them are quarantined
But everyone generally still feels
From the end of January to the end of May last year
During this period
Even in Taiwan
Not very, very serious
But everyone has some anxiety
Everyone still thinks
Oh, at that time
Uh, social support seems to be reduced
Then I also feel some of my own
Uh, freedom of life
It seems to have some restrictions
Um, but we can't go
Analyze in detail
How many people are he in contact with
Thank you
That one
I know your analysis
Please say
I'm sorry, I'm sorry
I just wanted to respond to the issue
That is to say, I know your
Uh, the way of analysis may be
Then read first
Then do coding
Then, but there is a way
Uh, you can also refer to it
There is nothing to do
I put it on the dialogue box
It is a more like
Like uh
Is natural language processing
You just let the city scan these
If you have a text
Then he will give these text
Make some labels
Oh, then I put this thing on
It is quite common in psychology
Then I know this thing
This thing is called look
Then I know in the eyes of computer science
This is very
Basically the same as the tools of primitive people
They are newer
But what I mean is
Maybe in this way
You can explore it first
Because we
Uh, because I actually
We have a lot of other cooperators
Then we also have some
As far as I know, there are some
Researchers, they also use
For example, computer science
In the field of computer science
Then explain to us some
What is it like
Natural language learning and so on
To analyze the content of this teacher
Then we do have some
But for the epidemic
It doesn't seem to have accumulated so much
Is that we
After all, he has a lot of power
He may have tens of thousands of power in the next few months
So we have to start with this power
To have a meaningful analysis
Also in line with our research
Then we go back to the main text
So if it's during the epidemic
Our main text seems not to be able to do
This thing or I don't know
Maybe this thing you just put on
L I W C this thing
Uh, we can do it in 60 minutes
I don't know his
How much information does it take
To do this
60 minutes I think you can try
Um, but
It doesn't matter if it's long or short
It doesn't matter
You can try it
At most it is not
Hahaha
Because I know our other
Other members of the other team
They are just analyzing other things
Then they did
This kind of natural language learning
In general this way
For example, uh, the instructor
With the user
The analysis of the user
And there should have been some before
For example, oh, maybe it's for people with depression
Which words are they more likely to use
That's what they use
For example, people with schizophrenia
Which words are more likely to use
These studies seem to be ongoing
It's just that I'm with this one
I learned it this year
It's just a very preliminary exposure
So I'm not very familiar with it
But I can imagine maybe we have something now
It seems
Also
Uh, just use this method to analyze
Take a look, but we're stuck right now
It's not particularly stuck in the analysis
Because it's actually fast to read the text
It's the process of erasing the text
It's more time-consuming
Ok
Hey, I'm done
Hey, I'll leave it to you
In fact, we also have these people
The narrative of the text is that we
At the end of the collection of data
That day we have
Let these people review
Just this month
Related to the epidemic
What he wants to say to us
Some of the things he's been through
Or something that impressed him
We actually have one
Uh, if you just talked about this
Liwc
If this thing can be done
We don't have a system to look at
Because there are no experts in text processing
But maybe I think it's classification
Just
One question is
In my eyes
Did he experience isolation or isolation
This may be possible
He mentioned this thing
I think the judgment rate may be quite high
Maybe the next step is to ask
Uh, how high is his negative emotion
Because these are also
There are sets that can be used to see how negative the words he uses
Does he have any risks
These may all be done
But I think it's a pretty good direction
It's just that I don't have the data
But maybe I need to think about it
If psychology already has these
Tools
Then we should try
Ok
I don't know if there are any more
Thank you, Yanping
If I suggest
I'll stop recording first
Then let everyone ask
Okay, then I'll pause
To record