Hello everyone, welcome to today's Taira Talk on November 14th.
We are honored to have Yuli Xue as our speaker today.
She is currently a post-doctoral researcher at the University of New South Wales.
Her doctoral program is at Purdue University, EECS.
Her research focuses on physics and the defects in semiconductors.
Her research focuses on simulation, but has a close relationship with experiments.
Today's topic is the relaxation process of donor spin-tubing in silica.
Before we get started, let's give Yuli a round of applause.
Now we will hand over to Yuli.
Today I will be talking about how to use donor spin-tubing as a quantum computer.
And how the relaxation process plays an important role.
There are five parts to this talk.
The first part is about quantum computing.
There are many different types of quantum computing.
Some people use superconducting qubits, others use topological qubits.
Today I will focus on semiconductor qubits.
I will be using donor spin-tubing as a quantum computer.
Next I will talk about spin relaxation.
What does it have to do with quantum computing?
How does it help to calculate spin relaxation time?
Next I will talk about how to calculate spin relaxation time.
Lastly, I will talk about the results of the experiment.
The first part is about quantum computing.
What are the differences between classical and quantum computers?
For classical qubits, you can only choose either 0 or 1.
For quantum qubits, you can choose either 0 or 1.
This means that when you operate on quantum qubits, you can operate on 0 and 1 at the same time.
If you only have a single qubit, it doesn't seem very powerful.
However, if you have two qubits, you can operate on four states.
Quantum computers can operate on these four states at the same time.
If you have n qubits, you can operate on 2n qubits at the same time.
This is very powerful.
If you want to solve the riddle, you can try the first method.
If it doesn't work, you can try the second method.
If it doesn't work, you can try the third method.
Quantum computers can try 100 methods at a time.
Quantum computers can solve complex problems in a short time.
Quantum computers can be used widely.
For example, data security, database search, quantum chemistry, or machine learning.
Next, I will introduce the most basic unit of quantum computers.
Quantum computers are mainly composed of 0 and 1 like classical qubits.
Quantum computers can operate on 0 and 1 at the same time.
We use the block sphere as a representation.
Quantum computers can not only operate on two qubits, but also on a channel or other points.
This information is very important.
Quantum computers can use quantum operators such as linear or horizontal derivatives.
Quantum computers can also use quantum operators such as electron spin, downspin, offspin, nuclear spin, or upspin, downspin.
Quantum computers can also use quantum operators such as electron ground state and first excited state.
For example, if we take electron spin as an example,
1 is upspin, 0 is downspin.
This is our single qubit.
First, we need to add magnetic field.
Electron spin is a magnet.
When it is parallel to the magnetic field or in the opposite direction, its energy will be different.
When the energy of the magnetic field is split, the two states are separated.
If we want to operate electron spin, we can add an AC magnetic field.
If the frequency of the AC magnetic field and the energy of the AC magnetic field are matched,
a resonance will occur.
The resonance will go from 1 to 0, then to 1, then to 0, then to 1.
The definition of qubit operation is the time evolution of two coherent states.
For example, we can measure the qubit after a certain period of time.
We will find that the qubit is originally in state 1, but after a certain period of time, it becomes 0.
In this way, we can realize the NOT gate in logic design.
1 becomes 0, 0 becomes 1.
This is our single qubit operation.
If we have two qubits, the most famous gate is called CNOT gate.
CNOT gate means that when we have control qubit, control bit and target bit,
when the control bit is 0, the input is 0 and 1, and the output is 0 and 1.
When the control bit is 1, the input is 0 and 1, and the output is 0 and 1.
This is CNOT gate.
How to use electron spin?
There is an interaction between two electron spins called exchange interaction.
If they work, it means that when the control spin is in the up spin and it is in the down spin,
the effect of the second electron spin is different.
How is it different?
For example, when you turn to this channel, the speed of the precessed channel will be different.
For example, after tau z, the spin turns half a circle.
When you measure, the spin is still in the down spin.
But in this case, because the control spin is different from the other direction,
the spin turns faster.
Because of the interaction, the spin turns faster.
For example, after tau z, the spin turns half a circle.
When you measure, the spin is in the up spin.
Originally, the spin is in the down spin, but now it is in the up spin.
One spin is not changed, and the other spin is changed.
This is how CNOT gate is realized.
If we have a single qubit gate and CNOT gate,
we can do quantum computation,
which is to realize a universal quantum computation.
Next, we will introduce the donor spin qubit.
For example, we need an electron spin to store 0 and 1.
But we need to localize the electron spin.
For example, there are so many electrons in silicon solid.
How do we know which one we want to control?
The concept is that the silicon and the phosphorus are next to each other.
One has 14 electrons, and the other has 15 electrons.
When you take out a silicon and replace it with phosphorus,
it will have one more electron.
In this way, the electron will go around the sphere.
The premise is that the electron will not run away at low temperature.
If it is at high temperature, it will run away when the energy is high.
This is our main structure.
The advantage is that the strain is very small.
It does not squeeze to the side.
Because they are next to each other, the quality is very close.
In 1998, Bruce Kane proposed this proposal.
He said that he wanted to put phosphorus in a certain position,
confine an electron, and use it as a quantum computer.
First, we need to encode 0 and 1 in the electron's up-spin and down-spin,
or in the donor's up-spin and down-spin, or in the nuclear's up-spin and down-spin.
Next, we need a low temperature.
This way, the electron will run around here.
How do we realize the single-qubit gate and the two-qubit gate?
For the single-qubit gate, we can use the magnetic field of the AC.
We try to have resonance with it.
The resonance frequency can be controlled by the gate above.
For example, if the gate is positive, the electron will be sucked up.
In this way, the resonance frequency will change.
When the electron is sucked up, the distance between it and the nucleus is large,
and the interaction between them is small.
The interaction will affect the resonance frequency.
In this way, for example,
if the two-qubit gate is coupled with a different bias,
the two-qubit gate will have different resonance frequencies.
If we only want to operate the left-hand qubit,
we can tune the magnetic field of the AC to match the resonance frequency.
At this time, only the left-hand qubit will rotate,
and the right-hand qubit will not be affected.
In this way, we can operate the left-hand qubit or the right-hand qubit.
As for the two-qubit gate,
as mentioned earlier, the two electrons will have an exchange interaction.
If the J-gate in the middle does not turn on,
the two qubits will not interact.
Their interaction is very weak.
For example, if I add a qubit and suck two electrons in the middle,
their wave function overlap will be very large,
and their interaction will be very strong.
Then we can do the so-called C-knot gate.
Can you tell me how much is the ionization energy of this electron?
Or if you can use the photon frequency,
and what is the energy of the splitting next to it?
First of all, the ionization energy is 45.6 mEV.
So mEV is about gigahertz,
which is about this range.
For the Zeeman splitting,
the Zeeman splitting of the electron is also about 0.1 to 1 mEV.
If your magnetic field is between 1 Tesla to 10 Tesla,
your Zeeman splitting is also in the range of gigahertz.
If it is a nuclear spin,
then the Zeeman splitting will be about 1000 times smaller.
Don't tell me that your temperature is 100 mC.
Isn't that a bit too high?
Your thermal radiation seems to be in this range.
Too high.
Because if it is 1K,
it is about 100 gigahertz.
So if it is 100 mC,
it is about 10 gigahertz.
A little higher than you.
Isn't that too high?
You mean the energy difference is too small, right?
No, I mean,
in the environment of 100 mC photon bath,
all your states can be randomized.
Or you can analyze them directly.
Sorry.
Wait a minute.
Ted, your microphone is on.
There seems to be some noise over there.
Can you mute it directly?
Okay, I will mute it directly.
You can continue to discuss.
You mean photon or phonon?
Photon.
I just want to know
where is your operating energy scale now.
So what is the temperature of your environment
to become the so-called environment without interference?
There should be no photon here.
No, there are photons everywhere, right?
It should be phonon.
But it is phonon.
No, even if you are in the cryostat,
there will be thermal radiation if there is temperature.
Right?
Yes.
Otherwise, how do you define vacuum temperature?
Thermal radiation.
This is what the theorists are talking about now.
In the end, there may be real problems in the experiment.
We will see its performance later.
Okay, let me see if I can finish later.
Actually, I am quite curious about the different approaches.
For example, what is the difference between the cryostat and the constraint?
I am mainly curious about this.
Sorry, I am not sure if I can answer your question.
But we can discuss it later.
Okay, we can discuss it later.
Thank you.
I have a question here.
Hello.
Hi.
I have a question.
I think B and TESLA are quite big.
Why are they so different?
Yes.
The first B is for z-splitting.
It is connected to the resonance frequency.
It shows how much the AC magnetic field is.
However, its strength is different.
Its strength is depend on the Robeot oscillation.
But, its strength is quite slow eventually.
You don't have to be fast to use Robeot oscillation.
Because
So, your BAC will correspond to the size of the off-diagonal term.
Yes.
What is B?
B is the size of the Zeeman speeding.
It is the inch gap.
Yes.
Ok.
I am curious.
Why don't you need to use Robeot oscillation?
I am not sure how much T1 and T2 are in this system.
Can you tell me the number?
Why don't you want the quantum gate to be faster?
I am a little bit surprised.
Ok.
I am not sure how short the measurement time is.
Theoretically, T1 and T2 should be faster.
But, I am not sure what is the limitation in the experiment.
So, maybe I am wrong.
T1 and T2 should be faster.
However, T1 is a few seconds.
T2 is a few seconds.
I don't have a good number.
However,
the applied AC magnetic field allows Robeot oscillation to reach 10 nanoseconds.
So, it is pretty fast.
Thank you.
Ok.
I am sorry.
I can comment on this.
In the experiment,
the time resolution is about 1 nanosecond.
It is the shortest.
Ok. Thank you.
I am sorry.
Let me interrupt you.
Please tell us your name and
briefly introduce yourself.
Thank you.
Ok.
So,
I will continue.
we want to realize the proposal using STM technique.
What is STM technique?
You have a scanning tunneling microscope tip.
You can remove the silicon in a certain position.
Then, you can dope phosphorus in this position.
This is actually a very difficult technique.
In the past, we doped silicon in a more random way.
We did not particularly control where the phosphorus atom should be placed.
This scanning tunneling microscope technique can control this.
It controls this variable.
So,
Michelle Siemens Group
at UNSW
made a device that looks like this.
The gate and donor are made using STM.
So,
the gate is removed and the donor is placed.
You can control the shape of the gate and the donor.
Another difficult part is
to load and read the electrons on the donor.
In 2010,
Andrew Marlowe
used STM to control the Fermi level of the SCT.
This allows the electrons to be tunneled to the SCT
or from the SCT tunnel to the donor.
When the Fermi level of the SCT is
in the middle of the upspin and downspin,
only the upspin electrons can be tunneled to the SCT.
The downspin electrons cannot be tunneled to the SCT.
So, if you measure the current peak,
the electrons are on the upspin.
If you do not measure anything,
the electrons are on the downspin.
Then we can measure the electron spin.
So,
in 1998,
Ken proposed this proposal.
In 2010,
Andrew Marlowe did the electron spin readout.
In 2015,
he did the single-qubit gate operation.
In 2019,
he did the two-qubit gate operation.
Now,
we are going to build a large-scale quantum computer.
Sorry, can I interrupt?
I'm Ted.
Sure.
You just talked about the readout.
Can you tell us about the single-qubit gate in the middle?
Which electron does it send to the AC field?
It should be ESR.
Yes, it is ESR.
Well,
it is...
If it is ESR,
there is...
I did not draw it here.
There is a global...
You can produce a globalized AC field
and control it.
But there is no...
It is a top-gate or back-gate.
It is not a...
What are the advantages of the donor spin qubit?
First, it has a long coherence time.
For example,
the natural silicon is silicon 28.
The nuclear spin is 0.
It means
only the donor's nuclear spin and the electron's nuclear spin are not 0.
Most of the other spins have no interaction.
For example,
it has a long coherence time.
It has a clear boundary.
For example,
if you have a phosphorus donor,
it looks the same.
It is very helpful to scale up.
Next,
the semiconductor industry
has a very mature technology for silicon.
It can be applied later.
The disadvantage is
the STM technology
We need to control it very carefully.
We don't know this.
It is not good.
Let's introduce the donor spin qubit.
Next,
I have a question.
I want to introduce myself.
I am Zhang Yuanyong.
I am a high-performance physicist.
Before you works
before you repairs in the future,
How clean does vapor look?
Can we buy it?
Yes,
we just mentioned
the natural silicon is still
5% silicon-29
The silicon-29 means
there is a nuclear spin.
So,
the trend is
to use purified silicon
to minimize the silicon-29
So, the requirement is quite high.
I have a follow-up question
Is the purified silicon commercially available?
Or do we need to make it specially?
I think we need to make it
with a special factory
not a mass production
I'm not sure
but it seems like this
Ok, thank you
Ok, next I will introduce
what is spin relaxation
What is the importance of spin relaxation
or T1 time?
First, if you load an electron
and you want to read out
If you load in up spin
then it should be in up spin
if you read out
If it relaxes in this process
from up spin to down spin
you will have an error
a read out error
This error is quite fatal
We need a lot of design
If there is a fault tolerant quantum computer
can handle this error
The current design is
In the case of fidelity
99%
So we hope
in the case of fidelity
99%
so we hope
that the longer the spin relaxation time
the longer the spin relaxation time
So t 1
t 1
t 2