Hello, everyone. Welcome to the Terra Talk on November 21, 2020.
We are honored to have Dr. Tsing Ke, who just became Dr. Yin Chao yesterday, to give a speech.
The topic of his speech today is Neutron Irradiation Effect on Tom Stanford Nuclear Fusion Reactor.
If you don't know what ITER is, you can google it.
It is basically the world's largest nuclear fusion experiment or nuclear fusion reactor.
Before we start, let me introduce Dr. Yin Chao.
Dr. Yin Chao's main field of research is the field he will talk to us about today,
which is material science, especially nuclear materials, nuclear fusion, tungsten, and neutron irradiation.
In the past, Dr. Yin Chao obtained a master's degree from the Department of Materials at Taipei University of Science and Technology.
After obtaining a master's degree in the same place, he went to UC Berkeley's Department of Nuclear Engineering and obtained a master's degree.
After that, he is now at the Belize Nuclear Research Center,
and also obtained a doctor's degree from the Department of Materials at Ruwen University.
Dr. Yin Chao's research focuses on nuclear power plants floating on the ocean,
and the nuclear fusion reactor material.
Please turn on the microphone so that our speakers can hear our applause.
Let's give a round of applause to welcome Dr. Yin Chao for his speech.
Thank you for the introduction.
As I said earlier, my speech will focus on the neutron irradiation effect of nukes.
The nukes will be applied to the nuclear fusion reactor.
Let me introduce my unit first.
Our unit is called SCK-CEN.
SCK and CEN have the same meaning.
SCK stands for Belgian Nuclear Research Center,
and CEN stands for Belgian Nuclear Research Center.
Belize is a bilingual country.
Our unit is located in Mol, which is very close to the Netherlands.
Our unit has three reactors,
BR1, BR2, and BR3, which are the Belgian reactors 1, 2, and 3.
BR1 is the earliest reactor.
BR2 is the most recent reactor.
BR2 has a carbon-free reaction.
All the experiments today are conducted by BR2.
BR2 was originally designed for material testing.
But because of the collapse of nuclear power industry,
some nuclear accidents occurred,
like Chernobyl and Fukushima.
Since the nuclear industry has fallen,
there are not as many experiments to do the material test.
Since the nuclear industry has fallen, there are not as many experiments to do the material test.
Some part of it has been converted into medical isotopes
and half-body doping.
The BRS-3 was designed to train the nuclear industry.
But they decided to dismantle it due to some problems.
Now it is a place to study how to retire the nuclear power plant.
Our company built a Mira.
It is going to replace BR-1, BR-2, and BR-3.
It is a new reactor,
which is controlled by a accelerator.
It is a reactor and accelerator.
If you want to know more about our company,
you can come here.
Let's continue.
My speech will be divided into five sections.
First, I will introduce what nuclear fusion is,
what kind of reactor it is,
why we use it,
what materials I tested,
how I tested it,
and the radiation testing.
Next, I will introduce the development method.
I will introduce three methods of development,
three methods of improvement,
to measure radiation.
Next, I will tell you about
the result before and after radiation.
I will tell you about the result before and after radiation.
First, introduction.
As you know,
2 million years ago,
humans discovered fire.
The symbol of the discovery of fire
is that humans began to control chemical energy.
If we did not control chemical energy,
there would be no industrial revolution,
and there would be no modern society.
In the middle of the 20th century,
another important thing happened.
We discovered nuclear energy,
and we learned how to use the energy of nuclear fission
to generate electricity.
We have been using it for more than half a century.
Among them, nuclear fusion is the holy grail of nuclear energy.
If we can control nuclear fusion,
we can get relatively clean energy,
and it is also sustainable.
It can be used for thousands of years.
Because the raw materials can be directly planted in the sea,
or mining lithium.
So basically,
its fuel is non-negotiable.
In addition,
we can even use this energy to expand the universe
and explore in another galaxy.
Because as we know,
if you leave the solar system
or reach the solar system's borders,
you cannot use solar energy
because you are too far from the sun
or too far from any core.
So the efficiency of using solar energy is too low.
If you use chemical energy,
the chemical rocket will not reach that far.
Even if it reaches that far,
if you use a fuel cell,
it will soon run out of fuel.
So the only way is to use nuclear energy.
What is nuclear fusion?
Nuclear fusion is an example of
the reaction of copper and iron.
There are two lighter atoms,
copper and iron,
deuterium and trillium.
They combine to form a heavier atom,
helium,
and release a neutron.
Then you can...
Sorry.
You can see from the picture on the right
that the energy released by fusion
is much higher than that of fission.
This is why we say
that nuclear fusion is the Holy Grail of nuclear energy.
Because the energy obtained
from the same amount of fuel
is about four or five times that of fusion.
Scientists are now studying
how to control nuclear fusion.
There are several types of reactors
that have been proposed.
If you want to make a general classification,
you can classify them into
magnetic fields and inertial fields.
The most famous of the magnetic fields
is the Tokens.
It is also called ITER.
ITER means the way in Latin.
The other one is the Stellarator.
The Stellarator is a centrifuge.
The most famous centrifuge is
the Winchester 7X in Germany.
The most famous inertial confinement
is the National Ignition Facility in the United States.
The National Ignition Facility
in the United States
has a slightly different way
of generating nuclear fusion.
The way it is confined
is the same as its name.
It uses a magnetic field
to confine the electric field.
The electric field is heated to
more than 1.5 billion degrees
to generate nuclear fusion.
The inertial confinement
uses a lot of lasers.
It hits the fuel capsule
to generate high-temperature high-pressure
and small nuclear explosions.
It is a controllable light explosion.
Among all the reactors
I just mentioned,
the one that is the closest
to commercialization
is Tokamak.
The most famous one is ITER.
This is its diagram.
As I mentioned,
ITER uses magnetic field
and the fuel is
a blade and a wire.
The design of the reactor
is postmode,
which is a kind of
pulse-mode reactor.
When the nuclear reaction occurs,
it releases high-energy neutrons
and high-temperature electrons
along the magnetic field.
The high-temperature electrons
are brought along the magnetic field
to the diverter,
which is the red part.
The diverter receives
high neutrons and high-temperature electrons
and is a pulse-mode reactor.
This is a very challenging
and rigorous challenge.
What is a diverter?
You can see the structure of a diverter.
The diverter cassette
is composed of many plasma-facing units.
You can see the plasma-facing units
are arranged one by one.
Each unit is composed of
several tungsten monoblocks
and is connected by a tube.
The tube is used to
let the coolant flow through.
You can see that
in a steady-state operation,
10 MW per m2
is deposited
on the surface of the material.
You can see that
the surface temperature
rises to 1,200 °C.
The temperature drop
is only 8 mm.
This is a very serious impact
on the material.
In addition,
it is a pulse-mode reactor,
which produces fatigue.
The temperature is very high.
It is like the temperature
produced by friction
when a spaceship enters the atmosphere.
This is a very extreme condition.
Why do we choose to use lead?
Because lead has the highest concentration
in all metals.
In addition, it is basically pure metal
and has a relatively small
concentration after oxidation.
In addition,
it is not easy to
keep the fuel in it.
However,
it is very brittle
at low temperature.
It is a bit like ceramic.
Why does this happen?
As you may have heard,
iron becomes brittle
at low temperature.
It does not become brittle
when you hit it.
This is the case
in BCC,
which is also a metal of
high temperature.
In addition,
the temperature may rise to 2,000 degrees
when there is a special situation.
In October,
it is like a solar flare.
It suddenly releases a lot of heat
and the surface becomes
more than 2,000 degrees.
This will cause the mechanical properties
of the material to deteriorate.
In addition,
there will be some
transmutation elements
due to lead oxidation.
This is why
different materials
are developed.
Urethane and
high deformation
materials
have a good feature.
Their DBTT,
which I just talked about,
will become brittle
when it is transformed.
The material that was transformed
will become as brittle as ceramic.
The temperature of transformation
is DBTT.
This is called transformation temperature.
In addition,
they also propose
Particle Reinforced Tonsils,
which contains some
oxidized or oxidized materials
to stabilize the grain boundary.
The heat stability
will be higher.
DBTT is the same.
It will contain some
fake elements
to stabilize the boundary.
It can suppress the phenomenon
of mechanical growth and tightness.
I have a question.
We also do a lot of
neutron scattering experiments.
We do particle physics,
so we care about
the energy of each neutron
more than the total energy
multiplied by its flux.
Do you care about the energy of neutrons
more than the total energy
multiplied by its flux?
We care about both.
I will talk about it later.
What I am talking about now
is the manufacturing process.
The material is brittle
when it is at room temperature.
It is difficult to process.
So we use cross-sectional molding
and spot plasma sintering
to reduce the number of processing.
So the final product will be produced.
They propose so many
different materials
but they never do the test.
When designing DBTT,
you need to consider
the strict conditions
for the machine to perform well.
So they need this kind of data.
So my PhD thesis is
to assess these
high-temperature neutron elation effects.
The conditions are
the highest temperature is 1200°C
based on the operation of the ETH diverter.
The ETH diverter's
end-of-life
which is the highest cumulative mass
is less than 1 dPa
which is displacement per atom.
Displacement per atom
is a method to calculate
how many times the atom is moved.
The higher the number,
the higher the displacement per atom.
Hello, can I ask a question?
Yes, you can.
I'm working in nuclear engineering
at Utah University.
So I've touched a lot of these.
So you said the temperature is very high
and it has displacement per atom.
But if the temperature is high
and you heat it up,
it will return to its original state.
Will it be able to repair itself?
It will repair itself.
But what I'm trying to say is
the calculation
because the displacement per atom
is not really displacement per atom.
It's interstitial or vacancy.
So the purpose of the cumulative dPa
is to calculate the fluence.
Because the neutron source
and the iron source
and the electron source
all have dPa.
They all have their own fluence.
So the purpose of the dPa
is to have a match
between the damage and the fluence.
It's just a comparison.
It's not that the density of the voice
will be that high or that low.
Because at different temperatures,
like what you said,
it will have a different effect.
Thank you.
We have a total of 12 materials
that are being studied.
One of them is a multi-crystalline material
and the other is a single-crystalline material.
If the multi-crystalline material
is divided by the composition of the material,
it will be divided into a pure material
or a particle-reinforced material
or a non-crystalline material.
For the pure material,
it's either purchased
or provided by different research units.
So IGP is made in Australia.
ATW is made in China.
IGA is made in Japan.
Particle-reinforced tungsten
contains some things like
zirconium carbide or titanium carbide
and ethane oxide.
For the tungsten alloys,
as I mentioned earlier,
it contains DOPE and
ferric alloy.
KR is ferric alloy.
If you divide it by the composition,
you can also divide it into three categories.
There are rolled and forged materials.
The advanced process is
spark plasma sintering.
The last one, recrystallized tungsten,
is a reference group.
It's to increase the structure of the fiber
and let us know more about
the impact of the corrosion.
If we divide it by the volume,
we can divide it into two types.
The first one is elongated grains.
You can see that
only IGP is carrier-like grains
because it's double forged.
It's broken on both sides.
So it's elongated and
looks like fiber.
The other materials are rolled,
so it's flat and pancake-like.
It's like a pancake.
The remaining four materials,
advanced process and recrystallized tungsten,
are all equal axis grains.
It's not particularly long.
The four pieces I use are all
metatrized samples.
You can see that it's only 12 mm in size.
It's about a dollar in size.
The elongated grains,
the forged and rolled tungsten,
are metatrized,
so their mechanical properties are ideal.
They have different properties in different directions.
So we took two directions to analyze.
How do we define the direction?
It's determined by the position
of the material when it breaks
If the broken surface is perpendicular
to the elongated grain,
we say it's an L-sample or LT-sample.
If it's parallel to the elongated grain,
we say it's a TL-sample.
There are four tests
applied in our experiment.
The first one is fractured tungsten,
which has a black line in the middle.
We used EDM to cut it
in a power-generating way,
and we cut out a small hole.
This small hole can be used
as a crack,
and it can be used
as a crack hole,
so we can test
the resistance of the crack hole expansion.
In the end,
we cut out the fragment.
Tensile test is the most common
mechanical property.
The test is mainly for
measuring the force-force curve,
compressive strength,
elongation strength,
and some elongation properties.
The third one is
3-point bending test.
The 3-point bending test
mainly tests the bending nature,
including bending force and bending hardness.
In our experiment,
we tested the 3-point bending test.
The last one is
micro-indentation test.
This is a very simple test.
I used an indenter
to press a crack on the surface of the material
to measure its size and hardness.
If the indent is small,
the hardness will be high.
The 3-point bending test
is different from the previous ones.
Neutron irradiation is
done in Fission Reactor 2.
As we all know,
fusion and fission are very different
in the neutron spectrum.
Fission has a very high
thermoneutron flux.
In order to make the spectrum
as close to fusion as possible,
we need to block
the thermoneutrons.
We use a steel capsule
to cover the sample
to block the thermoneutrons.
In addition,
we put the capsule
in the middle of the fuel channel
to reduce the thermoneutrons.
In addition,
we need to perform
high-temperature experiments.
The high-temperature experiment
is because the sample
will be gamma-heated in the fusion reactor.
The temperature of the sample
will be higher
if we reduce the thermoneutrons
and lower the temperature
if we increase the thermoneutrons.
We use a spacer pin
to control the distance
between the sample and the capsule.
The shorter the distance,
the lower the temperature.
Here are the three tests
that I developed and improved.
The first one is
the Fracture Time Detect
and the Sturman Bending Test.
I combined the two tests
because most of the standard tests
are aimed at steel.
We all know that
steel is a high-temperature material.
However,
we can't test the material
directly with the ANC standard.
We can't test the material
This is an improvement.
You can see that
the Fracture Time Detect
and the Sturman Bending Test
increase with the temperature.
When I combine the two curves,
you can see that
they are basically the same.
I can define a DVTT
when the Fracture Strength
is equal to 5%,
the Fracture Toughness
is equal to 5%
and the Fracture Strength
is equal to 5%.
This can be used
as a DVTT definition.
However,
you will find that
the DVTT can't be used
as a DVTT definition.
We can use the ANC test
to support or even replace
the Fracture Time Detect.
You can see that
the geometry of the sample
and the test setup are simpler.
It can reduce a lot of costs.
I have a question.
I can understand that
but do you have a goal?
For example,
what kind of spec do you want to achieve?
What do you mean?
For example,
what kind of data do you want to improve?
Do you have a goal
to meet the future needs?
Our goal is
to reduce the number of tests
and to reduce the number of samples.
When we do this kind of test,
the space of the reactor is limited.
The number of samples
is also limited.
Any experiment requires
high-intensity protection
and a lot of regulations.
For example,
a tensile sample
costs 5,000 euros.
So your focus is on
developing a way to test.
Yes.
What kind of value do you want to test?
The value I want to test
is the same as the standard.
I can use it to replace the standard.
I see.
So you don't do any value-changing?
The value-changing part
is done by other institutes.
I mentioned it just now.
I do the final approval.
It takes a lot of time to do the final approval.
I didn't talk about the time it takes.
For example,
I have to wait a year
for the final approval.
After the final approval,
you can't do it right away
because it's too high-intensity.
You have to cool it down
for half a year or even 10 months.
I don't have half the time
I can ask you a question.
Your BR2 Reactor.
I used the Belgian Reactor
as a benchmark.
Is this called Venus?
Is BR2 Venus?
Venus.
They used to build a reactor
for PWR vessel material testing.
They modified it.
I don't know if it's called Venus.
I've never heard of Venus.
Can I ask how much power
does your reactor have?
1 MW?
I don't remember.
I think it's 50 MW.
I have a suggestion.
You used steel for the capsule, right?
You want to block the thermoneutron, right?
Thermoneutron interaction
seems to be better with light material.
If the temperature of the reactor
is not too high,
polyethylene seems to be better.
Thermoneutron cross-section
is bigger.
If you use light elements
to block the thermoneutron,
will it be easier to produce more thermoneutron?
Because you reduce the number of neutrons.
So you basically use boron.
But boron will affect the reactivity.
Yes, so it will be more complicated.
They won't let you do that.
Thank you.
So,
based on the conclusion we just made,
we can come up with a method
similar to the ASTM standard
to test the temperature of the steel.
So here,
we only need one test temperature.
So we only need one temperature
to do the experiment.
We use the three-point slope
to get the slope of the curve.
Then,
we need to make two assumptions.
One is 23 MPa square meter,
which is the DPA we just defined.
The other is Kbase,
which is the lowest value of the curve.
Why do I use 5 to 10 here?
Because 5 to 10 doesn't affect
the curve during the transition period.
The result is basically the same.
So we can deduce the curve.
This is the deduced curve.
This is the experiment value.
You can see that it is quite consistent.
So you can see that IGP,
its elasticity is better than ATW,
but its dBtt is slightly higher than ATW.
The second test method we developed
is the Interrupted Tensile Test.
Generally, the tensile test is to pull it all the way,
until it breaks.
After we get the whole curve,
we will see the tensile strength.
But we do it differently.
We will see the tensile strength
when it reaches the tensile strength.
So how do we measure the tensile strength?
First, we provide a load.
You can see the stress goes up.
The load rate is the slope of the stress.
When the load reaches the half of its maximum value,
we stop the test.
We can stop the test
at a place close to the tensile strength.
At that point,
there is no major deformation
so it has no effect on its fiber structure.
When the load reaches the half of its maximum value,
we stop the test
at a place close to the tensile strength.
At that point,
there is no major deformation
so it has no effect on its fiber structure.
At that point,
there is no major deformation
so it has no effect on its fiber structure.
At that point,
we can see that this is a DBT range.
The advantage is that we only need one test piece.
This will save us more time.
You can see that the HMLR
is higher than the upper yaw strength.
The HMLR is higher than the upper yaw strength.
This experiment is very suitable for
the materials with the HMLR.
The materials with the HMLR.
You can see that the HMLR
is a drop in the HMLR point.
The HMLR is a drop in the HMLR point.
You have to be careful to control it,
because we don't want it to deform,
so you have to be careful to control the drop point.
So you have to be careful to control the drop point.
The third,
the last,
one that I introduced and we developed
a testing method.
This test method is very small.
A little test method.
It is an Indian test related to Danjin.
As we all know,
Danjin has a mechanical phenomenon.
In other words, it will have different mechanical reactions
in different directions.
So when it was doing the Indian test,
there was a similar phenomenon.
So when I pressed an indent,
I moved it to another place,
rotated it, and pressed it again.
You will find that the four pictures on the right
are rotated at 0, 15, 30, and 45 degrees respectively.
You will see that their shapes are different.
When we calculate the hardness,
the traditional method is called Diagonal.
So it is its diagonal.
Because its shape is different,
its diagonal is also different.
Then the diagonal is different,
the hardness you deduced is also different.
So there is a fluctuation.
What I use here is the True Project Area.
It will also be different.
The whole black part,
I just use this to calculate.
Then it will also be different.
Why is it different?
Because in Danjin,
we can use the Schwarzschild-Schmidt Law
to explain.
The Schwarzschild-Schmidt Law is related to
the relationship between the stretching force
and the cutting force.
It is related to the slip plane of the material.
It is related to the sliding system.
So if the relative angle of your sliding system
changes,
your M value will change.
If your M value changes,
your cutting force will also change.
So when your material is deforming,
your dislocation glide
will also require a different force.
So the deformation of the indent
you just saw will be different.
So we came up with a small
suggestion for future experiments.
Because basically,
there are a lot of people doing low-quantity
photocopying experiments,
such as 0.0dPa.
In this situation,
the irradiation hardening
is usually quite low.
If you don't take this into account,
the anisotropic indentation,
the hardness,
will cause some of your trends
to be a little weird,
to be disordered.
So we came up with this.
Because the indent we used
as you can see,
is a Victor hardness indenter.
It has four faces.
So basically,
the change it produces
is a cycle of 90 degrees.
So it's a sine function.
So the way we propose is that
you can do an experiment
at three different angles.
This is an indentation experiment.
Then,
by fitting this sine function,
you get H0.
This is a very accurate value.
It's a more uniform value.
You can use it to compare
the material hardening.
If you don't know
your crystallography direction,
which means you don't know
where your energy is coming from,
we suggest you use 8%
to represent your uncertainty.
Because we found that
no matter how the radiation temperature changes,
basically,
the amplitude is about 8%.
Here are the unradiated results.
So this is the general tensile property.
It's the tensile property.
As you can see from the right,
in the experiment at 400 and 600 degrees,
you can see that
the Zirconium carbide-reinforced tungsten
has the highest strength,
which is the brown line.
Before that,
I'd like to introduce
what uniform elongation is,
and what early necking is.
Uniform elongation is
the strength between
the yield strength and UTS,
which is the tensile strength
between the yield strength
and the tensile strength.
This is the uniform elongation.
If there is no uniform elongation,
this phenomenon is called early necking.
At 500 degrees,
which is 400 degrees,
you can see that
basically all materials
have different levels of uniform elongation,
except T-orientation,
which is the material
in the T-direction,
and L-orientation.
When you raise the temperature to more than 500 degrees,
you will find that
those with mechanical processing,
such as rolling and forging materials,
they all become early necking.
Their uniform elongation disappears.
However,
those tungsten with advanced processing
still have the phenomenon
of uniform elongation.
Because of their uniform elongation,
their work-hardening capacity is better.
Here we also analyze
the relative properties of fracture strength.
You can see that
IGP,
we use the machine
of fracture strength
and fracture strength
to evaluate their fracture resistance,
which is their toughness.
Basically,
when you multiply strength and toughness,
it is energy.
So we can know
how much energy
the material needs
to resist the fracture.
You can see that
IGP-L needs the highest energy,
so its fracture resistance is the highest.
In addition,
we will find that
in different directions,
the fracture strength of the same material
in different directions
is different.
You can see that
L's fracture strength
is higher than T's.
Although their waist strength
and ultimate waist strength
are basically the same material,
but their fracture strength is much worse.
Why is that?
Here is a possible explanation.
Because their fracture strength is different.
You can see that
the fracture strength of L's sample
on the right is like this.
So if you crack
and propagate,
the weakest part of the material
is the fracture strength.
So basically,
your fractures like to have fracture strength.
When you expand the fracture strength
in L's sample,
it will usually come across
the middle of the fracture strength.
Either it deviates
or it goes through.
When it goes through,
the energy needed
and the force needed
will be higher.
So why is L's fracture strength
higher than T's?
T's fracture strength
is basically parallel
to the fracture surface.
So basically,
it just goes through.
So it's easier to have
premature fracture.
On the right,
you can see that
the triple junction
is the junction point
of the three meridians.
Basically,
the force will be concentrated here.
You can see that
L's sample has more force concentration.
That is to say,
under the same force,
the force they share
is smaller.
This is why
the fracture strength is higher.
As for T's,
it has less triple junction.
This is why
it's easier to have
premature fracture.
So these two points
add up to
T's fracture strength
which is lower than L's.
Here, we use 3-point contour
to measure DVTT.
As I mentioned earlier,
we can use it
to replace fracture toughness
to understand DVTT.
We did a test here.
We found that
L's DVTT
is lower than T's.
That is to say,
L can deform
at a lower temperature.
However,
T can't.
Let me remind you that
T and TL
have the same fracture strength.
L and LT are the same.
But I use different symbols
because T is for
8-centimeter fissure
and TL is for
3-point contour fissure.
As you can see,
Advanced Tungsten Grade
has higher DVTT.
As for
Heavily Formed Tungsten
and Tungsten Alloy,
Tungsten Alloy
has lower DVTT
than 100°C.
Why is this the case?
Why is Advanced Tungsten Grade
has higher DVTT?
We found that
if you have
Raw and Forged Tungsten,
their
Low Angle Ground Boundary Density
is higher.
What is Low Angle Ground Boundary?
Low Angle Ground Boundary is
the boundary between
the two
less than 15°C.
The boundary
is Low Angle Ground Boundary.
Low Angle Ground Boundary
can have
dislocation nuclei
on top of it.
They can generate
a new dislocation source.
If you have more
Low Angle Ground Boundary,
you can have more dislocation.
I just mentioned that
you must have dislocation
to have Plasticity Formation.
That's what I was talking about
when I talked about the
single-strand boundary.
The more dislocation you have,
the more likely you are to have
Plasticity Formation at low temperature.
That's why
these fissures
have lower Plasticity Formation.
We have analyzed
the difference between
Fracture Surface and
Fissure Pattern.
On the left,
you can see the IGP,
Commercial Tungsten.
This is the tungsten
purchased by the company.
Fracture Pattern
is closely related
to Fissure Pattern.
Its denomination is
these small cracks.
These cracks
appear when the temperature is over 400°C.
Why do these cracks
look like this?
Why do these cracks look like this?
We can explain it
from the perspective of the crystal.
You can see the L-sample,
the sample above.
You can imagine the crystal
protruding from the screen
pointing at you.
As I mentioned,
the Wicked String
is the weakest.
The cracks like to go that way.
You can see the cracks
going along the crystal
or crossing.
The T-Orientation
is like this.
The crystal
is arranged one by one
on the screen.
It's like when you fold
a piece of wood.
If you fold it along the fiber,
it will look like this.
As for the Advanced Tungsten Grade,
their crystal is basically
in the same axis.
The cracks are easily
to go along the crystal
or cross the crystal.
They are extended
along the crystal.
They are basically
many intergranular fractures.
There are also partial
trans-crystal fractures.
Trans-crystal fractures are
pointed by the green lens
which is the
trans-crystal fractures.
The trans-crystal fractures
show the grain shape.
At higher temperatures,
we can only see
the fine grain
which is called FG.
There are also dimples
which show the cracks.
Let's talk about
Irradiated Results.
As I mentioned,
we also applied
the Inter-Rodent Tensile Type
to Irradiated Tungsten.
We can see the results.
We have estimated
the DVT-T.
You can see the two materials
of DVT-T.
Recoil-Covered Reinforced Tungsten
and ATW,
which is commercial tungsten.
Their DVT-Shift
is almost the same,
which is 200 to 250 degrees.
Why do we have a range here?
Although these points
have been measured
to see if they are irradiated,
their large
refractive deformation
is basically non-existent.
They have small refractive deformation,
which means that the
refractive electric field
is directly cut off.
As you can see,
the transition curve
basically has a range.
Therefore,
there is such a phenomenon.
When there is a transition range,
the refractive deformation
is relatively small.
As you can see,
the stress increase
of the two materials
is basically
doubled.
Here,
I did some tests
of Frager-Thomas.
You can see that
Frager-Thomas's
refractive deformation
increases as the
refractive field increases.
Here, I tested
the temperature at 600 degrees,
so all the points are made at 600 degrees.
The radiation condition
is also at 600 degrees.
As you can see,
when the
DPA of the radiation is getting higher
to 0.7,
it basically
reduces the
refractive deformation
of the material.
In other words,
it becomes
brittle.
It basically becomes very brittle.
In addition,
we also found that
the
tungsten of
ATW
also increases
the refractive deformation
as the
refractive field
increases.
This can prove
that the
refractive field
also goes
directly
through the
crystal.
It's not just
the crystal.
We also did
the Transition Curve Estimation.
I just mentioned that
the 23 MPa root meter
cannot be used.
Why?
Because it cannot be used,
we need two
experiment temperatures
to do the
Transition Curve Estimation.
Because we have
the reference
Frasier-Thompson test,
the non-irradiated
Frasier-Thompson test
uses the Frasier-Thompson test.
The K-base is 47,
and the rest is calculation.
As I mentioned,
the 23 MPa
root meter cannot be used,
so we redefine the DPET
as Tf.
Tf is the
anti-curve point.
The curve anti-curve point.
As you can see,
after the radiation,
the
Tf
drops to
23 MPa.
Why?
Because
the Tf
drops to
23 MPa,
and the DPET
goes higher.
If I use the anti-curve point
as the definition,
the IGP
grows only 20 degrees.
If I use the
anti-curve point as the
definition,
the ATW
grows 100 degrees.
If I use the anti-curve point
as the definition,
the ATW
grows 200 degrees.
The last curve,
the green curve,
is not a good fit.
The K-top
is too close
to the K-base.
The fitting is weird.
We need
a higher temperature
for the test,
so we can get more
experimental points.
But as we
saw,
we can say
the point on the right,
the 0.7,
the DPA
is higher than 600 degrees.
No,
the DPETT is higher than 600 degrees.
Here,
we use the hardness test
to evaluate the
irradiation harmony,
which is the hardness
after corrosion.
As you can see,
the highest change
in most materials
is in
irradiation harmony
at 1000 degrees.
At higher temperature,
as we mentioned,
there will be annealing.
Many DPETTs are annealed,
so the temperature drops.
But it's still high,
as you can see,
it's similar to 600 degrees.
We haven't done
the TEM yet,
but we are doing it.
We need to prepare the TEM
and use GLOBAL,
so we need to do it directly.
Many materials
have high irradiation harmony,
so we are still waiting for it to cool down.
We haven't done
the TEM yet,
but according to the document,
at higher temperature,
the chance of voice
will be higher,
the voice density
will be higher than
the dislocation density.
So,
these two parts
are composed of voice.
At 1200 degrees,
the voice density will be higher.
In addition,
the current theory
states that
the higher the range,
the more
irradiation-induced defects
can be absorbed.
So, the higher the range,
the lower the irradiation harmony.
However,
IGP is higher than
IGA,
even though
it has a lower
voice density.
Here is
a possible explanation.
IGA and IGP
are pure materials.
Because
of the
self-insidious atom,
which is a
it will produce
Frenkel pairs,
which is a
self-insidious atom
and a vacuum.
The self-insidious atom
will form an elliptical structure
in the BCC,
which has a
very low
dispersion energy.
Therefore,
the self-insidious atom
can move
in 3D.
Therefore,
the self-insidious atom
is more likely to be absorbed by the range
and leave a lot of vacuum.
After that,
the voice
is higher than
the irradiation harmony.
That's why IGA
has a higher voice density
even though
it has a higher range.
In addition,
we also know that
hardness and strength
are proportional.
Therefore,
we try to
evaluate
the growth of
the curve
of the waist strength
and temperature
after irradiation.
Here,
we can see
that the brown line
is the fractional strength.
If it intersects
with the color line,
it is basically
the dBTT.
The dark gray line
is the dBTT,
which is the position
of the rotation temperature.
However,
all of them are not exposed.
Only IGP is exposed.
Therefore, we can suggest
that IGA has a better
resistance to irradiation damage.
However,
we can see that
the strength
is doubled.
The fractional strength
is also doubled.
The last point is the broken point.
The broken point is also
doubled.
These brown lines
should go up.
Therefore,
we can't say
where the dBTT is.
However,
we can only say
whether the resistance
to irradiation is strong or not.
We can only say that IGP
and Zirconia Carbide Tonsil
have a better resistance to irradiation.
In addition,
all of these hardness tests
are done at room temperature.
Therefore,
some things
need to be considered
before making
the final decision.
Therefore,
we still need
some high-temperature
hardness tests
to verify.
Fortunately,
we will soon have
a high-temperature
hardness test device.
We will move it
to the control area
so that we can verify
whether the results
are correct or not.
Finally,
we can see
the single crystal tungsten
that we used
the unbiased hardness
to test.
As I mentioned earlier,
the hardness fluctuates
depending on the rotation angle.
Therefore,
if you don't have H0,
you won't be able to figure out
the exact temperature.
If you use H0,
you will find that
the highest temperature
for hardening
is 800°C.
800°C is
the highest temperature
for tungsten welding.
After that,
annealing occurs
and the temperature drops slowly.
Finally,
I will summarize
the irradiation results.
You can see that
the fractional tungsten test
and the internal temperature test
are used
to evaluate the growth rate
of dPtT.
You can see that
the growth rate of IgP
is about 0.1 dPa,
which is much lower than AtW.
AtW will
grow to
about 300°C
at 1 dPa.
At 300°C,
the cone covering
will grow to about 250°C.
I will also summarize
the results
after hardening.
You can see that
the results of the tensile test
are very similar to
the hardness evaluation.
The curves I mentioned
can be used as a reference.
They are basically the same
as the tensile test.
In addition,
AtW and IgP
have similar density.
You can also see
that their hardness
is similar.
The theory
may be correct.
In addition,
we can also see
the hardness
of the materials
at different temperatures.
You can see that
most materials
decrease at 1200°C,
except
titanium carbide reinforced tungsten.
This is a very special phenomenon.
We need to
use TEM to study further.
Because
there is no annealing,
the crack does not disappear.
It does not become larger
or self-expand.
It is a very special phenomenon.
We need to
further
analyze it
with electromagnetic microscope.
In conclusion,
this is a very simple
take-away note.
I have developed
three different
testing methods.
The first one is
Miniaturized Sturmanium Test
and Fracture Tungsten Test.
These tests evaluate
the growth rate of
DVDT and
its curve.
Interpolated Tensile Test
is a test
that can measure
the strength of
different temperatures
with a single test.
The last one is
Unbiased Hardness Test.
With this test,
we can get
accurate hardness
and hardness measurement
on a single test.
In addition,
as I mentioned earlier,
we use
mechanical testing
and observation of
fiber structure.
We found that
the higher the
membrane boundary density,
the lower the temperature
of the material.
In addition,
we found that
although IGP
does not have
a high density,
its hardness
is relatively low.
Therefore,
increasing the density
does not necessarily
reduce the hardness.
This theory may be
based on very small
nanometers.
This theory may be
based on very small
nanometers.
This theory may be
based on very small
nanometers.
Thank you.
Any questions?
There is a general question.
We all know that
material is expensive.
How much do you need
in Fusion Reactor?
Will it affect
Fusion Reactor?
Basically,
if you want to
use a magnetic field
or a laser,
you have to spend a lot of electricity.
If you want to use wood,
what do you think?
Because I play Fusion Reactor.
I have always been interested in Fusion Reactor.
But I don't know much about it.
Thank you.
What about the material?
The material is
about 900 tons.
The material is about 900 tons.
900 tons
1 kg of material
is not that expensive.
It's not that expensive.
1 kg of material
is less than 100 US dollars.
So,
most of the
experience
of
Fusion Reactor
is based on
the experience of
Fusion Reactor.
The cost of materials
is usually the lowest.
Compared to the cost of
the operation,
the cost of materials is the lowest.
So,
this should not affect
the future
development of Fusion.
Another thing I'm interested in
is that the material is basically
placed at the bottom
of Fusion Reactor.
I want to know
the activation rate.
After activation,
what is the radiation
of Fusion Reactor?
For example, SIVIR.
Yes, if we use SIVIR.
When it first came out,
it was more than 50 mSv.
Its activation rate is not that high.
Because it only contains
Rhinium and Osmium.
Basically,
the composition is low,
but you can't directly
contact it.
So,
it's not as high as
Fusion Reactor's
radiation.
So, 50 mSv per hour?
Yes.
That's pretty high.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I have a general question.
Can you talk about
the next step of this project?
I mean the whole plan.
Which part are you talking about?
Is it Diverter or the entire
Ether?
What is the next step?
So,
Ether hopes that
the first Ether
will be in 2025.
But we estimate that
it will be in 2027 due to
some administrative issues.
Some minor issues
during installation.
So, the actual Ether
should be in 2027.
After Ether,
there will be a
Demonstration Reactor
in Europe.
Demonstration Power Plant.
It's called DEMO.
They want to test
some new concepts
with Ether.
Like TDM,
or Blanket.
The power generation
depends on Blanket.
80% of the terminal
will be generated here.
As you can see,
Helium has only 3.5 MeV,
but the terminal has 14 MeV.
So, the main energy is in the terminal.
Fusion Reactor
harnesses
the terminal energy.
It relies on
the interaction between
the terminal and the material
to transfer the energy to the material.
So, Blanket will absorb the energy
and generate electricity.
In addition,
in Blanket,
you need
Deuterium and Trillium.
The terminal and the terminal
do not exist in the natural world.
So, you need to manufacture them.
We have the terminal
in the Fusion Reactor,
and we use it.
But we can't always
use the fusion reactor
to generate the terminal.
So, the concept of Ether
is to
generate the terminal by itself.
So, it contains a lot of Li.
Li generates the terminal
with the fusion reactor.
Then, it uses the cycle
to extract the terminal
and turn it into
the fuel to burn.
So,
this concept
will be verified in Ether.
Some new concepts
in Diverter
such as Liquid Metal,
can be used to
generate the terminal.
However,
Liquid Metal
does not have this problem.
So, many new concepts
have appeared.
I hope that
it will be applied to DEMO.
The goal of DEMO
is that the value of Q is greater than 10.
Q is equal to 10.
So,
the energy generated
by the fusion reactor
is equal to
10 times of the input energy.
However,
this is a very ambitious goal.
Because there is no fusion reactor
that has reached
this level.
Even JET has not reached this level.
It seems that
there is a theoretical value of 1.
But it has not reached this level.
So,
the goal of DEMO
is greater than
50.
The goal is to reach the state
where electricity can be generated.
So,
this is a European project.
However, there are also projects in other countries.
Ether is an international project.
There are seven countries participating.
If the EU is a country,
there are
EU,
China, India,
Japan,
the United States,
and South Korea.
Each country has its own DEMO.
So, there will be
different approaches
in the future.
However,
this is a bit of
imagination.
Although we have many meetings
that are already designing DEMO,
I dare not say that
Ether has not been built yet.
Thank you.
It sounds like the next
collider of LHC.
LHC can't finish it.
But they are already discussing
how to build the next one.
I know the timeline.
Thank you.
Any other questions?
I have a question.
Do you have a contact?
Or you can email me.
Yes, I do.
It depends on you.
If our audience
are interested in
the next project,
you can contact
our speaker.
If you want to
review this video,
we will upload the recording
in a week.
That's all for today.
Let's give our speaker
a round of applause.