The first TerraTalk in 2021, today is January 9th.
We are very happy today to invite Dr. Wang Mengren to tell us about his topic today.
His topic today is Introduction to Particle Transport Simulation Deep Penetration Problems.
Before we start, let me introduce our speaker today.
His name is Vince Mengren.
He is a Research Scientist at the University of Utah.
Let me introduce his background.
Before this, he got his PhD in Nuclear Engineering at Virginia Tech in 2019.
His main research interest is Particle Transport Simulation.
This is the topic he will talk about today.
There is another topic that is not today's topic, but it is very cool.
It is Robotic Arm Applications in Nuclear Industry.
Obviously, you can't do anything by yourself.
This is a very important application.
There is a very special thing.
This is our online speech.
Let's give a round of applause to welcome our speaker.
Please turn on the microphone so that our speaker can hear our applause.
Let's give a round of applause to welcome Vince to give us a wonderful speech today.
I'll leave it to you.
Thank you, Ian.
First of all, thank you all for coming to listen to my speech.
My topic today is Introduction to Particle Transport Simulation.
Basically, Particle Transport Simulation can be used in many ways.
My main focus today is Deep Penetration Problem.
I will introduce what Deep Penetration Problem is later.
In fact, this chart has already told you some information.
At first, I will talk about what Particle Transport is.
Why do we need Particle Transport?
Second, what are the main applications?
I just said that Particle Transport has many applications.
If I have to talk about everything, I won't be able to finish it in an hour.
So I'm focusing on Deep Penetration Problem today.
It's actually a shielding problem.
Basically, you need to have a method to do this simulation.
There is a Governing Equation behind it.
Then you have to develop some methods to solve it.
I will talk about what the mainstream methods are now.
What are their advantages and disadvantages?
What are some more advanced methods?
Basically, I'm talking about Variance Reduction Techniques here.
Finally, of course, I will give a Demonstration Problem.
Finally, there is a Summary.
Before we solve any problem,
we have to talk about the Governing Equation behind it.
The Governing Equation behind Particle Transport is the Boltzmann Transport Equation.
You can see that the above equation looks very complicated.
This is General Form.
You have Time Dependent Terms.
We talk about Particle Streaming.
Your particle will be in Boundary Loss.
Then you may have an extra position.
For example, if you are an electrolyte, you may have magnetic force.
Gravity is generally not considered.
Because the particle is very small.
Then you have Collision.
The right side is basically Particle Gain.
When we calculate the Particle Transport,
We will talk about whether it is Lost or Gain.
You can see that the left side is basically Lost.
The right side is Gain.
I won't focus too much on Mathematics.
Because if you are not doing this field,
Mathematics will take a long time to understand.
The above is General Form.
The following is basically
If you need to do radiation transfer calculation.
Calculate their mass.
This is the Governing Equation we usually use.
This is from the above equation.
We talk about Steady State and Linear Boltzmann Equation.
You can see that there is a word called Linear here.
Steady State should not need to explain, everyone knows.
Basically, what we mean by Linear here is
For example, if you want to calculate the mass today.
For example, I am Photon today.
Photon will cause mass to me.
Today I assume that there will be no effect between Photon and Photon.
So this Linear is from here.
So you can see here
Basically, it only looks like once.
This is the function we want to solve.
We call it Flux.
Basically, you can see that the above and below
These two equations actually look a bit like.
The only difference is that one is General Form.
The other is Specifically.
We are not too independent and it is Linear.
We can explain a little bit about what this equation is doing.
Just use this example.
This example is basically if you go to the hospital.
You often see these X-ray machines.
This X-ray machine basically has a radiation source inside.
The middle one is inside.
Basically, a general X-ray machine is a beam of light.
Basically, you can circle a boundary.
If this beam of light runs out of this system.
I don't think about it.
Because it basically won't come back.
Basically, my patient may be here.
You basically have to estimate the number of patients.
The beam of light that goes out here.
I just talked about streaming.
This beam of light has run out of this boundary.
Basically, it is unlikely to hit back again.
On the one hand, the energy you hit is getting lower and lower.
Its path will be shorter and shorter.
So this is basically a little bit.
Just connect this equation.
What is he talking about?
Take advantage of this problem.
OK.
Speaking of Particle Transport.
Its application is actually very wide.
What I just talked about is a medical radiation device.
Or a physical accelerator that is often used.
You need to generate high energy particles.
Basically, you know that when the electric field is turning.
You will put the light out.
Basically, you will need to design its radiation barrier.
How do you design it?
To make the staff at work.
Don't let its dosage exceed the specified limit.
Whether it's nuclear fusion or nuclear separation reaction.
I basically need it.
Nuclear fusion reaction, if you need a place.
Basically, it's the same as I said.
It's basically a high-energy particle.
You cut it out again.
It will emit light.
Basically, you will have the same radiation barrier.
The problem needs to be calculated.
Nuclear separation reaction is no longer necessary.
From the core to the radiation barrier outside.
Basically, you need Particle Transport.
Okay.
Here is a brief introduction to Deep Penetration Problem.
Basically, I just talked about Particle Transport.
There are many applications.
Basically, Deep Penetration Problem is radiation barrier calculation.
How much radiation barrier material do you need?
In front of your staff.
Let your dosage reach the value you want.
It's not too high.
Basically, we talk about Deep Penetration Problem in academia.
Why do we talk about Deep Penetration Problem?
Because these particles need to go through.
If it has to go through such a thick barrier.
Basically, this calculation is not very easy.
So basically, we talk about Deep Penetration Problem.
Generally speaking, if you are talking about radiation barriers.
We will have an interesting example.
Basically, there are only three.
Mainly the first two.
Medium value and light value.
Basically, there is time for electrons.
Basically, when you need electrons.
Most of them are in medical equipment.
Medical radiation radiation source equipment.
In the nuclear industry.
Basically, we do not consider this.
Because it is an electrolyte.
Then it's light.
It basically can't get out.
And the nuclear industry is basically.
The barriers you don't see are basically very thick.
So these two.
The first two are basically without electricity.
So it's easier to get out.
Basically.
Basically, every calculation.
You have to have his goal.
Basically, we just talked about it.
You have to protect the staff.
And you have to calculate.
Know how much your dosage is.
Here I listed some of the general.
The unit we will use for radiation.
You can take a look.
This is not directly related to the topic I am talking about today.
Just mention it a little bit.
You basically have some units.
It is considered to be biological.
Like these are what we usually use.
Some of them are not.
Because you have these different particles.
It may cause damage to our human body.
Will be different.
Especially the seed.
OK.
Ok, then.
If we take a system to do.
Which one is.
If there is a color system.
Let's do it.
For example.
You can take this.
This should be very necessary in Taiwan now.
Because Taiwan is basically.
Now the nuclear power plant is going to be established.
You will have these radiation.
In the process of loading the barrel.
In the process of shipping.
You basically have to.
Calculate how much radiation it will protect.
Basically, you can see.
Here is the nuclear fuel inside.
These nuclear fuels are basically.
Burned in the reactor.
I'm talking about burning here.
Actually, it's not burning.
It is nuclear transmutation.
Yes, because basically the nuclear reaction.
It's not the same as the general chemical reaction.
Yes, basically you.
Burned in the reactor.
It's basically been activated.
Is being activated.
Then you basically.
There may be these.
These radiation.
These radiation are basically.
Spent nuclear.
Is.
Used nuclear fuel.
Basically, it may be released.
Basically, you can't just.
Take it out.
Then.
Use people to operate.
So basically it's all mechanical.
Then put it in these barrels.
These barrels are basically very thick.
That light inside.
Inside is the inner barrel.
Basically, that steel.
That stainless steel is basically.
It's already 25 centimeters thick.
So basically there is such a thick.
There is such a thick.
Radiation barrier.
You basically have some particles.
You don't need to think about it at all.
For example, Alpha Particle.
Alpha Particle.
You are basically in the air.
It's about five centimeters.
So don't say you have.
You have a little bit.
Then Electron doesn't have to say.
It is very light and has electricity.
Then Neutrinos basically.
It doesn't react with matter.
So we don't consider it.
So basically.
Ah.
We basically.
You are in the nuclear industry.
We have to calculate.
Ah.
If it's a measure.
Basically, most of them are these two.
And it's about 100%.
The rest is basically.
You can say it is negligible.
It depends on the case.
OK.
So basically you can see that.
Because we only.
Only interested in this non-electric particle.
So we just use this.
Steady linear.
Steady linear Boltzmann equation.
Basically, you can use it directly.
Ah.
To do this calculation.
OK.
Ok.
Then you want to do this calculation.
The physical model behind you has developed well.
It is.
Ah.
Transport equation.
Basically, you basically have to.
To solve this equation.
Ah.
But that equation.
You just saw it.
Basically, it has.
Ah.
If you expand all the variables.
Include.
If it includes time.
It has seven variables.
Ah.
XYZ.
Then the energy.
Then the angle.
Is the particle.
What angle does it shoot?
Then.
There are basically two angles.
It has.
Ah.
Z-multiple and polar.
And then.
It also has time.
Basically, there are seven.
Then it.
That.
Ah.
Ah, basically, you can only solve the number.
So, basically, the number is.
This is the first deterministic model here.
You really have to go.
This equation.
Break it down one piece at a time.
Then you can see it has a lot of.
It is a square of space.
It is XYZ.
You have to break everything down.
And then you have to break down the energy.
And then there are two parts of the angle.
You have to break down.
So, this is basically a module.
It is a very difficult process.
There is another method.
It is basically a Monte Carlo method.
You can put this whole.
You can use this method.
Basically, you can.
You do not have to go directly.
The one who solved the equation.
You basically, we are.
All the physical processes.
Turn it into a probability function.
Then go down to do the signal.
Basically, these two methods.
It has good and bad.
So, basically, I am now.
I will talk about it next.
Where is it good and bad?
And why is it bad?
Because it is a.
It is a, it is a, it is a, it is a, it is a.
It is a, it is a, it is a, it is a.
It is a, it is a, it is a.
It is a, it is a.
It is a.