Thank you all for attending this lecture.
I am a PhD student at the University of Belize.
I am very happy to be able to host this lecture for Project TIRA.
From seeing people from satellites, urban transformation, moving and mental health,
applying remote data and machine learning cross-field research.
TIRA is a PhD student from various fields in Taiwan,
an organization made up of PhD students, post-doctorate researchers and assistant professors.
We hope to connect young researchers from different fields.
Today's speaker, Chi-Hsing, we met in the first English class.
We belong to different fields of science and technology.
Recently, because of this lecture, we are in contact again.
I think this is the purpose of Project TIRA.
To connect scholars from different fields.
Chi-Hsing just got his doctorate from the Department of Environmental Science at the University of Austria.
He is currently a post-doctoral researcher at Yale University.
When he was a post-doctoral student,
he conducted research on typhoons in Taiwan and the Philippines.
During his post-doctoral studies, he also conducted research in the United States.
His current post-doctoral research project is mainly in the Himalayas.
In the next two years, he will receive the Yale Gallaudet Donnelly Fellowship.
He is expected to travel from Africa to the world.
Chi-Hsing will give a lecture for about an hour.
After that, there will be a Q&A time.
I don't have much to say about Chi-Hsing, so I'll give you the time.
Thank you.
Thank you, everyone.
Today, I will divide this lecture into two parts.
The first part is about how we can use satellite imagery and machine learning to detect loss.
The second part will focus on the relationship between loss and mental health in Denmark.
Before we start, I'd like to take a short break.
If you have any questions, please feel free to ask.
Please let me know if the connection is bad.
At the beginning, I'd like to talk about my research theme from a view that you may be familiar with.
In this photo of Taipei City, if you can see my mouse,
this road here, the road under the building, what is it like?
In the north of Zhongshuo East Road,
you can imagine that this area is more like an apartment building.
The density of the street is higher, and the width of the street is narrower.
In the south of Zhongshuo East Road, the business district,
we can see that the construction rate is much lower.
There is a lot of space between the buildings.
At the same time, it is not a low-density form.
If you look at it from a vertical perspective, it has a lot of skyscrapers.
In the past, many urban planners and environmental scientists
have been thinking about what kind of urban form is the best or the most sustainable.
In terms of sustainability, there are two aspects that have often been discussed in the past.
The first is how to make urban planning reach the goal of carbon reduction under the climate change.
For example, if today's land use configuration can make the workplace and residences close enough,
so that people don't have to travel a long distance when they're on vacation,
this can achieve the effect of carbon reduction.
The second aspect of the study is to regard the city as a separate system for land use.
In addition to the city, there are usually rural areas or natural protected areas.
For environmental scientists and eco-scientists,
if we can make the city's land use appear in a very limited space range and efficiently expand to other places,
then we can save more land for agriculture or other crops.
My interest in the study is a little different from the two aspects of the city as another aspect of the environment.
What I'm interested in is the part about people.
When we talk about sustainability, it's not about the sustainability of the environment,
but it's about people and the environment.
People themselves have to be able to live in this place in a sustainable way.
I'm very lucky to work on this project during my Ph.D. period.
The main theme of the project is psychological health.
I also had the opportunity to start working on this project.
I'd like to give you a data on psychological health.
In the past ten years,
the World Health Organization has conducted a survey of various countries around the world.
It can be found that an average of four people in the world
will have a certain stage in their life when they are affected by any psychological disease.
This is only the population that has been recorded due to old age.
In fact, the number will be higher.
Psychological health has many social factors.
What is the relationship between the building environment and psychological health?
I can think of it in three directions.
The first one is that we can imagine that the sun's exposure to the sun is related to our physical and mental health.
This will affect our mood.
In terms of environmental vision,
people may look out of the window and see what the street scene is.
Or the environment gives you a feeling of pressure or a sense of pressure.
This will also cause us to have different reactions psychologically.
The third point is that the urban structure of our society is closely related to our social interactions.
Let me give you a simple example of my grandmother's house.
My grandmother's house is a fishing village in the south of Taiwan.
The main urban design of this fishing village is like this.
There is a series of residential areas around the main provincial highway.
This residential area is a large area.
The connection in the middle of this large area is a small alley.
The distance between each small alley is about five meters.
In other words, the car can't get in.
There are two main types of houses in this residential area.
One is a three-room house.
The other is a Milan-style building with about four or five floors.
The function of this three-room house in the residential area is that
there is an underground water drain in the middle of the three-room house.
So everyone goes to that place to chat and get water.
Every time I go back to my grandmother's house,
I can often hear that everyone is quarreling in the alley or in the three-room house.
But no, they are just chatting.
In another era, when my grandmother's children grew up and lived in the city,
some of them moved to Kaohsiung City and moved to Taitung City.
For example, my father moved to a community building in Taitung City.
In this community building, their lifestyle became that
when my father got home, he parked his car and went straight to the 11th floor of the elevator to the apartment.
Through the legend of the elevator in this apartment,
he was actually in the same building as his neighbor.
Maybe there was only a wall or a floor area.
But even so, it almost completely avoided the possibility of communication with those neighbors.
So what is the lifestyle of our residents?
It will also affect the way we interact with our neighbors around us.
In the past, the study of what kind of urban lifestyle is related to mental health
is actually a more abstract or simplified way of understanding it.
It regards urban and rural as a spectrum of urban and rural.
In this spectrum, they are usually divided into two groups,
that is, urban people and rural people.
In these two groups, they conduct a lot of research,
including in Africa or other European countries, as well as the United States.
This study is a comprehensive study.
It collects data from dozens of European and American countries.
It turns out that in general, in these countries,
the ratio of depression and anxiety,
that is, the ratio of population infection,
is higher in urban areas than in rural areas.
In the context of globalization and the constant increase of urban population,
it is almost impossible to say that
it is because living in a rural area is healthier,
so we try to encourage everyone to live in a rural area.
For me, there is a very interesting question here,
that is, in urban environments,
what kind of urban design and urban planning
can be psychological health?
This is my main research motivation.
Let me introduce it to you.
When I was doing this research,
in fact, there were already a lot of predecessors,
that is, the previous researchers,
who had already thought a lot about this issue.
But in the study method,
the past research is more limited to small-scale research,
because they need to go through, for example, questionnaire survey,
to understand what the living environment
of their subjects is like.
Because psychological health is a very complicated issue,
compared to other areas,
such as work, career, family life, etc.
Therefore, when it comes to the living environment,
in many cases,
if the sample is small,
it will be more limited to research.
Therefore, one of the main breakthroughs in my PhD program
is how we can use satellite images and big data
to achieve a large-scale environmental feature,
and then connect such large-scale spatial information
with health information storage,
that is, the entire population of Denmark.
Let me show you
what the satellite image I am currently using looks like.
This image is Landsat,
a satellite from NASA.
It is summarized in series from Landsat 5 to Landsat 8,
from 1984 to the present.
It took 16 days to take this image,
so you can see what the image is like.
This image has an obvious problem
when it is recognized in the form of a story.
You can see the comparison of these two images here.
The one on the left is Google Earth,
a high-resolution satellite image.
The one on the right is the same one.
It is more clear because it is placed further away,
but if we look at it closely,
you will find that it is blurry
like a mosaic.
It's hard to really see
which side is the tall building, which side is the low building,
which side is the crowded residential area,
and which side is the windshield.
If you want to use a satellite image
to understand the entire city's
shape, structure, and health,
in my thesis,
the first part of the problem to be solved is
how do we use artificial intelligence,
especially the power of learning,
to solve the limitation of the satellite image.
The second part is that
when we make a breakthrough in methodology,
and get large-scale spatial information,
how do we connect it with the satellite image?
The first part of the study will be
the first half of the study.
I will let you ask questions first
when the first half of the study is over.
The first part is mainly about
when we get a satellite image,
like this picture on the left,
we hope to convert this satellite image
through machine learning
into the spatial information on the right.
Spatial information includes
which parts of the image
belong to the tall building,
the low building,
the crowded residential area, and so on.
In this study,
we will use the image of
the limited landsat
to compare different methods of
machine learning and deep learning,
to see which method
has more advantages in this topic.
Then we will see that
if this method can be trained well
in the Danube case,
can it be applied to other places
and have more potential for expansion?
First of all, this is the framework of our classification.
As mentioned earlier,
in terms of urban density,
it is a concept of gradient.
It will be divided into low density,
medium density, and high density.
In terms of building height,
this is a system designed
for the Danube context.
There are not many tall buildings in the Danube,
so you can imagine that
it is a system of building height
below the third floor.
Above the third floor,
we call it an apartment
or an open space.
This is an overview of
the entire research framework.
In the upper left corner,
you can see that
this is the satellite image
we use,
which has been integrated
from 1985 to 2018.
There is an image that
has not been affected by the cloud.
After obtaining this image,
we need to
let this model
learn something.
We need to give it some training data.
This training data
comes from Guangda.
Guangda is simply
a laser pulse.
When it hits an object,
there is a time difference.
This time difference can measure the shape of the object.
Therefore,
this data is a 3D model
of the entire Danube.
We divide this 3D model
into two parts.
One is training data,
and the other is verification data.
In terms of models,
we have three models.
The following is a common
method of learning
deep learning.
It is not deep learning,
but its computing speed is relatively fast.
The two models above
are deep learning models.
Let's talk about the middle one first.
It is actually the simplest
rotating machine model.
You often hear of CNA.
The one above
is a little more complicated than the one below.
But its base is the same.
It also comes from a
3D model.
In the model design,
there is a pooling layer
in the middle.
To put it simply,
what it is doing
is to
increase the speed of the machine.
But what is it?
I would like to introduce it to you now.
As mentioned earlier,
when we use high-resolution
commercial satellites,
we can clearly see
the same structure
and different architectural forms.
But the same range
is completely different.
In the same range,
it is difficult to see
which side is the high-rise
and which side is the flat.
But if we can
consider the information
of the multi-level building,
it will be a little different.
For example,
in this block of the high-rise,
there are three long
pixels.
The reason why the pixels are darker
is because there are more
buildings in this area.
If we look further,
we can see
that
the design of
this new community
is more
urbanized.
For example,
the buildings in this area
are more organic
and more deformed.
So,
on a larger scale,
we can see that
the structure can help us
distinguish which side is the high-rise
and which side is the flat.
When we have trained
these models and data,
we will use
the verification data
to verify the performance of the model.
What I want to mention here is that
the year of verification
data is different
from the year of training data.
For example, our training data is 2014,
but when we verify it,
we want to know
whether the model
that has been trained
recently can be used
to draw a historical urban model.
So, we found data from
2006 and 1995
that can be used
to draw a historical urban model.
Here is the research result.
I want to introduce
the six types of urban models
in Denmark.
The first one is the high-rise
with high density.
The high-density apartment buildings
are mainly located in the city center.
Here, we found two big cities
in Denmark,
Denmark and
Denmark.
In this picture,
the high-density apartment buildings
are represented as one group in immigrant
communities,
the rest areas are
isolated to the city center
as one group.
In this picture,
the high-density apartment buildings
are represented as one group
in immigrant communities,
the rest areas are isolated
as one group.
The third and fourth
sheets of yellow
architectural formula
symbolize Denmark's
major residential system.
Republican apartments
are simply
high-density
built in contact
with neighborhood
between city centers
and settlements.
As you can see,
the yellow part
of the low-density
apartment
is all
high-density.
You can imagine
this type of apartment
as a house in Europe
with lots of greenery
around it.
What is a low-density
high-density apartment like?
This type of apartment
can be located
on the outskirts
of the city
or around the park
and next to the river
to the first row of water.
It is a high-density apartment.
The low-density
low-rise apartment
is a low-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of Denmark,
the low-density
low-rise apartment
is more
common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of
Germany,
the low-density
low-rise apartment
is more common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of Germany,
the low-density
low-rise apartment
is more common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of
Germany,
the low-density
low-rise apartment
is more common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of
Germany,
the low-density
low-density apartment
is more common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of
Germany,
the low-density
low-density apartment
is more common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of
Germany,
the low-density
low-density apartment
is more common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of
Germany,
we found that
in the case of
Germany,
the low-density
high-density apartment
is more common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of
Germany,
the low-density
high-density apartment
is more common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of
Germany,
the low-density
high-density apartment
is more common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of
Germany,
the low-density
high-density apartment
is more common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of
Germany,
the low-density
high-density apartment
is more common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of
Germany,
the low-density
high-density apartment
is more common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of
Germany,
the low-density
high-density apartment
is more common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of
Germany,
the low-density
high-density apartment
is more common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of
Germany,
the low-density
high-density apartment
is more common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
We found that
in the case of
Germany,
the high-density
high-density apartment
is more common than
the high-density
high-density apartment.
So I would like to refer to
the existence of
the lower and upper
density apartment
and the higher-density apartment
once again.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
It is more common
than the higher-density
higher-density apartment
on the same floor.
The lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor
is more common
than the higher-density
higher-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The lower-density
lower-density apartment
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
The Lower and Upper
Dependency Parking
is more common
than
the lower-density
lower-density apartment
on the same floor.
In other words,
relative to
the lower-density
apartment on the same floor,
the dwelling environment
in the lower-density
apartment
lower-density apartment
is not as positive
as the higher-density
living environment
in the lower-density
lower-density
low-density
and relative to
the upper-density
middle-density
low-density
lower-density
middle-density
As you can see
When we go from
yellow to red
It is gradually
more and more modulation
For example,
this high-density IR
In the original right of this curve
Its risk relative to
the lower-density is relatively high
However, when it controls the modulation
Its risk
is relatively reduced
In other words,
the high-density IR
can be controlled by
other social mechanisms
However, even if it is excluded
Its risk is about 1.4 times
higher than
the low-density IR
in rural areas
On the other hand
What is more interesting is that
we originally expected that
rural areas would have the lowest risk
However, in the case of depression
As you can see
The lower-density IR
is relatively low
Its risk is actually
lower than that of rural areas
In other words, although it is in the urban area
But in this architectural state
Its risk is actually
not higher than that of rural areas
We just
found the risk-benefit relationship
We present its spatial state
on the map of Denmark
and
the three main cities of Denmark
including Copenhagen
Aarhus
and Corpus
It also produces
an interesting pattern
In the original
we expected that
rural areas should be pink
Everyone is happier
The risk is relatively low
As you can see
Not only rural areas are pink
The city center of the city is also pink
Especially in the city center
On the port side
on the river bank
and some green areas
are the areas with the lowest risk
Which area is the area with the highest risk?
It is not in the center of the city
Instead, it is in
the suburbs
Especially
the areas with more walls
It is relatively
the area with the highest risk
So I want to go back
to the first question
of today
What is a more sustainable
urban mentality?
According to our research
on mental health
In fact, we found that
there is no
linear relationship
The higher the density, the better
or the lower the density, the better
We found that
it is a combination
of low density
and high density
In the case of Denmark
we found that
the risk is relatively low
It is like
a neighborhood in Denmark
So you can see
In this area
for the residents
it is relatively easy to access
public facilities
including commercial activities
such as coffee shops
It is also easy to have rest areas
such as parks
In comparison
In Denmark
these high density
low-rise
high-density flat areas
When the industrial development of Denmark
reached its peak in the 1970s
At that time, because of the huge population
many houses
were built outside the city
When they built
the design
the density
of the population was very high
but there were no corresponding
commercial activities or public facilities
In our research
we found
that
in the case of
moving houses
If the residents
moved to
high density flat areas
If the residents
live in such an environment
there will be a risk increase
In other words
compared to the residents
of high density flat areas
If the residents
moved to
high density flat areas
they will face
a higher risk
So
we are talking about
environmental justice
or social justice
In Denmark
there have been a lot of
urban renewal cases
In the process of urban renewal
the city retained
or increased the urban green space
and improved the quality of life
At the same time
it also increased the rent in the city center
In the past
the city center of Denmark
was mainly for the workers
After these places
were upgraded
when the rent became more expensive
some people
had to move to
lower rents
At the same time
the city council
contributed a lot
in this study
This is a problem
that needs to be noticed
in urban planning
so that we can provide
a more fair
and comfortable
living environment
Finally
I would like to summarize
the position of this study
in academic research
First of all
in the past
the researchers
mainly looked at the expansion
of the city
and simplified it
into a concept of
dual contrast
But
in addition to
the expansion of
if we can
look at some
urban design conditions in more detail
such as density and height
we will have a chance
to talk more
in the field of urban planning
and talk more about
psychological health
and other research
related to the extension
In the second part
the position of this study
is to use a global
method to conduct research
The advantage of global technology
is that when this method
is proposed
it can be applied to
many other countries
At the same time
it has a limitation
as mentioned earlier
because its coverage
is very large
and has a long history
so it is actually
a relatively limited
and difficult topic
Therefore, through
in-depth study
we can make progress
on this topic
This topic is actually
very broad
It requires a lot of people
from different professional backgrounds
to join in, including psychology, urban planning
and epidemiology
So I look forward to
discussing more with you
Finally, I would like to
briefly share
my next plan
I have a fellowship
in Yale in the next two years
My plan is
to expand
the three-dimensional
urban characteristics
I just mentioned
to the global research area
Under this global research
it is not just
the past
urban research
Most of the research areas
in Yale
are in large cities
such as
5 million people
The scale of the city
will receive a lot of research attention
However, compared to Taiwan
when urban development
has reached its peak
our urban update
may be a street area
These small-scale changes
or small-scale urban developments
in other Latin American countries
or even in Africa
their urban expansion
tend to start
from a small change
These areas
are relatively small
and remote
so it is hard to be seen by satellites
Therefore, in the past
we did not do much research
However, in the future
we plan to
do more research
in this area
This is a brief
reference
for you
If you are interested
you can read the articles
for more details
That's all for today
Let's start the discussion
Thank you, Chi-Hsing
If there are
any questions
please feel free
to raise your mic
to join the discussion
At the first stage
there was a question
from Xu Shi-Che
Do you want to
raise your mic
to ask Chi-Hsing?
Okay
Xu Shi-Che
seems to say
his mic is not working
Let me ask him
his question
His question is
how much
overall accuracy
do you need
to be able to
distinguish
your urban
development
between 6 types of urban
and 2 types of urban
This is a question
from the first stage
That's a good question
Because
overall accuracy
is hard to
distinguish
Overall accuracy
is easy to be
distinguished
by one type
We need to
look at
accuracy matrix
In this matrix
we can see
the top 3 are
horizontal
and the bottom 3
are vertical
and horizontal
When we
look at this
we need to
look at
our own performance
When each performance
can reach
60, 70, 80%
then we can
distinguish
Of course 60% is not good
But for now
we need to be able to
distinguish low density
houses from
non-houses
It is relatively difficult
When we see
our own performance
we can know
how to improve
our performance
Any other questions?
Hello
I have a question
about
Thank you for your speech
I think it is very interesting
My question is
You found that
urban conditions
are related to
residents'
mental health
Although it is not a simple
linear relationship
I am curious
At the beginning
you mentioned some
possible connections
For example,
we can have
social activities
so that people can
get along better
But you did not
measure it
So I am curious
What is your
imagination
about this mechanism
Do you have any
future research
to measure it?
I think
this question
I always
hear my own answer
I turn off
my microphone
Thank you
In fact, I think
when we do quantitative research
large scale
or big data research
we often encounter a limitation
that when we talk about
this mechanism
we can not measure it
So when we discuss
For example, when we see
that Denmark's
high-rise buildings are
in a low-risk state
we will look for
documents
through interviews
or through
small scale research
to discuss and respond
to the document
However,
in my research, I did not
measure it
In the future,
is it possible to
directly measure social interaction?
At present,
I see a chance
to use social media
such as Facebook
or Twitter
to make improvements
in this area
I am also curious
Do you have any ideas
or suggestions
I
I have no special
I just want to hear
your expert opinion
Because I am also quite interested
to know if you want to measure
what are the possibilities
But I do not know
how to do it
Hello
I am also doing
urban environment and psychological
research
But I am doing
green space
We will
Some say
because there is a
public space
so people will gather
and there will be some social interaction
There will be
social well-being
About this
public space
I have a question
In our research
it will affect
mental health
I want to ask
In your future research project
will you
turn green space
into your
control variables?
In Denmark,
the whole Northern Europe
pays a lot of attention to green space
I have a research
It is not my research
but there is a research in our team
It found that in Denmark
it uses a standard
NDE
It is from satellite image data
to see
when children
in their childhood
How high is the green space
for them to adults
will extend
different psychological
I found
green space is helpful
In my own research
Green space
is a hot topic
for psychological research
My next
research
I will talk about
cement
architecture
and then
cross analysis
When they are
what combination
they will do
effect analysis
Hello, I am Zhang Anping
Sorry, you just asked me
I thought about it
I am now
You listen to this thing
How likely
If we use
You see
Google map
Timeline
GPS location
plus
Wi-Fi location
to infer
a person's behavior
I am driving
I am walking
I am riding a bicycle
I am running
We can infer
a person's behavior
not on the timeline
But for the neighbor
He comes in
Quite close
Walking distance
This is a kind of confusion
Use that way
same as
Satellite system
Data
To model
Or at least to index
Different people
The difference in their behavior
Then put this as
To label them
Become a link
Urban design
Mental health or other
Well-being index
Link
Possibility
I think it sounds very interesting
If you can really get
For example, Google is willing to study
File and then apply
Get these users
The way you just talked about
Is it very
Can break through the current
I don't know what everyone is doing in this area
Discussion
Is that we can really predict
Some activities and then put the activity
What kind of space provides what kind of activity
Then enter the mental health
Can talk about this
Hello
Yes, I heard that I want to respond
Just now Zhang Yanping and
Your research is
Mainly this information privacy
Problem
Because you said before
The Danish Health Insurance Bureau's database
So it can reflect
Someone's
His illness and residence
A timeline
I think this
The feeling of privacy is very
Very high
Then you mentioned later
You also mentioned in the middle
There is positive
Force to move
I don't know how you know
He is
In what situation
This is also a personal
Privacy information
You mentioned that you want to put this research
To other areas in Denmark
For example, you are in the United States now
Then you feel
Denmark you get this database
The completeness of this information
Those in the United States
Or in other countries
Can you get it
Because it feels very private
Personal
Back to the example of Zhang Yanping
That is
Personal
Personal activity
But you still have his
Information about illness
Research in this area
The question you asked is very important
Is privacy
I can share with you
Denmark
Their Bureau of Statistics
How do they go
To ensure that researchers
Do not hurt
Privacy
The first one is
We are in
Denmark
sorry I'm back
can you hear me?
this works, thank you
sorry, I think I connected with the wrong network
I will continue with the
reply of the question
In Denmark
the statistics office
to use this data
first of all
this data is anonymous
and the people above
although we will see
there is an address code
but the address code is not an address
just a statistics office
behind to connect these
reading characteristics with their
social and economic attributes, it needs to have a code
to connect
when we researchers
see the data
they can't see
what the address looks like
we only see those that have been
linked
so above
we can't see who the person is
and we can't see the name of the address
or what the name is
so we
analyze
these variable combinations
and the statistics
but we can't take any
personal information
so in this way
we can only get a conclusion
but we can't
in this process
leak any personal information
what is it
the second one you just mentioned
how do I know
who is forced to move
and who wants to move
I don't know
in our research
we don't actually measure
this thing
when we respond to documents
especially Copenhagen
we find some documents
that have been interviewed
and they have targeted those
recent
because of Copenhagen
and the rent increase
including some of the meetings
and some of the records
and the records
and the results
and we
take this process
as a discussion
and put it in our research
and the last question
is
this kind of research
is it possible to be studied in other countries
in the US
I don't know much
about US security data
but I have some knowledge
about Taiwan security data
when it comes to Taiwan
security data
it is possible to study
psychological health
and we have ICD
so in our security data
every year
it takes a million people
to enter security data
and these people have their
ID
but in Taiwan
it is different
it is limited
in living address
currently in our security data
we can study
space information
the smallest unit is town
so we can only
study 360 towns
in Taiwan
but we can't study
250 square meters
this is what I know
do you have any question?
yes, thank you
I will ask
Xu Shizhe
about
accuracy
he said
from the picture
if we choose
deep lab
we will sacrifice
high accuracy
how to
overcome this problem?
this is Xu Shizhe
I have a question
about
your second part
I am curious
about the environment
will change
and the environment
how to
incorporate
these two
aspects
into your
logistic regression model?
this is my second question
thank you
I will answer
Xu Shizhe's question
indeed
when we look at
the picture
in the lower left
indeed
compared to
the other two models
the accuracy
is lower
when we
consider this
we will consider F1-score
simply speaking
F1-score needs to
measure
the balance
between different categories
if one category
is very high
the accuracy is very high
it means
if other categories are low
it means this category
is often overestimated
the model will
draw the whole map as tall buildings
so that all the tall buildings
can be measured
but not all of them
are tall buildings
so other buildings
are not drawn
the accuracy
of F1-score
should be
balanced
this is my first question
Gao Xian's question
is
the environment
has time and
historical changes
how to incorporate
these two aspects
into your research?
I have another
question
when we
track Danes'
moving records
or their
historical record
there are two factors
that affect their
environment
one is
moving
another is
in Danish data
the main environmental
changes are
from moving
not from
fast urban expansion
how to incorporate
this into
logistics?
in the
independent variable
that we added
in the last
five years
there is a
difference
between
last five years
and this year
this difference
is a variable
in our model
the result
is
these five
on the left
are not only
average
but also
high density
if
the change
is positive
it will
have a higher
contribution
Gao Xian
did I answer
your question?
Yes
I am curious
if you put them
in the model
will there be
a change
or covariance?
Yes, there may be
a contribution
for each model
there is a
PIF
the result is
less than 5
the contribution is not that obvious
I believe
there must be
a change
in the model
for each model
the result is
less than 5
the contribution is not that obvious
I believe
there must be
a change
in the model
for each model
the result is less than
the contribution is not that obvious
Any other questions?
I have no questions
Hi
My name is Qiao En
I am a clinical psychologist
I am interested
in urban planning
and psychology
I read a paper
about the different functions
of land use
for those who live in
urban areas
like Taiwan
there are 7 floors
1st floor for shops
2nd and 3rd floor for residents
in this case
people are more likely to
walk or ride bicycles
just like the student
who talked about
social behavior
for those who live in
urban areas
or high-rise
it is not easy
for them to walk
and be healthy
because they have to
drive everywhere
so I am thinking
maybe in the future
you can change this
to land use
is it related to
people's walking habits
yes
I think
it is a good direction
in the future
I am interested
in
specific
like what you said
would they
want to walk
or ride bicycles
in the future
yes
I think
I am working on it
I think it is interesting
it is a new field
I have not heard of it
but it is interesting
thank you
what are you doing
I am doing
health psychology
I am doing research
about sports
and mental health
urban planning
public transportation
yes
I think
we can
talk more
in the future
if you are interested
we can
talk more
in the future
ok
thank you
do you have any questions
for the audience
if you don't have any
you can
contact
Cixin
later
if you have
any questions
you can
contact Cixin
privately
thank you for your participation
Cixin also has
anything to add
Cixin
no
thank you
thank you for your participation
if you
haven't joined
Project TIRA
I have posted the application form
in the chat room
if you are interested
you can join
and receive updates
thank you for your participation
I will turn off the recording
if you
don't want to be in the recording
you can stay
after I turn off the recording