Hello, everyone. Thank you for coming to Project Terra. I'm your host, Su-Yi-An.
I'm your host, Hu-Jun-Wei.
I'm delighted to be joined by Fu-Chun to give us a presentation.
The topic is Data, Reading, Architecture, Environment and Energy, using Taiwan's energy data as an example.
Later on, I'll talk about today's process.
Today's presentation is hosted by Project Terra.
Later on, we'll record the entire presentation.
In other words, after the presentation, if you want to listen to it again or share it with your friends,
you can go to Project Terra's website to view today's recording.
During the presentation, if you have any questions,
you're welcome to raise your hand or ask your question in the chat.
The hosts will monitor your questions and talk to the speakers.
If you have a bigger or more complicated question,
we'll have an open Q&A session at the end of the presentation.
Please feel free to ask your questions.
That's about it for today's presentation.
Now, let's have another host, Hu-Jun-Wei, to introduce today's speaker, Fu-Chun.
Hello, everyone.
Fu-Chun is a Ph.D. student at the University of Singapore, NUS.
He is currently studying architecture and urban data science in the University of Singapore.
His research focuses on the application of large data related to architecture,
including architectural energy, indoor environment comfort, and architectural IoT data, etc.
At the same time, he is also doing some community activities in the lab.
For example, he held an energy prediction competition at the well-known data platform Kaggle the year before last,
and provided data science courses to the public in an open platform course, EDS.
Interestingly, before Fu-Chun was a Ph.D. student,
he worked as a three-year data scientist at a Taiwanese innovation company,
Knowledge Analysis Based Exploration,
and was committed to the development of large data related to architecture,
including the detection of labor abnormalities, energy prediction, and data visualization, etc.
In addition, he is also involved in the development of artificial intelligence services
and energy data analysis of the Taipei City Government.
Today, Fu-Chun will focus more on issues related to food in the industry.
In today's speech, he will talk about the academic development of energy prediction,
and finally share how to work with open data to do energy prediction.
Let's welcome Fu-Chun.
Can you hear me?
Yes, we can.
Great.
Next, let me play my video.
Today's topic is data reading, architecture, environment, and energy,
based on Taiwan energy data.
This speech is mainly about architecture data prediction models,
as well as the introduction of related open data.
At the end of the speech,
I will use the open data provided by Taipei Electric Power Corporation,
and the weather forecast provided by the Meteorological Bureau,
to cooperate with the model of machine learning,
to make an energy prediction service that can predict the future.
I hope the difficulty of today's speech is not too high.
The main thing is to let everyone know
how to apply data science in human resources or architecture.
I hope everyone can get to know more about open data
and how to do these things.
OK.
This is my basic self-introduction.
I am a Ph.D. student at INU-S.
I graduated from Shenzhen University of Technology,
and I had three years of experience as a data scientist before I got my Ph.D.
This also allows me to focus on the problems in the industry
during my Ph.D. career.
This is what I just said.
We have been doing some community-related things.
For example, in the Cargo Competition,
if you are playing this kind of data science competition,
this is the most famous competition at present.
We have held an energy prediction competition on it.
In addition, we also have some open data.
I put it in Cargo.
Cargo not only holds competitions,
but also provides an open data platform
for everyone to upload data and play together.
In addition, we also have OpenCourse on EDX.
It is mainly about construction, architecture, and engineering.
It is about building data,
including indoor humidity, CO2, and energy.
How to use some Python programs
to process these data,
and how to build a simple machine learning model.
Its difficulty is very simple.
Even people who don't have much programming experience
can take this course.
You don't need to have professional knowledge in architecture.
As long as you want to learn
how to use Python in the scientific field
or in some simple data processing,
I think this course is quite suitable.
This is today's agenda.
Because today's topic is mainly energy prediction,
we will spend some time reviewing
past energy prediction models and methods.
Next, we will use Cargo Competition
energy prediction competition as an example.
How do people predict energy?
What strategy do data scientists use
to accurately predict energy?
Next is Project Study.
We will use Taiwan's open energy data
to do a simple experiment
to see how it works.
Finally, we will introduce some interesting open data sets.
It is mainly about Taiwan's weather,
or open data sets related to holidays.
First of all,
I would like to let you feel
what the energy trend looks like.
This is a year,
from January 2017 to the end of the year.
This is an actual electricity meter
obtained from a campus in Taiwan.
First, I would like to let you observe
what is special about this electricity meter.
First, we can zoom in here.
You can see that after zooming in,
you can see some trends.
Because it collects data every hour,
so you can see that
a day is actually a profile like this.
It will have a peak,
which is around noon.
So you can see that the first pattern
is actually a weekly pattern.
It is weekly.
1 to 5 is actually a fixed working pattern.
It is high at noon and low at night.
But there is no one on the 6th,
so the peak is a little lower.
The next pattern is vocation.
1 to 5 is very low.
That's because it's the Chinese New Year.
It's the time of the lunar new year,
so the energy is relatively low.
In addition, there is a seasonal trend.
In the summer or hot weather,
the energy is relatively high.
In the winter or cold weather,
the energy is relatively low.
This is normal
because Taiwan is a country
that focuses on heat.
Most of us don't have heaters,
so in winter,
the energy is relatively low.
So this is our first and simplest model.
It is also a more classic model.
It is a TOWT model
proposed by Lawrence Berkeley National Lab.
TOW stands for Time of Week.
That is to say,
if we take the number of hours of a week
as X-axis and draw it out,
the energy is actually 365 days.
If you put it on this graph,
you can see that 1 to 5
is actually very regular,
which is higher during the day.
It is relatively low at night.
So we have several variables.
The first one is the time of week.
The second variable is what I just said.
It actually has something to do
with the temperature of the outside air.
So what we draw here
is the relationship
between temperature and energy.
But we also distinguish
whether it is occupied or unoccupied.
That is to say,
is there anyone or no one here?
But we can see that at night,
we will define it as the so-called no one.
During the day,
we will define it as the so-called someone.
So this division is actually very rough.
It may be according to what time to go to work,
what time to get off work,
and then cut it like this.
But when you cut it out,
you can see that
when it is occupied,
its trend is very obvious.
This is a
low-temperature
and high-temperature
transition.
Occupied is that it is
with regression.
It is actually a linear model.
That's it.
Basically, it is with
a linear model.
There will be a linear model.
Then it is related to temperature.
The return line of temperature here
is a
division to return.
Because in fact,
it is related to temperature.
If you call it out,
you will find that
cooling is actually related.
If in some Korean countries,
when your temperature is getting lower,
its energy will rise.
That's mainly because of heating.
It's a simple linear return.
So often you can
Of course, you can use a polynomial,
maybe two-dimensional or three-dimensional to beat.
Of course, you can also use a division.
Then again, if it is occupied,
there is no one.
Then it will be more like
using temperature to return.
It is a
single
one-dimensional
linear return.
Because at night,
it is usually simpler.
This is the result of the return.
In fact,
it can catch the profile.
It's just that sometimes the effect
is not so good in some details.
You can see some details
There will be a shock.
So its R-squared is about
less than 0.6.
The next one is a more traditional
physical model, thermal network.
It is basically the structure of the building.
There is heat melt, heat bamboo.
That is to say,
the temperature of the outside world
and the temperature inside
its temperature difference
will cause
its heat to be stored
in the wall.
Or it is said that it is
looking at the thickness of the wall
or its material.
Then decide how fast
it goes into the room.
So usually outside
For example, the surface temperature of the wall
and the surface temperature of the wall
in the room will have a
type.
In addition, the temperature difference
in the room will be relatively
slower.
So under this condition,
we will actually
make a building
all made up of heat melt and heat bamboo.
For example,
we may have
three heat bamboo
and two heat melt.
The outer wall or
internal mass
is a bit like an indoor furniture or an indoor wall.
The whole building can be done
in this way.
Its advantage is that it is very precise.
Its disadvantage is that you have to
decide how many heat melt and heat bamboo it has.
To be honest, this thing is not very simple.
The next one
is the machine learning
that we are more popular with now.
Here is an example of
LightGBM model.
Let's use this model to
make it.
The main advantage of this model is that
its computing speed is very fast and
its tuning is relatively simple.
So we usually use
this model
to do some competitions or some early tests
and so on.
Most of the participants
use this model
to do the cargo competition later.
The model here is actually
the time we just said.
It may be the number of hours in a day.
It is also a Sunday.
In addition, there is outdoor air temperature.
There are other IOTs
or META
or Lag Feature.
It can eat more parameters
than the linear model just now
to capture some more
detailed information.
In addition,
there are so many variables
we just mentioned.
For example, CO2 or
temperature
or weekday
or seasonal hours.
Which of these variables
is the most important?
The model of LightGBM can also tell us
that in the process of modeling,
we found that
the energy 24 hours ago
is the most important.
Then there is the outdoor temperature, etc.
It can tell you the importance of these parameters.
The importance is relatively low.
Maybe you can
get rid of it.
Of course,
some people will think that
the result of LightGBM
will be better than
the linear model just now.
It is less
detailed.
The score is 0.6.
Some people will think
that Neural Network
is another
popular method.
We often need to learn more about this method.
Indeed, this method
is often used in energy prediction.
Such as LSTM or RNN.
However,
unlike Tree-based models,
such as LightGBM,
XGBoost,
or Random Forest,
RNN
usually requires
more training time.
When you tune this model,
you will spend a lot of time and energy.
So in a short-term
competition or a mid-term project,
we still use
Tree-based models like LightGBM.
It is relatively fast
and efficient.
Let's jump to
the Kaggle competition.
Let's see how
professional data scientists
predict
the building's
population.
First, let me briefly introduce Kaggle.
Some people may not be familiar with it.
Kaggle is a subsidiary
of Google.
It is an online community
where data scientists,
students,
or social people
can share their ideas,
share data,
and participate in the competition.
There are three parts
of Kaggle platform.
The first part is competition.
There will be some sponsors.
It could be a company
or a school.
They will give prizes.
Kaggle will help them hold the competition.
There are some interesting competitions.
For example, Jamstree,
where you can use Wi-Fi
to predict where people are.
Next is dataset.
People can freely
upload their dataset.
For example,
COVID-19 vaccine development,
or Netflix,
or Trump's Twitter.
This is also an interesting topic.
Datasets include
professional or non-professional
data.
It is an interesting platform.
The last part is
notebook.
It is a code.
People will put their code on it.
It includes
how to visualize
or model.
Basically,
you can copy the notebook
and do the same thing.
This notebook can
connect to the competition
and dataset.
Basically, you can use
the cloud resources,
CPU and GPU,
to run the dataset
on the platform.
You can even use the resources
to participate in the competition.
You don't even need to use
your local notebook to run the model.
You can use the cloud resources
to upload and compute the data.
Let me introduce
what the competition is.
There are
more than 2,000
data sets.
They are from more than 1,000
countries around the world.
We want to find a good algorithm
to accurately predict
the resources of most of the buildings.
In the past,
most researchers
said that
some buildings are very fast,
some buildings are very accurate,
some buildings are very easy to run,
and so on.
But if we have so many buildings
across different countries,
it will be a more general way.
It's not just a case of
a single building or a single country.
This is the purpose
of the energy competition.
To find the most general
and accurate way.
This dataset
contains some data,
such as the most basic
meter reading.
This is mainly
the data of the meter.
It may be 24 hours,
single year data,
and its height.
In addition, there is building meta,
what kind of site it is,
and what kind of
purpose it is.
It may be office buildings, it may be school buildings,
square feet, floor area, etc.
It also provides
temperature, humidity,
cloud load, etc.
In this competition, it will provide
training data for 2016
to train your model.
You have to predict the energy data
for 2017 and 2018.
In this competition,
the method of the competition is
that you will first download your dataset,
which is your training data.
It includes the electric meter data
and weather data.
After training your model,
you can
upload your answer.
After uploading,
it will calculate a score.
You can see the score
on the leaderboard.
Now let's take a look at
the result of this competition.
First of all, it is very interesting that
most of the applications are Python.
Python is the most popular application now.
There is a little bit, but not the most.
What kind of machine learning models
do you use?
In this competition, it is usually
gradient boosting.
Because this data belongs to
tabular data,
it is structured,
like Excel table data.
In TreeBase model,
they are best at solving this problem.
In NN,
it is not impossible to deal with this problem.
Because the training time is too long,
and you need to tune the parameters
for a long time.
Then there are some tags.
You can find that
most of the notebooks
are provided by EDA or Beginner,
which are more visualized.
Data is its exploration,
which parameters it has,
its distribution,
and its time series.
Let's take a look at
most of the solutions.
You can see that
the rank is from
high to low,
from 9th to over 2000.
You can see that the score
can be from low to high.
Low means that this side is better.
Because the score here is actually
error, the lower the better.
You can see that
most people use
removeAllLiers
to remove data,
and imputation
is to make some
data maintenance.
Not everyone does this.
In Feature Strategy,
in Holiday Feature,
and Categorical Statistical Feature,
it depends on each person.
It doesn't seem to be consistent.
The number of Feature that everyone uses
is either a lot or a little.
Some people just didn't publish it.
I think the most interesting thing is
in Feature Strategy,
you can see that the numbers here
represent the number of models.
The higher the score,
the more models they prefer to use.
Why is that?
In this kind of data competition,
if you use a single model,
its performance is usually limited.
But if you use different models today,
for example, you use NN,
you use lightGBN,
or you use different modeling methods,
you put all the results of these modeling
If you use a simple average,
sometimes you can get very good results.
Maybe 0.5 times the first model,
0.5 times the second model,
and then add it up,
its performance may be better than individual models.
So that's why they use so many
models to do the average.
Because it can
effectively improve the performance of the model.
Let's take out the top five
and take a look at its content.
The most important thing is that
in preprocessing,
it is very important to remove anomalies
or outliers.
Because in this competition,
there are a lot of data missing and outliers.
In fact, this is not only found in this competition.
In fact, most of the real world data
is like this,
a lot of data missing, a lot of outliers.
If you don't do this,
it may cause your model to learn
some strange patterns or phenomena.
Next is features.
This is not necessarily the case.
Some people use 10, some use 28.
Some have outliers, some don't.
It depends on how you choose.
In modeling,
you can see that most of them use
LinearGBN, XGBoost,
which are tree-based models.
There are relatively few NNN models.
Post-processing,
as I just said, is a model
to do the average.
It's actually ensembling.
I made a lot of models today and
this is a simple
flowchart they provide.
This is the first flowchart they provide.
You can see the pre-processing in front of it.
This is what I just said.
Feature engineering.
Then there are a lot of models.
Finally, do the ensembling prediction.
These predicted results
are averaged.
In fact,
every
flowchart in the competition is a bit like this.
They do some pre-processing.
Then there are a lot of models.
Then do the ensembling.
This is also a classic
machine learning pipeline.
Pre-processing, modeling,
and then
if it's ensembling,
it's more of a special use than set.
It's a method
that will be used to get high scores.
The third is a similar method.
This competition,
to be honest,
is more data science.
If the audience
is more interested
in this place,
you can check the details
in our publication.
We have a review paper
for this competition.
You can go up and see the details of this competition.
If you want to know the program,
you can go to Github
to find some models
or some details.
In addition,
we even have their interview videos.
You can also find these YouTube videos
from Github
to see how they introduce their models
and how they do things.
The main purpose of talking about Kaggle today
is to give some
slightly interested in
energy prediction, but not
too familiar with these machine learning models.
It's a simple overview.
How does this competition work?
What kind of model is it?
Next, we will talk about
our project study today.
We want to do low prediction
using data from Taiwan.
We want to ask
if we can really do
an energy prediction service.
Let me put this PowerPoint
aside first.
This is the Kaggle
platform I just mentioned.
If you go to
kaggle.com,
you can come in here.
There will be a bunch of competitions,
some data, and notebooks.
Here,
Project Tyra has created
four notebooks.
You can see that
there are a lot of Python programs in this notebook.
You can just copy
and run it.
Here,
I want to copy
this notebook I have already built.
If you want to copy
and you want to use my notebook,
you can use the Copy & Edit Notebook here.
Click on it.
It will create a new copy here.
You can see that
it will use
cloud resources in this notebook.
But it's on the narrow path now.
There are some datasets here.
The dataset here is
from the Kaggle dataset.
You can read it directly
into this notebook.
You can see some CPU and RAM here.
You can even run GPU
and use its cloud resources
to do some operations.
In this notebook,
the first thing we need to do
is to download data.
We want to download weather data
and energy data.
Let's run this thing
on the scene.
Run all.
At the same time,
let's introduce
today's dataset.
The first is energy data.
It's data from Taiwan Electricity.
It contains
some peak
power consumption
per day.
The peak power consumption
of Taiwan Electricity
per day.
In addition,
there are energy categories
of Taiwan Electricity.
There are a lot of energy categories in Taiwan.
There are traditional
blue gas,
blue coal, nuclear energy,
and wind and solar energy.
These data
are also released by Taiwan Electricity.
In addition,
I know some listeners
are more interested in
local energy.
For example,
how much electricity they use
in a village or a city.
Taiwan Electricity does have some data
in this part,
but it's not covered
in today's speech.
In addition, there are some village metadata,
such as its precision,
population,
and area.
For example, the open data provided by this website.
If you want to know
its outline, you can also find
the open data provided by Hulu.
The picture on the left
is a good data visualization.
It's a picture provided
by Prof. Chen
from FB.
As you can see,
the village area
and energy are mapped
together to see
the density of energy.
Let's take a look
at the data
provided by Hulu.
First,
we have the weather data.
We got the weather data
from the weather data.
We got data for 2 years.
The first year,
the winter temperature was lower than the summer one,
and the second year,
the temperature was higher than
the summer one.
The third year,
we took the average of the three points
and used them as feature
to predict the power consumption.
The next one is the energy data
from Taiwan.
There are a lot of data in it.
In addition to the
monitoring load,
there are also data from various
power generation sources.
We can take a look at
the industrial power consumption
and the electricity consumption.
For industrial power consumption,
we can see that
the annual power consumption
is relatively low.
The annual power consumption
On weekends,
there is a fixed pattern.
There is a fixed pattern.
This is the so-called
near-peak power supply.
The power station must decide
how much electricity
to deal with the maximum
load on that day.
We can't let the maximum load
exceed the power supply,
or there will be power outages.
Next, there are wind power
and solar power.
Solar power is
relatively general.
It depends on how much radiation
you have that day.
In summer, it's more.
In winter, it's less.
Let's go back
to the data set.
As you can see,
weather data is what I just said.
You can use this to observe
the historical weather data.
This is the platform
that Cargo just grabbed.
This is the platform that Cargo just grabbed.
There is also a local weather forecast.
You can use the forecast API
provided by the Meteorological Bureau
to catch the forecast for the next week
and the weather forecast every three hours.
Google Trend
is more interesting.
You can search
the search volume
of a keyword on Google.
For example, you can search
the search volume
of a keyword on Google.
You can see a pattern.
One, two, three, four.
Sorry, I typed it wrong.
It's actually two, three, four, five.
It's Saturday and Sunday.
You can also say
that if I use
the date as a unit,
you can see that
one, two, three, four, five is higher,
and six is lower.
If you look at one and two,
you can see that
this is in the United States,
so it's actually lower
in the New Year
or in the National Day.
You can also see
that if I use
Taiwan's data as an example,
the search volume
mentioned in the first video
is the search volume
in Taiwan Campus.
If you compare the search volume
of Microsoft Excel,
you can see that
it can correspond to
some holidays,
such as the New Year,
and the search volume of
Excel becomes lower.
For example,
the search volume of
Microsoft Excel,
whether it's tourism
or your sales volume,
is a very useful keyword
to compare.
This is also mentioned that
if our Power Meter
is classified,
you can find that
some buildings are
related to education,
and some buildings
may be related to
the office,
which is also a very interesting
open data set.
Here I have provided
how to grab data
in Google Trend.
You can see that
it's lower in the New Year
and lower in the National Day.
For example,
October 10th.
October 10th, 11th, 12th, and 13th
are National Day holidays,
so these days are also lower.
Holiday data
is actually
from a website
called TimeDate.
You can find
the holiday of
each country on it.
You just need to enter
your country's name on the website
and its year.
Then you can find the national holiday
that corresponds to that country.
This is also a very useful website,
so I also grabbed
some data.
In this notebook,
the main thing we do is
to grab data.
In the end,
what we can
generate is like this.
In this notebook,
there is
an output.
We can output
Google Trend CSV, Demand CSV, Holiday.
You can even download
the data directly from here.
It's quite convenient to
store data
and build a notebook.
Next,
if we want to
predict Taiwan's
energy,
we need to build a model.
Here,
our goal is to
meet the deadline on time.
Of course, there are other things
that we don't need to cover.
Let's use a simple
time-to-time load to predict.
This is one data per day,
which is the highest energy load
in a day.
If we only use the simplest
weekday to predict,
that is,
let's say it's Monday or Tuesday,
or it's Saturday or Sunday.
First of all,
we can look at its trend.
0 to 4 is Monday to Friday,
and 5 to 6 is Saturday.
1 to 5 is higher,
and Saturday is lower.
It's normal.
If we build a model like this,
it will look like
a weekly forecast.
It's like a blue line.
This is the so-called prediction.
It's very inaccurate,
because it only has
the feature of Monday.
Its Oscar O is only 0.1.
It's terrible.
For the second model,
if we want to be more seasonal,
we can add weather conditions.
We only add temperature today.
The temperature here
is the overall energy
forecast in Taiwan.
So we simply sample
the temperature of three regions,
Taipei, Tainan, and Taichung.
You can see that
if we
use temperature
and energy
to get a plot,
you can see that
there is a very obvious curve on weekday,
and there is a very obvious curve on weekend.
We use a two-dimensional curve
to draw it.
You can see that there is a very obvious relationship here.
So
after we add it here,
you can see that this prediction
is actually a lot more accurate.
It can roughly draw this seasonal line,
and its Oscar can reach 0.81.
Sorry, I forgot to mention that
the training data is used to train
the whole year of 2019,
and then use 2020
as our test data to see its accuracy.
So you can see
that even if we only have
weekly weather conditions,
the prediction of the next year
is actually quite accurate.
The third model
is to say that
in addition to the weather conditions here,
we can see some
of the predictions here,
but it's not very accurate.
The main reason is that the model can't know
which day is the holiday,
so you have to tell it this feature.
The third model is called Holiday,
which is the holiday data
we just got from IronDate.
How many types
of holiday types are there here?
0 is the most common,
1 is the most
common ordinary day,
that is, it doesn't have a holiday,
and 2 is the weekend.
You can see that their grouping methods
are not the same.
After adding this,
you can see that the prediction
here in the new year seems to be a little lower.
For example, around October 10,
it will also be here
in these three days,
its prediction value will also be lower.
That's because there's a feature
added to it,
so it's improved from 0.81 to
almost 0.9.
The most important thing is that
our scope can actually predict
the energy for the next week,
so it actually includes the previous day,
including the previous seven days
and so on, these past energy data
can actually be our feature.
For example, I'm going to predict tomorrow's energy,
but if I can know
what the trend
of today's energy looks like,
then we can use today's trend
and maybe add a little bit more.
If the temperature is high, we can add a little bit.
Then predict tomorrow's energy.
So the energy data
from the previous day or the previous seven days
is also a pretty useful feature.
I'm here in Australia.
If we add
the energy data
from the previous day
and the previous seven days
and two weeks ago,
you can see that
in fact,
they are highly related,
that is, the previous day
our current energy
their relationship
is very close.
The previous seven days or the previous 14 days
are also very close,
which is also reasonable.
It's like 9 o'clock in the morning
and 9 o'clock in the morning yesterday.
It's like 9 o'clock now and 9 o'clock
a week ago, and it's like
9 o'clock two weeks ago.
So after adding this feature,
our Oscar can directly
increase to 0.94.
This thing is of course based on
my short-term prediction today.
If you predict tomorrow or the next week's energy,
then I can use this
energy from the previous few days as my feature.
OK, so here,
this notebook is mainly to do this model training,
which is to establish this model.
At the end of this model,
when it is to be output,
we will actually use two years of data to do training.
Just to do some validation,
we might have to come out a year ago
to see how it works.
If the parameters of this model are fine
and the effect is very good,
then we can use two years of data
to do training.
So the output here is
actually a light GBM model.
The last notebook here
is actually a real-time prediction.
Then we use the light GBM model
we built just now
to import it in.
Then we can use this model to predict.
Just before doing the prediction,
we still have to grab some data.
Because what we just grabbed is historical data.
If we want to predict the energy
for the next seven days,
then we have to catch the future weather forecast.
Then we have to catch
the holiday data.
Then we also have to catch
the energy data from the previous few days
as our feature.
So the first thing here
is to spread some
energy data.
Here we can see
that we will catch
all the energy data this year.
Then you can see that
here is
the energy data
a month ago.
You can see that it is December,
January, and then the data by the end of January.
Here is also
the estimated data
provided by Taiden.
Their predicted data
to predict what it looks like
at the bottom of the peak.
Then we will
catch the weather forecast
from the Central Meteorological Bureau.
Then we can predict
the energy for the next seven days.
Basically, we use the model
of LightGBM.
Here we can catch the weather forecast
for Taipei, Taichung, and Tainan.
Because this is a notebook I made
a week ago.
January 28th to February 3rd
is the estimated date.
So this is Taipei, Taichung, and Tainan.
Here is the temperature provided by the weather forecast.
Then
the following
are some features,
such as the week,
one day ago, seven days ago,
and 14 days ago.
Because only the first day
has the energy of the day before,
so there will be data here.
From the second day,
there will be no data on the first day.
Because our prediction will actually start
from the first day,
and then predict the second day, the third day.
Then the data of the day before,
we will use the prediction value of the day before to put it in.
So we can look at
the prediction result.
The prediction result can actually be seen here.
That is to say,
here is the data.
The limit is what happened in the past.
The blue line and the green line are
the LGBM model we predicted.
The green line is the LGBM prediction.
You can see that our prediction seems to be low.
So we can
predict it.
We can evaluate it later.
What is the difference between the two
we predicted with LGBM?
Who is more accurate?
Or what is the difference between the two features?
Because this is
the prediction 11 days ago.
So I didn't make any changes to it.
We can now
take a look at the prediction result.
Ok.
This is the prediction result.
You can see that the orange line
is the
LGBM prediction.
The blue line is the LGBM prediction.
You can see that
at the beginning,
the error was very high.
The blue bar is the error.
We almost accurately predicted
what the energy would be like three days ago.
But as time goes by,
the accuracy is getting worse and worse.
It's mainly because of the weather forecast.
It's very likely that
the accuracy of the weather forecast
is getting worse and worse
from the first day to the second day.
Or the temperature I brought in
is not enough.
So the prediction is not very accurate.
LGBM's prediction
is relatively stable.
It can maintain
a certain error every day.
I don't know how to do it.
The error of the prediction
is mostly positive.
But this is just a seven-day data.
So it can't be
simply solved like this.
You can find this phenomenon
from these seven days.
The accuracy of the prediction
is not very different.
Ok.
I also put the link of the notebook here.
If you are interested, you can go to Kaggle.
Or you can search for the keyword
pocket tyrant.
Notebook.
I didn't miss anything in the beginning.
The first part is
the introduction of OpenDataSet.
A brief summary of today's summary.
In the field of architecture,
in the part of energy prediction,
in addition to being affected
by external conditions
and the variables of these environments,
behavior is also very important.
When do people go to work?
What time does he go to work?
Is it holiday or non-holiday that day?
Or is it weekend?
In fact, it has a great impact.
The second point is that we actually
learned from Kaggle Competition,
which is what we learned in the energy prediction competition.
First of all, the tree-based model
is actually
most of the solutions
that Wiener will use.
Mainly because of its performance
and its training time
and tuning parameter time
can achieve a balance.
Then you can achieve good performance.
So everyone will use this method.
The other thing is that
the data scientists in it
mainly focus on this.
What I mean is that these data scientists
don't have any personnel or
building-related background.
But based on their data skills,
it is the sharing of the community above.
Everyone shares with each other
what they found in these data.
What are the characteristics?
Then everyone can use these knowledge
to make the most accurate predictions
based on their model experience
and their know-how.
So the winners in the front
don't have any professional
building-related background.
Then there is the actual
demand forecasting model.
Then use Taiwan energy
to do the actual part.
In fact, Taiwan Open Data is very
enough to do such a model.
It takes about two years.
But in my opinion,
Taiwan Open Data is already enough
to build a model with good accuracy.
In the field of architecture.
Then there is
its performance.
It's pretty good.
Everyone can do more than 0.9.
And it's also very simple.
You can support it for free
in the Kaggle platform.
Finally, it is Open Dataset.
In fact, Taiwan has a very rich
and very diversified dataset.
Compared to other Open Datasets
Open Datasets are very limited.
Taiwan has a lot.
Of course, there are a lot of messy
and I don't know how to use the dataset.
But in fact, there are some very useful
and very interesting datasets that
everyone can play.
In addition, these datasets can help
researchers like us
to find some interesting patterns.
For example, Google Search
can also help you
to find some details
in Building Energy.
Next, we will have 10 minutes
for Q&A.
Thank you for the wonderful
presentation today.
You made a very good
summary.
About the competition
of Azure,
the competition on the Kaggle platform,
and some model introduction,
LGBM,
XGBoost,
or Neural Network,
as well as the overall introduction
of architecture prediction
and Open Data Science.
It's very exciting.
Now we see that
in the chat box,
a friend asked
that he wanted to ask
that there may be no accurate
temperature prediction in the future
when actually using it.
Will the performance of the model
be affected at this time?
In fact, it will.
It should be said that
the difference in temperature
may be that
according to our observation,
the temperature difference in weather forecast
is very full.
But the temperature
prediction error
is about 1-2 degrees.
Most weather forecasts
can accurately predict
the temperature profile.
For example, 18-29 degrees
is actually quite accurate.
Next is the architecture energy.
It's actually a pretty stable
profile.
It's not because the temperature suddenly rises
or falls.
So in this regard,
although the weather forecast
is not completely accurate,
it does not affect
the accuracy of the prediction.
Of course, if you want to predict
the next month or next week,
the prediction error may be slightly higher.
But if you predict
one day tomorrow or three days later,
I don't think the accuracy of the energy
will be much higher.
Thank you for your answer.
Do you have any questions
for the audience here?
You can mute your questions
or type them in the chat.
Hello, I'm Louis.
I have one last question.
It's a very good question.
It's a time series question.
How do you do validation?
You mentioned that you use
2019's trend on 2019
and then 2020's
to predict.
Is there a more complete
way to do validation?
Sorry to interrupt,
but before you answer,
I'd like to ask the audience
to introduce their backgrounds.
So that we can
get to know each other better.
Thank you.
I'm in the US.
I'm a data scientist.
I haven't done much
on the time series,
but I think it's pretty interesting.
I'd like to learn more.
No problem. Thank you for your question.
For the time series,
I'm not sure
what you mean by validation.
But if you mean
how to cut the fold,
how to cut the data
to do cross-validation.
For example, we cut four or five
common cuts.
We don't do shuffle.
We don't do random
cut.
We don't do random cross-validation.
For example,
we do training
for the first four years,
and then validation for the last year.
Or we do training for the next four years,
and then validation for the first year.
We want to
cut the time series
to do cross-validation,
not to do random
cut.
We don't do random
Because time series
is related to
time before and after.
So you can't
randomly do validation.
Does this answer your question?
Yes.
Thank you.
Okay.
What a wonderful discussion.
Does anyone
have any questions
to ask?
Hi, I'm
Xie Cheng.
Can you hear me?
Okay.
Hi.
I used to study in Taiwan University.
Now I'm studying in the US.
My question is
if
your model needs to be
used in the future,
will there be any security concerns?
For example,
maybe not too serious security.
Maybe there is a sudden event.
For example,
there is a joke about Excel
that occurs on holidays,
resulting in a large increase
in the search volume of Excel
on holidays,
or something like that.
How to avoid
this kind of
negative situation?
Yes, there is such a situation.
If you apply it to the industry,
you still have to set a threshold.
If the temperature
is normal in Taiwan,
it may be 0 to
40 degrees or so.
You may say
there is a mistake here,
I may stop my service.
You may tell users
why the service has stopped.
For example,
you can't use automatic
or something like that.
This is really necessary to add
additional rules to avoid such a situation.
Because in the industry,
if you use this kind of low prediction
to do automatic control,
there will be such a risk.
Cool.
I want to ask another question
related to Cargo.
I have been studying for a while.
I saw that last year,
I don't know what to say now.
Anyway, I saw two competitions last year.
One is the target of wheat,
and the other is
the image detection of
a special type.
In fact, I also know some traditional
breeders who have collected a lot of
this kind of image data.
Their quality may not be
so uniform,
but they may have to give up.
But if you put it on Cargo now,
let this kind of
data scientist community
have a good result.
I'm curious about this kind of academic unit
to put the data on it,
and then let everyone
come together
to find a solution
and then publish it.
Is there anything to pay attention to
in this process?
How is it usually achieved?
This Cargo competition,
because I was
preparing for this competition
at the end of the previous year.
At that time, I had not yet
entered the lab,
so I did not participate in this part.
But as far as I know,
they will actually do some cleaning first.
I mean, this is our lab,
because we are the organizer.
We will process these data first
and then confirm that
the quality of these data is probably no problem.
Then it will be sent to Cargo
and their team to explain the data.
Cargo also has a group of
very professional data scientists
to check the quality of the data,
which is probably OK,
and they won't clear the data for you,
because data missing and outliers
are things to deal with in the competition.
Then they will go and see
if the data is OK,
and then they will
test it internally
and confirm that
if the data is used for the competition,
how much training data and validation data
do I have?
Although when we give him the data,
we give him two years of training and one year of validation.
But they strongly recommend
one year of training and two years of prediction.
They have their
basis,
which is what they think,
and we respect it.
They have a lot of know-how
to organize this competition.
Most of the Cargo competitions so far
are not very controversial,
so I think Cargo and their internal team
are still very strong.
If it's more local,
their data platform,
competition platform,
sometimes they have a lot of controversy,
and sometimes the quality of the competition
is poor,
but I can't say that the competition platform is wrong.
That is, their internal professionals
don't have much resources,
so they can't hire such a large team
to check the details of these competitions.
In addition, the domestic platform
doesn't charge
the organizer.
If it's in Cargo,
the organizer will use their team
to check the data and collect the fees.
So the prize is not only
the organizer
who provides the prize,
but also the host of the competition
who needs to pay
an extra fee to Cargo.
Yes,
to ensure that this competition
is of good quality.
Thank you. Nice talk.
Thank you for your question.
I don't rule out
any discussion
about Open Data Say
in Cargo competitions.
You can ask any questions.
It's fun.
Due to time constraints,
we will open the last question.
Let's see
if there are any questions from the audience.
If not,
we will open the last question
for our host.
It's the same.
Please introduce yourself.
Hello,
host and audience.
I am
the host,
Hu Junwei.
My father
used to be a student of
NTUC,
and I studied
renewable energy systems
at NTUC.
I am very interested in
today's topic.
I have a question.
This model
can be used
to assess
events in energy
or social development
such as dynamic events.
For example,
in 2016 and 2017,
there was a power outage
in Taipei.
Is there a way
to predict
when there will be
a power outage
in the next few days?
Or
in the case of
COVID-19,
many countries
are working
from home,
so the energy use
will be very different.
Is there a way
to do dynamic analysis
for specific events?
I would like to hear
your opinion.
I think it's pretty cool.
First of all,
if it is a power outage
or a power outage,
I think it is relatively difficult.
The first is that it is a rare event,
so the rare event
may only happen
ten times in the past.
It's hard to predict
because there is not enough data
for training.
Even if there are
a lot of events,
you need enough features
to describe them.
For example,
you need to detect
voltage, current,
frequency,
etc.
I don't know
if there is such open data,
but I know Kaggle
can also find open data like this.
Next,
let me think of
a recent competition
in IEEE.
They are specifically predicting
what the energy forecast
will look like after COVID-19.
They are heading
electricity demand forecasting post-COVID.
They want to know
what changes will happen
to most energy
after COVID-19.
Most of them should be
related to
human behavior.
I have done
one thing before.
If you use Google Keywords,
I can show you
quickly today.
If you use Google Trends,
this is what I found recently.
It is quite related to
travel keywords.
For example,
I went to
travel.
You can see that
it suddenly dropped
on March 1st.
It was quite stable
in the first four years.
It dropped in the summer,
but it suddenly dropped
in March this year.
Of course,
this is just a correlation.
Whether this is a causal relationship
may be confirmed in more detail.
This is just an example.
You can find out from some data
if you can predict
what will happen
to the energy
after COVID-19.
This is also what everyone is concerned about.
I am not sure
if this can be done.
You can find out
whether to describe
this feature.
This is a very cool question.
Thank you.
Thank you for the wonderful explanation.
Due to time constraints,
I know that
everyone here may have
some potential questions.
However,
this is the end of
today's presentation.
Thank you again,
Fuxun.
If you are interested
in this topic
or the speaker,
you can contact her
through e-mail
or social media
related to Fuxun.
If you are interested
in different fields
and different topics
of different speakers,
you are welcome to
continue to participate
in Project Tara's activities
as a speaker.
Thank you for your participation today.
I wish you a pleasant day
or evening.
Thank you.