I'm going to share my screen first.
You can share your screen at the same time, no problem.
Okay, cool.
Thank you.
We are really happy to have Yichi as our speaker today.
Yichi Hong is currently a second-year PhD student at Boston University.
Coincidentally, she studied psychology at Taiwan University.
She studied psychology at Taiwan University.
She has worked in two different research institutes.
One is a research institute run by Dr. Reagan Lin.
The other is a research institute run by Dr. Wu Wen-Chi.
She mainly studies behavioral coding and research methods related to FMRI.
Yichi is amazing.
She graduated three years in advance.
After graduation, she became a research assistant for two years.
Now, she has applied to Boston University for research.
Her research focuses on the characteristics of adult anti-social behavior that can be observed in childhood.
She studies these characteristics through the method of quantitative behavior inheritance.
Today, we will hear some research related to FMRI, behavioral inheritance, and so on.
I will introduce Yichi to you.
Let's give Yichi the floor.
Welcome, Yichi.
Please start.
Thank you for the introduction.
Behavioral inheritance is a difficult topic.
I will not talk about the research related to FMRI today.
I will start.
I am Yichi Hong.
I am a postgraduate student at Boston University.
My research focuses on the development of children before puberty.
We can estimate the impact of genes and the environment on behavior.
In a group, we can see the difference in individual behavior.
How many percentages can be explained by genes or the environment?
I will talk about behavioral inheritance and how to do it.
I will talk about the assumption and basic model of FMRI.
I will talk about the changes we have collected and the analysis we are doing.
We did not control or manipulate any of the changes.
We did not secretly send twins to different families.
Behavioral inheritance aims to answer a big question in psychology or philosophy.
The question is whether human behavior is decided by God or God.
Plato and Aristotle had different opinions on this question.
Plato thought that human behavior was decided by God.
Everyone was born with different abilities.
Aristotle thought that human behavior was created by God.
Everyone was born with a white paper.
The structure of society or education is the most important factor in our behavior.
We also saw this in the time of Simon.
Testamentarians often prioritized diversity and the experience.
Testamentians felt that human beings should have some talents.
They felt that human beings should have some talents.
It's Universalism.
But what is the current psychology on these issues?
We have been walking along a middle path quite sufficiently.
We felt that genes and environment
and others are responsible for human behavior.
We found that there are other researches on the relationship between environment and genes.
Through personalities in different religions
through personalities in different religions
we studies on to analyze genetic mutations.
Human is a sediment different environment
There are some unfavorable examples that we find on sexual environment,
The first thing is family study
people in Taiwan has monogamy books
We have now standardized this information
we have now standardized this information
family study looks like
Although it is shown by numbers
children are more likely to be sexually transmitted
Children are more likely to be sexually transmitted
The ratio of genes divided by family is high
the environment of each generation will be different
The information on different generations, as mentioned before, varies from generation to generation
However, DNA definition should only be applied in children
The ideal condition is to find тур
The task of double third-party studies is a good source of the teacher
the task of double third-party studies is a good source of the feeder
they are born almost the same time
you can see the picture
They are the same sex
they are the same sex
genes are 100% connected
10% of twins, mother and childω
they often havesoft egg
they often have soft egg
they can be more close in relationship
when they share the 100%
thus 50%
he can then estimate the influence with document
hence 50%
and the impact will be still small
that is a limitation of the research
even they have good genetic analysis
but it is hard to control the enviornment
then collectively
the research of pig breeding
has better analysis of the envientos
as you can see in this diagram
the research of children breeding
and the parents who breed
the similarities between them
can be explain in Template 0
they share the enviornment
the relationship between childrens and parents
the relationship between children and parents
that is related with their genes
but the influence of the same generation
can be seen in the design of the research
so the most perfect state
should be when we study the twins who are adopted
but the limitation of the research
is that it is hard to collect such data
the database I know in the world
should be one in Sweden
and one in Minnesota
so the limitation is that it is hard to collect the data
the above is the method of measurement
that is we can't directly see
which DNA
has influence on the behavior
but with the development of biotechnology
we can directly see the information in DNA
but I am not familiar with this
so I will simply divide it into
theoretical and atheoretical
to introduce to you
the former is like
candidate genes
for example
today I want to see the behavior of adulteration
then I will study
the genes related to the多巴胺
because we know that
the rejuvenation mechanism and adulteration
are closely related
so we will first select some genes
then put the focus on these genes
to see the variances of these genes
and the variances of the behavior
are they related
but now this method
is a little bit
unknown
because
human behavior
doesn't look like
there is a small part of genes
and then there is a huge amount of effect
to explain those behaviors
but
more like there are many many genes
and then their effect is very small
and then pile up
so
through the method of candidate genes
we can currently
explain
the behavior variation is about 1% to 5%
that kind of variation
and we use the previous
mentioned
quantitative behavioral genetics
to get the
estimate value
there is a big gap
so later
molecular biologists
or molecular bio-hereditary behaviorists
they use a more violent method
that is not to assume
and then go to GWAS
directly analyze all the DNA sequences
that can see a lot of nucleotides
that is
the ACTG in DNA
these sequences
and then we will go to see
these nucleotides
we will go through their
variance
and then go to some numbers
and then stack it up
and then go to see this
number
is it related to the behavior we are interested in
that this is the current
method of molecular bio-hereditary behavior
but the difficulties encountered
is that there are quite a few
that is, it takes about a few million
to be able to
estimate some more effective results
that
another question
is
just talked about
they are through
the effect of nucleotides
stacked up
so
this paper
they are looking at
intelligence
is intelligence
this
feature
that
assume that
the variance between the groups
is 100%
and then go through
nucleotides
to estimate out of the value
is probably
genes can probably explain
50% of the mutations
but by stacking this method
we can calculate
it can explain
about only 25%
that
the difference in the middle
represents what
it means
these genes may not be
a linear effect that can be stacked up
but
they will be related
or interaction
and so on
so
how to calculate
those genome score
that is
the direction of future efforts
yes
the above is a brief introduction
I want to stop
to see if you have any questions
and then
if you have any questions
you can directly turn on the microphone
then welcome everyone
directly turn on the microphone
to ask questions
or if everyone
is
you can also use chat
that I can
is to help you
help you with the speaker
is to ask
the other
if you have any questions
also welcome everyone
is a little
one sentence
can simply introduce yourself
you can get to know each other
thank you
that if there is no problem
is here
want to emphasize
is that every method
of some restrictions
but did not have
a perfect research design
so behavioral genetics
can be integrated through different methods
and then go to see a
more stable
can be found
trend
like this
then we look at
behavioral genetics
I will be here
with the example of biopsy research
that he
in the end
how to study
the impact of genes and the environment
on the concept
is the same
we look at
the relationship between individual genes
with the relationship on the behavior
that if this relationship
is significant, then
we will say
genes for us
are interested in this behavior
has a certain degree of impact
and then we
here to measure a biological term
called heritability
it refers to
how many degrees
in the observed behavioral mutation
can be explained by genes
but because this is a method of measurement
so specific
in the end what is the gene
we have no way to know
that part of the environment
we can further
divide into shared
and non-shared environment
that first talk about
the shared environment
it refers to the environment
those individuals
they experience the same factors
and these factors
will make the individual
for example, like
twins
their social status in the family
living in the community
or culture, etc.
on the other hand,
non-shared environment
as the name implies
is the environment
each individual
unique experience
and these unique experiences
in theory
will cause differences between individuals
such as
accidents
or miscalculations, etc.
so just like today
a pair of twins
if there is a person
with COVID
cough
the other person does not
then they sleep in different rooms
one person will be sick
one person will not
so although they are
twins
but their life experience
will not be exactly the same
or say
they are in the uterus
the position of the left bed is different
maybe one is above
one is below
so
the difference in the environment
will not be born to them
early birth
that physical development
is there any impact
that
this is also possible to cause
different factors
of same-egg twins
specifically
how do we calculate it
is that we are through
the similarity between individual
and behavior
that is to collect some
correlation
so we will collect
their behavioral data
and then in the model
we will have
twin 1 and twin 2
in this order
we will try to
we will randomize
to reduce some errors
ok
and then in the model
we will put three factors
that is
gene
and then the shared environment
and the non-shared environment
and then we will try
to use these three factors
to predict
their behavioral mutations
like this
ok
that
part of the parameters
is our assumption
ok
then we start from the gene
for same-egg twins
that is
monozygotic twins
so they are mz
that because they share
100% of the gene
so we will
put the correlation here
is 1
assume
the two genes
um
the impression
is exactly the same
ok
what about monozygotic twins
that is
dizygotic twins
they share
50% of the gene on average
oh
the gene here refers to
the 1.3% gene unique to humans
because we share with
black stars
98.7%
ok
so
that is
for monozygotic twins
this factor
we will put 0.5
as
the parameter in our model
ok
that
shared environment
because they will all
grow up in the same family
so
for
same-egg and monozygotic twins
we assume
this shared environment
has the same impact on them
so we will
put 1
as their correlation
and
in addition
in the non-shared environment
there is no assumption
because
um
for each individual
logically
it is unique
so we will
make it an independent event
and
put it here
if you have studied
psychology-related courses
you may have a little impression
formula
so
we just talked about
our analysis
is to analyze
the correlation between twins
so we will say
that
usually the correlation between twins
cause
the reason for this correlation
is because
they have 100%
the same genes
and 100%
the same environment
so
the correlation between
the same-egg and monozygotic twins
will be
half of the same genes
plus
their
100%
the same environment
to explain
and
it should be quite obvious
that
for
the prediction of the non-shared environment
we will
subtract the correlation between
the same-egg and monozygotic twins
by 1
so
next
I want to share
this paper
um
is written by
Robin Pullman
and
he should be
the most famous
behavioral geneticist
at least
in psychology
it's like this
so
if you are interested
you can look it up
he listed 10 points
that can be stabilized
by replicating
some
results
so
I will talk about two
um
the first one
I want you to guess
how much of human intelligence
can be determined by genes
and
um
in the process of growth
the part that genes can explain
will change over time
or less
and
I'll give you
10 seconds
to guess
in your heart
ok
so
um
this result
is a
meta-analysis
so
they
compared
in
childhood
adolescence
and
early adulthood
um
behavioral genetics
they saw
how much of the genes
can explain
the proportion of intelligence
and
what they found
is that
in childhood
um
genes can explain
about 40% of the changes
but
in adulthood
genes can explain
up to 70%
and
we see
in the
early childhood
we can see
that
um
the genes
can explain
about
50% of the changes
and
in the
early adulthood
we see
the effect of sharing the environment
is less
yes
I don't know if this is
a surprising discovery
because
maybe someone will think
after we are born
we are constantly
disturbed by the environment
and
the environment
may have a
positive effect on our body
but
at least in intelligence
we see
a
opposite result
um
so
how did behavioral genetics
explain
this phenomenon
we think
it's because
as a person
develops
he has a better
control of his environment
so
yes
how does a person
decide his environment
most of the time
we will choose
those that meet
our
conditions
we feel comfortable
we stay there
so
it should be through this logic
but
you can imagine
when you were a child
a lot of things
are decided by parents
and
after growing up
we can
control more and more
details in our lives
like
we are not
after growing up
more and more
indecisive
but
we won't
let things we don't like
appear on
our table
yes
oh
what about
the second study
they looked at
the negative attitude of
teenagers' antisocial behavior and mothers
they studied
teenagers' twins
so
teenagers' mothers
are like
an environmental factor
so
what did they find
they found
ok
the negative attitude of mothers
sounds like
a shared environmental factor
but
when they ran
that model
they found
genes
shared environment
and non-shared environment
can significantly explain
the relationship between these two concepts
so
there are a few
interesting
results
we can discuss
like
the first one
we found
individuals in the environment
are not
passively affected by the environment
but
those seem to be environmental factors
to some extent
reflect some of their
genetic characteristics
you can imagine
when interacting with people
we are not
interacting with them
in the same way
like
if you meet someone
who smiles more often today
you will
respond
smile more often
so I think
this result is quite interesting
like
some of the conditions of parents
are often thought to be
a shared environment
but
they may also be
affected by the genes of their children
so
parents may
interact with their children
in the same way
it is a bit like
the parent-to-parent relationship
shared by the high-level intelligence
maybe
the parents have too high requirements
so
I think
this result
can comfort some parents
like
oh
no
like
you may do something
and the child will not respond
or
what you do
is because the child
makes you do this
and so on
then
some environmental factors of parents
such as
this negative attitude
it can also
cause individual differences
if everyone has brothers and sisters
it may be easier to imagine
that
there will always be
when parents are biased
although
this mother
may have a negative attitude
is higher than average
but
her negative attitude
may only target a certain child
so
such a relationship
will cause
differences between individuals
yes
so
let's stop here
do you have any questions?
hello
I would like to ask
my name is Shi Qinghua
Shi Toushi
Tsinghua University
I would like to ask
about
the paper
on self-discipline
about self-discipline
their explanation is that
after adulthood
it is better to master the environment
then
such a component
if like us
international students
will there be any changes
did they discuss it?
because we are
in an environment
that we are not familiar with
and do not have a good grasp of
oh
understand
but I think
their paper on self-discipline
may be more like
the kind of self-discipline
that will not be affected by language
so
I was thinking
that
the part about international students
is that
the way of measuring
will it be more unfavorable for us
this kind of miscalculation?
not entirely
because like us
to a new environment
especially
when it is a very unfamiliar environment
many times
our performance
is actually
likely to be
worse at the beginning
of course
it is also
more in line with what they said
because we are in an environment
after getting used to
will perform better
but we
in fact, I just want to say
that we will not
because of the environment
to become a little stupid
like this
I think it will
there is a
more related
but they are
discussing the social economic status
is the parents
is the family
those social status
and so on
and then they found
that there is an interaction
that is
if you are
social economic status
family resources more
your genes can be better
but if your resources
less
most of the environment is oppressive
and then the environment
to explain
you that
the bad performance of the intelligence
yes
understand
thank you
hope to answer the question
but they do
is the social economic status
but I think
that is
discussing
that
the whole environmental change
is also quite interesting
Hi
I have a question
I am
my name is Qiao En
I want to follow
just that
the question of Tsinghua
want to ask is that
that
is because
after a long time
you see it
seems
the amount of gene explanation is rising
that
this means that
it will come to us
when we are adults
we choose
to have
should be like this
oh
I have to ask the question
should say that
how is it
the real state
is that after we are adults
see that
the performance
is in line with
the real gene explanation
or our childhood
that is
I think this question
is very interesting
I personally will be more inclined
I think
during adulthood
we really have
complete autonomy
measured things
is true
but I think it
behind the reaction is quite a lot
is that you want to see
development
is the concept of the human development process
I am more inclined
to adulthood
this result
is good
thank you
I also think so
I just want to know
what do you think
thank you
that means
there is a question here
Gao Xian, do you want to ask yourself
ask yourself
ok
I also posted it
on the chat room
I am quite curious
that
ok
I ask directly
that is
twins
they may
have different
interactions with the environment
their genes
may have some disappearance
for example, the fake plan
and so on
as a chemistry
assistant
I ask this question
if this matter
is also considered
then we
you just
mentioned in the last page
we assume
when talking about the parameter
you said
twin genes
we assume it is related to 1
but if we
consider
these
modified
issues
that obviously
should not be 1
that is
I do not know
this matter
on behavioral genetics
how to consider
I think
I think they
oh
behavioral genetics
it will explain the method
because you are in the process of the process of
gene is exactly the same
so that causes you
behind the fake plan process
will be classified as
non-shared environment
is the environment
stimulate the performance of your fake plan
like this
but indeed we can go to see
the environment and gene
some of the interaction
so that
it feels like
I do not know
in
statistics on this matter
how you will go to run this analysis
but it feels like
genes and the following
environment
these two variables
may be related to
is not it
in the model
is not related
to the assumption is not related
but in statistics
is not it
may be related
to the statistics
I do not know how you
run analysis
but I think in statistics
is not it
that is between the variables
there is a relationship
but may not have
a contributory problem
but
I understand
your assumption
I can comment on a small
good
is
epigenetics
side of the impact
in fact, a large part
is from the environment
so in fact it can
even if its epigenetic mutations
or mutations of histone modification
or other
modifications of the difference
in fact, a lot from the
impact of the environment
so in fact it should be
if I were
I would tend to put it
on the effect of the environment
like before there is a
study
it is a
identical twin
one up in space
one did not go to space
and then under the influence of neutrality
their genetics
part of the same
but epigenetic
modification
is very, very large
so it should still
count on the impact of the environment
thank you
I just tried to
express this thing
but I am actually a little
hesitant
about
if it is epigenetic
it seems to be through
the gene pathway
but conceptually we will put it
on the non-shared environment
this factor
thank you
understand
you are welcome
that
we still have other questions
that I will continue
that
will move to the next part of our laboratory
that we are called
the laboratory
PhD
Twin Project
and then my boss is PI
that we have done two
long-term tracking
first plan is to see
two to three years old
and then the second
is another set of children
and then from three years old to five years old
that my research is mainly
for the second database
is three to five years old before school
this stage
that our database
there are 310
twins of the same gender
and then a little bit less than
here
it is worth noting that
we are talking about the same gender
because the same gender twins
must be the same gender
but the same gender
may be the same gender
that we want to reduce
some of the gender-caused
measurement errors
so we agreed to
receive twins of the same gender
and then
I have a little story here
on the first year
when I still have a chance to talk to the boss
face to face
I asked him
where to find so many twins
and then said
oh, we are in Boston
the progress of reproductive medicine
is suddenly a big mistake
that these twins
some of the artificial
results
and then
so our search
is to be in the twins
three years old, four years old, five years old
before and after the birthday
and then invite them to the lab
to do the experiment
that the experiment process
about three to four hours
and then we collect a lot of data
that is, including behavioral observation
to some tasks
and then or questionnaire
that questionnaire will ask
parents
that is, the main caretaker fill out
and then the test taker
will follow
the process of interacting with children
to do some evaluation
that measurement of the phenomenon
we collect
the cognitive function of the child's temperament
learning performance
cognitive function and learning performance
there will be more detailed examples
and then there are some
behavioral problems
such as internalizing problem
or externalizing problem
that it is a more
psychopathology classification
internalizing problem
is more emotional
you can imagine
those problems that are deeper in the heart
such as depression, anxiety, etc.
externalizing problem
is more on behavior
can be observed
such as
antisocial behavior
or attack behavior, etc.
so we have this kind of data
and then we also have
the process of collecting parents
interacting with children, etc.
there are more than 300 variables in a year
so my first year
is probably to understand
what is in the database
but I think I have not yet
fully understand
what kind of data
and then show you some
photos of cute children
when we collect the case
when they are tested
are separately tested
so these are taken at the same time
is the behind the scenes
experiment outside the experiment
and then the computer
is to show you
we have some tests
are carried out on the computer
and then if the child
for sitting in the laboratory
if you feel uncomfortable
we will invite their parents
is to sit in the room
but is not to interfere with
the child's task
that is quite interesting
here is the pool
it is an observation
of the child's temperament
and then there is a story
that is when I applied
my boss told me
I do not have to collect the case
is to collect
the analysis of the data
and then want to see if I can accept
because someone is
must play with their own children
and then I feel a little pity
but I am not very persistent
and then I went to the laboratory
I saw the recording screen
because we will first record
and then the coding
and then see a lot of children
once put in the pool
began to cry and scream
I originally imagined
the pool is a very happy
environment
children should be very happy
but it seems that a lot of people
is to be put into a unique space
and then they feel very afraid
so like this task
we can observe
the child's fearfulness
or activity level
like fearfulness
is to cry and scream
or not
that activity level is also very interesting
is their activity
that we see some children
is standing crying
some will only play
the ball on their feet
some will run and jump
and then fall
and then stand up
continue to run and jump
some will throw all the balls out
and then the whole laboratory
is full of their fearfulness
so you can really see
a lot of different changes
children have different reactions
so
that is
during the experiment
we will not interfere with children
how to play
so they can even cry
the experimenter can only endure
and then scream
endure that scream for three minutes
so I feel
too fortunate
do not have to play by yourself
but this child
looks pretty happy
it's great
and then in the upper right corner
this is our collection
a task of parent-child interaction
this toy is called
Etch-a-Sketch
and then I do not know
if everyone has seen it in Taiwan
I do not seem to have played
it is a board
and then there are two whirls
and then one can be controlled up and down
one can be controlled left and right
and then
we will give the children
a few pictures with the parents
and then they have to
within five minutes
the more pictures the better
that in the process
we can observe a lot of aspects
like parents
will be more authoritative
to give instructions
or more like a cooperation
in helping children
and then we can also see
some of their physical interaction
language communication
or if the child
today is not
want to do this task
parents will give what reaction
and so on
yes
and then we
the recipient is
will be like this
one by one to the lab
is very cute
do not have to collect their own people
can say this kind of sarcastic
and then
then I will share
my two analysis
that the first one
we looked at
at the age of three
the relationship between
the child's temperament and school readiness
how to be explained by
genes and the environment
that we first talk about
what is temperament
temperament
it is a child's temperament
that it can be understood
on the concept of
the basis of personality
the most widely known theory
should be
Chase and Thomas
they divide the baby into
easy baby
difficult baby
and slow to warm up
and other
and then they have
developed more detailed
classification
such as
the ability of the baby's self-adjustment
the activity of the baby
their emotional performance
is high
or relatively plain
or positive emotions
more
or negative emotions
like this
in addition to
Chase and Thomas
theory
there are other theories
but
behavioral genetics
the interesting thing is
found that
no matter what classification
we see
the child's temperament
has a very high
heritability
that is to say
this thing
is a bit like a
metaphor
genes can explain
a lot of
that
in this study
we use
Methody's classification
it looks at
activity
emotion
and concentration
and then
in
school readiness
its concept
is
children
how well prepared for
going to school
so it's actually
a pretty broad concept
like
children's
physical development
because
like some kindergartens
they ask
children to walk
or eat by themselves
to go
then
or
children's emotional control
this kind of
development of ability
that
our study
focus
is more like
academic performance
then
we use
Bracken
this measurement method
includes
them for
shape
number
English alphabets
color
size
this
in kindergarten
knowledge
will be used in the environment
look at their
in such a test
how high the score can be
such
good
Why do we want to
put these two concepts
connected together
mainly because
past research
they found
children's temperament when they were one year old
can be predicted
three or five years later
school readiness
so
represent these two concepts
there is some kind of relationship
but
this is not a
behavioral genetics research
so
what exactly is
what
in
control
is
genes
or the environment
control
the relationship between these two concepts
we are not very clear
behavioral genetics
we
less research in this area
then
I found a
closest
is
they look at
concentration
and academic performance
in
three or four years old
and then they found
mainly
by genes
to explain
so
this
analysis of
novelty
is that we want to
consider at the same time
different
child temperament
and then see if
this child temperament
they
with school readiness
have
the same genes
in control
or say
is only
concentration
especially this
child temperament
is with
school readiness
related
because everyone can imagine
in the educational scene
in the field
does not seem to be
you very focused
sitting there
you can learn a lot
but
your
emotional connection
to some
other social cognitive functions
may be affected
or your
intellectual development
if today's children
are surrounded together
run around
some things
and then they can
learn from the process
but you just
sit there
very focused
so
it seems
to learn from you
is not necessarily
a very stable
truth
development
so
good
that
before we put
the data
into the model
just like
just to talk about
our analysis
is
the relationship between twins
so we have to make sure
the relationship is established
and
on the one hand
is that we are discussing
individual differences
we have to make sure
there are enough
individual differences
we go to
analyze that
these individual differences
because of the environment
or genes
more meaningful
that
picture
you can see
purple is
same-sex twins
and pink is
that
the picture on the left
is talking about
in each phenomenon
the relationship between twins
that is to say
in the emotional aspect
same-sex twins
their correlation
and same-sex twins
and
task orientation
refers to focus
and
score readiness
that
picture on the right
may be more interesting
it
we call it
cross-chain
cross-chain correlation
it refers to
we use
twins
one of the A-phenomenon
to correlate
another twin
B-phenomenon
then we go
is to run
related analysis
that
flesh and blood
we can see
same-sex twins
compared to
have a higher
correlation
so
this can
tell us very roughly
genes
in explaining
these two concepts
is a certain degree of
impact
that
how much is specific
we have to
run a
model
to know
then
this
we
fit
is a
biometric
cholesky model
then
it is
the general
cholesky
model
inside the factor
in
further
cut into
genes
shared environment
and
non-shared environment
then
it's a bit messy
so I
step by step
to look at
this model
that
is
we have three
phenomena
then
we use
genes
to
explain
this model
first
we first
see
here
there is a
A3
factor
it
represents
is to explain
task
orientation
that is
the focus
of the
child's
temperament
gene
then
we
at the same time
allow
this
change
factor
to predict
affect
that is
emotional
this
phenomenon
with
score readiness
good
that is to say
if
these three
paths
are shown
A3
this
factor
refers to
these three
phenomena
underlying
that
common
gene
factor
common
genetic
factor
what is the problem
here
first
listen
good
if
not
then
come again
is
so
this
A3
factor
it
may be
able to explain
a part
all
or
completely
cannot explain
emotional
this
phenomenon
that
causes
emotional
this
phenomenon
and independent
A3
this
factor
gene
we put
a
A2
factor
to explain
it
that
we
at the same time
allow
A2
factor
to predict
score
readiness
some
that is
the
variance
that
so
note
is
A2
and
A3
they
are
independent
good
that
the rest of
those
can not
be with
task
orientation
and
affect
those genes
but
can affect
score
readiness
genes
they
that
will be
counted
in
A1
factor
inside
they
are both
independent
that
the same concept
we can
use
is
the same
put it
apply
to
the
environment
and
non-shared
environment
that
here
want to emphasize
is
that
the picture
see
all these
factors
and
past
are
at the same
predicted
like this
and
then
we
use
a
model
trimming
method
that is to say
in
model
fit
beautiful
we will
drop
out
not beautiful
non-shared
past
and
factor
we
finally
get
the
parsimonious
model
like this
so
this
model
tells us
what
this is
indeed
in
these three
behind
the phenomenon
is a
common
gene
affecting
them
and
emotion
this
aspect
is
some
independent
task
orientation
gene
in
unique
affect
emotion
this
temperament
that
this
found
we
are not
very
elegant
because
we
past
years
is that
know
task
orientation
and
affect
is
the concept of
children's temperament
is
a very
strong
gene
can
explain
them
but
we
found
interesting
is
in
school
readiness
above
affect
its
gene
is completely
with
concentration
and
emotion
these
children's temperament
the same
these
genes
it
is not
independent
of
children's temperament
other
genes
affect
it
on the other hand
in
the shared
environment
we see
the shared
environment
can not
affect
children's
temperament
that is to say
you rely on the environment
want to change
children's
little
personality
is
no way
that
you want them
to be the same
is very
difficult
if you
today
to make children
very focused
that
is
quite
difficult
but
we can
through
family
some factors
like
parents
may read
stories
to children
listen
or
they
look
TV
may
look
Tienxianbaobao
then learn
some
color
and
numbers
such as the concept
of these
environmental
impact can
let children's
school readiness
to move in the same direction
may be able to
improve their
school readiness
ability
and
this factor can
explain the
variation is probably
about 40%
I want to square it
about
the rest of the
good part
is that
can be shared
environment
so
that is
including some of
us
do not want to face
the measurement
error
or say
this may be
because
the same
rater
in the evaluation
of children's
children's temperament
so we see
non-shared environment
can explain
the two
covariance between the two
good
and then
summarize
so this analysis
tells us
we are in
three years old
to see
child temperament
with school readiness
between the relevant
are because
the same gene
behind the child
temperament
in the emotion
this aspect
is independent
focus
this aspect
of the gene
and the shared environment
is only
in
school readiness
above
there is a significant
impact
so
that we have to
this analysis
there is no
what
you want to ask
the question
of the host
think
OK
very clear
thank you
good
that I will
move to
the second analysis
so
that
just a little bit about
academic performance
and cognitive functions
are not the same
so
now this story
will be more
around
the development of cognitive functions
that we look at
is three to five years old
impulse control
so
is
one of the cognitive functions
so
there is a background
introduction
impulse control
he is talking about
to adjust
impulse
with
inhibits
is also
to suppress
with the goal
unrelated
interference ability
that in early childhood
genes
and the environment
is how to explain
impulse control
we currently
find the result
a bit
diverse
such as
our lab
before
for
two or three years old
child information
with
UW
medicine
there
biopsy research
have found
the same
result
is
quite strange
when we use
parents
to assess
impulse control
to analyze
in
two years old
and three years old
we all see
inhibits
control
can be
explained by genes
but
when we use
behavioral observation
is
there is a
called
lab
tap
this way
we only see
genes
can explain
impulse control at two years old
he has no way to explain
impulse control at three years old
yes
that
more strange
is to say
in
nine years old
child
when we use
another method
is cognitive
phase
may be through some
cognitive
test
cognitive task
or computerized
test
to measure
their
inhibits
control
we found
it can be
explained by genes
so
this makes us feel
with
behavioral
observation
see
no genes
can explain
impulse control at three years old
a bit strange
because
although
development
is a
dynamic process
but you can not imagine
genes
will be open
so he
in the end is
can explain
or can not explain
that our
idea
may be
our idea
is to say
may be
behavior
observation
a bit
limited
like
our
test process
is to measure
children's
delay
gratification
that
task
like we
give children
to see
chocolate
but they have to wait
a certain
second
can eat
chocolate
so
yes
in the process of
experiment
we will feed
children
eat
chocolate
that
this ability
may be
at three years old
children
have
learned all
that
is
this is a
socialized
process
so
the environment
suppressed
their
inhibits
control
and then
put them
all
described
in the same way
that
this
environment
force
will let
genes
no place
to show
so we
want to say
oh
that
or we
use another
way
to measure
children's
impulse
control
good
so
in this
analysis
inside
we use
is
Flanker
task
then
it is
from
NIH
toolbox
inside
a
test
that
everyone
may have done
the adult version
of
Flanker
task
it is
there will be
different
arrows
pointing
different
ways
directions
and then
you have to
observe
the arrow in the middle
that
arrow in the middle
sometimes
will be with
the direction
of the opposite
that you can not
be next to the arrow
confused
like this
good
it is a
quite classic
measure
executive
function
task
that
for
children's
task
child's
experiment
we
in order to
let them focus
we will
the story
package
a little fun
then we
package
the story is
that we
today to feed the fish
so you have to
look at
the middle
of this fish
it is
facing
this
or
that
because they
answer
the way
is to
point
screen
is good
so even
the main part
can still
carry out
this experiment
and then
we
also look at
related
that everyone
may be
notice
this analysis
related
with the previous
analysis
relative
is
compared to
a lot of difference
but
they are still
obvious
so we can still
follow-up analysis
and then
another point
want to add
is that we
look here
is the
cross-age
relationship
is
every age
related
with
cross-age
related
that
we use
is
rank
order
that ability
multiply
is
PR value
so if
three years old
child's
PR value
is 95
four years old
that
the relationship
will be very high
and not
use the original result
because
in theory
this time
their cognitive
function
should develop
quickly
so you
three or four years old
get the same score
is not a
very good
phenomenon
that
here is not very
high
related
to tell us that
in this period of time
they
impulse control
ability to develop
in fact, there are many
changes
that may be
at any time
children suddenly
become black horse
and then become
super focused
and super
can
self-control
like this
and then
we put the same
data
fit to
model
although
here is also
fit a
Cholesky
model
but
behavioral genetics
or
twin research
is not only
this model
can be used
this is more like
the process of my practice
but
you can see
that this model
is actually in
the development of research
is quite
a good model
because
like
in the previous example
it tells us
how many factors
between different concepts
can be
how many factors
are overlapped
that
here, then
it can tell us
in
different periods of development
those
stable
with new
added factors
is
stability
and change
can be how
explained
is how to be
explained by genes and the environment
that
our
best
fitting model
tells us
the first
most important
is
the shared environment
does not show the impact
but
most of them
are
genes
are explained by genes and
non-shared environment
that
age to age
stability
is that
these will
cross
different age
paths
are
the effect of genes
so
why do we see
stable development between ages
are all because of genes
is explained by genes
that
but
those changes
across ages
is
genes and
non-shared environment
together
to create
the effect
like this
good
so
you may be curious
that
these new genes
represent what
this may mean
we are
in the process of development
like
just
right
no
good
this
we can see
the brain
or other
physiological development
that
this is
the place where DNA can perform
then
I put this
model
change a way to perform
is to put those
factors
into
the model
and then
here want to see is
in every age
between
we see the
variance
how much can be
explained by genes or non-shared environment
that
we can pay attention to is
every age
of
mutations are different
and then
we draw here is the percentage
so interesting is
although mutations themselves are different
but genes can explain the proportion
is quite stable
that
is 35%
36%
that
this is the proportion
we just mentioned
heritability
is genes can explain
what percentage of mutations
that
if we look more carefully
we can see
at the age of four
most of the
heritability
is explained by the genes
of the new performance at the age of four
about 80% of these
heritability
but at the age of five
the new genes
only show
50% of the
heritability
and the rest is
in the previous age
the effect of those genes that have been left behind
so this
result tells us
is the longest
highest number of
people
still worth it
it can tell us some
more interesting
genes
in the process of development
is how to change
this
good
that
the same
small summary
so we see
three to five years old
the stability of the age range
is all explained by the genes
but the change in the age range
is explained by the genes and non-shared environment
and
the shared environment
no way
to impulse control
has a significant impact
and I remember
I last summer
with my university teacher
Mr. Wu Wen-Chi
share this result
is that he is a pair of
dragon and phoenix
and then at that time
four or five years old
and I said
surprised
parents can not use the same way
to improve the ability of children to impulse control
and then he
laughed for a moment
do not need to do the experiment
I knew
because the children
do not care what you are doing
and I feel
so strong sense of helplessness and helplessness
is really quite hard parents
OK
here to stop
good for
these two analysis
have what
you want to ask the question
I want to ask
is
Although
because the environment
between the twins
is the same
but
every pair of twins
is the difference between
their social
economic
rank
will not affect them
I think
social economic status
so that is the family
family shared
those environmental factors
is it
right
because
it will be calculated to
the shared environment
you say in the impulse control
will not affect the shared environment
because I found that
there is no
I'm just curious to say
in fact, not in this
this comparison
but to say
in your observation
different pairs of twins
social economic
situation
will affect
their child's
impulse control
I do not seem to
particularly in this direction
development
discovery
Yeah
I think
in the impulsive control
or child development
in most cases, they will focus on
the education of the mother
is a lot of information
it is now
on this
but
is most of the mother
education
will be called
social
economic status
parel
but that
is not
the idea of ​​the whole big
SES generalization
there is
a
sort
have
it
I want to add just
Tsinghua
Tsinghua teacher
of the problem
so in fact
because you just
in fact, have mentioned that
you Boston
this
this study
is most of
the medical center of
medical promotion so I can imagine
in fact, your whole
I do not know
is not the fact
but I feel
your whole sample size
sample should be
very
very biased
is
I say so
is not
not to criticize your
sample
I mean
so it sounds like
your sample should
not
I just say
I like to hear
your sample
is more
higher
knowledge level
or high
economic level
and then
is just mentioned
you talk about that
educational level
in fact, I think
this thing
I think it is very interesting
because
I do not know
you know
that is
they have to discuss
all of the
social economy
of these
social economic
background
these social economic
it is actually a
cluster
that this cluster
inside
like
it
he thought
that is
formal education
is inside the host
that is
this change
it is actually
all of the control of that
your social and economic
for example, say
your education level
higher
your
whole economic level
you will be higher
usually
that is
if it is a large sample
it is such a phenomenon
so I think
that is
to reflect back
this question
is to say
this is actually
in your observation
will
this thing
is for you
the whole
discovery of research
is
there
an alternative
mechanism
I do not know
my
yes
I think
pretty clear
yes
this is indeed
our
inside the sample
is actually quite
homogenous
most
are
quite good
education level
and then
because Boston
is a lot of universities
and then
Boston population
itself is
mainly white people
and then
the proportion of black people
is quite small
Asians
more than black people
so this is a
quite strange structure
and then
I only
discussed with my boss
this issue
and then
he
gave me a
get over it
that
explanation is
we can say
a bit like
we are in the sample
regress
this
impression
but
even if
regress
this impression
we still have to see
common
those
environmental factors
that we can
focus on
if
good
we know
is not SES
that we can think about
that other
is what
environmental
common factors
can explain this
we find
those factors
right
that
is
that the problem
does exist in our
sample
that we
think of another way
to
how to be more effective
to use our
data
like this
I also have
understand
I also have a
curious question
that is
I am watching
your
this
research
because its
sample size
is very large
and
its
cross-age
is several
so
your
dropout rate
is probably how high
and I was thinking
if
very low
is not
related to
just
high-risk
because you
here
is the participant
it has a very special
this
high
SES
situation
right
I
must say
I think
300 pairs of twins
is not a very large
sample size
is
Robin Pullman
he was invited to the UK
they are doing
more than 7,000 pairs of twins
so I think
can not be compared
then
our dropout rate
in the first year is probably 10%
the second year is probably
12-13%
or so
so
I think it is a
state that can be accepted
because
mainly
as we have talked about
our
twin study assumption is
still twins
is 50% of the gene
that is on average
so
it will affect
we have to have
enough twins
to do this assumption
or there will be a lot of
bias
thank you
that
is not possible
I think
in Boston
the benefit of the case
should indeed be
parents will be more willing
to contribute
their children to the CNS
there are other questions?
Then I will jump to
the last slide
so it is
a simple summary
of the first behavior study
it is a
can be studied at the same time
genes and environment
how to affect
an experiment method of individual behavior
and then
is
to respond to
the struggle between Socrates and Plato
is in our human
development process
genes and the environment
are at the same time
have a significant impact
like this
and then
then
it is a bit of a response to
the previous
research by Robert Pullman
is that children in
the development process
is not passive
affected by the environment
but children's genes
will also actively
interact with their environment
is to produce
and then
it is
we know
genes and the environment
have a significant impact
on the development
and this impact
will change over time
this is the above
simple summary
of what I have covered today
and then
here, then
you can search
is that it will connect to my
Facebook Medium
or Clubhouse
and then
Medium
there are some
that is
in the United States
some of the
Dr.
Murmur
every month
and then
if you want to
group up
can read
that if you want to
save time
I will
put it in the description
and then
if you want to
use the social process of the Provincial Office
you can
send it directly to my email
I will also reply
like this
and then
is
Q&A time
I hope everyone
is not like this
little friend so confused
but
very welcome
all kinds of discussions
like this
then I will talk about it here today
thank you all
I think today
is like a word
learned a lot
this is not a course
because
that is
as a
developmental psychology
PhD student
is
often in the course
a lot of
research on this
but I think
is
a word
that can be like
I think there
may be related areas
may be different areas
can be very clear
put a
I think it may be quite complicated
that model
with
I
although you just
have very humble
said more than 300 teams
very little but
I think
300 teams
quite a lot
so
I think I can put
such a large-scale research
so clearly
I think
is a very difficult thing
and I think
it is really clear
and so interesting
and
the picture is so beautiful
so
now I will
play this Q&A time
so that
everyone can
freely discuss
and ask questions
that
everyone is like just the same
is that you can
unmute your own
that
audio
directly ask the question
thank you Yizi
thank you
that
Gao Xian to vote a question
this is
good
this is actually my first
model is
particularly interested
course the second is also very interesting
because it is
talking about stability
but I think
your first model
is that
in fact, you have talked about
a
conclusion
you say
that
emotion
affect
it to
score
readiness
is
no prediction effect
but I
look at
your this
what is this called
trusty
?
the
model
you do not seem
that you do not seem to use
affect
to predict
score
readiness
you want
because
I put
you this
think of
that
structural
equation
of
modeling
that is behind
those
circles
I treat it as
random
variable
then I
want to say
your
you do not seem to
go to pull
affect
to predict
score
readiness
and
a little curious
you this
conclusion is
how to come
is
I
is not I
for this
model
did not
particularly
understand
clearly
no no no
I think you look very
careful
so you mean
this
path
did not
show
be pulled up
I can not see
your arrow
now
can
this is your
affect
so you
must
from A2
to score
readiness
because I
originally thought
you said
because your
your
following
conclusion
above
is written
that
affect
did not
predict
effect
so I
originally
expected
you should
pull
a
affect
to
the second point
affect
does not
unique
contributed
to
score
readiness
so I
originally
expected
you this
sentence
should be
to say
your
affect
to pull
a line
then
to
predict
that
score
readiness
I
understand
I think
this
model
it is
put
three variables
and then
pull
out
up
so it is
not like
SEM
it is
pull it up
and then
these
factors
they are
each other
independent
so it
does not
affect
the path
and
it
I
I will write
that
affect
it
to
score
readiness
no
unique
impact
is because
this
path
is not
limited
so
independent
score
sorry
independent
task
orientation
and then
only affect
affect
these
genes
it
is not
significantly
affect
score
readiness
so
can explain
affect
and score
readiness
behind the same
is
through
task
orientation
this
gene
so
there
is clear
oh
understand
so
you actually
refer to
special
is
gene
performance
ah
gene
part of the
explanation
is not actually
the whole
affect
is
this
meaning
right
understand
and then
I
also
if you do not have
a question
then I will continue to ask you
is that I am
very interested
in your first video
or the next video
is
that
I seem to see
that you have a lot of
BART
and then go to see
that gene
explanation
this thing
and then
is
a twin
ah
this
that BART
is not
that
um
on another
BART
is
related to
that
is
to feel
up
I directly
from that
point of view
feel
right
ah
temperament
I guess
we are at an
estimate
right
and then
I
from
your
another
picture
I feel
is
ah
especially
is
AFET
there a
special
strong
gene prediction effect
compared to
other
like what
ah
text
orientation
I
I guess
this is actually
inhibitory
control
of a kind
I do not know
I am
not familiar with this
so feel
it seems
should be
self-regulation
a
phenomenon
so I
actually
for
this result
quite
curious
why
this self-regulation
this text
orientation
it is actually
no gene
prediction effect
ah
no gene
can explain
because the place
related to
relatively low
than AFET
ah
than
prediction
still low
so I am quite curious
that
your
explanation of
that
method
I think this approach
quite interesting
well
if AFET
I just
first thought
is that it can actually
from
our
ah
blah blah blah
we do not know how to see
animation is really a bit of trouble
is
because you can
indeed see
it in addition to
A3 this factor
to explain AFET
it has its own independent
equivalent to
it seems to have two
genetic factors
to explain AFET
so
I would think
we see in AFET
relatively high
that
heritability
is quite reasonable
but
talk about
why
task orientation
its
ah
gene
ratio looks
not very high
I think
this is very interesting
I have not thought about this issue
I want to plug in
because you just talked about that
Charles
I will not read
Ferski
of that model
is good
that model
is
you
if you put that order
transferred
you put
ah
I can look at the next picture
you put that
task
ah
task orientation
and AFET
two
contrast
in fact, there will be similar things
because it is actually
put
that
for example, A3
you can also put
predict
task
AFET
ah
school readiness
and A2
only predict
task
orientation
so it can actually
it is just a partial out
is to pull it
FERS process only
so in fact, I look back
it seems
I am still very confused
why
task orientation
so
I think
it should be a pretty
gene
thing
is self-adjustment
compared to AFET
ah
I do not dare to say
I do not
just
in short, I think
it should also have
a lot of
gene performance
but from just
your picture
from your bar
you can clearly see that
it seems that the gene
that performance
is particularly low
that I do not know
is not because you
now this child
only three years old
because the child
is probably around two years old
his
self-regulation
will be more
formal
I do not know if it is because of the dissection
but I think
three years old
in fact, it should be quite complete
but I think
I do not know if it is because
he is still relatively young
so
self-regulation
has not been completely
really
good
test
and so on
I do not know
I do not know what your explanation
will be
well
I think
it is interesting
I will answer it one by one
I think the first question
is a very expert question
is about the model
how to put those items
indeed
if you want to calculate some
is that you finally
pull out of the thing
you do not care how to put
calculated
estimated heritability
will be the same
but
we will put here
the reason is because
past research has known
task orientation
and score readiness
are related
so that
it is actually not a
particularly interesting phenomenon
that we are interested in is
affect and score readiness
they will not actually have
a unique
score readiness
related
so we put it in the second
that is to say
if these two
paths are obvious
it can be said
oh, we guessed
that is right
but we guessed wrong
so
its order
can
reflect some of our
questions we want to ask
then
score readiness
put at the end
means
it actually
we want to see
unique
for score readiness
those effects
because we actually
really interesting
is not the
temperament
we are interested in
it
temperament
and score readiness
related
with
score readiness
itself
in the end
what
special
effect
like this
so
that is
the order of the model
will
affect
how we want
to be more
effective
and convenient
to explain this model
then
I think
that
question of heritability
can look at
this path
so we can see here
that is
this path
square
will be its
heritability
so
here
calculated
actually
gene can explain
about 40%
variance
for
task orientation
so
actually
not particularly
low
although
in the
bar graph
inside
does not look
high
but
it is actually
explained
about 40%
right
I'm here
to interrupt
as a host
is
the time factor
because I think
there should be
some later
is
more detailed discussion
that
because I want to say
that we are now
recording
that do not know
if it can be a little bit
interrupted discussion here
and then I want
as a host
is to ask
that
I do not know
in today's
speech
is now here
to a paragraph
you have anything
that you know
in addition to just
the last slide
of take home
message
you have anything
that is more personal
a few words of
personality
want to talk to
Project Tara
for example,
after listening to
the audience
of this video
can share
that
may be
after you say
a few words
I will stop recording
here first
and then with us
live
or future audience
can share
some of you
do this
very interesting research
and I think
it is rare to study
some of you know
that is more personal
ideas
or something
I did not expect
this part
but I think
I want to say
a lot of things
are put in
take home message
inside
so everyone
is if there are
other questions
can write to contact me
like this
good
that today is very grateful
for this
official stop
recording
that should be
here
to continue with everyone
to do some
discussion after the meeting
that is
as a host
very, very grateful
for today
everyone is
inclusive
to participate in
such a wonderful speech
that I officially stop
recording