Welcome to today's TARTalk. We are honored to have Dr. Ronson to talk about his research on quantum bit during his Ph.D. class.
Before we start, let me introduce today's speaker.
Dr. Ronson graduated from Rochester University in the east of the United States this year.
His work in his Ph.D. class is mainly to use superconducting man-made atoms to achieve protective superconducting qubits.
Before his Ph.D. class, he worked in the 3D IC department of TSMC for two and a half years.
He just finished his Ph.D. class and got his degree.
He will move to IBM Research as a Research Scientist and continue to develop and integrate his most specialized superconducting quantum chips.
At the same time, he is also one of the members of the Qiskit Advocate of the IBM Q promotion plan.
In addition to his main superconducting qubit research, he is also very committed to developing quantum education and games with Qiskit.
Please turn on the microphone so that our speakers can hear our applause.
Let's welcome Dr. Ronson to give us today's speech with a warm applause.
Dr. Ronson, thank you for giving me this opportunity to share with you.
You can see my laser pointer.
Thank you.
What I'm going to share with you today is my work at the Ph.D. class.
There are three parts of my work at the Ph.D. class.
The first part is Low-EJ's Josephson-Johnson superconductor.
The third part is the prototype of a quantum circuit.
We call it bifloxone qubit.
Because junction is a little boring, and there are some time constraints, I won't mention junction.
The main focus is on the bifloxone circuit and a more important component in it, the superconductor.
Dr. Ronson is here again.
This circuit is very similar to the bifloxone circuit.
It's just that the black-shift junction is changed to a cooper-pair box, and the gate is used to connect.
Because I do Fab, not design, I will try to explain the circuit.
But there may be some Hamiltonian behind the theory.
Because of time constraints, I won't mention too much.
I'm not a specialist in quantum circuits.
You can discuss any questions you have.
Because not everyone here is doing qubit, I will briefly mention it.
In quantum computation technology, especially in qubit hardware, there are mainly five criteria.
These are the five criteria proposed by Dr. Ronson in 2000.
The first two are circuit depth, which is how long a circuit can run before the signal disappears.
So you can put a few gates before the signal disappears.
The other criteria is the number of qubits.
So Dr. Ronson's work is more like de-extending the circuit depth of super-canon qubit.
That is to say, try to increase our either coherent time or dephasing time.
Here is a recent meme, a web meme.
It summarizes the paper of super-canon qubit.
Now we can see that there are 12 kinds of papers.
Dr. Ronson's work is basically located in these three papers.
He wrote that Johnson and Johnson can do so many things.
This is my first work.
The second is to realize super-inductors, impossible inductors.
The third one is our prototype.
We made a new qubit and it is awful.
Just kidding.
This is my work at Dr. Ronson's lab.
The first one is super-inductors.
We try to realize super-inductors with granular aluminum.
The second one is super-inductors based on Johnson to realize bifluxon qubits.
The third one is super-inductors based on granular aluminum to realize bifluxon qubits.
This is an ongoing project.
Maybe we can talk about it later.
But today's main focus is these two.
Basically, this page is a brief introduction of Johnson.
Johnson is basically a capacitor.
Its two sides are super-conductors.
There is a thin layer of aluminum oxide in the middle.
In our device, we use aluminum-based.
We use a shadow mask to grow an aluminum layer in one direction.
Then introduce some oxygen into the vacuum chamber.
Then another layer of aluminum is cut in the other direction.
This is Johnson.
Johnson can be represented by three elements on the model.
One of them will affect the resistance of the circuit damping.
There is also a capacitor and a non-linear inductor.
The characteristic energy of the capacitor and the inductor is
Q2 over 2C
This is the energy generated by the Johnson effect.
Johnson effect basically describes
You can use the phase difference of the super-current on both sides of Johnson as a parameter.
To parameterize the characteristics of the circuit element IV.
Its current and voltage can be parameterized by phase.
Then you can get its characteristic energy.
In practice, what Johnson I did today
How much is the resistance of the two sides of the circuit?
It is inversely proportional to Ej.
Ej and Ec can be used in classical physics.
You can think of it as the kinetic energy and potential energy in classical physics.
Ej is like a potential energy in phase representation.
Ec is like kinetic energy.
When the quantity of Ej and Ec is in the correct position
When Ej and Ec are comparable
Because of the quantum confinement effect
We can observe the generation of energy levels.
In quantum computation, we take the first and zeroth connection to do the operation.
For example, if the energy level is non-equally spaced today
You can use the microwave to address the ground state and the first excited state more accurately.
This is the basic concept of quantum computation using superconducting artificial atoms.
I just mentioned that Ej can be compared to kinetic energy and potential energy.
In classical physics, we know that kinetic energy and potential energy
Because of the mathematical structure of kinetic energy and potential energy
We can expect them to represent their own bases.
For example, the kinetic energy base is the kinetic energy, and the unknown base is the unknown.
Therefore, P and delta P and delta X will follow the computational relation.
You can expect them to have certain principles.
There is a similar phenomenon in superconducting circuits.
We use the basis of charging energy, which is the number of cooper pairs.
And the basis of Josephine energy, which is the parameterized supercurrent phase.
These two operators will also follow the so-called oscillating principle.
In superconducting circuits, we are more concerned about charging energy.
If we want to minimize the charge noise, we need to maximize the phase fluctuation.
To maximize the phase fluctuation, we need to compress the energy spectrum into a parabola.
Therefore, we need a large inductance to flatten the parabola.
In this way, we can get a relatively low charge sensitivity.
This is why we want to make a superconductor.
Traditionally, in semiconductor, the way to make a superconductor is to make a line.
The thinner the line, the larger the inductance.
Last year, there was a paper to demonstrate how large the inductance can be.
This paper realized about 1 uH and 30 kΩ.
The reason why kΩ impedance is an important parameter is that
we want a superconductor to operate at a certain frequency.
We want the superconductor to maintain an inductive response.
That is to say, the operating frequency must be higher than the operating frequency.
This resonant frequency can be used to equal 1 over square of LC.
That is to say, if you have a large L and the corresponding F is fixed,
your specific capacitance must be small enough.
This will correspond to a high enough impedance.
The reason why impedance is an important parameter is because of this.
This paper demonstrates that it is already a limit.
Because the black part of the device is hollowed out.
However, it is quite difficult to do this.
To make a device of hundreds of microns in size and hollow out the substrate,
leaving only a very thin dielectric, is very challenging.
Generally, we use superconducting kinetic inductance to do this.
Here is an example of what we do in our lab.
We use a material called granular aluminum.
We will see a simple structure of it later.
This material is provided by Cooper-Pear kinetic inductance.
On the other hand, we use Johnson-Johnson inductance.
I forgot the name of the professor.
This is Professor Lin's lab.
This is made by Maruchan and his group.
This is the largest inductance in the world.
It is 2.5 microhenry with an impedance of up to 200 kΩ.
The way they do this is to remove the entire Johnson-Johnson substrate.
It is similar to the concept of suspended graphene.
After removing the oxide at the bottom,
and over-etching, the metal will rise up due to the force.
By doing this, you can remove the substrate and get a very high impedance.
This is provided by Johnson-Johnson superconductor.
This is a simple description of why we need a superconductor.
These are some of the challenges we face in superkinetic qubit.
Whichever is smaller, either T1 or T2,
the shortest decoherence is not equal to Tg.
The number of times a circuit can operate is the so-called circuit depth.
What we need to do is to try to extend the circuit depth.
The next thing I want to talk about is how to extend the circuit depth.
One way is to use parity protection.
The concept of parity protection is...
Sorry, let me first talk about what T1 and T2 are,
and what we are focusing on in this talk.
T1 and T2 are a number in the NMR system.
T1 refers to how long it takes for a qubit or electron to be excited to the first excited state,
and how long it takes for it to relax back.
If this is a block sphere in a qubit,
the physical picture is that when you excite from 0 to 1,
after a certain amount of time, the ball will slowly shrink back to 0.
Defacing is more like how to decoherence the information on the face of the xy plane.
We are mainly talking about the relaxation of T1,
which is to say, how to suppress from 1 to 0 before 0 to 1.
I have made a brief video on how to realize 0 and 1 in superconducting qubits.
This is a device for charge qubits.
It can be written as 4EC times the number of qubit pairs,
which is the number of qubit pairs on the island.
In this structure, we can see that when n is equal to 0,
it means that there is 0 charge on the island,
and when n is equal to 1, it means that there is 1 charge on the island.
There will be individual parabola corresponding to this.
For example, if you are 0 today, your energy should look like this.
When there is 1 charge on the island, it looks like this.
In fact, the energy is the number of qubit pairs you add up,
and the whole charge is your charging energy.
If there is a charge running on the island today,
we expect that your energy will jump from here to here.
For example, you have some quasi-particle tunneling.
On the other hand, you will have some local charge noise.
If you have some local noise today,
your energy will jump from here to here.
At this time, if I turn on Jordan-Johnson tunneling today,
I just saw that Jordan-Johnson is a capacitor.
The energy diagram we expect looks like this.
If I turn on Jordan-Johnson effect today,
what we see is that we will have so-called anti-level crossing,
and then you will have 0 state and 1 state.
In this case, it is a similar situation in our system,
but we only use flux as the basis.
What we are actually observing is the so-called flux zone.
The concept of flux zone is the circulation in the circuit today,
which is your super-current phase winding.
For example, if you have a flux zone tunnel today,
your super-current will have an extra graph,
and your phase will have an extra graph wrapping.
The concept of flux zone is used to...
As I mentioned earlier,
the concept of protection today is...
Let's say we have a system today,
which is completely invisible to each other between 0 and 1.
In other words,
I have a...
Let's put it this way.
Basically, if we play today...
Because of this Jordan-Johnson tunneling,
what will happen is that it allows you to jump from 0 to 1,
but you can also jump from 1 to 0 because of the coupling with the outside world.
But if we have a switch today,
we can put the system between 0 and 1.
Because in this case,
let's say we have a degeneracy.
Basically, when I open 0 and 1 today,
that is, when the switching system is in a different situation,
I can do...
When I want to read and write the system today,
I can do 0 and 1 writing.
When I want to read today,
I can let the system enter the so-called protective state.
At this time,
the signal will be preserved.
It can be preserved better.
I may not have done a good job.
I tried to use the concept of degeneracy to explain,
but the effect may not be very good.
But basically,
if we write it down...
Vincent, sorry.
Can I ask a question?
Yes, you can.
Hello.
Can I go back to the last page?
Yes.
I want to ask you...
This seems to be a very basic thing.
So when you do the rotational...
Because the part below you,
minus one-half EJ,
is your transition,
right?
Then the above is basically
the amount of charge
on your island.
If...
We discussed it last time.
When you do it,
you should also see some charge drop.
It should be on the top.
It affects NG here.
So when you do rotation with approximation,
it should eliminate the above.
But if it's charge drop,
the frequency it affects
will probably affect
the order of magnitude.
My understanding is...
I'm not doing charge qubit.
But my understanding is
it's effective the same.
It won't affect.
Why?
So the above...
4EC N-NG square.
This basically turns it into frequency.
So you want to do
rotation with approximation?
Yes.
OK.
But...
But there's a shift.
It affects the picture.
I think it's probably calibrated.
OK.
So let's say...
You usually put
1,000 electrons.
Then you jump an electron.
Your frequency jump
is about one-third of the jump.
How much is that?
Two-thirds?
Because it's N square.
So I don't know...
I should say...
I think I should say...
I don't know...
It's under rotation with approximation.
In fact,
I don't know how to do calibration.
So I can't comment.
Sorry.
Yes.
But my understanding is
it's...
In fact, charge jump
happens for a long time.
So we actually
don't really...
If you really meet it,
you're not very lucky.
But we usually
take it as
the main calibration.
So we don't worry about it.
It's just that it takes a long time.
For example,
10 milliseconds,
you'll see it once.
10 milliseconds, you'll see it once.
But if you see it,
because we basically do single shot,
so we don't really worry about it.
So I'm not very convinced.
Got it.
OK.
It doesn't matter.
Keep going.
Thank you.
OK.
Sorry.
Then I'll...
I'll talk about it more smoothly
this week.
Because this week...
Basically, we...
Our basic concept is
we're in Flux on Parity.
I'm going to build a mechanism
in my circuit
to turn on and turn off
my protection.
Suppose I...
The concept of on and off protection
comes from what I just said.
Suppose it's a degeneracy lifting.
That is to say,
suppose my system has degeneracy.
Then I can somehow prevent
the degenerated ground state
between the two.
They can communicate
Suppose I have this ability.
Then I can do one thing.
That is, I can
preserve the data
in the protected state.
In the unprotected state.
That is, I can disable this protection.
Then it has degeneracy lifting.
Then we can do
0 and 1 read and write.
Then this is a...
a...
a concept.
Then our work this time is
a proof of concept.
Then we actually use
the mechanism I just said.
It's the so-called Aruna-Kesher effect.
Aruna-Kesher effect is basically
Aruna-Bohm effect
which is a dual version of Aruna-Bohm.
Imagine that
Aruna-Bohm is
an electron in the gas.
Then there are some
non-zero vector potentials in it.
When the electron propagates,
it will have
destructive or
constructive interference
because of this vector potential.
Then Aruna-Kesher effect
refers to a fluxon.
When it is tunneling,
there is a junction on the left or right
to do tunneling.
In the process of tunneling,
how many charges
exist on this island
will have some impact.
In the case of
a single electron,
this tunneling will have
destructive interference
which suppresses the
tunneling of a single fluxon.
The specific performance
in Hamiltonian
is that
there are two
degenerate ground states
in the optimized point.
However,
these two states
cannot see each other.
This is why
we call it
parity protection.
So,
do you have any
questions
or
need to explain more clearly?
If not,
let's move on to the first part.
The superconductor.
The superconductor of quantum mechanics.
OK.
I will continue to explain.
I just mentioned
how to
realize the circuit.
A very important element
is to
make the
superconductor.
The superconductor
is made of
granular aluminum.
Its microscopic structure
is like this.
The red one is aluminum,
and the green one is aluminum oxide.
The way to
grow it is
to add some oxygen
to the argon plasma
during the sputter process.
Then,
pressurize
about 1%
to 1%
of the concentration.
Then,
we can get a structure like this.
The grain size is usually
about 3 to 4 nanometers.
This graph shows
the experimental data
extracted from
the literature.
This graph shows
the TCE and resistivity.
We can see that
as the resistivity increases,
the TCE
starts to grow.
The pure aluminum
is about 1.3K.
Then, it will grow to 2K.
In different degrees,
we can get different films.
The grain size is different.
The maximum TCE
can reach 3K.
However, when we continue
to increase the resistivity,
the TCE will not grow.
It will not have
the so-called
disorderly induced
SI transition.
Why do we need to increase
the resistivity?
The reason is that
kinetic inductance
can increase
the resistance.
This is the
experimental demo
of a sub-inductor.
We basically made it
into a resonator structure
to measure its
resonant frequency.
Then, we can get
its inductance.
We got an impedance
of about 30kΩ
and an inductor
of 1.3uH.
Here are some details
about the application.
This is the resistivity
as a function of oxygen flow.
We later found that
the more accurate method
is to use a flow meter
instead of oxygen pressure.
If you are interested in
the details,
we can talk about it
in more detail later.
The resistivity we made
can be controlled
by a flow meter.
We just mentioned
that we made it
into a resonator structure.
The black part is
the granular aluminum.
The white part is the pure aluminum.
We made it
into a resonator
of half-wavelength
called planar waveguide geometry.
Then, we threw it into the fridge
to measure its
resonant frequency.
We extracted
the quality factor.
We further
characterized the quality factor
as a function of temperature.
We got
a feature
of the quality factor
which is
a line
that does not change
with temperature
when it is
below 250kΩ.
We observed
that it is
an exponentially
decaying
quality factor.
It is
similar to
the superconductor
in many disorders.
We observed
a two-level system behavior
at low temperature.
At high temperature,
we observed
a semi-regenerated
quasi-particle.
What is the difference between
these two things?
At low temperature,
it is a two-level system.
A two-level system
usually has
some non-saturated
or non-reactive
oxides or dielectrics
in the dielectric
when the film
is growing.
These dielectrics
will produce
some local
electrical dipoles.
They will have
some oscillation
with the
EM field
in our
micro-resonator.
This will
cause an additional
loss.
This loss
will not change
with the temperature.
At higher temperature,
a quasi-particle
will be produced.
It is similar to
when you get closer to Tc,
your couple pair
will start to break
due to temperature.
These normal electrons
will reduce
your quality factor.
These normal electrons
will produce
some excitation
from exponential
1 over kT
to produce a model.
This is the so-called
Martin-Spartan theory.
So basically,
our work here is to verify...
I have a question.
Do you have exactly
the same geometry
as ordinary aluminum?
We are curious
about the difference between
granular aluminum
and ordinary aluminum.
We didn't really
calibrate the two-level system.
Pure aluminum
has a
very low
kinetic doctrine,
so
we didn't really
calibrate
the two-level system.
Oh, okay.
I understand.
I think
another
crude comparison
is that if you
make exactly the same feature
but ordinary aluminum,
what is the difference
between your QI?
If your QI is
TLS lost at low temperature,
you can compare, right?
I think
the two-level system
I just mentioned
is highly related to your QI.
For example, if we make
granular aluminum,
I also suspect that our aluminum...
Because granular aluminum
is built-in oxide.
So will the material itself
have some two-level system loss
from the structure of the material itself?
This is also possible.
Yes, I'm actually
worried about this.
Okay, I understand.
Okay, so...
The details
need to be more
detailed.
It does require more detailed
analysis of the structure.
Because the two-level system is
the source of
the NOES of OneOF.
So
we need to spend more time on it.
For example, for surface cleaning,
we need to be more careful
and more detailed.
Right.
Okay, thank you.
Thank you.
And...
Right, so basically
what I'm talking about here is
we are fitting two parameters,
which are the parameters in practice,
the results obtained in practice,
which are my frequency shift and my quality factor.
Then I can get
a very good match,
that is, the contribution of my loss
is basically
temperature-independent.
At low temperature,
it is temperature-independent
two-level system loss
that dominates.
At high temperature,
more than 250 mC,
I can see the sum of
the sum of the generated
quasiparticle that dominates.
Yes, this is a simple summary.
Okay.
Next is our
performance QP.
This time we use
Junction to do super-inductor.
It is closer to
what Meru and Quarren did.
Then,
as we just mentioned,
using quantum mechanics to do super-inductor
to build this structure
is still an ongoing process.
In this circuit,
how can this circuit
be mapped to this place?
Basically, you turn this 90 degrees,
then these two junctions,
these two red cross,
then this super-inductor,
half here,
the other half here,
then the last two sides
are connected to this.
This thing turns 90 degrees counterclockwise,
then it will be mapped to this graph.
Then connect to a radar resonator.
This radar resonator is coupled
to a microwave line.
This is a strip-line structure,
not a coplanar waveguide.
These are basically
how we do this device.
Then,
the device parameters,
what we do on the structure
is that we
use
our super-inductor,
we can't do much in this device.
Basically,
I remember
this device is
less than a microherry.
This device
is less than
a microherry.
It's not an ideal device.
When our super-inductor
is not big enough,
we still have
T1 protection,
but our defacient protection
is not too big.
Basically,
our T2 data
is about
1 microsecond.
T1 can be
10 to 100 microseconds.
Our device
is
basically
a charge-sensitive device
because it has a coplanar island.
Then,
in this device,
we do
quasi-particle trap.
The concept is basically
because we have
an island structure,
we have three different
films,
three layers of aluminum.
They are all aluminum,
but they are made in different processes.
These three layers
can be separated.
These two are the same layer,
and this is the other layer.
We can adjust the thickness
to make the aluminum in the middle
thinner.
The aluminum will have a bigger
Tc, a bigger bandgap.
This kind of structure
can make
the middle
island
have a bigger bandgap.
So, the quasi-particle
is not easy to come up,
and suppress
the quasi-particle poisoning.
It is simply controlled
by the thickness of the film.
Then,
we observed that
in 8 hours,
we only saw a few times
the quasi-particle
jump.
The number of times is relatively small,
and each measurement
ends very quickly.
If it is a time domain,
it ends very quickly,
so we rarely
encounter it.
Basically, we measure the data
and
this is a relatively impressive
place.
If you don't do
quasi-particle trap,
the frequency of the jump
is about 10 ms.
In our system,
the shortest
is also about
10 ms.
This
is our
frequency domain
of spectroscopy.
These are
X01 transition,
which is
the cubic spectrum.
The blue data
is the
unprotected state,
which is the
anti-level crossing.
The orange data
is the
island bias 1E,
which is 0.5.
We see
degeneracy,
which is the Arunacheshire effect.
When we enable
the system's protected state,
we see
degenerated ground state.
When
we enter
0E,
we enter the unprotected state,
and we can do the reading.
On the other hand,
the linear fit
is basically
the super-inductor.
We can get
the super-inductor
inductance.
Sorry, the inductance is
0.1 mH,
not 1 mH.
On the other hand,
we observe
the
self-resonance
frequency, which is
0.1 mH.
From this frequency,
we can get the junction-based super-inductor.
Its impedance is
about 4 kΩ.
The proof-of-concept
shown here
is how to
enable
the protected state
and
compare
the protected and unprotected state.
This is the
microwave protocol.
The y-axis
is the charge,
which means
I turn on
the protection
on i.e. bias 1E,
and turn off the protection
on i.e. remove the gate.
What we do
is to let the system
be in unprotected state,
and then we
write the system into 1.
Then we turn on the protection.
This is a 30-minute
pause to
turn on the protection.
The duration is Δt.
After Δt,
I turn off the pause
and read the system
to see whether it is in 0 or 1.
This is the relaxation of the system.
The delta is here.
If there is no
gate,
the T1 feed
is about 12 microseconds.
When I turn on
the protection,
the T1 can reach
100 microseconds,
which is 10 times
the improvement.
However,
the T1 of this device
is still quite bad,
which is only 10 microseconds.
We can use
ArrayCatcherEffect
to demonstrate
that ArrayCatcherEffect
can help us achieve
a protected effect.
Basically,
we verify
this graph
at different flux-biasing points.
We can see
about 10 times
the improvement.
The location of 0.3
is PhiExternal
and 6 PiExternal
are matched to
the read-out resonator.
Therefore, we get
0.3
or 6 GHz.
These 6 GHz
are the
read-out resonator
frequencies.
This is the
conclusion.
We realize
a prototype circuit.
This circuit
can have
a protective
mechanism.
We can
enjoy
a short gate-time
while
enjoying a higher
improvement of T1.
This is
the main topic of today.
Thank you to all my collaborators.
Thank you for your
participation.
I'm ready to take questions.
Before
the Q&A,
let's give a round of
applause to Wen-Cheng
for his wonderful speech.
Of course,
if you have any questions,
you can
open the microphone to ask.
Is there
any question?
Actually, I have a question.
Let me ask a question first.
Sorry.
OK.
Can I
ask you a question?
Sorry.
OK.
Very nice talk.
The result is
very exciting.
I want to ask
about
the following
work.
T1 is
102 microseconds
under the protective state.
I want to ask
if you have studied
what limiting factor
limits it to
102 microseconds.
Yes.
Basically,
it is...
It is
junction symmetry.
In short, it is junction symmetry.
If the two junctions
are not symmetric,
it will affect
the original T1.
Even unprotected state
will affect T1.
Yes.
I don't think
I put it here.
Basically,
if these two junctions
have either oxidation
or size asymmetry,
it will
limit T1.
Is it different from
dielectric loss
limitation?
Is it?
It is not caused by
two-level system.
At least,
in modeling,
they know better.
According to their feedback,
in modeling,
asymmetry will have a big impact.
Asymmetry can be
from our...
We can look at it
with a squeegee.
We can
look at
asymmetry
at the lowest point
of the field.
Our equipment is bad.
We make
asymmetry,
put it in modeling,
and push it out.
It tells us
our equipment is bad.
Or
maybe not.
The junction symmetry
is more particular.
We must use two junctions.
The asymmetry of these two junctions
is quite critical.
I have a question.
What is your
asymmetry?
For example,
your asymmetry
can be parameterized.
For example,
in Squid,
there is a defect.
How much
difference
is there?
Ideally,
what is the difference?
We use
gigahertz.
0.6 gigahertz.
So your
delta
is about
0.4 gigahertz.
I see.
There is no difference.
Asymmetry
is a must
for junction.
Our
situation is
that
our device
must have these two junctions.
You can't just make one.
You have to have both.
If you make one,
there will be such a problem.
The device
is particular about delta.
It takes time to tune.
If you don't mind,
I have a second question.
Why your
super inductor
junction
is
a two-angle junction?
It looks like
a rotating-angle junction,
not a
stolen-bridge junction.
Unlike what we did
in Maryland.
Our boss doesn't like
stolen-bridge junction.
He thinks
our junction
won't be broken.
So I want to fix it,
but my boss says it's too slow.
Is your
blow-dry
like a trick?
What?
Do you have a special trick
when you blow-dry?
I remember that
top-mask
was a PMMA
last year.
It collapsed when I blow-dry it.
I couldn't finish it in 4 or 5 years.
My boss told me not to do it again.
So I want to ask you.
According to
normal
fab,
our yield
is quite high.
As long as
the first step is OK,
and the next step is OK,
it's usually
not a problem.
It's usually not a problem.
No, we just can't do it.
I've been doing it for
a week, and my boss said
there's nothing special
to fix.
Nothing special.
OK.
I see.
I'll let others
ask questions.
Thank you.
I have a question.
Can you go back to
TC?
TC and
granularized.
My question is
for different
samples,
do you know
the delta
bandgap?
Is it almost
the same?
Or not?
I didn't test it.
But you feed
Matisse-Bardini
and you get the value.
Oh, no, sorry.
This TC is independent.
I just use it
to test TC.
Oh, I see.
So each data is
transported by TC.
And there's no microwave.
Matisse-Bardini uses microwave.
Right.
So we don't...
Suppose
there should be
a resonator chip.
Suppose
if it's 100% Matisse-Bardini,
it should be exactly the same.
But we're worried
because we don't know
how much of it is not Matisse-Bardini.
We're curious.
Yeah, that's
a very good point.
But in that case,
if it's
what you want to do,
you don't want it to be Matisse-Bardini.
You want the
alpha factor to be high.
You want it to
deviate from Matisse-Bardini.
Not necessarily.
But I hope
if it really comes from
the energy deposit,
it can still break the pair.
Then I can test the documenter.
Otherwise, it reacts a lot
but it's useless
if it doesn't interact with the particle.
Interesting.
OK.
My understanding is
if it follows BCS,
it's Matisse-Bardini.
We haven't
thought about it.
At least the first part,
the alpha factor is good.
We've demonstrated this part.
As you can see,
we want to test it because of this.
But we're worried
if it doesn't interact
with the physical particle
in a normal response,
it becomes a very powerful
but it only reacts with RF.
It's useless.
OK.
Because what I did before
is HKID.
The pair I read before
is more HKID.
I haven't thought about it.
OK.
As I said last time,
in low resistivity,
it usually follows
strictly
Matisse-Bardini.
If you push it
to close to 800
or 1000
Michael-Henry per square,
sorry,
you'll get
a nonlinear phenomenon.
It makes sense.
It's in line with the prediction.
It's not Matisse-Bardini.
Yes.
OK.
This is my question.
Do you have any other questions?
If you don't have any questions,
please turn on
the microphone.
OK.
Now I...