Hello everyone, I'm the host of today's Terra Talk, I'm Hsih-Hui-Ting.
I'm very happy to be here today to participate in this talk with everyone.
Our speaker today is Yao Naijia.
I personally know Naijia, and I've known her for a long time,
because Naijia is my college classmate.
Naijia's college, master's, and doctoral degrees are all in the Department of Physiotherapy at NTU.
Naijia was also the secretary-general of the World Physiotherapy Asia-Pacific Region.
She has now graduated, and is currently working as the director of the World Physiotherapy Asia-Pacific Region.
In today's talk, Naijia will mainly share two parts with us.
The first part is about her doctoral thesis,
Child Development Genetic Environment Interaction.
The second part is about medical information design.
The first topic, Child Development Genetic Environment Interaction,
focuses on early treatment intervention,
as well as the development of genes related to dopamine in children,
including cognitive development, action development, and behavioral development,
as well as the impact of parent-teacher pressure.
We will also discuss the interaction between genes and the environment.
We look forward to the future long-term development,
and we hope to design a more personalized medical plan for these children.
The second topic is about medical information design.
After Naijia graduated from her doctoral degree,
she went to the industry,
focusing on medical information design and science and technology education.
Through community platforms or activities,
she will promote medical knowledge to the general public.
She will also share some of her experience with us.
In today's talk,
Naijia will share common digital marketing content
and discuss more possible developments with our guests.
Naijia, please share your PowerPoint.
Thank you.
Let's give Naijia a round of applause.
Thank you, Naijia.
Let me share my screen.
You should be able to see it now.
Thank you, Naijia, for your presentation.
I think that's pretty much it.
My background is a physics teacher
who specializes in children's development.
I was lucky enough to be a part of a new initiative
in 2016.
I'd like to share two main points with you.
The first one is
about my PhD thesis.
The first one is about my PhD thesis.
The second one is about medical information design.
I know that Project HERA is a research-oriented project.
I'd like to share my work with you
and see how we can share our knowledge
in the future.
We are an intellectual industry.
I'd like to make a formal apology.
My family is at home.
I'm sorry that my audio recorded my talking.
Please forgive my crying.
I'll start my presentation
in the next few minutes.
I'll start my presentation in the next few minutes.
I'd like to focus on gene-environmental interaction.
We need to understand which causes older than usual development for kids.
We select here oviparous and hormone-related over-time.
And we focus on early pregnancy.
In the past, differential susceptibility theory tells us that the worse the environment, the worse the performance.
The better the environment, the better the performance.
On the contrary, people who don't have this kind of environment may not be affected by the environment.
Another theory is that there is only a negative environment that makes me perform worse.
The positive environment is not bad at all.
Another theory is that there is only a positive environment that makes me perform better.
The negative environment is not bad at all.
In this case, we hope to see the advantageous sensitivity.
This means that the better the environment, the better the performance.
This structure is divided into several areas.
First, the environment.
We want to see if the environment affects the development of children.
Second, the pressure on the parents to have a child.
This is the part of the day after tomorrow.
This is the part of the day before tomorrow.
This is the part of the gene.
In the past research,
we have known that early birth parents will be more stressed.
In the past, the intervention program also told us that
the intervention program can reduce the pressure on the parents.
However, most of it is focused on the mother,
and there is less discussion about the father and mother at the same time.
In this study, we will include the father and mother at the same time,
and it will be a part of the long-term tracking.
In terms of children, the conclusion of the past study is inconsistent.
Some say that the effect can be delayed to 9 years old or later.
However, some say that the intervention period is 1 or 2 years old,
and the effect is almost the same.
In the future, there will be no effect.
So our study is also a large-scale study in Taiwan.
We want to see what effect it will have in the long-term tracking.
Especially in terms of cognition, action, and behavior.
In terms of genes,
we chose the gene related to multiple sclerosis and hemoglobin.
Because the gene related to multiple sclerosis and hemoglobin
has been proven in past studies,
it may be related to children's development,
including cognition, ADHD,
which is related to autism and attention deficit disorder.
So there are four parts of this study.
The first is whether our medical intervention
has a positive impact on the development of children.
The second is whether our medical intervention
can help parents to reduce their stress.
The third is whether the gene related to multiple sclerosis and hemoglobin
can be related to the development of children.
Finally, it depends on the interaction effect of the gene environment.
In terms of research,
we use low-fat premature babies.
This research is a bit more complicated.
It will include four studies.
So if you have any questions about our participants,
you can discuss with me.
In terms of procedures,
we will have a hospitalization period,
which is when the baby is still in the nursing room.
We will start to intervene.
After discharge,
there will be medical intervention in 0, 1, 2, 4, 6, 9, 12 months.
As a rule,
we will use a phone interview to care for the baby.
So this intervention will include,
including when the baby is in the hospital,
as we just mentioned,
there will be some suggestions on feeding,
massaging,
and some development stimuli.
After discharge,
there will be some transfer to the hospital.
We will also teach the baby how to adjust the home environment,
and how to interact with the baby in the future.
As we know,
parent-child interaction
has a positive impact on the development of children,
especially children under the age of six.
Because they are basically at home.
Of course, there is also the basic child health check-up.
Basically,
this is what every child needs to do.
As for the measurement,
we use Bayley to measure the development of cognition,
and CBCL to measure the behavior.
As for the action,
we use MoveMVC.
Bayley also includes the action part.
As for parenting stress,
we use PSI.
Let's talk about our four studies.
The first part is for the development of children.
Does our medical intervention have a positive impact on the development of children?
The conclusion is that
it is interesting that we use Bayley-2 and Bayley-3.
These two are because we have been working on the case for a long time.
We used Bayley-2 when there was no Bayley-3.
When Bayley-3 was developed,
we changed it to Bayley-3.
But what we see in Bayley-2 is
that it has a positive impact on the cognitive behavior of children.
The biggest effect was in Bayley-4.
However, in Bayley-3,
we see a significant difference.
It also happened in Bayley-4.
On the left,
we use a more longitudinal analysis,
which is also a mixed-event model.
On the right,
we combine two RCTs together.
We use Bayley-2 and Bayley-4 as a forest plot.
The result tells us that
there may be a difference between Bayley-2 and Bayley-4.
It may be a difference in the era.
Therefore, the normal group has improved.
In other words, our normal care has improved.
This difference will gradually disappear.
On the other hand,
why do we think that our therapeutic effect
seems to be obvious or lasts longer?
It may be that in some past studies,
their therapeutic process only lasted until the age of three.
However, our therapeutic effect only lasted until the age of one.
Therefore, it may extend to such a long time.
For example, at the age of nine or even older,
our frequency and length may not be enough.
On the other hand,
we may not see any therapeutic effect on behavior.
It may be because our content
is not as close to the part of behavioral modification
as some past programs.
The second part is to see
whether our medical research has a positive impact on parental pressure.
The result shows two interesting points.
In the case of mothers,
the pressure of mothers has always been greater than that of fathers.
In general,
the pressure is always greater at any point in time.
On the other hand,
our therapeutic effect mainly occurs on fathers,
but not on mothers.
This difference can only be seen for a long time.
That is to say,
when children reach the age of four,
the pressure of their fathers is significantly reduced.
We have also done some research
on the relationship between parental pressure and children's behavior.
In fact, the relationship is quite high.
That is to say,
if the behavior of children is worse,
the pressure of mothers is greater.
In addition,
we have also done some research on
home activities.
In our program,
some activities are done by parents.
Most of the executors are mothers.
In fact,
more than 90% of the participants are mothers.
This result is quite consistent with past research.
That is to say,
the pressure of mothers is basically quite high.
The reason for this possibility is
interesting.
In the previous large-scale research in Taiwan,
we also found that
most of the main caregivers are mothers.
This is consistent with our research.
In addition,
this past research also mentioned that
regardless of whether the mother is a full-time job
or a part-time job,
in fact,
most of her household chores
are more than that of her father.
As for the intervention effect,
we see that
the effect of the father's part is effectively reduced.
It is particularly high in the 48-month period.
It may be because
there is a demographic effect
that tells us
that it is very similar to the rolling snowball effect.
It may be that
this good effect is getting bigger and bigger later.
So it is particularly obvious in the 48-month period.
Another one is that
the reduction of this part
is actually related to
the better child's action development.
That is to say,
the better the child's action development,
the greater the degree of pressure on the father to reduce.
As for the mother,
we did not see any intervention effect.
It may be because
our intervention program
did not pay much attention
to the mother's part.
But in the past,
the part that helped the mother
may mainly be
the part where they have a lot of behavioral adjustments.
It tells us that
in the future research,
we may be able to focus more
on the part about mental health.
This may help more mothers.
Another one is that
the father and mother's performance
are actually quite different.
In the past research,
it also told us that
in some problem-solving strategies,
if the father gets more information
in this area,
it can actually reduce the pressure.
Mothers may need more
emotional support.
The third one is
to see if the gene
is related to the child's development.
We chose 15 SNPs.
Among these 15 SNPs,
there are 8 special connections.
That is to say,
there are 8 red boxes on the screen.
Basically,
it can be used as one of the representations.
Because the results will be about the same.
What we see is
that the MLA gene
is related to
the preterm child's mental score.
We also chose
an independent copy sample.
It can be used as a verification function.
The results are exactly the same.
It tells us that
the MLA gene is related to
the child's cognitive development,
especially in premature babies.
The results are the same
in the learning sample
and the replication sample.
The results are the same
in the past.
In the past,
the MLA gene was used
in children with
attention deficit hyperactivity
and autism.
The MLA gene is used
in premature babies.
The fourth one is
to see if the gene is related to
the environment.
It's a pity that
the MLA gene is not related to
the environment.
The MLA gene is used in
the SNP sample.
the VNTR sample.
The VNTR sample is used
to see if the gene is related to
the environment.
For example,
if the gene is related to
the DNA of the parent,
the MLA gene is used.
However,
the MLA gene is not related to
the environment.
The reason is that
the MLA gene is not related to
the environment.
The second reason is that
we don't use
GWAS or NGIS
for genetic information.
The MLA gene is used
to miss a lot of
genetic information.
The MLA gene is used
to miss a lot of
genetic information.
The MLA gene is used
to miss a lot of
genetic information.
So the conclusion is that
the results of the
hopes study show
better genetic
identifications.
In the parents' cases,
the parents' effective
down grade of the
MLA gene is seen.
The MLA gene is related to
the early-childhood development.
So the MLA gene
is related to
the early-childhood development.
If you have any questions,
please feel free to ask.
The second part
I want to talk about is
the medical information design.
This part is
mainly because
I'm working on the initiative.
Why did we start
this part?
The main intention is to change.
What do we want to change?
Because we often find
a lot of information
in the hospital or clinic
for the patients.
When the patients go back,
the family may ask
what the doctor
told you.
The patient may tell
his family that
he doesn't know much about it.
So we hope
this kind of case
can be more clear
in the clinical environment
in the future.
Many people in the academic world
have done a lot of research.
But how do you explain
such a complex and detailed research
to the general public?
For example,
how do you let the public
know why you need
or don't need a sample?
This is actually a very professional question,
but the general public may not know.
They can only say
don't let me get infected.
This is why
we want to make
such a change,
including medical education,
medical students, doctors,
clinical environment,
or preventive medicine for the general public.
So we want to start
from the information design.
I don't know
if you have any special ideas
about information design,
or if you already have a certain
understanding of it.
In our team,
it is a multi-professional cooperation.
We may have academic professionals,
project managers,
designers, and engineers.
This is actually a part that needs
everyone's cooperation.
Sometimes when your team is discussing,
you will find that the interesting situation
is that the designers are not
professional backgrounds,
so when they are discussing with you,
they may have more interesting
opinions,
and you may say that
I still don't quite understand.
Can we think of a better way
together?
So our main audience
will be divided into three main types.
The main medical staff
is the more professional part.
It may be like what we usually
do in academic communication.
Like what I just said,
there will be more professional information
in the discussion.
The medical staff will definitely
know more about their own disease.
It's not like the general public,
who may just accept the knowledge,
scroll to Facebook to take a look,
or scroll to Instagram to take a look.
But the medical staff must assume,
for example, I have cancer today,
I will definitely go crazy to check
the relevant knowledge of my cancer.
So it will be a little deeper.
The general public is basically
you have to capture their eyes,
because they may not have
the knowledge to know,
or how to attract their interest.
That's another different part.
In our team,
we may do a lot,
including interactive animation design,
such as animation web games.
I will introduce it later.
Because I want to say that
we may use works to share with you,
which is more helpful for discussion.
If it's not too commercialized,
it may be more interesting
to do it this way.
For example,
we have a great video,
which was also submitted
to the conference
of the World Health Alliance.
So the information design
is not completely decoupled
from academic research.
It can also be published.
Because of my
lack of knowledge,
I may not be able to
share it with you.
So I may not be able to
I may not be able to
play the video,
but there is a link,
so you can watch it later.
I'll show you a simple demo.
The picture looks like this.
There may be animations,
and there may be real shots.
The real shots look like this.
I hope you can figure out
how many red cards there are in the video,
and there may be some answers
or questions at the end.
I think the effect will be much worse.
So back to our video,
our production process
is basically like this.
We may have an academic team
based on facts,
because we are basically medical professionals.
The main background of these founders
are doctors,
or like me, a therapist.
So we are all professionals.
Of course, we don't want to
pass wrong information like an underground radio station.
This is our first commitment.
The second commitment is to make it clear.
So we hope that
even your grandma can understand it.
These are our two main commitments.
Then we make this kind of related video.
In this part of the video,
our process will be
what I just said.
First, the academic team will finish
our basic search documents,
and then there will be some facts.
Then it will be transformed into
an interesting line,
and then we will talk about
how to draw the boundary,
and then collaborate with the animation designer
to produce the final result.
In this part,
I still have a lot of works left,
but I want to talk about
some terms first.
Some people may already know
these terms,
but we can still talk about them a little bit.
For example, what is social media?
Because this is very important
now.
Of course, everyone will think of
Facebook or Instagram.
But in fact, a long time ago,
in our ancient times,
there were already bad cows or PTT.
In fact,
these are also so-called social media.
There may be different styles
and different things suitable for each social media.
For example, on PTT,
it may be very suitable for reading a lot of text.
On Facebook and Instagram,
it may need some graphic support.
On Instagram,
it may be mainly based on some beautiful photos.
The definition of social media
is basically
the technology of computer media,
which is to use a computer
interaction device as a base.
As long as you can use this
to interact with the community,
it basically counts.
There are a lot of social media
like this.
I don't know how many you can recognize,
but what we are listing now
are all social media,
including Facebook, IG, LinkedIn,
and even Douyin and Dcard.
In addition,
when we do this,
we also have to consider our target audience.
In fact, I think
it's the same when I do academic research.
If I tell my community
and tell the general public,
basically what I want to do
should be a different form.
Of course,
as we just quickly talked about
, I used a lot of content
when I was in Defense.
What about the target audience like this?
We can see that
different age groups
are using instant communication software
or social network.
In fact, what everyone is familiar with is different.
For example,
Facebook currently has more
slightly older age groups,
and everyone is more familiar
with these two on Line.
But most of you are students on Dcard.
What kind of presentation do you want to use
in front of different audiences?
Another point is
the part of the legal common sense.
Because different laws are easy to violate,
so whether it's
the Intellectual Property Rights Act
or we are doing some
introduction,
will it step on the line of medical advertising
or be related to contract writing?
For example,
can we just use a picture on the Internet?
In fact, this part is also mentioned
because it is especially related to
our academic world.
It is said that in schools or educational institutions,
you can broadcast
other people's public publications
within a reasonable range of education.
In other words,
many professors
may take pictures
in this book,
but they can't draw
all these pictures
by themselves.
It must be explained to everyone
in this way.
In addition,
we have a mechanism
called Creative CC.
It will show six pictures
as shown here.
For example,
if you see a person in this picture,
it means that as long as you have a name,
you can use
my work.
For example,
a picture or some articles
in your own PowerPoint.
For example, it says NC,
non-commercial use.
It means that you can only use it
if it is not for commercial purposes.
Another one is also related to
the academic world.
Is it necessary to pass the teacher's
or the speaker's approval
to record in class?
Basically,
it is said that it is necessary
in the Department of Economics and Finance.
So if you encounter
such a problem in the academic world,
you can use it to explain.
Since we have some time left,
I would like to introduce
some of our past works.
They may be of different forms
and have different characteristics.
For example,
Professor Chen Zhenhong
from Stanford University
and Dean Lin Zhaofang
from Fudai Medical School
often have red faces
after drinking.
This is because
there is a deficiency of ALDH2.
So how can we
make people understand this?
We use animation
to quickly introduce this to everyone.
How to measure
if you have ALDH2 deficiency?
It is also introduced in the animation.
In addition,
this animation also wants to show
people in their 50s and 60s.
So it actually has a Taiwanese version.
Because
it also wants to show
people in their 50s and 60s.
So we also have an English version.
That is to say,
in different age groups,
we may first adjust the language.
In addition, we may also adjust the speed of speech.
For example, the Taiwanese version
may slow it down a little bit.
Because our research also found that
young people may speak faster.
Older people may speak slower.
In addition,
in addition to the animation
for the general public,
there is also an animation
for medical personnel education.
It is a more professional part.
Like this animation,
it actually talks about
a RCT related to breathing.
It is introduced in this RCT.
It is the kind of feeling
I just introduced my own research.
That is to say,
what is his knowledge background?
How did he do it?
What is his result?
In this way,
the animation explains
the process of giving medicine
to the medical personnel.
We also give medicine as a meal.
In this way,
everyone can understand
why we do this whole process.
What is the preparation of the front desk?
What is the last one?
There is another one
that is more related to the academic world.
Now, in some top journals,
they sometimes publish podcasts
or video abstracts.
He is a dean now.
In fact, he has made
his video abstracts
on the Goethe's journal.
You can take a video
and add the introduction
of PowerPoint next to it
to briefly introduce
what you are doing.
In fact, many new journals
like to use this way
because it can attract people's attention.
I think you may be thinking
about how to make some
videos that everyone can understand.
Otherwise, it is like the ivory tower
where everyone is locked inside.
It is a pity
because a lot of rich resources
can be shared.
In addition,
we also make websites
for ordinary people
such as the liver test room
which cooperates with the foundation.
In addition, we also make
general medical journals
in the form of comics
where we talk about
liver cancer,
which is a non-infectious disease.
However, you can't expose other people's children.
We use a more dangerous way
to introduce liver cancer.
We also publish
a series of
liver-cancer journals.
In addition,
there are different ways of presentation.
For example,
this liver-cancer journal
introduces a series of comics
about what happened
to the main character after he grew up.
The grandmother died at this time,
so she came down to the earth
and became an immortal.
In addition,
there is a part about the cervical cancer.
The advantage of this
liver-cancer journal
is that you can give different pages
to different diseases
and different groups.
In this way, you can draw at any time.
If you draw,
you can design the information
that you want to get.
Otherwise, you can't accept it.
In addition,
we also have a community platform.
On this Facebook platform,
the community platform is basically
all public.
There is no commercial part at all,
which means that we have no advertising income.
We also refuse any commercial
introduction.
In this part,
we actually draw
a little bit of our income
to make a public response every year.
For example,
this part of the Cervical Cancer Journal,
we designed it
like a game card.
We want to let everyone know
some ways to avoid cancer.
In addition,
last year,
we also designed a character named Wu Wan.
He is a little boy.
We use this Wu Gu Ji
to let everyone know
why we can't
use alcohol to disinfect
or how to wear a mask.
Why masks can prevent
us from being infected.
There is also a more complicated part
in the middle on the right.
He said why
this picture of acute lung damage
is more professional for professionals to see.
In addition,
we also cooperate with the WHO
to create a Vietnamese health community platform.
We can make knowledge
promotion in Vietnam.
In addition,
there is a micro-hearing interactive web page.
This is a cooperation between the foundation.
They want to introduce to everyone
that children may have micro-hearing.
He may not really hear,
but he may not hear clearly.
What kind of problems
may occur if you can't hear clearly?
We can take a look at this web page directly.
We made this web page.
It is a small game.
He can introduce the background knowledge
to everyone.
What is the situation of hearing loss?
What is micro-hearing loss?
This micro-hearing loss
may make children
can't hear clearly,
but he can still hear a little bit.
Because of this problem,
they may
run around
or move their ears
to one side.
It's not that he doesn't want to talk to you.
He may want to hear more clearly.
So we will
design it into different levels.
He will tell you
that I have to get closer to hear other people's words.
So in this game design,
you have to move left and right
to receive
what these people say.
The more you receive,
the higher your score will be.
He must finish
in this ten lines.
Finally, it will be divided into score levels.
In this way,
you can let everyone know that
children want to hear
what you are saying.
They don't want to ignore you
or disrespect you.
He is not like this.
You can let parents,
teachers and people around him know more.
When the time comes,
you can even share your score
on your social network.
For example, on Facebook.
Of course, there are different levels.
You can share your score
on Facebook.
Let's go back to what we just said.
Interactive games are one of them.
Of course, there are many other forms of interaction.
In this game,
we want to improve
people's interest and connection.
In medical education,
there is a more professional part.
It's called
Antibiotics Week.
It's for medical students and doctors.
The Taiwan Institute of Infectious Diseases
has designed a series of
challenges.
There is a week's challenge.
You can go up every day
to answer questions.
After answering the five-day questions,
they will have a radar map
to tell you the direction of your score
and tell you where your ability is.
In the end,
they will tell you some professional tips.
In this way,
you can learn more about
the professional part.
In the end,
there will be some activities
like a small lottery
to boost your motivation.
In addition,
there is also a information chart.
It shows
some bacteria
here,
medicine,
and related symptoms.
When you click on the mouse,
it will show you
the relevant information.
In the end,
there are some related
activities.
These activities are not the point.
The point is how to
attract people's interest
and present the knowledge in different ways.
That's all for today.
I hope
we can have more time
to interact with you.
This way,
we can learn more.
I have a question.
Do you use
Intel
instead of
SNP?
Do you use
DNA modification
such as
epigenetics?
Do you use
SNP
instead of
SNP?
Do you use
DNA modification
instead of
SNP?
I don't use
DNA modification.
However,
I know
epigenetics
is related to
pregnant women.
In the past,
epigenetics is related to
pregnant women.
In the past,
You will be able to see this part.
Recently,
I have been reading
that Intel
insertion and deletion
and copy number variation
affect
gene expression.
Do these things
affect
similar connections?
Also,
is there any other problem
with your chosen SNP?
I don't know.
Because,
like GWAS,
its design is for common variants.
So,
in the case of low probability,
is it a good way
to use common variants?
In fact,
we have tested
the SNP first.
Because,
there is a determination
that the SNP cannot be too low.
Like you said,
if the SNP is too low,
there is no point in testing.
But I didn't release it,
because there is too much content.
So, there is a determination.
You just mentioned
that copy number variation
is related.
In the past,
many complicated genes are related.
But,
to be frank,
we had limited budget.
So, we could only do
candidate genes.
We did our best to research.
We didn't do it on
present children.
We did it on autism
or attention deficit disorder.
We did it in a similar way
as you mentioned.
Another thing I want to ask is,
you chose early birth
as the sample.
In some studies,
early birth
is not related to genes.
It is related
to microbiome
or environmental impact.
Do you think
the subjects you chose
share similar
environmental impact?
Or they are highly variable?
It is possible.
For example,
we did analysis on
sex,
gender,
or the education level
of parents.
We did analysis on these.
We found that they are
middle-high education.
Early birth
is more likely to
have early birth.
So, their education level is higher.
We did basic analysis
and control
on these variables.
In addition,
we did research on
genes first.
My research sequence
is not the same as my report.
We did research on
genes first,
but I have to admit
that in terms of
child development,
the environmental impact
is significant.
This is the reason why
medical intervention is needed.
Thank you.
Thank you for the discussion
and questions.
Any other questions?
I would like to add
on the previous question.
In the past,
there were more
information collected.
For example,
at home,
they used
video recording
or tracking.
However, there are some
income restrictions.
Some people don't want to
be informed.
So,
although we know
these factors are related,
we can only
collect information
as comprehensively as possible.
There are still
many missing points.
I think this is a problem
for any child development research.
However,
the good thing about the previous question
is that it reminds us
that there are many factors
that need to be considered.
This is what I didn't mention
in such a short time.
I want to tell you
what the result is.
Thank you.
Any other questions?
I'm curious
about the difference
between the intervention
in the day after tomorrow
and the interaction
with the environment.
In the day after tomorrow,
we will see
whether the medical intervention
is effective or not.
It is a simple
intervention.
The interaction
with the environment
depends on the day after tomorrow
and the day after tomorrow.
However, there are many different
statistical models.
Some use hierarchical regression,
some use mixed-effect model.
In short,
we need to see the main effect,
i.e., the gene
and the development,
as well as the medical intervention,
i.e., the environment.
Then, we can put it
into the model
to see the difference
in the statistical model
and the complexity.
Do you want to ask this?
Yes.
I have another question.
I want to ask
how do you
evaluate your
web pages and
interactive games
are effective
and how to improve them?
We think it is good
but users
don't like it.
How can you
improve it
and make it acceptable?
Many people
ask this question.
Sometimes,
it is hard
to collect
the information.
However,
we can tell you
how to do it.
First,
if you make your own web pages,
you can know
the traffic
and the links.
For example,
you connect different links
to the same website.
For example,
I put it on my Facebook
or my personal website.
It can detect
which link you click.
Then, you can analyze
the user.
Also,
you can collect
the information.
If you use
Facebook or
LINE official account,
you will have
the information
about the user
and the time.
Also,
because
Facebook is
a public service,
we don't advertise.
If you want to
advertise,
you can design
different gender, age,
or region.
You can try
different results.
For example,
if the user is different,
the result will be different.
For example,
the number of clicks,
the number of shares,
the number of comments.
Basically,
you can collect the information.
For example,
we have a website called
Weijiao Dangzhang.
It's a little bit difficult.
Most of the time,
you can only ask
the user's opinion.
If you want to
collect data,
you can ask the user.
Any other questions?
We have time
for one or two more questions.
Please go ahead.
Hi, I'm Xie Chen.
I'm a PhD student.
I want to ask
a similar question.
I recently
wrote a
scholarship supplement.
I need to make
a few videos
about my research.
I want to
ask if you have
observed the trend
in 2021.
Does YouTube still need
to make 10-minute videos?
Or do you need to
put some essence in the first 30 seconds?
Is there still this trend?
Or has it changed slightly?
In addition,
10 minutes is a common standard.
But if it's a video,
they all need to
catch up to 20 minutes.
Is there any other standard
similar to this?
Can you share
some tips or tips?
In terms of science and technology,
it's what we do more often.
In fact,
it's shorter.
We usually catch 3 to 5 minutes.
Of course, if you say it will reach 20 minutes,
it may be
a real-time video
or a live broadcast.
It will be longer.
Of course,
if it's an animation,
like we do a lot of animations,
you will find that
animation costs a lot.
The longer you do it,
the higher the cost.
If it's a real-time video,
I can talk for a long time
and it will take a long time.
This is the first one.
We usually recommend science and technology
to not exceed
3 to 5 minutes.
As I said,
there is a platform analysis,
like YouTube.
It can let you know
how many seconds
most people watch
before leaving the video.
We found that
if you don't catch
everyone's attention
in the first 10 seconds,
everyone will leave the video.
As I said,
it's not for normal people
who don't like the first 10 seconds.
They think it's too hard
and they don't want to watch it.
They can't listen to it
and leave the video.
We want to let people know
why they need to listen to it.
Why?
It may be funny
or informative
or you can share it
with your friends.
Think about
what causes
them to watch
your video
until the end.
Another tip is
to consider your audience
and try to catch
their attention in the first 10 seconds.
When we make
general public videos,
we don't know
if you want to use real-time video
or PowerPoint or animation.
If you use animation,
you can make animation.
It's okay.
In the early stage of animation,
we tried to use pure PowerPoint
to make animation.
It's okay.
No matter which one you use,
I want to remind you
that the dubbing
sometimes affects
whether people can listen to it
or not.
It's easy to be ignored.
Whether it's
quality,
smoothness,
or smoothness,
it may affect
whether people want to
listen to it or not.
If you're worried
that the speech is too dry,
sometimes you can
add a little bit of
background music
that won't affect your speech
to make it softer.
It's very helpful.
Thank you.
I have a random question.
Recently,
the rate of fan-professional
is so low that it's hard to describe.
Do you plan to
make a community
or switch to another platform?
Or use the coordinate force
that they joke about now
to open a fan page and interact with others
to attract more people?
Do you do something like that?
Yes.
Whether it's Facebook
or Google,
it's all up to them.
It's like raising a shrimp.
In the early days,
the algorithm wasn't that terrible.
But now, it has
blocked the fan page to an extreme level.
As I just said,
some of the things
I just shared
are more about craftsmanship.
Fan pages are also about
business.
Basically, we don't expect
any business feedback.
That's why
we can't put
100% effort
on it.
Then,
the rate of fan-professional
will be lower.
But if it's better,
we hope that
we can build our own website
or app in the future.
We don't want to be affected
by the algorithm.
Otherwise,
you'll never know
how to apply the algorithm.
You'll never be able to
catch up with it.
It's also difficult
to spread information.
But we haven't changed
our original intention.
We've always hoped
to produce high-quality products.
We believe that
we can still survive
as long as we can
move the same things to our website
or other places.
I think
it's a good question.
We've been thinking about it.
The algorithm is bad.
It's not today's issue.
It's trying to charge you for advertising.
But we're craftspeople.
We can't spend money on advertising.
It's a waste.
We'd better produce better products.
I think what you're doing
is very meaningful.
I hope you can
keep doing it.
I have no more questions.
Thank you.
We hope we can
keep doing it.
Otherwise, many people will die.
Okay.
Now it's time to
sign off.
You can leave if you have
anything to say.
If you have time,
feel free to stay.
If not,
I'll stop the recording.
Thank you.