Good morning, good evening, and thank you for joining me today to share my screen.
We don't have a lot of people today, so feel free to interrupt me at any time if you have any questions, or just turn on the microphone.
The topic I'm going to talk about today is called Invisible Risk Data Sharing Activities of Data Brokers.
My co-authors are Aaron, who just got his PhD from Rutgers.
His PhD peers are also here.
He's going to go to California State University, Fullerton.
The other teacher is a Rutgers teacher.
Let me introduce myself.
My background is actually accounting.
I'm a CPA, and I'm a Certified Internal Auditor.
But my PhD is Management Information Systems.
I usually teach data analytics and data mining related courses.
Because of my background.
I'm currently on the list of Fulbright specialists.
I specialize in curriculum development.
I've worked with Computer Science before.
They have a task force on how to design cybersecurity curriculum.
So I'm in that program.
My research is mainly IT management and security management.
Almost all of them are in this area.
I often give lectures outside, maybe at universities, conferences, or some professional organizations.
I used to be a panelist at the Federal Reserve Bank.
About three or four weeks ago,
I helped them do analytics training at McDonald's.
I also did some training for the California Department of Justice.
I also gave a lecture at the Taiwan Monetary Authority.
In 2018, I was at KPMG, a large audit consulting firm.
I was a professor-in-residence there.
So I worked with them in New York for 10 weeks.
I also do projects with them.
I've done more than 15 projects so far.
I'm the incoming president of Accounting Information Systems.
This is my LinkedIn.
If you're interested.
About this paper.
Data Broker has been around for a long time.
It's just that it's been noticed for the past 10 years.
As you can see, a lot of news is about Data Brokers.
The earliest one I have here is from 2013.
I've been seeing it since this year.
Especially after the Facebook Cambridge Analytica scandal.
More news.
Who is a Data Broker?
A Data Broker is not the organization we usually come into contact with.
For example, if we go to a website.
We all know that it collects a lot of our information.
We also know that some websites will sell or share our information.
But the Data Broker is actually hiding behind these websites.
So when it's collecting data, we probably don't know.
For example, we have a free app on our phone.
Then we log in.
In fact, this app is free.
It's not free.
It's actually because there's an additional information sharing action behind it.
So it's free.
Or, for example, we go to the supermarket to buy something.
All of our purchase records and so on.
In fact, it's all shared behind it.
Or it can go to, for example, Facebook.
All of our public information on Instagram.
So the photos we posted.
What we wrote.
How to write.
Is it a relationship?
It knows all of these things.
There are also some public sources that it can find.
For example, in Illinois.
For example, who paid for which house's property tax.
That's all you can see.
So there's actually public registration information.
And then these companies will collect all of your data.
And if it's not enough, it will go to other Data Brokers.
Share it together or buy it from them.
And after you've bought it, you've sorted it out.
In fact, each of us will have a tag.
It can have some influence.
For example, this person is their family.
There will be a baby recently.
Or this person will have access to a golf club.
Or this person is Facebook's social media influencer.
It can all know that you have some preferences.
Or you have some characteristics.
It knows it all.
And this is the most common thing.
These marketing or advertising Data Brokers.
They can actually do it very accurately.
For example, when I was in another school.
My colleague, every time he received an advertisement letter, he asked him.
Do you want to buy a house?
Do you want to buy a new car?
Do you want to buy a new boat?
And then he got this.
I got it all.
Do you want to borrow Personal Loan?
Do you want to borrow Mortgage?
How much money do you still have to pay for Mortgage?
So you can see that he can know.
What is your current financial situation?
The advertisement he gave you.
It's all different.
There are also two more common ones.
Fraud Detection and Risk Mitigation.
For example, when you go to the bank to borrow money.
He needs to make sure that the information you give is correct.
It is also through Data Brokers.
This part is very important.
There are also some websites that actually allow you to find other people's websites.
He also collects the information of these people through Data Brokers.
So you can judge if that person is the one you want to see.
So why is this information useful?
That's actually because if he can get a lot of customer data.
Collect it all.
And then whether it's online or offline.
What happens after he finds it all?
Then he has a way to reconfirm these data.
For example, the same thing.
I went to find it from a lot of sources.
I can tell which one is right.
Then you can put that data quality will be much better.
So he has a way to use it to make some predictions.
Then he doesn't care what happens to each of us.
What he wants is this large amount of aggregated data.
Then he can make predictions for him.
After this prediction, it's actually very useful.
It's because he can sell it.
For example, this person may have to change cars next year.
He has a way to tell these people.
You can send a marketing material.
Or he can buy more useful information from other Data Brokers.
To make his data richer.
So you will see all kinds of Data Brokers.
These four are relatively large.
For example, Axiom is actually very large.
They are all doing marketing campaigns and fraud detection.
Then the three people in the back are for business or government.
For example, tell you what the financial information of these people is.
Or someone told you that his customer transaction.
What does it look like?
Or he can tell you that I have collected this information.
Not just for marketing.
Financial service products can be given.
In fact, this is when you understand all the profiles of a person.
In fact, all the information is very useful.
So what kind of information did they collect?
Uh, this is a bit vague.
Because this is a screenshot.
But if you can see, he actually tells you here.
Axiom is a big Data Broker.
He is a Public Traded Company.
He has 45 years of historical data on name changes and residential history.
He has all the data from the past 45 years.
Who are you here?
How did you change your name?
He has it all.
That gender, age, education level.
This is very simple for them.
He also knows you.
For example, what income level do you currently have?
What is the car?
Then when there is this information, he can do prediction.
For example, is there anyone in your household?
Recently planning to have a baby.
Or is it planning to adopt a child?
Or are you in the United States every year?
Are you paying taxes every April?
Or are you a heavy Facebook user?
Or are you easily influenced by social media?
He has a way to know.
Do you have major medical insurance?
All of these are known.
Then, surprisingly, they have more than 3000 different attributes.
So in the United States, everyone, if he has collected your information, he has 3000 different attributes to describe the various characteristics of this person.
So he actually knows very well what happened to each of us.
Sometimes we don't even know our own preference.
But these data brokers will know.
Then you will find that this is actually quite scary.
The reason is because he is not the organization we will directly contact.
For example, we go to Amazon.
We know Amazon.
We go to Facebook.
We know it's him.
But he's actually doing these things behind the scenes.
So in 2014, 2013, the Federal Trade Commission in the United States, they actually have two articles.
They're all talking about this.
What they're talking about in these two articles is actually that they're talking about data brokers.
Their biggest problem is that we don't know what he's doing.
We don't know what information he's collecting.
We don't know what he's doing with our information.
How to share it, how to sell it, who to sell it to.
In fact, we all don't know that his whole practice is actually a black box.
So we don't know what they're doing at all.
So this Federal Trade Commission in 2013 and 2014, we hope that everyone can have some action to limit that.
At least let us know more about what these data brokers are doing.
So this is the main content of these two articles.
So what they're talking about is a very interesting thing, which is data brokers.
They're actually competing with each other to see who they can sell their data to.
So there's no problem.
But they're not actually competing with each other.
They're actually cooperating with each other.
For example, they asked nine data brokers.
And then they'll know where each data broker comes from.
For example, you're collecting public data from government agencies.
Or it could be any other publicly available source.
But it could be commercial sources.
Or it could be collected from another company and given to you.
You'll see that these nine data brokers actually have very different ways of collecting data.
Some people only use commercial sources.
Some people use everything.
And the most special thing is that although they're usually competing for clients,
that is, who can buy their data,
but you can see that their data is actually shared with each other.
Or you can say, ah, I've collected this data today.
And then if you need it, I'll sell it to you.
So you can see that they're a very complex network.
And in these nine, there are actually only seven,
which is the one on the bottom left.
The seventh is that it has nothing to do with other data brokers.
There are no data sharing activities.
Everyone else will buy or sell to a certain extent.
Or where do you share it from?
They all have it.
This thing is very interesting to us.
The reason is because if they don't just collect it themselves,
they'll take other people's stuff and use it together.
If today the hacker can attack a certain data broker,
it's actually like a grand prize.
The reason is because the data you get is not just his.
All the information you get and all the other people,
all the information they share with each other.
That's actually our hypothesis.
It's just that we later found out that there really was this thing.
For example, many years ago, in 2018,
Equifax had a big breach.
They forgot to update their software inside,
so they had a big breach.
Their breach is actually not just Equifax's data being leaked.
In addition to Equifax,
the other two big credit bureaus,
which is Experian and TransUnion,
are actually all leaked.
In fact, our data collection is from Dark Web.
So we actually found that
if you go and find Equifax's data breach,
you can actually see the data of the other two.
It's actually all mixed up.
There's also some anecdotal evidence.
When Equifax had a breach,
the other two reported the credit fraud data.
So all the data is actually leaked.
If we go to, for example, Google Trend,
and look at their fraud report trend,
you'll find that these three are actually almost the same trend.
One company has a problem,
and the other two have a problem.
We think that this is definitely because
of the influence of the exchange of information between them.
So as long as one person has a problem,
everything will happen.
That's a lot of trouble.
So you'll see that in fact,
there are a lot of regulations in the United States.
They've been around since 2013.
The early focus was actually that
these data brokers should let those consumers know
what kind of data they've collected.
So in 2013 and 2014,
Axiom would actually let every user,
no matter who you are,
you go and log into your data,
and then you can see what information you have.
You can see it all.
There are also some other points that
they feel are not transparent at all.
What is your practice?
What did you collect?
Who did you sell it to?
So far, it's all black box.
This is early 2013 and 2014.
And then in 2018 and 2019,
there were two new things.
In Vermont,
there's a data broker law.
It says,
if you're a data broker,
we'll talk about its definition later.
If you're a data broker,
you should register with its Secretary of State.
To register,
simply put,
before the end of January every year,
you have to go to its website
and provide all your data to it.
The provided data actually looks like this.
Which company are you from?
What is your website?
And then if the user doesn't want you to collect information,
can you opt out?
I don't want you to collect.
So how do you do it?
It actually has all the details of the disclosure.
Or it says,
do you have any
statement about opt-out
or data collection?
You can actually write it up.
This example is written a lot.
Some companies,
although it says it's registered,
but in fact,
you'll see that there's no information at all.
A lot of them just say,
please see our website.
If you click on it,
there's nothing there.
You can hardly see it.
This is one.
The second question is actually
data broker,
even if it meets the definition of regulation,
it's a data broker.
If it doesn't register,
the penalty is actually very low.
I forgot if it's Vermont or California State.
If you don't register,
you'll only be fined $100 a day.
And it's online.
I've been fined,
for example,
$10,000,
and I can't pay anymore.
For data brokers,
this is almost nothing.
They might make more than $10,000 a day.
So,
uh,
the penalty is actually not that big.
It's not like GDPR,
which has such a big impact on European privacy regulation.
If you have a violation,
it's just a few percent annual sales revenue.
So,
the effect of this thing is not that good.
it's actually very simple to define.
Simply put,
when a company,
you know you're collecting data,
or you know you're selling it,
you take the data you've collected and sell it.
And then it's actually a data broker.
As long as you collect the data and sell the data,
you're not directly facing those customers,
it's actually a data broker.
So,
uh,
it's actually a pretty big definition.
But actually,
you have to think about this definition.
It's very simple.
For example,
if you only collect data,
buy the data and use it yourself,
you're not a data broker.
Or,
say,
the data you collect is actually your customer's data.
For example,
Amazon,
what I collect is actually the data of these people who buy things from me.
And then I take these things and sell them.
Actually,
I'm not a data broker.
So,
there's actually a loophole.
that's going to cause some problems.
A lot of companies are actually data brokers,
because they're actually doing business.
But,
uh,
according to this law,
you can't actually see it.
The California State is the same.
Uh,
that is,
if you go to his Attorney General's office,
you can also see this big,
uh,
almost all the requests are exactly the same.
It's just that it started working a year later.
It started working in January 2020.
All the definitions are the same.
Almost everything is the same.
Although,
uh,
California's privacy regulation is actually more strict.
But it's actually the same in this regard.
So,
the information he's going to reveal is actually almost the same.
uh,
if you don't have a chance to go to their website,
you can see something like that.
So,
uh,
let's talk about it very quickly.
Uh,
we think,
why do they compete with each other and cooperate with each other?
Why do you think this is going to happen to them in the future?
Security breach or,
or,
or information will,
will,
will be stolen by someone.
This state is actually related to the reason.
The first big point is actually not in this.
Competition or data sharing.
It's actually because it's actually an unregulated industry.
He said,
he said,
everything is actually self-regulated.
They have their own privacy standards.
They have their own norms.
But,
uh,
for us,
in fact,
they are unregulated.
That is.
You take your information and share it.
Uh,
what is your penalty?
Or,
what can be shared?
What can't be shared?
In fact,
there are no restrictions at all.
Simply put.
So,
if there is a hacker.
If you can find a data broker,
if you can take all his information,
the impact will be great.
So,
this is why,
like Equifax,
the main one.
In fact,
the main one is a data broker.
If there is a breach,
it will have a great impact.
These information can actually be sold.
So,
that will have a greater impact.
there are more benefits.
So,
people are more likely to want to go,
uh,
get your information and sell it.
So,
this paper is still in a very rough stage.
But I think,
uh,
we still hope to be able to present.
And then I hope to give you some awareness.
Or,
uh,
some extra ideas.
Especially in,
uh,
how to protect privacy protection.
Or,
how to be more,
more effective to understand what they are doing.
So,
uh,
you will see that in fact,
our hypothesis,
in fact,
everything is still in a very rough stage.
So,
but we still hope to be able to share more.
the other one is,
uh,
we want to know if this registration has any impact.
Uh,
we,
of course,
we let these broad data brokers,
they are all transparent.
Or,
everyone knows who they are.
Will they say,
their practice is better?
They are more transparent.
Or,
they have some pressure to say,
they can't be so easy.
There will be a security breach.
But the problem is actually in,
not this regulation.
In fact,
because even if you don't register,
it doesn't actually work.
So,
uh,
I think,
Yeah.
So'.
So.
Um.
So,
So.
So Self Disclosed Information.
Security bridge.
Dark web.
Roberts University.
Dark out.
FBI Department of Justice.
Dark web.
Surface web.
Iceberg.
Deep web.
Authentication.
Intranet.
Login.
Online banking.
Medical information.
Hidden place.
Deep web.
Tor.
Configuration.
Control.
Censorship.
Drug dealer.
Hacker.
Hacked out information.
Illegal activity.
Dark web.
All.
Equifax bridge.
Equifax data bridge.
Equifax information leak.
Equifax.
Experian TransUnion.
Co-leakage.
Data broker.
Data bridge.
Analysis.
Private.
Characteristics.
Competitor.
Dark web.
Information leakage.
No.
Self-selection.
Security measure.
Transparent.
Shared.
Disclosure.
Privacy statement.
Data broker.
Data broker A.
80%.
Information leak.
Dark web.
Leakage.
Unique data set.
Information leakage.
Security bridge.
Data uniqueness.
Unique.
Unique data set.
Profile.
Unique.
Conclusion.
This research is actually very rough.
That's actually an ongoing project.
Actually, we've always wanted to keep going.
The focus of our presentation today is actually that we want to
improve everyone's awareness of data brokers.
Or I hope to encourage everyone to say that if you are interested,
you can join this project.
So we can think about how we can do it.
Uh, more accurately or more effectively.
Data collection.
Sharing the practices.
Privacy protection.
Privacy regulation.
Law-related.
Regulation-related.
Transparency.
Talk.
Stop sharing.
No problem.
Very clear.
I just want to think about it.
I don't know much about this, but I think it's a very important issue.
I want to share with you.
How do you protect your own data?
For example, because every website you use now has cookies.
Then you have to accept or reject.
Then there's something we can do to protect it.
Or it's already too late.
Our profile is already known to everyone.
We found that most of the data is already out there.
So we have to protect it.
We have to protect it.
So most of the data is already out there.
And then I'm trying something now.
It's a cookie on the website.
For example, I'm connected to Wall Street Journal today.
I'm connected to Amazon today.
What's behind it?
Collecting our data or activity.
Uh, we found that actually.
I can't control it in the middle of an upper bound and lower bound.
Upper bound is to say.
Uh, I'm Google today.
In the situation of signing in.
So Chrome knows who I am.
In that case,
In fact, they collect a lot of data.
It's pretty amazing.
But if I'm not logged in at all.
My browser is open again in private mode.
That can be limited to the amount.
It's a lot worse.
So that's another way.
Just try to close it.
No way.
There are some cookies that are actually more troublesome.
Uh.
Although he told you,
Do you want to accept it?
But in fact, whether you accept it or not.
That's the way it is.
You can't see any effect.
There are some websites that can make you willing to let you choose.
Uh, different cookies.
At that time, there was.
But some of them can't be turned off.
Because he has to know who you are.
Otherwise, you can't browse the website.
Yeah, so, uh.
There are still some restrictions.
Yeah, but, uh.
You'll know that they've actually collected a lot of data.
In fact, you probably know who we are.
What are we doing?
Um.
Yeah, that's terrible.
Yeah, well, uh.
I have another one with a computer science.
Before doing it.
We can actually use it.
Posts on social media.
We have a way to predict, uh.
Buying clothes or buying accessories.
Preference.
And then there's that.
We can know that.
What kind of clothes do you like to wear next season?
Color, brand.
And that prediction accuracy rate is probably over 90%.
That, uh, that's a lot of trouble.
It's just that we do it ourselves.
It's just that we collect it ourselves.
We have a very small part of the data.
We can do it so well.
You can tell that they're going to do it.
It's actually easier.
Then you would think.
Try not to post your own.
Too many personal things.
Or preferences or something.
But I think.
We still have a question.
I think so.
This is a preference.
Uh.
Uh, if we don't share this information.
We can't have those customized services.
Our search will be very bad.
Uh, it's almost not what you want.
Yeah, so if we want.
You can't do anything about the specific service.
You have to write, right?
But this is actually a preference.
So I'm talking about what they said to Google before.
That's more accurate.
What is your privacy?
It's your own decision.
It's actually from 0 to 100.
How much do I want to share?
It depends on what you like.
It's not necessarily a bad thing.
Then we have a question.
Uh.
You are me.
My name is Chen Peiying.
I am now at Indiana University.
Read information science.
Although I don't do data privacy related issues.
But because this is very popular now.
So I just wanted to say.
Let's listen to the speech.
I think there are a lot of gains.
Especially this kind of data broker role.
At least in our field.
This kind of investment information related area.
In fact, it is less mentioned.
Everyone is basically targeting a single website.
This kind of.
Uh.
Data privacy is being discussed.
So my question is, since this is a data broker.
Um.
How do you say they are very critical?
They have so much data on their hands.
Why would they let their own data so easily?
Give it out.
Just their own privacy.
Their own privacy.
Their data security.
And because once they are leaked.
Just assume that I am a.
I have that data set.
But I was harmed.
This information is somehow.
It is available on the website.
Yeah.
Isn't he supposed to prevent this from happening?
So we think it's very.
This is the weirdest thing we think.
And you see there are so many competitors.
To say that this is actually a very.
Profitable business.
So there will be thousands of companies.
In fact, doing this kind of thing.
But their information is.
Everyone has it.
But he can still continue to sell.
So why do we want to know more?
What are they doing?
And what happened?
But the problem is that they are actually hidden players.
That is.
They don't even know who they are.
Or the company name.
It doesn't make sense.
It's like a mess.
It's like we're talking about it in class.
So I can't find them at all.
So if there are more people.
You can jump in and find a way to know.
Who are they?
What are they doing?
That would be very helpful.
We would love to know.
Because.
That will have a lot of impact.
Because, for example, Amazon or Google.
They are actually sitting on a mountain of data.
So if we can find their security.
It would be very useful.
Like Amazon, he actually.
He put his report.
It's their information system.
The audit report of security control.
It's all shared on the website.
They are very confident that we are very good.
But these people are actually.
It's completely blank.
For example, since they have registered.
And then, although there is no URL.
Will they at least provide one?
Like a physical address.
That is to say, my company is definitely open.
In a place like this.
They have a physical address.
Like a registered address and a phone number.
Is there any more.
Is there a clear geographical distribution?
Or is it actually.
I don't think so.
We can't see any.
Specific phenomenon.
Because they collect data.
In fact, there is no limit to a specific.
State or something.
Because for example.
Because after all, you can pass it on.
To another server.
Because I know they will have some distribution.
For example, I need this.
I remember it seems to be Google and Amazon.
They have to find that kind of resource.
All kinds of natural resources.
Very rich place.
I want to have enough electricity and water.
I want to make sure he has a power outage.
Very warm.
But these things are actually.
It's not a company.
It's not their physical address.
Must be.
Not necessarily related.
Their company may be very small.
Because they are actually not sitting in the office at all.
Those people.
That's right.
I was talking about this before.
Someone said that we have no way to know.
Who is the European data broker?
Because of the GDPR.
The privacy law.
His control should be stricter.
So if we can find them.
Maybe they have more information.
It's easier to know what they're doing.
But I still don't know.
That's our data source.
Where to find it.
In fact, we don't know yet.
So this is interesting.
We think this is really like research.
I don't know what I'm doing.
I think it's a very interesting relationship.
Because like you said.
It's a school hire.
He's still looking for these companies.
He's using your background.
To make a background check.
So I think there's some information hidden in it.
It's not right.
You said the school information office.
Why don't you find someone to find it directly?
Maybe you can find it.
But it may be based on various cost considerations.
We just have to sell your information to these companies.
So there is a.
There is no mutual benefit.
But I think there is a relationship between the two.
Why are these people.
Although we think they are doing something.
But in fact.
You probably.
Because it's a school.
He still relies on.
Relying on these brokers.
To provide some information.
That's like a financial institution.
We go to apply.
For example, mortgages.
He is also exchanging information with these people.
To confirm our.
Are we giving the right thing?
It's just that this side is more compliant.
This side is more highly regulated.
For example, there is something called.
Fair Credit Act.
Something like this.
We can review our credit score.
In case something is wrong, we can ask him to change it.
There is.
But like other data brokers.
If his information is wrong.
In fact, we don't know where his information is wrong.
Or where is it wrong?
If people use this to verify.
Who are we?
In case it's all different.
Then the problem is big.
Another question is.
There are so many competitors.
Their niche.
What is their selling point?
I can only think of it now.
It's just that you use some wrong information.
To earn that kind of benefit.
Because if I know there is a company.
Can provide more.
What is the so-called more accurate?
How to define it?
Right.
Or whose model is better?
Or who has it?
But there should be some data brokers.
There is really some very special information.
No one else.
They never sell it.
Because I think that's the competitive advantage.
Some of you really don't have it.
So they are not selling real data.
They are not saying that I will provide you.
All the scores of this person.
I sell it to you based on our model.
The preferences of these customers.
Both have.
Like if it's that kind.
Fraud detection.
That is.
I sell data to you.
For example, how much is the annual income of this person?
Where does he live?
That kind is sold one by one.
If it's marketing.
I just sell the model.
Ok.
Maybe I can only be sure.
These people.
That is.
Their employees may be quite smart.
It may all be automated.
YouTube is the same.
In fact, all processes are automatic.
But it's still the same.
Just like FTC said.
What are they doing?
In fact, no one still knows.
Even though everyone keeps talking about it.
But there is no information.
Too mysterious.
I hope there is a legal expert.
Can answer.
They are on the law.
Is there no regulation?
I have a student.
I told him.
Hey, you next.
When the next assembly.
You mention this regulation.
Control the data broker.
Then he said yes.
He thought about how to do it.
Because before I told him.
You know Illinois has a.
AI interview act.
That is, if you are using a machine to read.
Job applicants interview video.
You have to disclose.
This thing is all from.
We talked about it in class.
Because he was in my class.
Then I told him, he went to mention it.
Then it happened.
So he often asked me.
Is there any interesting topic?
I think they should pay attention.
I told them about the data broker.
That depends on.
How to deal with it.
Because it's all bad.
There are some controversial issues.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Any other questions?
I just want to.
You just mentioned.
I just want to share it quickly.
Information error problem.
Because I applied for a loan.
Then the information is actually.
Some information is wrong.
It's already.
It's not right to meet different people.
Then your credit score is lower.
Then you can't apply for a loan.
So your problem is.
That's a big problem.
But you can't.
Don't tell anyone.
In the United States.
If it's below the credit score.
You can see those public.
The information they grabbed.
If there is a mistake, you can tell them to correct it.
But.
Then you have to see that there is a mistake.
Otherwise, it's still very difficult.
Then if they find the data broker.
You don't know.
What did he see?
Maybe the only way to know.
How does the data broker work?
Become a data broker yourself.
Do I still have time to ask a question?
Can.
I want to ask.
The question of the background check.
In the United States, you have to find a lot of work.
In fact, they will go through a background check.
I'm just curious.
What kind of information did they get?
That.
Like.
I came here to find a job.
I found that I couldn't find it.
Because he lived in Taiwan for too long.
But how could it be possible?
I can't get the information.
If this kind of thing has always existed.
How could it be possible to receive the information?
I'm just curious.
I just moved in.
It's blank here.
You can't receive it.
Because he should not be across the country.
But he is an American citizen.
He is an American citizen, but he is blank.
Yes, so we are very curious.
How did this happen?
He said he couldn't find the background check.
Can't find any information.
This is too strange.
What our school does most often is.
What is that?
Criminal record.
No matter how light or heavy.
All have to check.
Many schools are like this.
He will have a connected identification.
I said that kind of data broker.
How many years will they say?
Will you delete all the previous information?
Will there be such a situation?
It's a good question.
How do they deal with this?
All the name changes in the past 25 years.
Residential information.
Will there be in the future?
I don't know.
How long do they have to save?
How long will they save these data?
I'm curious.
The longer it takes for me, the more useful it is.
Because after about 50 years.
You may be the only one.
You are the only one.
People with this information.
That means that company.
Maybe the company's data is not good enough.
Is that possible?
It's possible.
Because like.
According to their FTC data.
They said that the data broker should have.
Almost all the data of all Americans.
Thank you.
This is another issue.
Who has it?
Why is there no one?
Any other questions?
Otherwise.
Today's speech.
Ends here.
Thank you.
David.
For giving us such a wonderful speech.
I think everyone has learned a lot.
And more awareness.
Then.
I hope.
You can come again next time.
Tell us.
How is the future development of this project?
Let's see.
Thank you.
If you haven't become a member.
I want to post a link.
You can join.
It's free.
It's a free.
Membership.
You can continue to receive.
Every week.
There will be a speech.
On different topics.
Thank you.
Bye.