Hello, I'm Annie, and I'm honored to have Ian here to give us an amazing talk.
Ian is a PhD candidate at Cornell University.
Today's topic is called Killing the Obvious, a Scientific Analysis of the Incompetent to be Executed.
Today's talk will be about 40-45 minutes, with a 10-15 minute Q&A.
The recording will be uploaded to Taira's YouTube channel or blog in about a week.
Without further ado, let's welcome Ian.
Thank you, Annie.
I'm not a PhD candidate yet, but I hope to be one soon.
I'm very happy to be here today, especially with the support of my Taiwanese friends.
I'll try to be more introverted, and introduce the topic to those unfamiliar with it.
I'll start by sharing my screen.
Can everyone see the video?
Yes, I can.
If you can't see the video, please let me know.
Today's topic is Killing the Obvious, a Scientific Analysis of the Incompetent to be Executed.
In Chinese, the word oblivious refers to an ignorant person, or a person who has no awareness.
It's a difficult word, so it's normal if you don't know it.
I'm Ian Su.
I'm a postdoctoral student at Cornell University.
I'm currently studying Human Development.
I'll be joining the Department of Psychology.
This is a project I'm working on with Cornell Law School.
Today's talk will be divided into three parts.
In the first part, we'll go over the background of Killing the Oblivious.
In the second part, we'll look at what the project is about.
In the third part, I'll talk about how the project combines psychology and law.
I'll use a simple way to explain how we view food.
I'll start with the first part.
The reason I'm doing this research is because
I was a lawyer in Taiwan two years before I came to Cornell.
During my time as a lawyer, I was involved in a number of cases involving killing the oblivious.
I didn't choose to be involved in these cases,
because my major was Law.
My master's was Psychology.
I was fortunate to be a lawyer with a background in both psychology and law.
I was involved in a number of cases involving killing the oblivious.
Many of the defendants were mentally ill.
The reason I came to Cornell Law School
is because I had a five-year Ph.D. program in psychology,
but they have a very strong cross-field discipline.
They have a dual degree program.
The professors here are very strong,
and they like to combine psychology, law, and research topics.
Although I didn't mention the six-year dual degree program on the screen,
my professor told me that I already had a law degree in Taiwan,
so I didn't need to come to the U.S. to study law.
What I'm actually doing is trying to combine the law and psychology that I learned in the past
and see how I can use my research to study legal issues.
The reason I started the killing the oblivious project
is because the two professors above me are professors in the Department of Human Development.
They know that I had experience in the death penalty defense in Taiwan,
so they strongly recommended that I go to Professor John Bloom of Cornell Law School.
Professor John Bloom specializes in death penalty defense,
and he is probably the most famous death penalty defense lawyer in the U.S.
For example, he went to the U.S. Supreme Court to defend himself eight times.
For a lawyer in the U.S., this must be a very difficult experience.
So I went to Professor John Bloom and asked him if he had any interesting topics that we could work on together.
Professor John Bloom is currently the Director of the Cornell Law School's Death Penalty Project.
Law schools in the U.S. usually have to study for three years,
and in the first two years, students will look for the so-called legal aid,
the so-called legal aid clinic course,
and students will usually choose a certain professor to lead the clinic
and hold a special case for this professor.
Professor John Bloom specializes in death penalty defense,
so his legal aid clinic is also a case related to death penalty defense.
So he has been working on this relevant topic.
And because death penalty is very special,
it is often intertwined with many psychological or psychological issues.
So these two books are some of the books he helped with.
Professor John Bloom studies death penalty from a lawyer's point of view.
In the process of death penalty,
he may often come into contact with some so-called intellectual disabilities or mental illnesses.
So he may use a more legal perspective to discuss or observe these things.
Today, we will not discuss the nature of death penalty,
but will focus on one of the issues from a purely academic point of view.
Cornell is quite special.
In addition to focusing on local death cases in the United States,
he also has another center that looks at the death penalty all over the world.
For example, they are currently looking at how to look at it from a more human perspective,
even if it is death penalty.
Some countries may lack the so-called legal procedure for the execution of death penalty.
For example, Cornell's Law School is currently helping some African countries
to reform the execution method of death penalty or related laws.
So this is probably why I am in contact with death penalty-related psychological research here at Cornell.
Because he originally had these faculty members doing these researches.
Now we come to the main topic, what is Killing a Belief?
What is he going to discuss?
The first part is that this research is about criminal liability.
You may think that this ability is abstract.
Basically, in the general criminal litigation process,
because you can imagine that in Taiwan, Taiwan is a three-level, three-provincial system.
So if there is a criminal case today, and it involves a death penalty,
for example, a more serious case, such as murder,
it will go all the way from the local court to the high court to the Supreme Court.
The situation in the United States is similar.
In this process, in addition to the judge going to interrogate some facts,
the judge must also pay attention to whether the parties in the process have the ability to arrest the parties.
So in the U.S. judicial process, including Taiwan, there is a similar law.
Usually, I list the four basic abilities that the parties need to have.
The first is that the parties must have the ability to interrogate.
That is to say, at least he needs to know what the court process means,
and what the role of each person is.
The second ability is competency to plead guilty.
That is to say, if he pleads guilty, does it count?
If he is mentally ill, does he have the ability to plead guilty for himself?
The third ability is competency to waive the right to counsel.
In the United States, it is more special that these serious crimes are not necessarily forced defense cases.
That is to say, the government does not necessarily need to help him get a lawyer.
In this case, or if it is a forced defense case,
can the parties say, I think I have the ability to defend myself,
can I waive the counsel?
I don't need a lawyer to help me.
If a party makes such a statement, is it an effective statement?
The last ability is competency for execution.
This ability is very specific, only in criminal cases.
That is the topic we will focus on today.
Competency for execution means that if a case involves execution,
in the end, he is sentenced to death,
and after being sentenced to death,
that is to say, this person is already in the so-called death penitentiary.
He also obtained an execution date,
that is to say, maybe the state government has issued a date of execution,
where and how he will be executed.
In this case,
he himself or his defense team can help him fight for
that this person may not have the ability to be executed.
We will explain later why the ability to be executed is needed.
For example, he may have serious mental disorders, etc.
This is also equivalent to the judicial procedure,
if it involves an execution case,
he will need the ability to be sentenced in the end.
We will focus on the last one today,
competency for execution.
In Taiwan, the current method is more like the ability to be executed.
At present, Taiwan's execution method is also being revised.
It should be revised recently.
This ability is quite interesting.
It originates from the U.S. Constitution 8th Amendment.
The U.S. Constitution 8th Amendment also states that
there is no way to tolerate
a cruel or unusual way of punishment.
Whether in Taiwan or the U.S.,
execution is a way to punish criminals.
So, in the U.S. judicial discussion,
if it is related to execution,
it is usually quoted in the sentence of the 8th amendment of the Constitution
to discuss the execution.
For example, the most common discussion may be the purgatory,
where the execution is considered unethical or cruel.
As for the specific method of execution,
the U.S. Supreme Court has three very decisive judgments.
They are Fort, Penelope, and Madison.
Today, we will introduce these three judgments.
Why do we need to discuss them?
The reason why we need to do this research is because
although I just explained competency for execution,
it is a legal ability that judges need to consider.
But in fact, its standards are very self-explanatory.
Although in the past Supreme Court judgments,
it said that to have the ability to be executed,
you must be able to understand the facts in a rational way.
What is execution?
And why are you sentenced to death?
Or why are you sentenced to death?
And when this person accepts the relevant judicial procedures for execution,
he must have the ability to help his lawyer.
Although the court has these two standards,
how do you actually,
for example, if a psychologist or psychiatrist,
how do they operate this standard is very self-explanatory.
Next, we will go through these three judgments
and talk about what impact these three judgments have on competency for execution.
Before we talk about the judgment,
I can give you an overview of what the U.S. execution procedure is like.
It's a bit similar to Taiwan.
So let's start with the column on the far left.
Generally speaking, the three columns on the left are very similar to Taiwan's three-level three-judgment system.
The bottom left is similar to our local courts.
Then the top left is the Supreme Court,
and the top right is the Supreme Court.
So generally speaking, the death sentence will almost always end
at the three levels of the column on the left.
Because it's a more serious crime,
and it may be related to life.
Generally speaking, if we take Taiwan or the U.S. as an example,
sentences that are not related to execution usually end at the column on the far left.
But if it's a death sentence,
they also have the so-called re-trial system,
which is the middle column.
The re-trial system also usually has the concept of the so-called three-level three-judgment,
which may reach the Supreme Court all the way.
Re-trial means that the court may want to review some new evidence,
or new facts, or new reasons, etc.
Each has different regulations.
But simply put, it's not like the first column is over.
It will go to the second column.
Even most death sentences may go to the third column.
The third column is very special in the U.S.,
which is related to the part of the life protection order.
It means that because the death sentence is a serious crime,
so they are in the process of the entire legal process.
They are almost all locked up in the so-called death cell,
or in the confinement cell.
This is equivalent to locking people up.
So as long as it's locked up with people,
it may involve a violation of the law.
According to the U.S. law,
people can go through a three-level three-judgment system
based on the issue of life protection.
So if a U.S. death sentence is a serious crime,
there will usually be the so-called nine steps.
This is about five to ten years on average.
So the process of execution is very long.
You might imagine that
if a person may have a mental disorder
or a lack of mental intelligence,
the process of nine years is actually very dynamic.
And because if they are all in the so-called prison,
or if they are suppressed in some organs,
and the medical environment may not be so good,
their mental state may deteriorate.
This is a very common case in the U.S. death cell.
Even if they have been sentenced to death,
it may be a very, very long process
from the day of execution to the day of execution.
So the death sentence in the U.S.
is a problem that many people will discuss.
The death sentence in the U.S.
has a huge number of people,
with thousands of people in each unit.
And the number of people on duty
is also thousands of people in each unit.
So it's less than 60 people
in the current death sentence in Taiwan.
This is a big difference in the number of people.
So this is to show you
the process of execution in the U.S.
There are about three parts,
and there are nine steps.
The earliest sentence is called the Ford sentence.
It was the first time in the U.S. Supreme Court
to discuss the death sentence,
because the law stipulates
how we should deal with it.
Mr. Ford himself,
he committed the crime of killing a police officer.
In the process of execution,
it should be said that
in the process of case trial,
he had schizophrenia,
and he had some obvious delusions.
For example, he had a delusion
that the U.S. was involved
in racial discrimination
with the 3K Party.
So in the end,
he went through the nine steps
that I just mentioned.
And then his lawyer
helped him file
the so-called claim
for the ability to be executed.
The challenge is that
he may not be able to be executed
because he had schizophrenia.
He had a very serious delusion.
At that time,
the judge said
that they didn't judge
Mr. Ford directly
whether he was crazy
enough to completely lose
the ability to be executed.
But they gave a rough definition.
In other words,
as long as the person
who was executed
had the rational ability
to understand
his execution
and his reason,
we would say that he was capable.
On the contrary,
he may not be able to be executed.
This was a judgment
about 40 or 50 years ago in 1986.
After the Supreme Court
made this judgment,
he said,
okay, we have finished the definition.
Then he threw it back
to the lower court
to judge
whether Mr. Ford
was capable of being executed
or not.
Unfortunately,
Mr. Ford passed away
due to other reasons.
At that time,
it was not clear
how to operate this definition.
It seemed that
everything was possible,
but in practice,
it seemed that
Mr. Ford was not capable
of being executed.
So many cases
were failed.
After 20 years,
there was a second judgment
called Panetti v. Quarterman
in 2007.
It was a judgment
after 20 years.
It was a similar situation
where the person
had a long history
of visual impairment
for example,
he wore western jeans
and helped his lawyer
to open the court.
He may decide
to call many different witnesses,
such as the deceased
President of the United States
or Jesus,
to be the witness of his case,
which is not related
to the case itself.
In this judgment,
the judge
re-explained
the long history
of the previous judgment
in detail.
However,
this time,
the judge
re-explained
the reason
for the execution
and the reason
for the sentence.
In this case,
the execution
is meaningless
because the judge
should be responsible
for what he did.
If the judge
can't understand
what he did wrong,
there is no way
for the execution
to work.
Therefore,
when Panetti v. Quarterman
was released,
the court finally agreed
to solve
the issue
after 20 years.
However,
the reason for the confusion
is that the court
has to say more
in the next 20 years.
For example,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
the judge
has to say more
in the next 20 years.
For example,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines for the execution.
However,
the judge
has to say more
in the next 20 years.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
However,
there are psychiatrists
in psychology schools,
so at least
there should be
some guidelines
for the execution.
This is the second part.
The third part
is about the
legal strategies
for the execution.
The third part
is about the
legal strategies
for the execution.
You may think
that you know
the legal context
but you don't know
how to operate it.
However,
most of the laws
in Taiwan
are against the U.S.
and other countries.
In terms of
the execution
of the Fourth Claim,
the progress between Taiwan
and the U.S.
is not that different.
We just started
a paper in 2014
and we are still
working on it.
At present,
many U.S. law firms
will come up with
creative legal strategies
based on their lawyers.
If a particular state
is successful,
it may influence
other states.
In the end,
each state will
have its own
lawyers
who will
determine if
a particular client
has a serious mental illness
and how to
deal with it.
If the client
has been in the prison
for more than 10 years
and he looks very sick,
the state government
will not issue a death warrant.
If the state government
does not issue a death warrant,
the defense lawyer
will have no choice
but to watch the client
either go crazy
or die in the prison
for other reasons.
The defense lawyer
will coordinate with
the state government
and if the client
is very sick,
the state government
will issue a death warrant
for the client.
If the client is in a
very bad condition
and the state government
does not issue a death warrant,
the defense lawyer
will not be able
to issue a death warrant
for the client.
The defense lawyer
will not be able
to issue a death warrant
for the client.
Another example
is from California.
The state government
will issue a death warrant
for the client
if the client
is in a bad condition
and the state government
does not issue a death warrant
for the client.
The state government
will issue a death warrant
for the client
if the client
is in a bad condition
and the state government
does not issue a death warrant
for the client.
Another example is
from California.
The state government
will issue a death warrant
for the client
if the client
is in a bad condition
and the state government
does not issue a death warrant
for the client.
So far,
the first legal strategy
has been used a lot
and the probability of success
is relatively high.
It's like the tacit understanding
between the defense team
and the state government.
Basically,
they will hold a hearing
to determine
whether the person
is mentally ill
or not.
The second strategy
is the litigation strategy.
Lastly,
I'd like to thank
my collaborators
and the RAs
who helped me
code my lawsuit.
We're still
looking at these
long-term death warrant
and we're still
looking at these long-term
death warrant
and the MakeAuthors Foundation
has been focusing on
the research on mental illness
and death.
Is there any possibility of
racial inequality?
That's all
for my presentation
and I'd like to see
if there are any questions.
Thank you.
I'll start with Ian.
Thank you, Ian.
This is not my area
but I've learned a lot.
I'd like to ask
if there are any questions
for Ian.
I'm happy to ask questions.
I'm curious
and this might not
have much to do with
your presentation
but I'm curious
how the US
identifies
mental illness
when it comes
to death warrant.
For example,
how much
mental illness
does this person
need?
How do they
consider this?
I don't know
much about the US.
The US court system
is not the same as Taiwan.
They have a national judge
for public prosecution.
I'm using the term
from Taiwan.
I'm curious how they
consider these things.
Currently,
there are a few
institutions
that have tried to
provide guidelines.
The guidelines are similar
to the ones
provided by
psychiatrists and psychologists.
First,
each state has different
qualifications.
There are no rules
for each state.
For example,
how many people
can be identified?
It's a mess.
For example,
there are two psychiatrists
in Texas.
They need to
write their own
professional report.
They need to write
their diagnosis
according to
DSM-5.
The rest is left
to the judge.
This is an interesting
aspect.
There are a lot of judges
with serious
visual impairments
and delusions.
Some people succeed,
some people fail.
I don't know why
we need to look at
so many factors
to determine
the outcome.
In Taiwan,
there are no
cases like this.
I'd like to ask
about mental
disorders.
This is related
to the third example,
which is about
medicine.
You said it's related to
people in prison
for a long time.
I'm thinking
that
people in prison
for a long time
are sentenced
to death.
After a long period
of time,
it's normal.
For example,
what's the mechanism
for them to
apply for
this kind of
sentence?
Is it
impossible to
enforce?
It's rare.
Most cases
require
the person to be
transferred to
a medical institution.
It's rare.
The reason is that
the death penalty
is stricter
than the death penalty
in the United States.
It's not easy
to get the person out of prison.
In fact,
thousands of people
in the United States
are waiting for death
and unable to
get help.
That's why
the so-called premature
is used
to determine
whether the person
has the ability
to survive
for a long time.
It's to
determine whether
the person
has the ability
to survive
for a long time.
Most people
are in prison.
Is prison
different from other prisons?
Is prison different from other prisons?
It depends on the state.
Some states have
so-called heavy prisons.
Heavy prisons may have
one death cell.
For example,
Texas or California
may have thousands of people
in death cells.
They may have
all death cells
in prison.
Heavy prisons
are more common.
Some states have
fewer death cells.
They may be in
more independent prisons.
It depends on the state.
I think it's interesting.
I don't know if
they are still different.
Except for
all death cells,
what about
other prisoners?
What about other prisoners?
It depends on the state.
Some states
have
heavy prisons.
Some states have
It also depends on the state.
Some states
have more open prisons.
They have fewer
medical resources.
Some states have
no prisoners.
many prisoners.
Some states have
no prisoners.
They are waiting for death.
It's not like
there are no prisoners.
The treatment is different.
The prison is different.
The prison is free.
It has minimum
guarantees.
They are waiting for death.
In theory, they can't use
too much resources.
But there are many people in the US
and their policies are changing.
It's weird.
Some people have been
in prison for years
but they are not dead.
It's awkward.
It's not certain.
It's a complicated
situation.
Yes.
Any other questions?
No.
Thank you for the wonderful report.
I'm looking forward to
your coding.
I was thinking
to do a Lenten class analysis
to see
whether the prisoners
are successful or not.
Their backgrounds
and profiles
are different.
I'm looking forward to
your analysis.
I hope we can
finish coding soon.
Thank you, Annie.
Thank you, Gao Xian.
It's comfortable
to talk about
heavy topics.
I think the topics
are sensitive.
The ability to save lives
is the last
decision
to be made.
It's a complicated decision.
I'm glad
to have the audience
here today.
Thank you, Annie.
Thank you for the wonderful
presentation.
Thank you for staying up
to listen to our
presentations.
Thank you.
I hope
Annie,
next year
you can
tell us
about your research.
OK.
I'll share it
with you.
Thank you.
Good night.
Good morning.
Good afternoon.
Thank you.
Bye-bye.