Thank you all for coming to today's Taira Talk.
Today's speaker is Zeng Kewei, who graduated from the University of Taiwan's Department of Physics.
After that, he did a PhD in quantum computing experiments in Singapore's CQT.
He wanted to do quantum computing because he won the Nobel Prize for quantum computing.
I remember when I won the Nobel Prize in 2012, I was wondering what was going on in this field.
I remember that the story really started like this.
My high school teacher can testify for this, not me.
Today, he will mainly talk about the control beam splitter technology.
Today's topic is Experimental Swap Test in Infinite Dimensional Quantum State.
Let's start with Kewei.
Before we start, let's turn on the microphone and give a round of applause.
I'll leave the time to you, Kewei.
No problem.
Can everyone see this laser pen?
Yes.
Can you see this laser pen?
This laser dot.
Thank you for listening to my talk today.
I'm Kewei.
What I'm going to talk about today is the Exponential Swap Test of Infinite Dimensional Quantum System.
This is an experiment in quantum computing.
Of course, I will talk about the theoretical background of quantum computing.
Then talk about quantum computing as a whole.
I will use the infinite dimensional system, which is not a common quantum element.
We use the quantum vibrational mode to do this.
I will first talk about the general quantum computer.
Then talk about the quantum computer using quantum vibration.
If you want to do quantum computing, you have to be able to use those gates and logic to do the calculation.
After talking about some of the standards of quantum computing, we will talk about the pros and cons of our lab.
Or our killer key is that we can make control gates.
After talking about the theoretical part, we will talk about what we do in our lab.
Let me talk about this slowly.
The first thing is to start with the scientific part.
What is quantum computing?
If we just look at the general situation, we can say that quantum computing is not just pointing to 0 or 1.
It is not just pointing to the North Pole or the South Pole.
It can point to any place between 0 and 1, including 0 plus 1 and 0 minus 1.
In addition to 0 plus 1 and 0 minus 1, it can also point to 0 plus i1 or 0 minus i1.
It is not just a number, it can become a negative number.
The first concept of quantum computing is that its quantum state is a negative number.
Because it is now a negative number, it can be between 0 and 1.
This is why we often hear this addition state.
It's amazing to hear the addition state.
You see that one quantum element can have two addition states.
100 quantum elements will have 200 and 100 qubits.
This is a big number.
Is it because it can be obtained by parallel computing?
Of course not.
The main reason is that when you actually measure, you randomly find an answer from these addition states.
If you can't find the correct answer and select it, the result of your measurement is a random result.
You can't just get the effect of quantum computing through addition states.
So parallel is not enough.
If you hear the complex number and the superposition, if you are doing quantum computing, you will feel that it sounds very similar to the electromagnetic wave.
Because if you use the addition state for the Maxwell equation, if you are in a rectangular or even just using a drum today,
This drum can also have superposition.
It can have different tones.
It can have different tones, and the tonal mathematical structure can also be expressed in complex numbers.
The answer is whether you have measured this part.
This is the first thing.
If you have an electromagnetic wave in addition state today, you will not be able to measure the electromagnetic wave.
The electromagnetic wave suddenly says that I only have 100 Hz left.
The part of 200 Hz is gone.
This is the first feature.
The second feature is that quantum is not just one quantum element.
It's so interesting.
The point is that it has to be entangled.
It must have this entanglement between this quantum state or its connectivity.
Of course, we are talking about Schrodinger.
Let me talk a little bit.
But let's start with entanglement.
Entanglement will make the quantum state have a very strong connection, but not a cause and effect relationship.
Although its connection is still in the quantum space, so in the time and space, in our universe, it can be in a very far place.
There is a very strong connection.
But it can't do superlight transmission.
So you won't see this kind of destruction.
It is a correlation, not a causality.
This is something that needs to be emphasized.
So quantum computing simply relies on the parallel superposition.
It has to have a strong connection between these states.
This strong connection, you would think that it may not be a problem in a small space.
If there is an electron pointing up, the other electron must point down.
On the contrary, if it points down, the other point up.
There seems to be nothing.
It's just a very strong connection.
But the problem is that if you let this connection run from the small world to the big world today, it feels like a very interesting situation.
Let's look at the picture on the right.
If the first case is that your element is above or below, it may trigger a whole complex system.
In the end, this cat will be in a state of death and fire.
It is often seen in Schrödinger's cat.
If you look at this up, it means that if you go up, the poison gas will not be opened.
So the cat is smiling.
If it is down, the poison gas bottle will be broken.
This is the case of crying.
So if you can use some physical mechanisms to slowly extend the interesting situation of small worlds through a bunch of chain reactions to the big world.
You will often see this Schrödinger cat.
The interesting thing about Schrödinger's cat is not just that the cat can be in a state of death and fire, but that you can make the small world of quantum mechanics look very magical.
These strong connections can be extended to the big world step by step.
Because the cat does not suddenly become a death and fire.
It must be through a certain kind of macro situation to slowly make it in a state of entanglement with small things.
That's how we see this Schrödinger cat.
Of course, we do not see a human or a cat in a state of death and fire in the real world.
This is an interesting situation.
That is to say, when a huge object interacts with the outside world, it produces decoherence.
In other words, maybe overall it is still a quantum type.
However, if you have a big system called a cat, the exchange of information between the cat and the outside world will not be able to describe the cat in a pure state.
It seems to have lost the outside information, which is called decoherence.
This decoherence can be said to be the place where we talk about entropy in many places.
You can say that the interaction between the system and the outside world produces decoherence from this decoherence.
In fact, it is the measurement mentioned in the front page.
It is a special process.
In fact, it is just an interaction between the system and the outside world.
The result of the interaction is that you only have the information of this system.
It is no longer a pure quantum state.
Because it is not a pure quantum state, it will produce entropy when you describe this quantum state.
Some people may know that a pure quantum state has no entropy.
If you take the whole universe as a wave function, it will not have entropy if it is completely evolved according to quantum mechanics.
It will not have decoherence.
But we can see decoherence and entropy locally.
This is a place where we can talk about it in a special way.
The last thing I want to say is that quantum mechanics is so interesting.
It has entanglement and superposition.
Through entanglement, we can solve all the problems faster than the index.
Of course, it is not like this.
We can only solve a few problems and only solve different situations.
The first category is whether we can find a problem.
But it hides some cycle patterns.
As long as it is a hidden periodic function, you can use show arithmetic or a similar family.
The key point is that you can do this kind of entanglement conversion.
You can extract its cycle information.
So if you have a hidden cycle information,
Show and a similar algorithm can solve this problem faster than the index.
Of course, this is very important, but it is also a good definition and a definition limit.
It does not solve any problem.
If you have a hidden periodic function,
Of course, this is also directly related to the encryption method of the national defense industry.
Because we often see this kind of elliptic encryption or RSA encryption.
Will be directly attacked by show.
It should be said that show was proposed in 1995 and 1996.
Show arithmetic is also the reason why the whole quantum computing or quantum computer will develop rapidly.
You can say that 1995 was the year of quantum computing.
Show can solve this periodic problem.
Is there anyone else who can find something interesting?
The answer is yes.
So Grover said that if we want to do it today,
For example, if we want to search for the name of a telephone book and its phone number,
It has nothing to do with any hidden internal relationship.
If you want to search for a search without any structure,
You can use Grover to make your search faster.
The number of times you need to search will be multiplied by the number of times you need to search.
The interesting thing behind it is that you can actually use quantum random walk.
You can use this kind of random walk that you often see in traditional computing.
Because in general, if you add some random to this CS algorithm,
You will make it perform better.
In fact, Grover's quantum random walk is a one-sided relationship.
But Grover can only be faster than the number of times.
It can't be faster than the number of times.
If you have no knowledge of the problem you want to search for,
Grover has been proven to be quantum optimized.
It can't do better.
If you want to search for some internal structure,
You can use some special algorithms to do better than Grover.
For example, if you want to find if there is a triangle in a pile of patterns,
We know that a triangle needs three sides and three corners.
Because the pattern you are looking for today may have some internal connections.
It can do better than Grover.
But if you don't know if you want to find this data,
Grover can do the best.
These two are the algorithms produced by Shor and Grover in 1995 and 1996.
Is there anything interesting in the past 1, 2, 10 years?
The answer is yes.
HHL algorithm, or matrix inversion,
It is a big breakthrough in 2009.
In the early days, we thought that HHL algorithm,
It can be faster than the classical number of times.
Because it is faster than the classical number of times.
If you can calculate the matrix inversion faster than the number of times,
It means you can calculate linear regression faster than the number of times.
It also means that you can calculate all kinds of interesting quantum mechanics,
Including PCA, SVM, etc.
So HHL is one of the core of quantum mechanics.
It was originally estimated to be faster than the number of times.
But unfortunately, in 2019,
Someone proved that the classical number of times can be faster than the classical number of times.
If some quantum tricks are used in the classical number of times,
The classical number of times is wider, but the quantum equivalent is not faster than the number of times.
It's only ten times faster.
So we now say that HHL is a bit of a quantum speedup.
Its quantum speedup is not so high.
Its acceleration from the level of Shor becomes the level of Grover.
It's still great, it's still fast, but it's not so fancy.
That is to say, the quantum algorithm can only solve three problems in general.
Find the cycle, find the data search, and find the inverse matrix.
It can't solve the problem of arbitrary,
There is no such thing.
But there are currently three major categories.
Then this is probably the part of the background we are talking about today.
That is to say, if quantum is something interesting,
It can have additional states.
But one additional state is not fun.
It must have a bunch of entanglement.
Then you can see those interesting things.
What is the specific algorithm of entanglement?
You will see quantum Fourier transform, quantum random walk, and HHL.
This is probably the part of the background introduction.
Okay, then we'll find this.
This thing sounds very scientific, very mathematical.
We have to find a real physical object.
You can run, for example, what is 0 plus 1 or 0 minus 1.
This kind of quantum element.
We have to find one.
In fact, we can operate it.
Really let it produce entanglement.
Let it produce entanglement.
These quantum logic operations for us.
So we have to find a physical object.
Because this world is that we are not living in the field of HHL.
We live in the world of matter.
So we have to find the material to do this thing.
So now there are two or a few more leading.
There are two more famous.
One is to do it with a quantum well.
Or do it with a super-mass chip.
The quantum well on the left is what I did in CQT.
This is the experiment.
We are using a more primitive way of doing this.
So when you hear the chip ion,
The first thing you want to say is that you want to use one by one.
You use one by one of the quantum in this vacuum.
How do you catch the quantum?
Why can I do this thing?
Because it's not like you can clip it with pliers or something.
You have to think about why you can catch a quantum.
So the first question is that we can catch it.
The answer is that we can't take a quantum.
Hanging in a space without moving.
Because this violates Gauss's law.
If you simply operate it through the power plant,
It must be in a certain space.
This is Gauss's law.
So you can't let it stop at a point.
But linear potentiometer,
After you let it have an AC current,
It can have an average confinement time.
It is called Ponder Multi Potential in the professional field.
But we can use very simple.
We should do this thing by watching this video.
This doesn't look very good.
Wait a minute.
Okay, now you can put it.
So what we can see at this time is that
You have a quantum in a vibrating plant.
You can catch the quantum in a certain place without moving.
So the first problem is solved.
We know how to produce quantum.
After we catch a quantum,
Remove one of its electrons.
And then we go through a vibrating battery plant.
You can catch it in space without moving.
So the first two quantum can be caught.
There is no problem.
What are the advantages of quantum?
What are the benefits of saying that we caught it?
The first one is that the quantum lives in a very, very high vacuum.
It's probably 10 to the 12th square.
It's not a problem.
How vacuum is it?
It's more than what we see.
The degree of vacuum is more than the track between the earth and the moon.
Low-Earth vacuum is still vacuum.
So if you look at the international space station,
The degree of vacuum outside is not as good as the vacuum in our lab.
It's still vacuum.
So this vacuum is basically
If the system is stable enough,
The quantum is able to live for a few months.
It's not a problem.
We have a quantum.
We caught this quantum once.
It's been alive for about half a year.
From September last year to March this year.
Until one time, one accident, it's gone.
So it can live very long in this situation.
It won't interact with the background.
So it won't have a lot of strange noises.
Or it won't be affected by the outside environment.
Quantum computing needs these intangibles.
It's very fragile.
It's best to live in an environment where it doesn't interact with the outside world.
But we can manipulate it.
How to manipulate it, I'll talk about it later.
But it doesn't have any background interaction that we don't want.
The second is that when you catch a bunch of quantum,
Every quantum looks the same.
You won't find that my quantum,
For example, after my quantum, my quantum,
It's not the same as the other one.
Because quantum is essentially through nature.
Instead of through artificial production.
So we don't have to adjust the nature of each quantum.
Because if the nature of the quantum is different,
Then we have a big problem.
It's the same for every one you catch.
This also means that if we use this system to catch this quantum,
We can use this system.
If we use this system to catch and operate,
We can use this whole system to deal with another quantum.
It basically has no problem.
We don't need to adjust each one or measure it.
Basically not necessary.
Another feature of quantum is that,
Because it is through the battery factory,
Every one has electricity.
In the case that every one has electricity,
Every one can directly auto or connect in the same trap.
That is to say, if you catch 10 quantum today,
You can directly let the first quantum and the tenth quantum have an entanglement.
You don't have to say that I have to do this through 1, 2, 2, 3.
Because in theory, they are actually in this trap.
They can all see each other.
This thing can make the complexity of quantum computing much lower.
As long as you don't need a bunch of complicated quantum,
You can make your experiment more accurate.
Because we all know that quantum computing is not perfect now.
As long as you keep doing all kinds of quantum logic,
You just let your error rate rise.
Basically, the quantum computing of the quantum system is in this.
Because of these good qualities,
Its quantum logic is in single qubit rotation.
About 99.999 is not a difficult thing.
In the case of 2-qubit, which requires entanglement,
98 or 99 is not difficult to do in a normal lab.
It can be very easy to do very high quality in a small number of small systems.
This is the characteristic of the quantum system.
How do you do a lot of them?
This is not the scope of our discussion today.
We know that it is very good if it is small, there is no problem.
But there are hundreds of kinds of quantum.
We open the element cycle table and it looks like there are more than 100 kinds.
So why do we choose Eterbium?
What are the benefits of Eterbium?
The first one is that if we look at it now,
There is a hyperfine cube in the lower left corner.
The place where we define 0 and 1 is here.
What are the benefits of it?
This Eterbium 171,
Its nucleus is a spin half.
Its nucleus has a 1 in 2 spin.
So the result is that it will produce a hyperfine cube.
It is very natural, like a straight line or a straight line.
So it is a hyperfine cube.
The second is that if you kick off one electron,
What is the layer of the outer chain?
So there are not many cases where you kick off the first one and it is full.
So your first requirement is that if you want to have a hyperfine,
And then you want to kick off one electron,
The outer chain is full.
At the same time, you also hope that in the process of your experiment,
Your nucleus will not go to any strange place.
For example, if we put the nucleus here,
Through this experiment,
It may have a part of the probability to get here.
When it gets here, we'll figure out a way to kick it back.
That is, we can kick it back through 935 and 638.
You have to make sure that you can find your nucleus back to where it wants to be.
You can initialize it to where you want it to be.
This is quite important.
Because you don't want to say that it has all kinds of good qualities,
But after you do the experiment, you don't know what kind of strange state your nucleus has gone to.
Of course, another important point is that
You hope that the laser you do the experiment can be bought on the market,
Or at least it's not very exaggerated.
For example, our laser here is 369 nm.
If your laser is 500 to 1000 nm,
That's very, very good.
That is to say, the range of visible light is very good.
Although 369 nm is already very close to the blue light,
It's a little bit of an outline, but it can still be done.
Whether or not you can do the experiment with a sold laser,
It will also affect whether or not you can do a good amount of electricity.
So you can express it in various ways.
It meets a series of good qualities.
It is a spin-1 in 2.
After it kicks off an electricity,
The outer layer is full of electricity.
Its various complex connections can be easily
We can simplify it to just look at the connection at the bottom left.
As long as we have those auxiliary lasers,
It can be regarded as non-existent.
At the same time, it mainly operates 369 nm.
This frequency can be bought on the market.
So why do we choose to use Ethereum?
Ethereum does not have a very long history.
It was probably around the 2010s
It was established by Chris Monore, a professor at the University of Maryland.
It is to use Ethereum to use its 369 nm
Transition to do all kinds of quantum computing operations.
So why is Ethereum a good reason?
Let's talk about why the reason system is a good system.
Why is Ethereum a good reason?
After the two-step logic is completed,
But the reason system can only be a small system.
If we want to simulate a large
What should we do if we need a lot of Hewlett-Packard space?
So the first simple way is to say
Each of our particles has a spin-down and a spin-up
One 0 and one 1
Then we can make it
Let's just find a bunch of particles.
We have n particles
So in this case, our total Hewlett-Packard space is 2n square.
Sounds good
But can we find a faster way?
Maybe there is
Your particle is
In addition to the ability to pick up,
The particle will vibrate.
Because we just said
We are using this
This
We are adding an AC power plant
Let this particle be in vacuum
Affected by this power plant
Then after the back and forth vibration, the waiting price is restrained there.
This means that the particle will vibrate.
The vibration of this particle is also a quantum.
In theory, you can put a quantum
You can put two
You can put three
You can put n quantum
So you can put a lot of quantum in every quantum
Theoretically, it is infinite.
In practice, of course, it is limited.
So the reason why my paper is said to be this
The reason for this SWAP test in Infinite Dimension is because
We are using a quantum
We are not using 0 and 1 as a calculation standard
What does this mean?
Look here
The mainstream approach
We can say that this is more common
We have a lot of 0s and 1s
A lot of 0s and 1s
You are on the top of this side
Then this kind of vibration
It's like a bus
Responsible for the information from the left to the right
It's like it's a
After you finish the calculation, you will be forgotten
I want to hope that it is
Not as a
Support function
But what you have to think about is
Every quantum has only two dimensions
But it contains this
Continuous Variable
Or its Vibration Normal
Its vibration is an infinite dimension
Can you turn their characters upside down?
That is to say
Let you
This part of the infinite dimension
It becomes a storage and calculation character for quantum computing
Let this two-dimensional system
It becomes a quantum bus character
If you turn it upside down
Maybe we can use the same system
But this can be done
Can manipulate a lot of
It's a lot of quantum dimensions
So this is possible
Then there is another point
It's special to say
Why do I seem to switch
This infinite dimension
Interact with Continuous Variable
Your infinite dimension
This matter is seen through its vibration
That is to say, one vibration, two vibrations
It can go to the infinite dimension
The reason for the Continuous Variable
This vibration
If you look at it with quantum
It is in x and p space
It is in the phase space
Is a continuous situation
So this infinite dimension
With this continuous variable
This matter is exactly the same
It's not that I don't seem to get it
Just
People in quantum will prefer to say
It is x, it is infinite dimension
But if you are from the light system today
You are doing quantum light
You might be saying
This is a continuous variable
OK
So now we know
Can you open it?
No problem
I want to ask
That one of yours
Motion state is also
The direction of x is still
Is the direction of radio
This
We are all using the direction of radio
OK
We are not using X
Thank you
The main reason is because
Our experiment is
Need a few vibrational modes
Interaction between
Then X
If we pull to the front page
This is to say
You each
There will be three vibrations
But his three
There are two directions
Is radio
Is
You can say it is horizontal
Then one is horizontal
So you use this
Horizontal vibration
He has more
He can also choose
We won't choose
Like here
The two he drew here
Both are
X
But we don't use these two
These two are just memories
We use radio
Correct
OK
So
Is it because of radio
His ability to separate
Probably with his weight
Separate
The range is probably where
Is there
Probably all in
Kilohertz
Megahertz
Radio
Probably up to
0.5 or up to 5
It is possible
Then generally speaking
X will be smaller
Because
X it is not
X it is from that
Cap to confine
It is clamped by two electrons
Generally speaking
We
Uh
Our X
His
Frequency
His that
His frequency is smaller
Correct
Of course this is not
Why don't we choose him
The reason is right
Correct
Understand
So simply put
Say yes
OK
So simply put
Just pull it back
Just say good
We now know this
This computer
To do it with a microscope
Very good
But the speed of ether
Maybe there is no
This kind of vibration
Better
So we decided to use
Vibration of ether
To do experiments
After that
We want to say
Then we have to make sure
He can do quantum computers
Is the quantum computer
Is a series of requirements
First
You have to make sure you can
Your quantum information
The subset can be more and more
For example
If your spin has 2
You can find
For example, more
Two spins
You can find a very large
Kilohertz
This quantum space
This thing
Can be done in spin
That in quantum information
In this
Of course I can do it too
So theoretically
We can catch
A vibration
You can catch two
Vibration of ether
You can catch
You can catch a vibration
This quantum
You can catch two
You can catch three
So he
Scalable
The first one is fine
The second
He can last a long time
Coherence time
He must not
He must not be easy
It's easy to interact with the outside world
This thing
In spin
Can last
Ten minutes
This is a pretty exaggerated world record
What about the vibration
It can only last about
Ten to twenty milliseconds
One millisecond
Is one thousandth of a second
But it's been a long time
Because our experiment
Faster than this
The rest is more standard
That's what we want
Can we go
Effectively go to this
Put it
Initialization in a certain place
I said we hope
When we start
We can know where he is
So we do
All kinds of operations
That's how it will be
To the place we want to go
Of course you
You can put it
To a certain place
Let him
After all kinds of operations
You have to be able to read it
How can you read it
The answer is also
Is
Initialization skills
And reading skills
Use spin
To read
This
With spin
With continuous
It's the same
This technology
In
In this
Whether you use this
It's the same
The real point is
Is that
Can you find the middle one
Can operate
Vibration
That kind of logic
How do you make logic
Or the most difficult place
OK
So let's go to the next place
I want to see
That is to say
In the case of QB
We see the logic
You may see it more often
That is to say
We have a single QB
We can turn it
At the beginning
QB is like a
North and south
This
If the North Pole is 0 and the South Pole is 1
You can see above
Turn around on the surface
The first one is
If you have only one
Just turn it
That
If you can do it
Any quantum state
You have to be able to do
Any quantum
This
If you need this result
You also need one
Can control two
quantum
What about our common practice
That is
This is the first one
Is this controlled
Then the second one
Is controlled
You can do
If the first one is 0
The first one is 0
If the second one is 0
It's still 0 0
That's his logic
It's a simple output
This situation
That
QB is the quantum
In the binary system
Can do this
What if we have a
What if we have an infinite system
So we have the situation on the right
Like this
Single QB
It corresponds to a series of
All kinds of different things
What is this
Displacement
Rotation
Squeeze in
Bean splitter
These
It corresponds to this single QB
This
You can say
Continuous
These basic
This is the basic tool
But it needs a
Very important point
The most difficult thing is
If you want to do this
Non-linear
If you want to do that
Can let
Between the two
To produce
This is
This is the trouble
So the next point
We have to say
Okay, then we
Which one do we choose
To do this
We have to choose
Control swap gate
What about the control swap gate
There are three quantum
The first one is spin
Is our
Quantum box
There is a quantum behind
It's called A
There is a quantum called B
it is good
If you go through this
Control swap
It if this
It if this middle
This quantum
This spin
This box
It belongs to
Spin down
It won't
It won't do any action
But if it spins up
It can put two quantum
Exchange
It's very simple
If today
Your indicator
If it's down
No action
If the indicator is up
Exchange
It seems to be very specific, right?
Of course what to do
If you today
You have this very simple
this
Gate is that you can do this
Howdermann
this
If you spin the spin
Then you do it at the same time
This is a swap
gate
You can get
You can get these two
Unknown quantity
How similar it is
But attention
You don't need to know the quantity
It doesn't have to know
Quantity B
You go straight to measure
This quantum box
You can find these two
you
You get these two
Quantity
How similar it is
That's right
So this
This
He can give us this
This circuit
It means
We can
We can now
Unknown two
The details
In the case of details
But you know
How similar these two
How similar it is
This is actually very good
Because that is to say
Sometimes we are just curious
Our results
For example, the two of them
Is it
Similar quantum
But we
For its details
Maybe not so much
But the previous situation was
You might want to know first
What does A look like
What does B look like
To know how similar A and B are
But you can now
It's very simple
Just know how similar it is
And you don't need to know
What are their details
OK
Ok
Then next
This
In theory, we need
This is very simple
This
We need this
Complex control swap gate
It involves
One
Spin and two
Motional mode
Two oscillators
That
In theory
That's what it was like in 2001
But in practice
It's not that simple
Because we have something in practice
It's called the control bin splitter gate
It's very similar to the control swap gate
But it's not the same
What's the difference
You'll find out
If you use the middle one now
This
If you use Hamiltonian for evolution
You put X and Y
It will turn into Y and X
That's right
But there's one more thing in front of it
Very annoying to us
This
This face
Uh
This face is here
Because we know
The quantum world
It's a negative number
So of course it can produce this
This kind of virtual
This face is here
We need to find a way
Get rid of this face
When it only becomes X and Y
It becomes Y and X
No need Y and X
Plus a very annoying face
How do you do this
The answer is that we need three gates
We need three modes
We put what we want
This measurement thing
Ready in mode B and mode C
And then we let mode B and mode A
Interact
Let mode A and mode C interact
Its final result will be mode B
Interact with mode C
But its face
This face will be miraculously eliminated
So you only need two
Control beam splitter
And then you have three modes
You can do it
Just now we said
We really want to see this
We can know
How similar are the two quantum states
But
Uh
But you don't need to know
The details of these two quantum states
Of course, a very important point
No matter how complicated these two quantum states are
The measurement process is the same
It's the same time
You're not going to say
My quantum state is bigger
So I'm going to need more steps
No need
The quantum state may require more steps
But whether the two quantum states are similar
This thing
It is a constant deep circuit
Its length is stable
OK
This thing is pretty important
Because it
This thing is far more than this
SPIN system
Uh, efficiency
Of course, its
Its fidelity will not be higher
Because this is a relatively new system
It will have all kinds of infidelity
You'll see later
Where is it imperfect
So
It's very simple
We only need two control bin splitters
With three modes
We can get this
We just
Hope to get this
The core of this
Control swap gate
OK
Can I ask a question?
Good question
Because I don't know much about this system
So can you tell me a little bit
Physically
How did you do it?
Control bin splitter gate
Uh
I'm going to the next page
Ok
Ok, I'm going to the next page
The next page is physics
We just said so much
It's like you said
What can you do with a Hamiltonian
What kind of result will it have
What is its physical situation
Very simple
We now
I just
Uh
Every
Every particle is in
It's in
There will be a vibration in the z direction
There will be two vibrations in the x and y direction
Then we said we need three vibration states
So we can only use the x and y direction at this time
We caught two
After the particle
It's in the x and y direction
There are four vibrations in total
We used three of them
Called Moe ABC respectively
What about this Moe ABC
What if we go at the same time
Uh
If you apply this Moe AB and AC
That is to say
If we have this
If we laser this
Bichrome
That is to say
We applied this laser
It has
We applied the laser
It's not a single frequency
It's two frequencies
And if it's between the two frequencies
The interval is this
380kHz
Or 490kHz
It can
It can successfully go
Drive
Just what we want
This one
Control beam speed
What is control beam speed
That is to say
I let
One more x
Then let b less than one
This concept
So
You just let your
This frequency driving is
Difference
It's
It's the difference between the two modes
It will automatically become
Like the one we just had
This control
This situation
So our physical system
Is that we catch two particles
Let him use it
There are four vibration
Choose three of them
And then
Let one of the particles
It's in a special state
It won't interact with our experiment
It simply contributes to the vibration
It won't
Contribute to its
This energy level
It's just
I can't see it going somewhere else
What about the last one that I can see
Let's go
Use this
This post laser to drive it
Do this
Control beam speed
This thing
OK
Then
We have this mode
ABC
What about this mode ABC
We are not going to turn ABC now
We are going to turn
The difference between AB and AC
OK
So
If you do this
Then we can get
Control beam speed
Then we stack it up
Use that logic to put it
We use that
Just stack it up
We will get
We want this
The final result
This is our swap task
That
This experiment system
That is to say
The gate time we need in total is
1.2 milliseconds
Then we have this
It's 10 to 20
That is to say
Theoretically, we can operate
10 to 20
After the gate
It will only
There are all kinds of problems
But in fact
I can't do it for so long
The reason is because
Ah
Our state preparation
That is, when we are preparing
Those vibrations
There will be a lot of
Error
How to say
That is to say
We are now
We are now in this 0
0 and 0
Come to this
When this stacks up
This overlap
It is 80% of this
Overlap, that's right
But if you take 5 and 5 today
If you do the overlap
Its overlap rate is about 50%
The main reason
It says here that
There is a possibility that our
This state
This preparation
It's hard to do well
Of course, one reason is because
As your time goes up
Just follow your
When this phonon mode increases
His
Ah
The coherence time will be shorter
Then his heating rate
May be bigger
That is to say
As your mode
When going up
He has all kinds of imperfections
So even if your
Even if your coherence time is long enough
Coherence time is not now
The bottleneck of this experiment is right
OK
So that means we are now
Overlap 0 and 0
Great, he saw his 80%
Then 1 and 1 overlap
2 and 2 overlap
3 and 3 overlap
4 and 4, 5 and 5 overlap
No problem
But you want to say
Overlap 0 and 0 and 1 and 1
This thing
It doesn't seem to be very quantum
Can you overlap 0 plus 1
Or 0 minus 1
This thing
The answer is of course
So our practical approach is
We have a 0 plus 1
Then fix it
Then we prepare another state
He can run from 0 minus 1 to 0 plus 1
Along the
Just follow that 0 plus 1, 0 minus 1, 0 plus 1, 0 minus 1
Run around
But what about the situation
Let's find this overlap
It will become very overlap
Then it becomes very non-overlap
Then it becomes very overlap
Then it becomes non-overlap
So this thing is what we see
We can
We can not only fold
This
We can fold
So we can now put a
Fold it up
But you can't fold a simple one
He also wants to say
Then we can fold different things
Of course we can
We can not
We are now preparing a coherent state here
Then we will
We just sweep it like a radar
Sweep a circle
It means that you can imagine
This one
Like a
Like a plane
Or a submarine
Then we sweep it like a sonar
Sweep a circle
So this sonar picture
The result is
Its overlap
One circle one circle
We will see
Basically your coherent state
It's really here
Just this
There is no problem with this sonar
Yes
Then at the same time
If you put this circle in the middle
Is
The length is root number 3
Take out this circle
If you take out the slices
You will find
It overlaps
It's actually not bad
It overlaps here
In fact, there are still 80%
About 70-80%
So this is
We can really see this
Overlap two coherent states
This is two
Two coherent states
It's not bad
But I want to say
Can we do more
The answer is actually yes
That is, we are now preparing
Squeeze state
That is
This is also in the coherent state
A state that is common
We can put it
This
It
You can imagine
We
When we go up along R
It this
Its squeeze state
Will become narrower and narrower
It will be squeezed more and more
Like a
It's getting more and more elliptical
So it's at the bottom
When this circle
It's very close to the circle
That two circles
If the center of the circle is overlapping
And then you turn it
It's basically a complete overlap
You see here
It's close to 1, that's right
But as you do it now
It's getting more and more elliptical
You let the two elliptical
When the core is overlapping
It finally becomes more and more like
It's just
When overlapping
It just turned to the right position
It overlaps
In the middle of this place
Other places
Other places you will see
It's basically black
So we can be sure
We can overlap this
0 plus 1, 0 minus 1
And overlap all kinds of Fox
We can overlap
Squeeze and overlap
This Cohedron
it is good
So this is physically
We solved this
We successfully obtained
Control
Binslip gate
Can get a control swap
Get these interesting things
That's us
This is my paper
The content is that
We can actually do this
That
Of course you want to say
That this thing sounds like
There seems to be no quantum calculation
Or what quantum calculation
It's just more physical
The practical way is to say
If you can overlap
If you have two quantum
You can
You can think of two quantum
It's two
Two quantities
Because we all know that quantum
It's 0
Quantum plus one
Quantum minus two
Quantum
This plus one third
A three-quantum or so
So
The next step is to say
Can you make it
It becomes like two quantities
To overlap
Overlap two quantities
This thing is
This one
We all know that linear times
Overlap two quantities
The whole computer science
Is also the beginning of machine learning
So we
So our next experiment is
We go through
This one
This control bin
With some other
More skills
We started to want to do some
Things about quantum mechanics
But today
I stopped at
Control swap gate
It is indeed possible
Overlap two unknown quantum states
And its complexity
The complexity of its own experiment
It won't follow
You have to prepare
It will rise
Yeah, that's about it
Yeah
OK, so that's about it
Uh
OK, that's it
Let's see what the problem is
Because I know I'm talking
More
It will be faster
Because I think
Uh
Just cover the whole
More general background part
And then cover
For example, the part that is more theoretical
And then at the end
It really belongs to us
This part of the experiment
So the overall content
May be more
So if you are interested in any part
You can ask me directly
Thank you all
Thank you, Kewei
OK
Does anyone have any questions?
We can just pull it back
Let's see what the problem is
That is
The front is actually not too special
Just some
Background part
Because I think
Maybe some people
Not doing quantum manipulation
Just take it all out
OK
Yeah
So this is very physical
There is basically nothing here
Part of the quantum information
Because that's another one
Right
I want to ask a question myself
Just
That one
I actually haven't studied this
Continuous
What is it called?
Continuous variable
Yes yes
This thing with
Just the general
That kind of quantum gate
Is there anything different?
And they can
Do the same thing
Or
Can you explain a little
Just
Ok
That is to say
We know this
Dimensional
That is to say
If you enter this quantum computer
He can do
Just
Do you have a way to use
We all know that
Uh
Two-dimensional system can do anything
Quantum
Uh
In your two-dimensional system
You only need single qubit rotation
With ckn
You can do any quantum calculation
Is this thing
Continuous variable
That is to say
You are today
For example
Can he do this thing
Is
The fifth point here
This
He proved
You only need
You
You need these things above
With one
X and P
Separate
He
You need a bigger than X
Square or P square
This type
You can do
Any of this
You can simulate any of this
Uh
Hamiltonian
You can do any quantum calculation
That is to say
What is continuous variable
Uh
You can think of continuous variable
Is
Light
In the phase space
X and P
That is
That's what I mentioned later
This
This is here
He is an X and P
Then why is he a continuous variable
Because you can put this quantum
Put it in this
Anywhere in the space
That is
Uh
You can put this thing in the space
Anywhere
He is a continuous variable
You can prepare this vibration today
To this side
This side
He is here
But you can also think of it
This space
He is
Uh
These vibrations
Or these coherent states
It can become
Zero phonon
One phonon
Two phonons
Three phonons
So these two symbols are equal
You can express it as
The distribution inside the phase space
You can also express it as
He is a variety of phonons
Superposition of phonons
These two are equal
Oh
Comparison value
In fact, it is the quantum optics
Put the photon into the phonon
That's right
Yes, that's right
It's two
The mathematical structure is exactly the same
Just quantum optics
People will love to say
X and P
But like this
But people who do quantum mechanics
Say we see one
One by one
That is
So we like to say
Infinite dimension
So
This page
I think the point is
Uh
Wait a minute
Here
So here
I will say
It is continuous
Variable quantum information
But you look at the picture
It's actually not continuous
It's obvious in the picture
It is
It's infinite dimension
That's right
So these two are equal
Just
Because the tool is different from the system
So the language used is not the same
Yes
So continuous variable
This word must have appeared earlier
Because quantum mechanics
Maybe there was in the 1980s
But infinite dimension
So we do quantum mechanics
Will use
Because it is
More fancy
Theoretically, the vibration of infinite dimension
Because
It's like your x and p in theory
Like a vacuum
Can be pulled to infinity
In practice, of course, it can't be pulled that far
But it is theoretically infinite
OK
understand
Yes
Then
Sorry
OK
I understand now
What I want to do
But I want to understand again
That
What is this
Con
Control beam
Control beam splitter
Yes
That is to say
When you just said
Our
OK
Our purpose is simple
That is to say
Our purpose is to get control beam splitter
But our physical system
Can you give us control beam splitter directly
It can't give us control beam splitter directly
It also gives us a very close
Control beam splitter
It can give us
That is to say
Oh
But one point is that
The picture we drew here is in z-basis
That is
G and E
But we can get it in practice
Is in x-basis
But this is a small detail in practice
We ignore it first
That is to say
Here is x-basis
But the point is
After you get this Hamiltonian today
You throw it down
The result of it running is
In addition to being able to swap
It will get a
In the process of swapping
Like
Why do you say that
You imagine
You see your light
After the reflection on the glass
It's beam splitter
It will get a fragrance
You put a light on the glass today
So this thing is completely reasonable
That is to say
Because
This Hamiltonian
In fact, it is the Hamiltonian of beam splitter
It will naturally get the feature of beam splitter
That is to say
You hit this
On the beam splitter
It will get a fragrance
We have to kill this fragrance
Otherwise
We can't get this
Swap gate
That's right
So we kill this fragrance
The approach is
Let's put things in B first
Then B and C do something first
Then put
B and A do an action first
Let A and C do an action
We can wait
Kill it
As for why this thing
It will be like this
Anyway
This thing is
In 2020
It's been a long time since someone discovered this thing in math
I want to ask
How is it done physically?
That is physically
Why
Beam splitter gate
You mean
Why this
Or why
You use two lasers
After hitting
Why is it
Will be a very similar
Very similar to swap gate
What I'm asking is the experiment
OK
Why in practice
In fact, the obvious reason is because
Can you go to the next page
OK
Is it in this page?
Yes
That is
It's pretty obvious
That is to say
If you know what is blue sideband and red sideband
Blue sideband
Hit it
It's sigma plus and A
You know this
That is
Let me see if I can draw it here
I should be able to draw a picture
Let me see
OK
So
If we are in this today
This thing
We
If you just hit one
It will become sigma plus
And
A
OK
That is to say
So if we are now
OK
Then add cc
Anyway, I don't draw cc
That
You want to say
Can we reach a higher level
Is the second order sideband
That is
We know we can do sigma plus A
Sigma plus B
Sigma plus C
But if we do it today
Sigma plus
A
B plus
Then we add
Sigma
Minus
A
B
Plus
Then add cc
Just add that complex conjugate
Ignore it
That is
Then there is cc
In this case
When you combine these two items
Sigma plus plus sigma minus is sigma x
So it will automatically become
Sigma x
A plus B
That is
You drive two second-order sidebands
It will become
Control beam speaker
That is
That is to say
Because
We know that in terms of food
You are going through this
That is
You are you are
When you expand that
Lanadaiki parameter
Can allow all kinds of
All kinds of interactions
You don't just open carrier
Just
It's not just a sideband
You can go all the way up
Right
Which day is this thing
Paper
It is
This is it
I think this is still
Oh that's it
This one
This is the theoretical basis of the experiment
It should be said that it is the experimental
Toolbox
I think the theoretical basis is how to say
What is the theoretical basis of the experiment
The theoretical basis of the experiment is
You can say that the theoretical basis
The point is this
That is to say we
If we want to measure
If this is the case
That's 2001
Some people say
Hey
In theory, if you have this gate
We can do this
Then this is great
Correct
Then we can do this
Right
That
The reason why this thing is done
I
I think the reason why this thing is done
It can be said that the one just now is right
But
Oh
This one
This should be 2017
Right
But the problem is coming
You get it through that one
It's called control
How to integrate
This one
Or in 2002
It is said that someone
In theory
Do this thing
But in practice
By 2016
17 years
Just come out
This is what it is
Right
Really
So
It is how to integrate
This is reasonably early
Someone picked it up
Of course
I don't know where it is
I didn't find out until I found this
Otherwise
Then I thought
Because
Our time is
Paper of 2018
Is to do control
But then I thought
How to do the next step
I don't want to say
We should do cswap
But how to do
I don't know
Because I want to say
That waste time
Can't be eliminated
Then I thought
Someone said he already thought
How to eliminate
That is to do it on the experiment
Then write a model
It proves that it works
Then do it
Right
It is a
Quite a lot
Background process
That's right
So
It's just that you simply say
How to do control
Hit two lasers
The frequency difference between it
490 respectively
380 or 490 respectively
It will become a
Control
But
why
Two
Control
Combine
Can become a cswap
This thing
It's not that obvious
Right
Need a little math
Then
Let's
Right
The omega ab
Is
Above
Omega b
Omega c
Omega a
Right
Then omega
ac
Omega c
Omega a
Right
That's right
I want to ask
Just like
We look at this
Mode
abc
Obviously
b and c
Feel like
Orthogonal
But
Your side
a and b
a and c
Is it orthogonal to each other?
These are all normal mode
All normal mode
He is
Orthogonal
One
OK
Because normal mode
It's you
You solve it
Between them
There is no linear
Dependent relationship
Right
Understand
Then you said before
You choose
ab
With ac
The two
Interaction
Hey
What is it
Special reasons
Like
In
You are in the front page
The first slide
There
You can choose
a b a c
Right
You ask
OK
This is the reason for choosing
That is to say
Mode c is coherent
We look
Let's look at it from this page
That is to say
You will find mode a and mode b
Is a
It's all face
The two of them
Vibration direction is opposite
That is
You will find
Although they are both
One vibrates in the y-direction
One vibrates in the x-direction
They are both anti-vibration
Only mode c is the same vibration
What will happen
The problem is
The coherence time of mode c
Is the shortest
The shortest
Because you vibrate in the same direction
Easy to get noise
With all kinds of strange effects
So the coherence time of mode c
The shortest
So compare it
We have to
Let a and b interact first
Then let
Then let c come up at the end
This is what we found
This kind of performance is better
That is
A mode and b mode
Is a better mode
So we let it do
After the thing
Then let c come up at the end
Right
This is
Why
Because he
He
These modes
The
Coherence time
Is determined by what
Not the same
He
A big part
Is either out of phase
Or in-phase
Is
Tonight
The
Vibration
K2 rotation
Is a vertical vibration
Is an inront vibration
Now this mode c
Is an index vibration
It's so vibrant
Is
When this particle
Moves to this side
This one would move there
But if we use mode b and mode a
So
Compared to
If you have a noise outside
When it comes
A and b basically
Will not be affected
But c will be affected
So c coherence time
The shortest
This is why we
Of course there is a d
But we later chose
Just choose to use a b c
Just ignore it
We use a b and a c
To do this action
So
So we
You say sorry first
We are in our time
That is to say
Our a
b this
Bitter
The particle is better than a c
Because a and b are all good modes
a c has a mode
So
It's better
That's right
Assuming another d
It's a bit like
Mode a
But it's the same vibration
Yes that's right
That's it
OK OK
Then that one
The coherence is also very bad
It's not good
The reason it's worse
It's the same as what you just explained
Yes
So it's the same
It's the same
Understand
If it is in phase vibration
It's easier to pick up all kinds of noise
Then it's easy to pick up noise
Because
It's hard for us to find a source
Is
In such a small space
It actually kicked in two directions
So you assume
You suddenly have a burst coming today
Or you have one today
Your this
If source has a noise
When it comes
It
Maybe
Oh
Understand
It's just
It has a negative effect on mode c
But it doesn't affect a and b
Basically
Because a and b are opposite
It's impossible to be in this direction
Give you two opposite kicks
It's not possible
So
This noise source
It's with his special
Because he's in
His mode
This one
Is it related
Is
Because of his
On the space
Really in position
And really
Cause his
Is the source of this noise
You can think of it as
He is today
He is in
Uh
He's in
He's like a swing
Such a positive direction
And then if you have one today
If the wave of Sinusoid comes
It will be kicked
It will be accelerated or decelerated
But
If you compare today
You suddenly have a Sinusoid in your space
This one
EM wave
But it doesn't affect mode a and mode b
Because
He can't drive him
He can't
He can't increase his phonon
Yeah yeah yeah
Really
OK
Oh
His energy won't be like this
OK
Oh
So interesting
Yeah
This is
This is the details of the experiment
It's in this place
That's right
Why do we
Don't choose ABC
Because this is the best choice
Yeah
I can ask a little bit
That's what you didn't mention
That's the readout part
Is there
OK
Our readout part is
Uh
Our
The real readout in the experiment
Is that we actually
It's just a spin
You see here
The readout is only on this side
We can do it
We
This
Readout b and c
but
Our
The selling point of this experiment is that
We are constant dips
Then we don't need
Measure b and c
But in fact
If you really prepared a state
How do you measure it
You go
You just go straight to drive
This
Read the sideband
Then look at his fit
Just
You just go straight to drive
His sideband
Then look at him
0, 1, 2, 3
This thing can be done directly
But we don't want to do this either
We just want to go straight
Look at the spin
You can see how similar b and c are
This is the goal of our experiment
In fact
In fact, here
Say this
Measurement
That is to say
It's very standard
Uh
This is the same as the general
It's the same as the general
Just
Just use this
State detection
Then
You can use the sideband to see how much he has
Phonon in
In
In each number ratio
Right
Um
Understand
Oh, there's another one
I just mentioned this
So
I said this is 1.2 seconds, right?
But
If you find out
You'll find this
The first one here is how long his gay time is
His whole paten's gay time
The paten here is his
His paten is only half paten
But his face is different
Let's ignore the face now
Don't look
You'll find that he's longer here
It's shorter here
Because we know this
A and B are all good
So A and B
It takes a longer time
He's less likely to happen
There's a problem with A and C
So he
We only gave him half the time
That is
We know we have to
One control
Is running full paten
The other one is running half paten
Then we put
The better one is running full paten
So this part here
It takes 0.8 milliseconds
This is 0.4
So 0.8
Divided by 0.4
0.8 plus 0.4
So 0.8 is here
This is the number
That's right
Does anyone else have any questions?
I think
Like you
Sorry
Ted, please ask
I have a lot of questions
This
You
I'm just going to ask this picture
You just stopped here
He
Stay here
His this
M12345
You
You have a picture later
He is
Is he a coherent state?
In Fonin's
Spectrum
He's a coherent state
This
Here we are
Prepare
Fog
Then let it overlap
But because of our
Fog
I can't prepare well
In a very high Fonin
So
The difference in performance here
It's not our
Control
The difference in performance
It's because we can't
A very good one
Fog
Five
The state is right
OK
So he's not a state preparation
The problem
He is
I see
We did it later
We did all kinds of simulations
What does it include
We found
In
When n is equal to 5
If the state preparation is perfect
Plus all kinds of noise
With all kinds of problems
His Fog
It should be 90%
Even if n is equal to 5
But we see here
In fact, his Fog
It's about 50%
The middle
Most of the problems are in
State preparation
That's right
I see
Thank you
This is where you can do
Overlap
And then this is where you can do
This
Coherent state
That's right
I think the radar map is still
It looks pretty interesting
This radar map
It's actually a circle
That's what we
Every experiment is to draw a circle
And then draw it
The place of the circle
In
It's a beautiful radar map
And then he
That's it
Here
And then
You'll always see
There's a
It's not a beautiful place
This is what we found
That's right
You think you only drive
One direction
Coherent state
It's not
The experiment is not so perfect
He's going in the opposite direction
A little bit of stuff
That's right
So here's a little bit
It looks like that
The dirty stuff is here
That's
That's existence
That's right
And then here
We don't draw radar maps
Because this thing
Its
The form of expression
This is better
So
How did you generate that
That's Omega A and Omega B
Omega AB and Omega
AC
I remember you said
You use Pulse Laser
That's right
You
Pulse Laser, for example, is
After a frequency
How do we operate it
That is, we let it pass through AOM
After you pass through AOM
You can
You can operate the frequency of AOM
It will
It will shift to different places
That's right
That is, we use AOM to
To control the frequency of the laser
That is
The whole laser
It might be
For example, 369.58
Something like that
Assuming this number
Then you want it to become
369.58 plus 380kHz
Then you let your AOM
Have
You just let your AOM shift it
It will
It will shift away
OK
In fact, this
Of course it's a whole
A whole laser thing
But we're talking about it now
It's all
It's all good
It's okay
That's right
Let me confirm it again
This thing is
Your Pulse Laser
How long is it
Three hundred
Three hundred and sixty something
Or 370
It should be 375 times
This number
I'm going to check it out
Because
I remember more
It's 369
Because that is
Static connection will be needed
No, no
That is
We
What do you think
He asked
He may
Jason may be asking you
That Pulse Laser
Pulse Width
How much
Yes, yes, yes, Pulse Width
What is it
You mean
Oh, we're Pico Second
I forgot how many Pico Seconds
OK
You mean
You mean time is right
OK
Yes, yes, yes
We're pretty standard
But I forgot
I forgot how many Pico Seconds
I remember his time scale
It's right there
Uh-huh
Right
I don't really understand this
You are a
Pico Second Laser
Then its bandwidth
There may be
About one nanometer
But your
OK
Atomic Transition
Isn't it all
We are
But we are
Because
This is the feature of Frequency Com
Frequency Com means
You have today
Uh, wait a minute
I'll take a pen
Frequency Com features
You're here today
And then you have a middle
But because you're running out of time
A bunch of
Right
But
The advantage of this experiment is
You don't have to care
Because you use another
You split this laser
So it's
Because it is
So you share it
He's gon na grow up like this
Because it is
Frequency Com
Then two Frequency Com
For example, if I lost one
And this one is
Then this one is
Then this one
You can risk it
So
The point is that
Although it is a pile of
But the point is
His
His relative
Whether it's fixed
It doesn't matter if both of them are on the left side
It's the
His
The point is that
Your
AOM
Shift it to the point
Is it because
Because it is
Equal spacing
That is to say, the middle of it is
You just let the first one
For example, with
We actually let the first one
With the 166th
Will
Resonance
OK
That is
Yes, we actually do it
166 is right
But in fact, you think
The tenth one should be fine
But we choose the 166th
So
In fact, this one
Will be with a very far
Here
So this one
Will be with the first
For example, 165
Resonance
But
Because they are from the same laser
So
If this frequency
When the left shift
The one below will be left shift
It doesn't matter
As long as they are relative
Just lock it
They
It doesn't matter if it shifts
That's right
His
His absolute shift
It doesn't matter
So why do you hear me
I don't seem to remember
His absolute wavelength
His absolute wavelength is about the same
The result you came out today is
Your central frequency today
Is 369
Or 369.5
369.5
Anyway, what he came out of
Is stable
Then
Our focus is on whether I can
His ALM
His two
Relative is not stable
This is more important
Understand
OK
If you don't have any questions for the time being
Thank you first
Then I will finish this video first