Today, we are honored to have Dr. Teng-Ting Yun with us to discuss today's lecture.
Today's topic is Data Crisis in Astronomy, Machine Learning Techniques to Galaxy Studies.
Before we start the lecture, let me introduce Teng-Yun first.
Teng-Yun is now at the Center for Extragalactic Astronomy at Durham University in the UK.
She is an astrophysicist.
She got her bachelor's and master's degree in Taiwan.
Then she went to Nottingham, also in the UK, and got her doctorate.
She got her doctorate last year.
Her main interest is galactic evolution and formation.
She is now focusing on machine learning techniques for galaxy study.
In today's lecture, she will talk about her specialty, machine learning for galaxy study.
She will also talk about her past work.
She will also talk about how machine learning will help galaxy study in the future.
Now, let's welcome Teng-Yun with a round of applause.
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you, Chair, for the warm introduction.
Hello, everyone. Good morning, good afternoon, and good night.
I'm Teng-Yun.
I'm a postdoctoral researcher at Durham University.
I'd like to apologize to everyone first.
I think I'm going to talk a lot in Chinese and English.
Because I can't show my speaker notes.
I usually speak in English.
So my Chinese sometimes gets stuck.
What I'd like to share with you today is about machine learning.
It's becoming more and more popular in astronomy.
This is a research topic for my postdoctoral research.
I'm going to share with you some papers I did in my postdoctoral research.
First of all, let me introduce myself.
What is an astronomer?
Basically, every time I tell everyone that I'm an astronomer,
everyone has a different idea of what an astronomer is.
Most of the time, people will ask me,
Do you know what the meteorite of Saturn is?
Or people will point to a star in the sky and ask me,
Do you know what that star is?
I have to be honest and say I really don't know.
If I tell people I'm a postdoctoral researcher,
my mom will exaggerate and say,
Do you know that my daughter is a professor?
It's not that exaggerated.
Mom, please calm down.
If you are an astronomer or a theoretical astronomer,
the most common thing we do every day is to use a computer.
We're not writing code, we're debugging.
Especially what we do most often is data analysis.
You may be analyzing certain stars.
Or like me, I'm analyzing big data.
I may be analyzing hundreds of thousands or even millions of galaxies at a time.
I'm interested in two directions.
One is information classification,
which is Galaxy Morphological Classification.
The other part is more cosmological.
I do Lama Napa Forest or IGN-CGN.
I don't know what this term means.
Because today I'm going to focus on information classification.
It's relatively straightforward.
This is the most famous information classification system.
It's categorized by human eyes.
It's called Hubble Sequence.
It's a name given by a famous astronomer, Hubble.
Information classification can be divided into many types.
You can classify according to different brightness,
or different degree of evolution,
or even different information structures.
Unfortunately, human eye classification is the most commonly used system in astronomy.
We've been using Hubble Sequence for almost 100 years.
As for big data,
I'm showing you the data from various surveys in recent years.
As you can see from the left side,
the data you can see in the astronomy survey is about 1TB.
In the future, we expect to break through the 1TB scale.
So we find that the data is growing very fast.
Because of computer technology, we can store a lot of data.
But the problem is that in astronomy,
we can't handle such a large amount of data in a traditional way.
We have data, but we can't handle it.
Let me show you the big data.
Since 2005, SDSS has been a very famous large-scale field tracking program.
It has observed about 50 million stars.
But in fact, we've done a lot of analysis,
and we've done a lot of detailed research.
There are only about 1 million stars.
You know that the speed of our analysis is very, very slow.
It's far less than the speed of our data generation.
The most famous program in information classification is Galaxy Zoo.
Galaxy Zoo is a program that invites people from all over the world to do information classification together.
Because you can imagine that information classification is actually a very straightforward thing.
You can look at a star and see if it has a spiral.
Then you can analyze whether it is an elliptical star or a spiral star.
Galaxy Zoo thinks that people from all over the world can do this kind of thing.
So they let the general public participate in this information classification program.
But even if they gather people from all over the world to do this kind of analysis,
they only classified about 900,000 galaxies in about three years.
So you know that if, for example, the data I'm doing right now is DAS data.
The initial data for this part of the data is about 30 trillion galaxies.
The analysis I did in my paper is about 2 trillion galaxies.
So you know that if we want to do it in a traditional way today,
we need to analyze it in a human way.
Even if we do it in the way of Galaxy Zoo,
you may not be able to finish it in your life.
So we need some help at this time.
When we say we are in trouble, I always say I am in trouble.
I can't do this kind of large-scale survey analysis because I have too much data.
At this time, many people will start to seek help from machine learning.
This is my topic today.
Here you can see the recent paper on machine learning in astronomy.
You can see that there has been an exponential growth in the past few years.
More and more papers are doing related things.
I started to read the textbook in 2017.
When I was reading the textbook, I was very impressed.
At that time, basically no one was doing it.
Everyone is just starting to do it.
But after that, I will probably have a new paper every day.
I will see a new paper every day talking about machine learning applications.
Let me talk about it.
In astronomy, I think it's pretty much the same in computer science.
Machine learning applications are roughly divided into supervised, unsupervised, and self-supervised.
Of course, there are other more detailed things.
I won't talk about it for the time being.
This is a more general classification.
I will talk about these three categories later.
So my talk today will be more technical.
If you have any questions that you are not familiar with machine learning, you can ask me right away.
It doesn't matter.
In terms of applications, you can roughly divide it into three different questions.
You can do classification, or you can do regression.
You want to predict a continuous value.
Or you can do data generation.
These are the things that machine learning can help with.
I basically have a list of these three.
But I'm going to focus on the classification problem today.
In terms of its purpose, most of the things we want to do in astronomy are what I just said.
Because we have a lot of data.
But our traditional way of analyzing is far less than dealing with this data.
The biggest problem is that we want to deal with efficiency issues.
A large part of it is related to how we measure quantity.
Machine learning can basically help us improve the accuracy of some measurements.
So the two main purposes of machine learning are to improve efficiency and accuracy.
But today, in addition to these two, I want to talk to you about what else we can do.
What else we can do with machine learning?
You can be more creative when it comes to machine learning.
To sum up what I just said, it's a long start.
I'm going to divide it into two parts today.
The first part is very short.
It's about how to improve efficiency and accuracy.
The second part is about what else you can do.
I'm going to focus on unsupervised machine learning and self-supervised machine learning.
Let's go back to the very beginning, the Hubble sequence.
Let's simplify the problem now.
I don't know what you think of the Hubble sequence.
But I'm going to try to explain it in a way that's not my area of expertise.
So my explanation is going to be a little more shallow.
You can usually divide the Hubble sequence into two categories.
The elliptic sequence and the spiral sequence.
It's very simple to classify them.
There's the concept of a spiral coin.
I don't know if you can see my mouse.
Can you see my mouse?
The spiral coin is very obvious.
It's the shape of a spiral.
As long as there's a spiral coin, we define it as a spiral sequence.
The other is to define it as a elliptic sequence.
So far, you can just say that it's a very straightforward, very simple thing to classify.
So that's why Galaxy Zoo can get the public to help with this.
I'm sorry, can I ask a question?
I'd like to ask a naive question.
Why are all the stars in the galaxy in the shape of a circle?
Is there a possibility that they're in the shape of a triangle?
Yes, there is.
As you can see, they're in the shape of a circle because of the projection.
In fact, every star has a depth.
In terms of elliptical stars, they're basically like a ball.
They're like a ball in a triangular space.
Their light distribution is also the shape of a ball.
But if you look at a spiral star today, it's more like a disk.
So if you project it to 3D today,
the distribution of light will be more like a disk, not a ball.
So this is also in the galaxy.
So my question is, why are some of them in the shape of a disk,
instead of a triangular elliptical shape?
That's a good question.
This question is mainly related to the evolution of stars.
For example, this question is a bit difficult to answer.
But it's mainly related to the evolution of stars.
Our current theory is that
we start with the spiral galaxy.
How do I say it in Mandarin?
Can I speak English?
Yes, you can.
For spiral galaxies, they think that in the beginning,
you will have some gas that accretions into this structure.
It's not like a ball.
It's more like a disk.
It's a flat disk.
It's in the shape of an accretion disk.
It's not like a whole ball.
In our understanding,
the main formation of stars should start from that.
So in our understanding,
the spiral galaxy is formed first.
Gradually, the two galaxies merge together.
After the momentum dissipates,
it slowly forms the shape of a ball.
Because the shape of a ball is more like an accretion disk.
Does this answer your question?
Yes.
It's okay. We can discuss it later.
Okay.
This part is actually quite long.
It's not related to what I talked about today.
The first part is supervised learning.
Let me tell you what supervised learning is.
Supervised machine learning is a very simple concept.
We feed a picture to the machine.
Then we give it a label.
For example, I tell the machine that this is a dog.
Then I tell it that this is a fried chicken.
Then I feed it a lot of pictures.
Pictures of different dogs and fried chickens.
After the machine learns,
it will ask the dog if it is a dog or a fried chicken.
This is the concept of supervised learning.
Supervised learning is a very common concept.
In my 2020 paper,
I studied 10 different supervised machine learning algorithms.
Today I will focus on the Confluential Neural Network.
Let me briefly introduce the Confluential Neural Network
to those who are not familiar with machine learning.
The idea is that we have Confluential Layers
to do feature extraction.
What Confluential Layers is actually doing
is a bit like a filter concept.
It actually wants to capture some features
that can best represent your image.
When you want to produce these labels,
what are the key points?
What are the key points for the machine to make judgments?
Which part of this image is the key point for the machine to make judgments?
In Confluential Layers,
for example, the first layer has 6 channels.
Each channel uses different metrics.
Basically, it's a different filter concept.
You will get 6 different images here.
After passing the filter, you will get 6 different images.
Layer by layer,
the machine will gradually learn
which part of the image is the most important part for you to make judgments.
The machine will gradually learn this.
Let's look at the dog's side.
Here is a concept.
This is a heat map to show which part is really worth paying attention to.
The machine will ask,
where is that part of attention?
If you want to identify which part is worth paying attention to,
the machine will find out which part is worth paying attention to.
The red part is where I need to pay attention to.
Next, they will input these extracted features
to fully connect layers.
After this,
they will connect all the features together
and use the softmax function
to give a probability concept.
For example,
if it's a dog or a cat,
based on this probability,
the machine can give a category.
This is what the Confluential Neural Network is doing.
Now, let's look at the example of a dog and a fried chicken.
In my example,
I input galaxy images.
My image is from dark energy survey.
Based on this image,
I use Galaxy Zoo's visual classification to train my machine.
Basically, I tell my machine,
this galaxy is elliptical,
and this galaxy is spiral.
After the machine learns the concept,
it will ask the machine,
is this new galaxy elliptical or spiral?
In this part of the study,
we get some interesting results.
In the first part,
we found that some galaxies,
CNN is very sure that it is a spiral galaxy.
However,
when we look at Galaxy Zoo's classification,
we found that they think it is elliptical.
Later, we found that
because the depth data has a better resolution
and a deeper depth,
it can observe a deeper scene.
Therefore,
the data used in Galaxy Zoo is better.
You can see that
in the two images I show,
they are all the same depth.
However,
the depth data on the left
clearly shows a spiral arm structure.
However,
the SDSS data on the right is not visible.
Galaxy Zoo is based on SDSS data to do visual classification.
Therefore,
we found that
using our machine learning and depth data,
the most reliable visual classification catalog
needs to be updated.
We found that
about 2.5% of the galaxies are mislabeled
and need to be updated.
After the correction,
we found that
using binary classification,
we can achieve about 99% accuracy.
It's quite impressive.
In some cases,
it is almost more accurate than the human eye,
especially in darker conditions
or higher redshift conditions.
This is the heavy ending.
It sounds like
Galaxy classification using supervised machine learning
seems to be very reliable.
You can achieve 99% accuracy.
There's nothing to worry about.
But not quite yet.
You can probably imagine
that Hubble Sequence is the most commonly used
binary classification system.
Hubble Sequence is the most commonly used binary classification system.
It's based on the human eye.
I don't know how much confidence you have in humans,
but I don't have much confidence.
I think the human eye is very biased.
A lot of research shows that
even if two very professional astronomers
are doing the classification,
their results may not necessarily match.
Especially if the image resolution or image quality has changed,
the two people may have different opinions.
So let's take a look at Hubble Sequence again.
When we did supervised,
it was actually very simple.
We did the elliptical star system and the spiral star system.
But in fact, it's very detailed.
And you don't know why it can be so detailed.
I've been doing galaxy morphology for a long time,
but I still don't really understand
why they can be so detailed.
For example, like the spiral galaxies,
it can be divided into at least three different evolution stages.
A, B, and C.
They are different evolution states.
The elliptical star system is a little bit more understandable.
It's based on different ellipticity
and there are seven different stages.
Then there's another one that's more incomprehensible,
which is the lenticular galaxies.
Lenticular galaxies are a very awkward existence
between the elliptical star system and the spiral star system.
And it doesn't have spiral arms.
It's basically obvious that it doesn't have spiral arms.
But sometimes it might be because of the resolution.
But it's more like a spiral galaxy in terms of structure.
So we think that
the current theory is that it's in the middle.
Maybe it's a transition period.
We also have another one called spiral bar galaxies.
It's in the middle.
There's a bar in the center of the star system.
This is called a bar galaxy.
And of course, there's the rest.
We really can't classify it.
It's called irregular galaxies.
It looks weird.
Then let's talk about the classification.
I don't know if you can...
I don't think you can leave a comment,
so you can turn on the microphone and say it.
Let's test it.
Can you tell which one is a spiral galaxy?
Actually, you can turn on the microphone and say it.
But you can also leave a comment.
If you want to vote to count it,
you can type it right next to it.
I don't think you can see the comments.
I can...
Because you're sharing the screen now.
But I can help you see it.
Someone said 3.
I'll type 4.
Someone said 4.
Now 1 also has one vote.
3. 3 also has one vote.
So 3 has two votes now.
4 has two votes now.
1 has one vote now.
2 is very popular.
There's no 2.
There's 1 and 3.
Yeah, that's about it.
Okay.
The answer to this question is 3.
3 is an early spiral galaxy.
It's a relatively early one.
You just saw the SA part.
This question is relatively simple.
Let's move on to the next question.
Which one is an elliptical galaxy?
Okay.
YT, do you want to answer the previous question or this one?
I think it's an elliptical galaxy.
Oh, okay.
So from Ethan...
Sorry, it's not Ethan.
What is it?
Alpha.
Okay, start.
It's 4.
Then I'm going to answer...
I don't know. 2?
I don't know.
Okay.
4 and 2.
It's probably 2.
2 has one vote.
Okay.
I have the same answer as YT.
I'm very confident now.
And Wicca also answered 2.
YT is an expert.
Okay.
Then we're going to announce the answer.
None of them is an elliptical galaxy.
Oh.
Yes.
Everyone can...
In fact, everyone can give a concept.
Here, 1 and 2 and 4.
You think it feels like an elliptical galaxy.
They are actually all elliptical galaxies.
So you can probably feel that
human judgment is actually a very, very inaccurate way.
Give everyone a feeling.
Okay.
So this is my other research.
I'm also doing this part more often.
I'm more interested in this part.
Excuse me, can I ask a question?
Yes.
In those questions just now,
maybe I missed something just now.
How do you know what the correct answer is?
My correct answer is...
This is a good question.
So our correct answer is actually based on another astronomer.
Just the other two astronomers.
At present, it is what we think is the most accurate judgment.
Go up and give the correct answer.
But in fact, they may be wrong.
So...
Yes.
According to you, there may be...
This is actually...
Maybe 2 is really an elliptical galaxy.
We are not sure.
But according to his answer,
We think he is the correct answer.
OK, I see.
Thank you.
Yes.
1 and 2 are both a little bit tricky.
I would say it's a little bit tricky.
2, I might be more inclined to say it's an elliptical galaxy.
But...
It's just that it's really tricky to judge.
Then I actually mainly want to express a concept that is...
The decision boundary of this judgment is actually not that accurate.
And this is why I want to go...
Uh...
Start my second part of the research.
What about this part of the research?
I...
In fact, I just want to answer this question.
That is, if...
If a machine can comprehensively see all galaxies,
How would he categorize them?
The basic idea is that I hope to use machine classification to replace the classification of human eyes.
Because now our galaxy morphology is basically based on this Hubble sequence.
This Hubble sequence has been used for more than 100 years.
It's not more than 100 years.
It's almost 100 years.
So...
It is a good time for them to change.
To revolutionize an idea.
So...
There are two parts of this problem that you have to deal with.
One is how to make the machine comprehensively see.
The second part is how to do the categorization.
What about the first part?
I...
Uh...
I thought of...
Of course there are many different approaches.
Because in fact, apart from me,
There is another team doing it.
So...
Before I wrote this paper,
In fact, there are two other papers.
Of course, the methods we use are different.
What I choose to use here is Autoencoder.
I'm not sure if you're familiar with Autoencoder.
Autoencoder itself is a self-supervised machine learning algorithm.
So...
Self-supervised means that its input and output are actually the same data.
When you're in the training machine,
Your input and output are exactly the same thing.
The idea is to say...
Uh...
When you, for example, like this image today.
You input an image.
That goes through the convolutional layers.
You try to extract some features.
And then you can represent this input image.
And then you use these extracted latent features.
And then you want to rebuild your image.
Become your output.
Ideally, your output and your input should be better and better.
If it's well rebuilt,
That means your latent features have caught the point.
That's one of the reasons I use Autoencoder.
And then use it to do feature extraction.
Find some better features.
Next, unsupervised machine learning.
It's a representation of this picture.
It's simple.
We don't tell the machine what these images are.
We don't tell it what a dog is.
We don't tell it what a fried chicken is.
We just give it this picture.
And then you say, hey, you sort it out.
Sort it out.
So, uh, it's very obvious that you can see a little bit.
Uh, because we didn't give him any prior knowledge.
So, in fact, unsupervised machine learning often encounters a situation.
Uh, machine sorting.
We human scientists want to do is completely different.
It's just that it doesn't match at all.
So, how do you make it comprehensive?
The idea of ​​comprehension is that the concept of human beings can be more integrated.
It's more related to the science we want to do.
It's going to be a big problem.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Can I ask a more naive question?
That is to say, when you are in these pictures,
You are.
Will he do it, for example, like CNB?
Make it a fully transformed map to a post.
On the bed.
And then do it again.
Or just do it directly.
Directly to him.
Uh, for example, the mass distribution of Gauss.
And then do the analysis directly.
Do it directly and apply it to the machine learning model.
Inside.
Uh, we're just using images directly.
We don't even do the mass distribution part.
If it's an image.
Because we're doing Gauss morphology.
So, in fact, our focus is only on that.
It's like doing an analysis when you look at it with the naked eye.
We just look at the image itself.
So, I hope that the machine will capture the image.
That's it.
Oh, then I want to ask another question.
Because he might be because of your image.
For example, you might have some white noise or red noise or something.
So why not?
For example, like CNB, they also have very strong white noise.
So why don't you know?
Maybe someone did that.
The question is, would you do one?
For example, do a mapping.
Map it to another one.
A different one.
Uh, for example.
Maybe it would be better to do an analysis.
Because.
Because it's like a picture of a dog or a picture of a fried chicken.
Their white noise is also very strong.
For example, the fried chicken powder on the fried chicken.
It's a white noise.
It will affect your analysis.
So if you just do an analysis of this image, it will be more difficult.
And then it's not just doing this.
For example, it would be better.
Would anyone do that?
Uh, I haven't heard of it.
But, uh, you mentioned a pretty important point.
We actually have preprocessing.
Just get rid of the noise first.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, so getting rid of the noise is actually a pretty important step.
So all of our images have been preprocessed first.
And of course, sometimes.
Uh, for example, I just mentioned the supervised part.
I even use gradient image.
It's not just a pure linear image.
There's a lot of preprocessing processes that need to be done first.
Got it.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Okay, so, uh.
Uh, this left picture is my main pipeline.
Uh, using the pipeline.
What about the feature learning process?
I'm actually using a special autoencoder.
And then it's called VectorQuantizedBiorectionalAutoencoder.
And it's Google Demind.
It's an algorithm that was made a few years ago.
So the idea is, why use this?
In fact, it has a big advantage.
Uh, vector quantization.
It can speed up the entire feature learning process.
Because if there's no vector quantization.
Uh, this process.
Uh, my previous research was that I used a general autoencoder.
Convolutional autoencoder.
So it's in, uh, feature learning.
It's about 100,000 images.
And in the case of using GPU.
It takes about four to five days.
But, uh.
The use is VectorQuantizedBiorectionalAutoencoder.
It basically only takes a few hours.
So you can find this.
It's a very big leap.
So, uh, that's why I'm using this part of the reason.
So, uh, the process of speeding up this feature learning.
For the future, if I want to go further.
Uh, extend this research to make it.
Adapt to survey data.
It would also be more helpful.
Because the survey data itself is already very, very huge.
So if it's 100,000, it's going to take four to five days.
Then I might not be able to finish it.
And then, uh, after feature learning.
So now it's every image.
You can, uh.
Every image is represented by a set of.
Extracted features.
That's what you just said.
Lantern features.
So we're going to use this lantern feature.
To do unsupervised machine learning.
So we're going to, uh, we're going to use hierarchical clustering for this part.
So the concept of hierarchical clustering is actually quite simple.
It's every image.
Uh, at the beginning, every image is a group.
So we're just going to merge it little by little.
Uh, according to the similarity of your, uh, lantern feature.
The similarity of the row combination.
To gradually merge them.
So the advantage of using this algorithm is, uh.
A lot of, uh, machine learning clustering algorithm.
He actually needs you to guess.
Is to give a data distribution first.
For example, Gaussian distribution.
Yeah, you might need to guess in advance.
Or know in advance what some of this data is like.
How is it distributed in the feature space?
But hierarchical clustering doesn't have to do that.
So relatively speaking, there is no bias.
And then in this study, we are.
Oh, my God, I'm running out of time.
In this study, there are three very important strategies that we have proposed.
So this part is to make our eyes, uh, to make my, uh, classification skin.
It's more.
Uh, it's more sensible.
So the first part is, uh.
When we're doing feature learning.
After that, we thought about a quick clustering result.
What about this quick clustering?
We're going to divide it into two groups.
What about the idea?
Why do you do that?
The idea is to say, uh, we want us to extract it.
Features.
He can not only rebuild your input image.
At the same time, you want to capture some features.
It can be well divided into two groups on the feature space.
Groups like this, two groups.
So, uh.
What about this approach?
It's quite effective, which is to stabilize our whole algorithm.
To divide the initial two groups.
The idea is like this.
This is a simple result.
Uh, after this.
Uh.
After this design.
Uh, we're always in.
If we force our class to be divided into two groups.
What about the time?
We always get one.
It's the last feature group and the feature group.
Uh, this part is relatively easy to understand.
Because you know, they're on the back of the virus.
It's just.
How, how different you are.
So there should be less feature group and feature group.
But, uh.
After we've designed this, we've added an extra classroom.
What about the process of feature learning?
Our last feature group and feature group.
They, uh.
Visual class.
Uh.
Visual morphology.
Percentage is different.
Uh.
That's not easy to say.
Um.
It's just a different type of human eye.
The ratio in these less feature groups or feature groups.
Is stable.
And that's a pretty important thing.
Because if you don't add this classroom process.
Then he.
He might still be like this.
But there's a difference in proportion.
Then you'll find that, oh, this whole machine, it's actually.
You know, it's kind of like that.
But he's actually not very stable.
So, uh.
Involve this strategy becomes very important.
What about the second point?
Uh.
You can find the code on the line.
It's basically allowed a single cut.
Single cut means that I'm on this picture.
It's a bad one.
Horizontal straight line.
Uh.
This straight line is the class.
It's just.
It's just telling you, oh, this is my top.
So, uh.
You figure out how many clusters are how many clusters.
But there's a big problem with that.
Especially on the gas.
It's a big problem.
Uh.
That is to say, um.
If you're in.
For example.
Galaxies.
You can imagine that.
It's just that they're actually extracted.
It's not going to be much different.
It's easy to imagine because it's actually the same thing.
It looks like it's on the ground.
In fact, it doesn't look much different.
Of course, it's not going to go anywhere.
But it's not the same.
It's just that his appearance can change a lot.
For example, your spiral is in a different position.
Ah, or your spiral is closer to you.
Or is it far from you?
The whole thing is going to be a lot worse.
But they're all called Spiral Galaxy.
So, if you're only allowed to be single, you're going to have a situation.
It's you.
Your less feature group has too many unnecessary.
Uh, clusters.
But your.
Feature group may not be enough.
It's your.
Uh.
Group may not be enough.
So.
So, uh, at this point, we're going to, uh, in this study, we're going to allow it to have different.
Uh, on each line, in different branches, in this merger tree, we allow different distances.
So.
The next obvious question is where to cut.
So, where are we going to make that line?
So, here, I'm going to jump out and talk about a very important question.
It's when you're doing unsupervised machine learning.
And when you're doing gap, uh, when you're doing this research, a very basic question, a fundamental question is how many classes.
We should have.
And this is actually a question of how many classes you're going to have.
And this question is actually a tricky question in every unsupervised machine learning.
Uh, ideally, of course, you can have as many as you want.
But there's always going to be a point where you're going to find that, uh, it doesn't make any sense at all.
If you divide too much.
And I just mentioned that, uh, before I did, there were actually two other.
Paper is related to this.
So, they're in the galaxy morphology classification that they came up with.
It's about, uh, let's talk about it.
Harbour is probably divided.
You're strictly, uh.
Strictly speaking, you can say that it's divided into eight categories.
What about the paper before that?
They divided it into about 160 classifications.
So, you know, it's, uh, 160.
It's not that you can't, but you're analyzing it.
On the scientific research, you'll find that, uh, it doesn't seem to be able to find some.
Uh, similarity or do some, uh, conclude something.
So, how many classes have become very important?
Uh, what kind of numbers are correct?
What about here?
It's us.
Uh, we chose to use a very different way from the previous research.
So, our way is that we want to use, uh, the variation of gas orientation.
So, what does that mean?
Basically, you're going to find that some galaxies, especially spiral galaxies.
They actually look pretty much the same.
But they just seem to be turning an angle.
So, this kind of galaxy is what you're going to do if you're using auto-encoder.
They're just turning an angle.
But because, uh, auto-encoder is going to keep them, uh, it's going to be completely different.
So, auto-encoder.
Uh, after auto-encoder, when you're using classroom, they're going to be divided into different groups.
So, that's not the result we want.
Because if they look pretty much the same, of course, we want them to be in the same group.
So, the idea is that, uh, there's always going to be a point on your merger tree.
Because they're all based on, uh, similarity.
So, at some point, you'll find that there's a cluster.
The reason it's because of this gas orientation.
So, if we can find out where this happened.
To calculate what is distance of this gas orientation.
So, we can use this to do a distance cut.
So, this way, we can solve our first problem.
Where to cut?
So, this gas orientation can provide the place where to cut in each different branch.
And then, it can also solve a very important problem.
How many branches do we want?
So, it can provide a number of classification that doesn't behave gas orientation.
So, the final result is to give us 27 clusters.
So, this number is definitely much more reasonable than 160.
It's a little biased, in my opinion.
But I think most astronomers will agree with me.
So, 27 should be more reasonable than 160 in gas morphology.
So, I'm not going to talk too much about the details.
But we have found that they are basically based on the gas structure and gas shape.
And then there's this kind of classification.
So, this picture is a little bit more difficult to explain.
But the general concept is that we each.
So, a bar here is a group.
So, you can see that there are two groups here.
And then there are three groups here.
This is a machine-classified group.
So, the general concept here is to say.
A galaxy with a similar structure.
So, they are structurally very similar structures.
Because they are divided into the same group.
It means that they are structurally very similar.
They can be visually classified as multiple different morphology.
For example, here is the galaxy in this group.
It can be judged by your eyes.
They will be classified into either elliptical galaxies or lenticular galaxies.
So, what about the different blue parts here?
There are different fractions of bar galaxies.
The darker it is, it means that there are more bar galaxies in it.
So, we're going to show you an example today.
So, for example, in this group, there are no significant bar galaxies, bar features.
And then this is a relatively weak bar feature.
And then there's a group that has a relatively strong bar feature.
And then there's another point.
You'll find that it's pretty important.
You'll find that it's visual classification.
Like I just mentioned, galaxies with similar structures can be visually classified as multiple different galaxy morphology.
Especially, for example, lenticular galaxies.
We just mentioned that lenticular galaxies are a very awkward existence.
It's between elliptical galaxies and elliptical galaxies.
So, we're going to do some analysis of lenticular galaxies in a group.
We're going to use the search index.
Basically, the smaller the number, the more likely it is to be this galaxy.
And then we mean it's more likely to be a spiral galaxy.
The larger the number, the more likely it is to be a bulge galaxy.
And then there's the elliptical galaxy.
We found that the blue one is group 27.
It's a mix of lenticular galaxies and early spirals.
The red one is a mix of elliptical galaxies and lenticular galaxies.
Only the yellow one is really full of lenticular galaxies.
So, you can see that in terms of structure, only very moderate structures can be called lenticular galaxies.
Most of the time, the judgment of the naked eye is that lenticular galaxies are actually all mixed up with early spirals and elliptical galaxies.
It's not that easy to tell the structure apart.
So, in the end, we're going to take the 27 clusters that we've divided up and we're going to do some physical comparison.
So, you can see that we have color, absolute magnitude, standard mass, and size, physical size.
So, you can see that there's a slight difference between each of our clusters.
It's a slight difference, but it's obvious.
It's an obvious change.
It's a gradual change.
So, here are two plots.
Basically, these two plots are the plots that we use a lot in our information analysis.
It's a color magnitude diagram and a mass size diagram.
The star part is visual classification.
We're going to do a comparison over there.
You can see that our 27 clusters are actually well distributed between different visual morphology.
It means that if you use this machine classification method, you might be able to find some missing morphology.
It actually needs to be identified.
But in visual classification, it's not that obvious.
It's just that the eyes can't be so sensitive to find out that there's actually a difference like this.
So, basically, this is the end of my talk.
We still have some continued follow-up plans for this part of the research.
My main goal is to use machine learning to build an unbiased and reproducible machine classification scheme.
It can be used by different people and different surfaces.
It can even be applied to different redshifts.
This is a pretty ambitious project.
But I think this is a way to revolutionize what we know in current gas morphology.
Because we're now relying too much on visual classification.
I think the main thing I want to share with you today is that machine learning is a growing area.
And in the astronomy world, we're mostly still focused on accuracy and efficiency.
But in fact, machine learning has more potential to be explored.
For example, here, we use machine learning to think of ways to change our concepts of astronomy.
I hope it can change some of the concepts we have about astronomy.
That's about it. Thank you.
Please turn on the microphone.
Let's give a warm round of applause to Tim for his wonderful presentation.
Let's start the Q&A.
But before we start, I'd like to ask a few questions for those of you who are in the chat.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
The first question is, which of the algorithms is better?
I think this question is a little too general.
So if you want to clarify, you can just open the microphone and say it.
If not, we'll just ask Tim to answer.
Like I said, this is a little too general.
I think it depends on your science topic.
But in terms of the last part of my presentation,
in terms of my classification scheme,
I think the algorithms I'm using are the best combination of all the algorithms I've used so far.
Because I think auto-encoder is probably the best explanation for this question.
Some people used self-organized maps in their previous research.
It's also a way to unsupervised machine learning.
But I don't think it's as effective as auto-encoder.
A lot of people want to de-rotate the galaxy orientation first.
De-rotate the galaxy so that it's all facing the same direction.
That's another algorithm.
It's also a form of auto-encoder, but it's a concept of de-rotation.
So there are actually a lot of different algorithms that can be used.
But I think the simplest is the best.
At the moment, I think this pipeline is the best combination I can think of.
Otherwise, I wouldn't use it.
I hope that answers your question.
We can chat later if there are any further comments.
We have another question.
The next question is from Altha and Herman.
They want to know if you can briefly introduce your other project, Lyman-Alpha-Forest-IgM.
Sure.
I still use supervised machine learning.
I use a convolutional network.
I have some Quasar spectra.
I try to identify Lyman-Alpha-Forest using a convolutional network.
I also predict some physical properties like current density, Doppler width, and the rate shift of these systems.
I'm currently writing a paper.
This machine has already been developed.
We use this machine.
It's a chain with mock spectra.
But it can also predict values for observation spectra.
So we're going to provide this machine with the highest data.
It's a very high resolution from Keck Observatory.
So we're going to use this part and build a catalog.
So this is another catalog paper we're writing right now.
Based on this catalog...
Because we have a lot of...
In Lyman-Alpha-Forest, there was a 2012 catalog.
So you know, it's a long time ago.
The author spent three years to analyze 15 spectra.
Now our CNN can reach the same accuracy as him.
But we only need five minutes to analyze a Quasar spectra.
So now we have a lot of data.
Because the highest data actually has hundreds of spectra.
But he could only analyze 15 at the time.
So based on this catalog, we're going to do some IGN or IGN transitional to CGM research.
Okay, I hope that's the answer.
If you want to ask further, you can continue to ask.
Then I personally have a question.
My question is this.
In addition to using your algorithm to directly put it on the real data.
Have you ever tried to put this on?
You know his underlying physics assumption simulation.
And then see what happens.
For example, the mass of dark matter is very heavy galaxy.
Will it all fall into one of your classification?
Or will dark metal fall into one of them?
That is, so you can understand that these classes.
Uh, what is the underlying physics?
Have you ever thought about doing that?
Uh, uh, actually, this is one of the projects I'm doing right now.
The direction is a little different.
Because that's what you're talking about.
It's the next step I want to do.
What we're doing right now is we're using simulations.
And then we apply this classification scheme.
And then we look at the different classifications.
Uh, different classifications.
Then he, we respect his history.
To see, to see if he has a single history.
Basically, we want to know that our classification scheme is not.
Visual classification is more physically meaningful.
That's what I'm doing right now with the simulation.
Because this part is more important.
We have to make sure that our classification can be.
Uh.
The next step is what you just mentioned.
We would like to be able to, if this part of us is confirmed.
After this part is strengthened, the next step we will want to know.
What kind of physics will influence us to form this kind of gas morphology?
Whether it's from the simulation or from the observation.
This part is going to be very interesting.
Because if we look at it from the simulation, we can see it directly.
Uh, you can see that, uh, you can understand it directly.
Study that today's gas morphology is.
According to what kind of physics process to form.
So, from the observation, you can build something like a family tree.
Of a galaxy.
This idea, or you can add you.
We have a lot of different terms, which is used to define gas.
For example, like slow rotator, or.
Uh.
Red, red, red nuggets, blue nuggets, etc.
They may actually just be because of their.
Formation history is different.
Then we hope that the machine gives a more detailed.
Classification can help to explain such a question.
Thank you.
Okay, so do you have any questions?
Uh, okay.
Can I ask a question?
Um, so I actually have two questions.
And then the first question is.
You just said that orientation.
That is, there is.
What algorithm you can look at a galaxy map and then you can know what its orientation should be.
So you can.
Just put it back in the direction you want.
And then the other question is.
Uh, you, you use the data, we use it, is the data of the multi-colour.
Go down and turn together.
Because it's just the same as the galaxy.
It should be a very strong correlation.
It feels like there's more information to use.
Uh, the first part of the question.
It's actually just the rotation.
It's a very, very difficult problem.
Simply put, you can think about it.
That's where your reference point is.
So how do you know that you're going to measure first?
Uh, where to see the orientation direction is a question mark.
And then there's your reference point.
Where is it?
So, of course, there are people in this part.
You can do it because you can actually define where it is.
You can actually define where it is.
Where is it?
Then you might use it.
It's to define where the direction of the rotation is.
You can probably do that, but.
Overall, it's just that he's still a little tricky.
So this part has always been in our.
Because there were two different studies before.
So this part is.
A lot of people want to deal with this.
But we're doing this research today.
We're doing this part of the research.
Think about it in a different direction.
He might not be a problem.
He might be able to help us make more effective decisions.
In the end, how many classes do we need to produce?
So far, he's not an ideal.
Ideal solution.
But, um.
It's him.
Anyway, the concept of this paper is.
A different way to solve the problem.
You don't have to think of it as a.
You have to solve it.
You have to have a low rotation.
You can think of it as a.
Just let you decide.
Oh, how many classes are we?
We are the most reasonable.
Is that a solution to your question?
Yeah, I get it.
Thank you.
The second part.
The second part of the question is.
The second part is.
Do you use it?
Oh.
Yeah, that's part of it.
What I'm doing right now.
Because when I was doing this project.
I'm a Ph.D. student.
I basically don't have that much.
Uh, memory or space.
You can put so much data.
So I only used it at that time.
Okay, go ahead.
Yeah.
This is a problem that is not enough.
But it is in this part.
Uh.
Multi-color is a very important point.
But multi-color processing.
He has another question.
We have encountered it so far.
Just be very careful.
One thing is.
Indeed.
Galaxy morphology is related to color.
But he is not.
Uh.
Not completely.
You know.
How to say.
To say that.
We know.
Most of.
They are passive.
They are red.
But.
There will be an exception.
The so-called exception is.
We have red.
Uh.
If you go.
That's what we're thinking about today.
To say.
Do you want to use multi-color or single color?
Because single color can actually.
Purely let you focus on the galaxy morphology.
Then you.
You can know.
If today.
Maybe there are some things.
He has some galaxy.
He's actually a tree.
But he is.
This kind of.
You.
Just look at his galaxy morphology.
You have to be accurate.
But if you involve those colors today.
Information.
Then.
You might be.
Plus.
It's in there.
It's just that you might make us feel like.
Oh.
He has to be divided like this.
So this part.
It's actually a bit tricky to deal with.
So we're still dealing with it.
What the hell.
The second part of the data.
Yeah.
I see.
Thank you.
Do you have any questions?
Oh, if you don't have any questions.
Let's give it up again.
Applause.
Thank you.
We'll have another great speech.