Hello everyone, thank you all for participating in this speech from different cities around the world.
Thank you very much for the detailed introduction just now.
What I want to introduce today is what I want to talk about my research and what I did in the past.
Then there are one or two slides to bring a little bit about how I plan to do this topic in the future.
For the overview part, I will try to use the Chinese slides and the Chinese way to do the speech.
For the more detailed research part, I will try to speak in Chinese, but I will use English slides.
Because I'm not so confident in Chinese translation.
But I will try to introduce it to you in Chinese.
I also know that the background of the speakers and the audience is not the same.
So if you have any questions, you are welcome to interrupt me.
Then we can go back and forth once or twice.
If you find that there are still some problems that cannot be solved, then we can do some more in-depth discussions at the end.
What I want to discuss today is the impact of mechanics on the instability of dyeing.
Especially when looking at this problem from the perspective of cell division.
We know that we learn a lot of loss division from high school and high school biology.
Loss division usually means that when a cell produces a tissue, both sides of the cell will have the same number of dyes.
Let me quickly go through the process of loss division.
In the process of cell division, the dye will become this shape.
It's a bit like a sausage.
If you fix it in the way of dyeing and look at it with a microscope, you will find that it looks a bit like two sausages.
In the process, the membrane will begin to decompose.
In the process of decomposition, the dye will begin to form the so-called epithelium.
This epithelium will try to form the shape of this epithelium.
In the process, the dye will interact with the epithelium.
The dye will be brought to the center by the epithelium.
Let's call it neutralization.
There is a very important component called the connective core.
Connective core means that the dye will react with the epithelium at this point.
When the dye is well arranged in the middle, the cells will enter the so-called anaphase.
At this time, the dye will be divided into two sides.
This process is actually very difficult.
Many people are discussing why this process can be so perfect.
There are two things that I must highlight.
The so-called spindle assembly checkpoint.
This checkpoint is a checkpoint signal.
When the dye is not connected to the spindle, the checkpoint will be turned on.
When this signal is turned on, the cells will not be able to go down.
This is the concept of a checkerboard.
If the checkerboard finds that the system is a little problematic, it will try not to let this happen.
There is another system called error correction.
Let's call it the error correction mechanism.
This error correction mechanism is that when it finds that the dye is not arranged like this,
There is a set of error correction mechanisms in our cells that try to arrange it correctly.
In this way, when it enters the process of cell division, there will be no errors.
But in fact, there are many times when there are so-called errors.
Let's call it abnormal division.
In the process of abnormal division, the dye will be unstable.
Let me give you an example.
I have two sets of dyes here.
I color-coded them.
You can see that these two sets of dyes are all connected to the same side.
The other side is not connected.
So you can imagine this process.
If it passes through the post-division and then divides into two cells,
The dye of the two cells will have different numbers.
We call it aneuploidy in English.
Let me check it out.
It's called aneuploidy.
It's quite strange.
This is a problem.
There are some problems with aneuploidy.
For example, if the number of dyes is increasing, it may be able to express more things.
If there is one more or one less dye,
Is there no way for some proteins to increase or decrease?
This will cause some problems.
In recent years, some people have been discussing this problem.
This is the so-called homeostasis problem.
Another problem is that the dye is labeled in red.
In fact, this problem is more serious.
In this case, this aneuploidy will connect two different cells.
By the way, this aneuploidy is not only one-to-one.
Because there are hundreds of proteins on the aneuploidy.
It also has dozens of proteins that can interact with the aneuploid.
So some aneuploid proteins may be connected to the aneuploid on the other side.
Some will be connected to the aneuploid on the left.
If this aneuploid is connected to this red situation,
In the process of separation, you can imagine that
Because the aneuploid usually has a pull force to pull the two aneuploids apart.
If this red one is not eliminated,
In other words, if the error correction is not done well,
Then this red aneuploid can't run normally to this group.
Then it is incorporated into a homo.
So at this time we call it a lagging chromosome.
Because it runs slower.
What's special about this lagging chromosome?
In fact, many people have been studying this problem in the past ten years.
Because this lagging chromosome can't get into the main homo.
So the cells will automatically produce a small homo around it.
We call it a micronucleotide.
If you really look at some of its biochemical properties,
Or the properties of cell biology,
You will find that it is very different from the original homo.
It has a lot of holes.
It has a lot of holes, which means that many enzymes in many cells
Or these messages can run into this homo.
Then go to decompose this protein.
This is actually a very typical immune response in our cells.
If we encounter this problem, we can find a way to...
You know, our cells may have some...
Because usually if you look at the cell membrane,
If you see some double-stranded DNA in the cell tissue,
Then we all think that it may be a virus.
So some of our cells will have some reactions,
Will try to cut these abnormal double-stranded DNA.
So in theory, this cell will be cleared.
But if this cell survives,
Those cut off oxidants may be regrouped.
Then there will be a lot of mutations.
So the people in this field feel that
If this cell survives, there will be serious mutations.
Is the cancer cell going to use this method to increase its genetic diversity?
This is a big topic in the field at present.
Okay, let me talk about some of the classic problems of cell division.
First, how does the instability of the cancer cell affect the occurrence of cancer?
I said last time that
The instability of the cancer cell can make some cancer cells regroup.
It can promote the genetic diversity of tumor cells.
It sounds like the instability of the cancer cell is good.
But we found out again that it's not us.
The research field found that
If your cancer cell is too unstable,
It will lead to some signal of cell division.
The cancer cell can't increase its genetic diversity.
Because it's all dead.
So there are some ideas in this field.
Is there a so-called Achilles heel?
It's the heel of Achilles.
Cancer cells can use CIN to increase its genetic diversity.
But if you give it too much CIN,
Cancer cells are not so happy.
Does this tell us some
Potential therapeutic strategies?
If we can make the entire baseline
If the cancer cell becomes very unstable,
Is there a chance to find a way to kill this cancer?
Give a very typical example.
For example, we now know that the acupuncture point is a chemotherapy drug.
Acupuncture point
Cells may feel that
It may cause these so-called
A bunch of
The problem of cancer cell division
So there will be some instability of the cancer cell.
Of course, this is the current idea of ​​the cellist.
So true or false
There are still a lot of hypotheses to verify.
But I'm probably talking to you today.
The idea is probably like this.
The second question is
How do cancer cells produce unstable cancer cells?
If you look at the ACS or AAC website,
You will find that those cancer cells
Or tumor cells, that is, oncogenes and tumor suppressor genes
In fact, it seems that they are mainly not in the process of cell division.
If it is not in the process of cell division,
How does it cause cell division?
This is very paradoxical.
So our idea is
Will there be other ways besides genes?
Will it lead to the instability of the cancer cell?
After my doctor,
What I'm doing next
Mainly discussing
Does chemistry affect the instability of the cancer cell?
If you have any questions, you can interrupt me at any time.
First give an overview
There will be a lot of changes in chemistry during the tumor.
I have listed four possible points of change here.
I can't talk too much because this is what I'm doing.
But I will try to connect what I used to do.
For example, in the process of cancer cells,
In fact, it is with its neighbor,
The force of contact with the cell next to it will begin to decrease.
Then, the tumor will begin to accumulate some so-called cells near it.
So the tumor will begin to mutate.
Then, in the process of cell division,
This cell will also begin to mutate.
There are three obvious chemical changes in the process of tumor development.
In addition, for example, like the liver cell.
Let's change the system a little bit.
In addition to the process of tumor development,
In addition to the mutation of cells,
Sometimes a lot of liver cells accumulate some fat.
This fat is obvious.
For example, in the process of fatty liver,
The liver will accumulate some fat.
Then we want to say,
For example, some so-called changes in the nature of cells,
Will it cause some changes in the chemistry of the entire cell?
And thus cause an unstable cancer cell.
How do I think about this problem?
I use this New York magazine cover as a comparison.
We know that cell division,
I just talked about a lot of processes that are related to the body.
How do we think about this problem?
Because we study cell division.
Our perspective is the same as this New Yorker.
This is New York 40 years ago,
New York 45 years ago.
The New Yorker's idea is like this.
I live in the egg yolk area.
Many buildings near the egg yolk area,
Many sell some desserts,
Of course I know.
After a while,
Maybe it's a little bit of a little bit of a place.
Then go a little further,
Passing the Hudson River,
I don't seem to care about other places in the United States.
Especially after the Pacific Ocean,
There are still many strange countries.
It has nothing to do with my life.
I'm not talking about New York.
I mean,
Our cell biology is also like this.
I am now studying the process of cell division.
Of course I care about the oxidant.
It's related to the oxidant.
For example, the point of interference,
Those things.
It may be very important.
I may know him a little bit.
This spindle pole seems to be a little bit important.
It's a little bit less important.
Then I...
Okay, let's take a look at it.
Like Cortex,
Extracellular Matrix,
Far away,
Maybe I don't have to look at it at all.
At least in the past few years,
Everyone is not so serious about this thing.
One of the reasons is because it's too far away.
Another point is because this system is in
Ah, the area below this area is already complicated enough.
You have to add these things.
Maybe this system can't go either.
Ah, you can't get one either.
Some conclusions.
But now the technology has advanced.
I'm starting to know that
In fact, the
That's what I'm going to talk about next.
In order to make this
Cellular matrix,
What about the matrix?
Hey, I especially want to focus on this so-called
Because there are a lot of proteins on the spindle itself.
Spindle itself will also produce force.
So we want to say,
Hey, if there's a force here,
Will it be a very interesting and efficient system?
Can let
Do some communication between the cells and the cells.
As a result, it affects the split of the protein.
Okay, now I'm going to start talking.
I'm really studying the subject.
Ah, start with the English title.
So I want to introduce the so-called
Ah.
The intersection point.
Between the two intersections.
In fact, there is a so-called tension between it.
What about this tension?
We call it Interconnection Tension.
It is a very important signal.
What about this signal?
Ah, you can tell the cells.
Hey, is this dyeing body correct?
Align.
Or is it aligned?
Is it aligned with a block?
So,
Ah,
Cells,
So,
You can imagine it as a dyeing body.
It's a kind of spring.
There is a kind of spring between the two.
Between these two intersections.
That's because the matrix is pulling it.
So if it's lined up very well,
It will pull more.
What if it's him?
If it's not lined up,
That's because he.
For example, like this one.
The matrix is all on the same side.
Then he might be on both sides.
It will be closer.
What about this one that is closer to the distance?
Hey, or is this force bigger?
Or is it smaller?
You can tell us the cells.
Hey, is this dyeing body the correct arrangement?
Or is it a wrong arrangement?
Ah, this is from the cells.
Know that this is right.
This is wrong.
What about it?
Then he will use a system.
Ah, there are actually many systems.
But the main system is the so-called Aurora B.
Kines.
This system.
What about Kines?
Kines is a phosphatidylmethane.
That is, it can be added to the protein.
Phosphatidylmethane.
What about this?
If you add phosphatidylmethane to it,
Hey, you'll find that this is the point.
The interaction between that matrix seems to be weak.
So the idea.
So the whole.
Ah, the so-called spirit of the error correction.
It's like this.
That is to say.
Hey, this place is wrong.
Then I'll try to get it out.
After that?
This dye system can be rearranged again.
Ah, if there is still a problem.
Let's do it again.
That until the whole system is well arranged.
After that, the cells can say.
Hey, let's keep going.
Okay, that's the so-called regulation.
Let's just call it upstream regulation model.
That is.
Li Li?
Become a upstream control mechanism.
Tell the cells that this place should be corrected.
This place may be good.
Then we don't have to correct it.
Okay, of course, behind this area.
In the past 20 years.
A lot of people have been thinking about this issue.
That is to say.
Hey, why is that?
This force will cause.
It can be a signal.
Then tell the cells that this is right or wrong.
For example.
Hey, maybe after you pull it away.
What's that?
Because the original B is in the middle.
So it's not easy to follow.
Pulled away from the dye.
Pulled away from the left point to do some interaction.
Or maybe after you pull it away.
There is a force, and then the force changes some protein structures.
So I can't do it.
This left point is a lot, a lot, a lot.
In the past 20 years.
A lot of reviews.
A lot of research articles.
They're all looking at this mechanism.
Ah, if you're interested.
You can refer to me.
I wrote a review with my post-doc mentor.
Ah, this review is mainly summarized.
Let me advertise.
This review is mainly summarized.
That is.
How do we use some chemical methods.
To understand the process of cell division.
Ah, there are some interesting ones.
The use is from a lot of different research.
They have some very insightful uses.
So you can refer to it.
Good.
Of course, the Austrian Regulation Model is great.
But he also has some problems that can't be solved.
For example.
Hey.
Like this at the beginning.
You have to say, hey, if he opens this.
Ah.
He has some problems that can't be solved.
For example, hey, how does he dye.
If he doesn't have no interest.
It will fall off.
How did he go?
Ah.
How did he start to do interaction with the anti-water?
Because at the beginning of the interaction, the force was also very small.
So the force is also very small.
That is, by definition, this should also fall off.
So.
So there will be a so-called paradox like this.
The other point is that there is another mistake.
Like I said at the beginning of the time.
This focus point will be connected to different levels on both sides.
That.
Ah.
We don't know if this interest is.
How to deal with this problem.
Good.
So there are a lot of problems.
Austrian Regulation Model will have some problems.
Of course, he solved a big problem.
That.
So we put forward a hypothesis at this time.
That is to say, hey.
Will it be a downstream control signal?
Because the whole field is looking at his upstream control signal.
Then we say, hey.
Is it possible to become a downstream control signal?
To affect the function of Aurora B?
Good.
Then we have to know the function of Aurora B.
We have to know first.
Is he a downstream signal?
We have to know what the Aurora B function is.
There are currently two models being proposed.
This is what Aurora B can do.
The first model.
Everyone is.
Conceptually, everyone thinks he is right.
Is the so-called Release Model.
This Release Model tells us.
If Aurora B.
After the loss point is optimized.
This hammer will fall off.
So after he fell off.
Hey, look at this.
The loss point is empty, right?
What if it's empty?
That.
He can connect.
Have the opportunity to connect.
The hammer that came out on the other side.
Hey.
If this system is effective.
Then he can.
Quickly become a symmetrical array.
This model is very powerful.
The biggest problem is that there is no direct.
The evidence of cellular biology.
Confirm that this release model exists.
So, uh.
Since there is no evidence, let's just say it.
That a lot of.
Uh.
Protein storage system.
Invisible system.
In fact, it tells me that there is a hint that this should be right.
But.
Cellular biology has not really made it yet.
This.
This model.
What about cellular biology?
There are different models of life.
It has been proven that there are diplomacy models.
This is a bit special.
It's a bit complicated.
This model is to say.
Hey, if this.
What happens after the left point is oxidized?
This.
B, he will lower this.
The so-called lowering of this hammer.
In the process of lowering.
This dye will also move to spinopo.
When he moves to spinopo.
What about this spinopo?
There are some enzymes near spinopo.
For example, A is a good brother of B.
He will be responsible for it.
That is.
Is to find a way to put.
Uh.
This is the point of contact with the water.
The interaction is eliminated.
So in this model.
It's also very complicated.
This model basically tells us.
What about the Aurora B?
Mainly let.
The dye is moving.
It's not used to do error correction.
So the Aurora A is the error correction.
This.
With the beginning.
It's just that everyone's idea is not very good.
Because everyone knows that the Aurora B is the same.
There should be a problem in theory.
Because otherwise.
This is the reason.
I think.
The Aurora B is to do error correction.
But.
This is the model.
This model.
More.
Uh.
Some evidence in cell biology.
Okay, so what about our project?
There are two models.
Then we want to know.
The first model.
Does this release model exist?
The second.
Physics is.
Is it possible to control these two different.
Uh, function.
In order to do this.
Our most direct idea is.
Then we put the Aurora B.
See if you can stick it to the point of contact.
Then see how it works.
How does this cell deal with this problem?
How to connect the Aurora B directly to the point of contact?
We have this chemical optogenetic system.
This system has three components.
The first one is.
This probe has three components.
The first one is that it has a halo ligand.
It can interact with halo tag protein.
It has another TMP ligand.
It can interact with DHFR tag.
So in theory.
After these two probes are added.
This DHFR protein will be connected to the halo tag protein.
Then the two of them can do something.
In order to increase the time and space of special temporal control.
We added a cage on this TMP.
So the reason for this cage is.
Hey, look at the cage.
So this pink can't bite this pink.
Uh, peanuts.
Then.
When I use light to put it on this cage.
This one.
He can go to him.
Then at this time we can use light to control.
Interaction with this protein.
Then I just said that my main job.
The job is to connect that Aura B to the core.
So of course I hope to put this piece on Aura B.
This piece is connected to the core.
So I use this system.
Ah, we put this so-called.
Ah, this tag.
This so-called Aura B activator is called INBOX.
He is a.
He is an Aura B activator anyway.
Then in order to put this Aura B.
Aura B is connected to this.
Ah.
Outside the point.
Then we put this point on top of it.
We chose this.
We put HaloTag on this so-called.
Ah.
SPC25.
He is a point of contact protein.
What about doing this?
We can do it in a short time.
In about a few ten seconds.
Aura B is connected to the so-called.
Ah, the point of contact.
Then we can see.
Hey, how do the cells deal with this problem?
We.
Okay, so the first one I'm doing is.
Then let's take a look at Aura B.
If we connect to the point of contact.
Let's take a look at that.
Ah, if the point of contact is selected.
If the force is very.
If the force is very low.
Let's see.
How do the cells deal with this problem?
What about this reflector?
It's actually a dynamic balance.
The.
In this case.
He is a dynamic balance.
The process.
Ah.
I should introduce this system.
This system.
I put this.
Ah, this.
Ah.
Separated cells.
Add a so-called.
This.
Ah, this is a very powerful inhibitor.
This is a very powerful inhibitor.
After this inhibitor is added.
This cell will form these two.
The two will not be separated again.
It will form.
A very star-shaped.
A reflector.
What about this reflector?
Ah, this dye is on top of it.
He will.
He is his position.
It is a dynamic.
His.
The connection of the reflector.
He will pull him.
But there are some proteins on his dye.
For example.
These motor proteins.
He will pull him out.
So in theory.
Ah.
This dye is a.
A reflector process.
That's why he's going to be here.
So if I put this Aurora B thing.
Stick to.
This place.
If Aurora B Trigger.
Ah.
This.
The point of focus and the reflector.
That is, if he falls off.
What about this time?
You will win.
So he will.
This.
You will find out.
Hey.
Is the entire dye running out?
Relative.
If he triggers a decay.
That's it.
Because we know that the reflector decays.
Will produce a lot of pull.
That.
So.
If he triggers a decay.
That.
At this time.
This dye should pull inwards.
So we can start.
Ah.
The dye is going out.
Or go inside.
To explore.
Which model is right.
Ah.
This is our experiment process.
Is.
Hey.
This is.
For example.
This channel on the left.
Is a.
Ah.
Is.
The so-called.
Point of focus and.
I.
I also labeled.
That spindle pole.
On the right.
Is.
He can activate.
That.
At the time equal to zero.
You will find that.
Hey.
This one.
The system.
That he.
In the signal inside.
In fact, it is quite uniform.
But after t equals zero.
If you activate this.
Cell.
You will find that.
Hey.
This.
Aurora B or Inbox.
He.
Inbox or Aurora B.
He will stick directly to this point of focus.
In a minute.
This phenomenon can be completed.
That.
You find that.
Hey.
After he stuck it up.
The whole point of focus.
Go inside.
Okay.
So.
Hey.
We put.
We.
Uh.
Collect a lot of data.
Data.
Then we found that.
Hey.
In fact.
Most of the cells.
In fact, they all run inwards.
Ah.
Here.
Uh.
Coordinate.
A little change.
It means going up.
Ah.
In a minute.
Because.
In order to match the data afterwards.
So.
You will find that.
Hey.
Aurora B.
He will let the cells.
Ah.
This mk14.
mk14.
He is a.
Ah.
It will decouple.
One of the anti-Claustrophobic enzymes.
So I put.
I recoup mk.
Because he is.
Then he.
Also.
Also run inwards.
So.
If recoup Aurora B.
With recoup mk.
Tell us.
Similar.
If the phenomenon.
Then I can say.
Hey.
Aurora B.
Is not it.
Is caused.
Anti-Claustrophobic decoupling.
So.
It seems to be more correct.
At least in this.
He can also.
Be born.
Because he can decouple anti-Claustrophobic.
In fact, he can also be used.
To control some anti-Claustrophobic.
That.
This is also my future.
I plan to use this system.
To.
To explore some cells.
This is anti-Claustrophobic.
Some problems in mechanics.
But anyway.
This is our current.
No need to discuss this mk problem.
Okay.
So.
The second.
I want to say.
Hey.
Then I know.
Aurora B.
Will deploy.
Then.
If.
My second question is.
Hey.
If in.
Ah.
Aurora B.
Will do the same thing?
That.
In order to explore this problem.
I want to put Aurora B.
Stick to.
A.
Hammer.
Ah.
Stick to a.
On the point.
Another point.
I don't want to stick to it.
Then you can imagine.
If Aurora B.
Trigger.
Release.
Then.
At this time.
The other side of the.
That.
The anti-Claustrophobic.
Will pull the entire dye body to the other side.
That.
Relative.
If.
He triggered.
Deformation.
Then.
It's the same.
From the direction.
We can.
To explore.
Which model.
Is right.
Okay.
This is our example.
You can also look at this video.
So it's the same.
At the same time.
Hey.
This.
Aurora B.
It's a.
Ah.
Even distribution.
At the same time.
I'm going to figure out a way to.
Stick Aurora B.
To this one.
You.
You should be able to see this.
There are two.
This is possible.
Then I'll figure out a way to stick this one.
The point.
That.
Hey.
About.
A minute.
Less than a minute.
The signal is saturated.
After that, you'll find out.
Hey.
In fact, this.
Uh.
The dye.
He didn't run away right away.
He's still there.
After two or three minutes.
Slowly.
Run over.
Hey.
So tell us.
It seems to be released.
It seems to fit better.
Is.
After you hit it.
It seems that he ran to the other side.
So it seems to be released.
More correct.
That.
I put it.
I.
We.
Let's take a look at 1m.
When this.
The dye.
After leaving this middle plate.
Let's fix this cell.
Then we take it to 1m.
Let's take a look at the bottom.
Hey.
Is it.
On both sides.
Uh.
Is it.
Is there a waterproofing on both sides of the magnetic point?
Then we found that if this.
Magnetism.
Ah.
If this magnetic point is connected to Aurora B.
Hey.
There is no magnetism above.
But if the other side, I did not activate it.
That.
So he doesn't have it up there.
Aurora B.
There are more than a dozen.
Several.
Ah.
The so-called magnetism.
That.
Here is only one slide.
As it is only about 5.
But there are other times.
There are other.
The.
So hey.
So Aurora B.
Activation.
It will really cause release.
At least in this case.
Okay.
Then you may find out.
Hey.
It seems that I found two different.
Ah.
Mouth to mouth.
Is.
Found two different.
Function.
So how do we discuss.
You see in the monopole spindle.
It seems to be a trigger.
Deprecation.
But in.
High tension or bipolar spindle.
It triggers release.
So we started to think.
Hey.
Is it.
Magnetism.
Ah.
What about the magnetic force on the magnetic point?
Will tell Aurora B.
To do this.
I'll explain to you guys later.
Ah.
Okay.
For.
Explore this.
Is this the problem of tension?
Then I just wanted to say.
Hey.
Let's use a.
Use some chemical drugs to go.
Ah.
To change his.
Tension.
So let's use these two.
Inhibitor.
These two.
For.
You'll find out.
The distance from his defective point.
Lower.
OK, tell me.
That's what tells me that the tension is getting smaller.
Then we want to say.
When he was small, we sat on the same.
Do it again at the same time.
See if it gets the same different result.
Then our idea is to say.
Hey, I'm going to make this tension smaller.
Is that not.
This release.
Will be.
It's not easy to happen.
Ah.
What about here?
I did some tricks.
Because we.
We know that this inhibitor.
He.
It may also affect the department.
It's just two at the same time.
So we want to see.
Ah.
Explore a little more detailed.
It's just that we look directly at the release.
This.
Condition.
So we want to measure directly.
Release.
Some kinetics.
So how do we measure release?
Kinetics?
We know that.
This.
Like I just said.
That is, if I hit the dot.
After that.
This dot will be here.
Stop here.
Stop for a while.
Then start to go in the other direction.
So I just put this.
Ah.
This.
Trace it.
Record it.
You will find that it is probably like this.
What about the beginning?
When there is no fire.
The two sides are symmetrical.
But in the process of the process.
Hey.
The other side is gone.
So he's on the other side of the sea.
Go.
Then go to the end.
He will be near the extreme.
Stop near the back.
This waiting time.
Here.
Tell us.
Hey.
This waiting time.
Here.
Tell us.
Very useful information.
Because.
If this waiting time.
If it's too long.
It means that the effect of Orabi.
The efficiency is not very strong.
Hey.
That waiting time is short.
It means that the effect of Orabi.
The efficiency is very strong.
Then I just put this waiting time.
After collecting it.
Then I took a look.
Is there a case of medicine?
There is medicine.
Is.
The force is relatively low.
No medicine.
When the force is stronger.
Then we found out.
Hey.
Add medicine.
This is.
Or.
When the force is lower.
Ah.
The effect of Orabi is worse.
When there is no medicine.
Is.
When the force is stronger.
Hey.
His waiting time is shorter.
Tell me.
He is faster.
So we know that.
Hey.
If the force becomes smaller.
He will let.
The release.
The kinetics becomes slower.
Okay.
Today.
Give you a summary.
That is to say.
Hey.
We.
This.
Work.
Get a.
Result.
That is to say.
We think that.
The dye makes the force.
In addition to becoming an upstream signal.
It can also become a downstream signal.
He will release the microchip.
Just try to find a way.
The left point will leave with the anti-slip.
In addition.
He will also reduce.
Ah.
Anti-slip.
Then we found that.
In a situation where the force is very strong.
Hey.
Orabi will let the left point go.
Ah.
Go with the anti-slip.
Leave.
Go.
Combine.
That in.
In a situation where the force is very low.
Orabi will be more inclined to go.
Ah.
Go.
Reduce this anti-slip.
Ah.
Then we.
From a cell biology perspective.
How do we explain this phenomenon?
We know that.
There are two wrong ways in the cell.
The same.
The left point can be connected.
Ah.
These two left points can be connected to the same.
Binopole.
Ah.
What if.
Orabi.
At this time, the cell has a problem.
The cell found that there was a problem with this dye.
Hey.
He will recruit Orabi.
Then at this time.
He will deploy microtubules.
At this time.
The dye can run to the pore.
In this case.
It can be immediately.
Directly.
Transmitted to.
In the middle of the cell.
So it will be arranged.
A little faster.
This is on the kinetic.
There will be some advantages.
That is, the cell biology.
But.
Another wrong way is like this.
This is a more serious mistake.
It is a left point to connect two.
Ah.
Binopoles.
This.
What about this situation?
We found that.
Hey.
In fact.
It seems like.
If you buy these three.
If it's the same thing.
In fact, it seems that there is no way to solve this problem.
What about in this system?
Because we think.
Hey.
Is it.
His tension is higher.
So, in fact, this.
Mistake.
Attachment.
In fact, it is in the way of release.
To relax.
You can also do this.
You can do this.
The wrong way.
Cut it off.
After?
He.
This system can become.
The normal.
Uh.
Process.
So, we think that zhang li.
Ah.
A very important.
A signal of downstream control.
Tell the cell.
To do this.
Or do this.
Ah.
In addition.
We can also explain.
Other problems that can not be explained.
Like I just said.
Hey.
I want to dye.
How did it start?
Connect.
Connect the.
The.
That according to the past.
The idea is to say.
Hey.
If he.
Orabi.
When the fire is very high.
He should fall off.
But we.
We can find out.
Hey.
In fact, he may not fall.
Because at this time.
You can also know that he is very low.
He.
He doesn't have any tension.
So.
After he connected.
In fact, he is not so easy to fall off.
So.
This.
We just.
Somehow.
That is.
Resolve this problem.
Hey.
I just talked about this.
If you have this.
Cell.
Uh.
If you are interested in the micro-surgery.
Hey.
You are welcome to refer to my article.
Yeah.
Just released today.
Okay.
So.
We know that the changes in the mechanics of the cells.
It will affect the instability of the dye.
So my main topic now.
It is to discuss that the skin.
Uh.
Just like I just said.
That is.
The cancerous process of the skin cell.
In the process of cancer cells.
In fact, there are some changes in the mechanics.
Then we think.
Hey.
For example.
Cell.
I just said.
Or the tension between the cell and the tissue becomes smaller.
Then everyone already knows that this process.
It may cause an instability of the dye.
Then let's think about it.
Hey.
I just explained it.
That is.
Cell.
The tension in the micro-surgery will also cause problems.
The tension outside the cell will also cause problems.
Then we think.
Hey.
The tension inside the cell and outside the cell.
Is there a certain degree of coupling?
The so-called connection.
Okay.
The other question is.
Hey.
What about the division cell?
I said.
It.
It usually becomes harder.
What about the cell tissue?
It also becomes more.
The cell tissue also becomes harder.
Then we want to say.
Is this process?
The hardening process of cell division.
It can help this cancer cell.
In.
In this harder environment.
You can go.
To split.
Because we also know that.
If you go to suppress this cell.
You find out that he.
It's like.
The dye can't be arranged in the middle plate.
So.
It will cause some split problems.
Let's talk about this.
Hardening.
The hardening process of split cells.
From whether or not.
Let the cells grow in this harder environment.
This question is more like.
The problem of fatty liver.
That is to say.
We hope to know that.
Uh.
In the process of fatty liver or liver hardening.
The inside of the liver cell will produce a UTI accumulation.
It will also produce some hardening accumulation on the outside.
Then we want to say.
These so-called constraints inside.
The outside of this.
Constraints of cell division.
Is it possible?
Is there some interaction?
Then it leads to the whole.
The cancer cell becomes the cancer process.
Of course, there is no so-called.
The study of the mouth.
Now I just feel that.
Hey.
Uh.
Fat liver.
Liver hardening liver cancer.
It seems to be a high-level mouth.
That.
So this part is still a bit like open question.
Uh.
Ah.
Then I want to be now.
That is.
This process.
In fact, there are a lot of people helping me.
Like, for example.
Ah.
Our lab.
There are two of these.
In fact, at the beginning.
Uh.
Helped me build a lot of systems.
So.
I'm just a human.
Will put.
Put these things in the end.
A process.
Just put it together.
So.
I have a lot of credit for this.
He.
At least do a lot of work.
So I.
Save a lot of time.
Of course, I also have some work.
There are some people.
For example.
He is.
Do some organic chemistry synthesis.
He can synthesize those light.
Some of the light chemistry.
Uh.
Materials.
It can be used to make light.
Can be used to control.
That.
Because I can't do this myself.
So I have to give them a little credit.
What about the other one?
He is in a university in New York.
Ah.
Then they.
This lab.
It's amazing.
What about, uh.
It's amazing to do that.
Then we just put our sample.
After fixing it.
And then send it directly to them.
They can watch em.
Then, uh.
There's always going to be some beautiful results.
So I have to.
Thank them.
Of course, this.
The dust has a very strong.
Comma members.
He.
This.
Comma has five levels.
Including our level.
So these labs.
Some are doing cell biology.
Some are doing.
Ah.
Some do biochemistry, computer physics.
He has done bioengineering.
Then.
Let's discuss the problem of cell division together.
So I think these teams.
It's.
It's really strong.
So I, I highly recommend that if you're looking for a blog post.
You can go to these labs.
If you're interested in cell division.
You can come and have a look at the background.
And of course, there are some so-called, uh.
That's probably what I'm talking about today.
Thank you.
OK.
Uh, that.
What's the problem?
Uh, you still.
Hey.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Thank you, thank you.
Thank you.
So, I wanted to ask this question
because, around four or five years ago,
we saw this phenomenon,
especially in myosis.
It's...
or, I should say,
in ogenesis,
it only has one chromosome
that goes all the way to the next generation.
Then the rest three are omitted.
So, you'll drive, right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Only one will remain.
So, when they're shown in rows,
some genes will sense that
it's arranged in the wrong place,
and then it will loosen up the whole process
and start over.
So, eventually,
it has a higher chance
to reach the next generation.
Yeah, yeah, that's right.
So, I'm curious,
in myosis,
is there another layer
to control it?
Or is it a very different thing?
Yes, there is.
We first...
About three or four years ago,
there was an article in Science.
It was written by another Japanese.
He mentioned that
he used mouse eggs to make the system.
You know, eggs are also used for myosis.
In M1,
after myosis,
it will be divided into four cells.
He found that some components
will make some of its genes...
will make some of the colored cells
more flat,
or the dead spot is more likely
to stay in the egg.
Yeah.
Then he found some phenomena.
For example,
for example, the iris
will actually have an asymmetry.
But this may just be the mouse.
I don't know if there is
such a phenomenon in the opposite color.
But I know the mouse has this.
Myosis will have additional controls.
For example, the iris will have an asymmetry.
Then its size...
The size of the left eye
will also affect its problem.
Because the size of the left eye
is like what we just talked about.
MKEG, Deployment,
will also have different activities.
So myosis is indeed more complicated.
So now everyone in this field
is actually mainly going that way.
Ah, I can't be a mouse.
I don't want to be a mouse.
So I didn't go that way.
I went the other way.
But your question is very...
On the point.
I have to say.
Thank you.
OK.
Questions?
Before asking questions,
please introduce yourself.
Everyone knows you.
I want to ask a question.
OK, please say.
I am an outsider.
But I still want to ask a question.
Oh, OK.
You just mentioned
the intercellular and
external cells.
According to my understanding of intercellular biology,
there will be a cell membrane.
The cell membrane is actually quite strong.
What is the mechanism for coupling?
I know that
there will be some holes on the surface.
It will allow some things
to enter the cells.
But I don't know
if this thing
may be some...
There may be substances in it.
But I don't know
the coupling of tension.
What is the possible mechanism?
This question is really great.
I have to say this question.
In fact, people in this field
are thinking very seriously.
But they have never thought of a way.
There is no good mechanism
to solve this problem.
Let me tell you
a few possibilities.
If you look at it from the perspective of mechanics.
Let's say this.
Someone in my class is doing this.
That is to say, you know.
In fact, the magnet will move.
And it will swing.
This process is because
there are some proteins on the cell membrane
that will pull it.
In fact, there are many groups
that have been doing this for more than ten years.
Many engineers have done this.
They found that
if you change the cell tissue on the outside.
For example, integrin
or those adhesion molecules.
In fact, the direction of the magnet
will change with the distance.
Of course, you can ask a question.
How did this happen?
It may happen
because these molecules
may cause some
small molecules to gather.
The small molecules are not actually magnets.
It's the cortex around it.
There is another cytoskeleton on the cortex.
It's called actin.
It may be in the process of gathering.
It also gathers those things that will connect to the magnet.
So it will relatively
zoom in on this path.
This is one possibility.
Another possibility is
some regulations like biochemistry.
For example, those molecules
will actually induce some
message transmission.
Those message transmissions may make
some signals of the entire cell.
For example,
it may make some
places easier to decompose.
At this time, the tension will increase.
So there are some
of these two models.
In fact, everyone doesn't quite understand.
But I already know that there is such a phenomenon.
That is to say,
what did you change outside?
In fact, the spindle pole will change.
Now our question
Actually, my question is not very
so-called
very
deep.
Everyone already knows this process.
I already know that
the spindle pole and
the magnetic core will be connected.
I just want to say
that these two pieces
are not
so-called interaction.
I'm just
adding another layer on that question.
I hope I have answered your question.
It seems a bit complicated.
I'm not a very good presenter.
So I try my best.
OK.
Actually, I have another question.
But
let the audience ask first.
Is there any other questions from the audience on the spot?
Hello.
Please say hello.
I am Zhou Jia.
I am from Bristol University in the UK.
I also do cell biology.
My own research has touched on some active parts.
So I'm curious.
Because in your project,
you mentioned that
the tension between cells
will affect
the performance of magnetism.
So when you train cells,
will you particularly consider using
some different software?
Or
will you specifically set
the confluence of specific cells?
In fact, maybe cell contact or no contact
may affect the performance of some cells.
Because when I do experiments myself,
I seem to encounter this kind of trouble.
Yes. OK.
I have to say that
when you were doing cell experiments in the past,
let me tell you first.
There are several points to discuss.
The first point
is what cells are different and what cells are not different.
I believe that different cells will have different differences.
Because what we use is
what I just said
outside will affect inside
that cell
is actually the primary cell.
This is the mouse's membrane cell.
Then it is raised in 3D culture.
So I believe that they feel that
there is such a coupling.
If you are studying
the so-called general cell line,
you know that the cell line has been isolated
and raised for several generations.
Basically, we think that
it should be adapted.
It has adapted to this environment.
So at this time,
the coupling may not be so strong.
Because it can split itself.
Because if it can't go through that,
it can't survive.
So there are some selection processes.
So
I think
but recently
someone started to discuss this issue.
For example,
I know that Sample has a group.
I just started the lab recently.
He is discussing that
cells will become longer
in the process of classification.
As I just said,
Anaphase will actually become longer.
This process
is actually very important.
Then he did a
more harsh approach.
He just tried to make the cell
become super hard.
So hard that
cells can't do
the work of prostitution.
You will find that
there is also a strange phenomenon in the mouse.
I think this is quite abnormal.
But I think it's quite interesting.
So actually
the direction you just mentioned
is exactly
what people have been doing
in the past five years.
After technology has matured,
people started to study.
But it's mainly
about
cells
and the so-called
3D culture.
I hope I answered your question.
Yes, thank you.
Sorry.
I want to follow up on a question.
Because
what we just talked about
is like
white blood cells.
Especially like cancer.
If you look at it,
will it have
a very different mechanism on it?
Good question.
Yes.
So according to
the article I just mentioned,
what you just said is
I use breast cells, right?
That work is actually
a group from MIT.
But that PI
seems to have died
in the past year or two.
But this is a bit unfortunate.
That group
made a lot of cells.
It found that
what you said is right.
If it was originally in the blood,
it doesn't need
cell proliferation.
Then it won't have this phenomenon.
But if it's breast or liver,
it has this phenomenon.
So it looks like different cells
live in different environments.
Indeed, there will be different responses.
You have a good intuition.
Thank you, thank you.
OK.
My friends didn't ask any questions.
Strange.
Do you have any more questions?
If not,
I will turn off the microphone
and turn off the video later.
Before turning off the video,
please turn on the microphone first.
Let's give a round of applause
to thank Geng Yuan's speech.
You should be able to hear
the sound of the video being turned off.
Thank you.