Okay, thank you.
Thank you, everyone.
I'd like to share my screen with you.
This is the topic I'm going to talk about today.
The influence of early Western missionary Chinese education on modern Chinese language and culture.
First of all, this is a very new topic.
In fact, it is my experience of studying the history of Chinese education in the past few years.
Because it is the first time to publish, there may be some lack of evidence or some points of view are not mature enough.
So I'd like to ask you to give me some feedback later.
Or you are welcome to contact me after the meeting.
So thank you, everyone.
In addition, I would like to thank my instructor.
Because the idea of ​​this topic is probably related to his leadership.
That is, Professor Xin Shichuang.
There is also my Chinese teacher, the instructor of the course, Mr. Gu Baili.
This whole topic and some of the content is also the result of the cooperation between this teacher and the teacher.
Okay, so let's get into my structure first.
The topic of my report today is roughly divided into three parts.
The first is the preface.
The second is the main part.
Discuss how missionary Chinese education affects the influence of this country's language and culture.
I will discuss it at about 6 o'clock.
The third part is the conclusion.
At the beginning of this part, I would like to explain to you first.
In recent years, there has been a lot of discussion about the influence of missionary Chinese education on China.
But this topic focuses on the ideas developed by the missionary to learn Chinese.
Or his learning process.
Or some of his teaching materials.
How do these things affect modern China?
We will not discuss the impact of missionary Chinese education on science.
We will not discuss the impact of missionary Chinese education on painting and architecture.
We will focus on the impact of missionary Chinese education on language learning.
Now, let's first understand how missionary Chinese education entered China.
In fact, the spread of religion is very long and has a great impact on the interaction of various nations around the world.
China's earliest external religious exchange was Buddhist culture.
What impact does Buddhist culture have on China?
At that time, there was a lot of communication between Buddhism and Chinese in the Wei, Jin, Nan, and North Dynasties.
This actually stimulated the development of Chinese linguistics.
Chinese linguistics is said to be four-vowels.
One of the characteristics of Chinese linguistics is that we have a tone.
In fact, it is influenced by Chinese learners.
The second wave of religious transmission and language learning,
the second wave of high tide is the part we are going to share today.
The second wave of high tide is the part we are going to share today.
The missionary Chinese education did not come from the West.
However, what we are discussing today is the missionary of the West.
Therefore, the earliest systematic Chinese-speaking ethnic group in the West,
I emphasize that there is systematic learning of Chinese.
In fact, Catholicism has been passed down in China for a long time.
A while ago, there was a very famous TV series called The Twelve Hours of Chang'an.
Many people may have seen it.
It talks about the Great Qing Jin religion.
In fact, it is the Eastern Catholicism at that time.
It is based on Syrian literature.
There is a Persian prince in it.
It represents the entry of Catholicism at that time.
However, as early as the Tang Dynasty,
there was already a translation of the Tantric literature version.
However, the Catholicism has been in contact with China for a long time.
In the Song Dynasty, the Catholicism has become more subdued.
In the Yuan Dynasty, the Catholicism has reached another peak.
We know that the Yuan Dynasty people have a so-called Sermon people.
The Sermon people are Westerners.
A story that everyone is familiar with is the Marco Polo travel diary.
Marco Polo is a businessman.
He came to the Yuan Dynasty with some religious missions and met the emperor.
Later, Pope Francis sent him directly to the Yuan Dynasty to make contact with China.
However, these contacts did not really become a systematic study of Chinese.
The real beginning of Chinese research is still at the end of the Ming Dynasty.
At the end of the Ming Dynasty, at the end of the 16th century,
the Jesuit Church was established in France.
The Jesuit Church has a strong mission to preach,
and they are willing to go to the distant Far East to explore.
The second point is the great breakthrough and invention of the sea.
The people we just talked about are all through the road,
which we are more familiar with is the Silk Road to China.
The road is very far away.
This is more difficult and dangerous.
The Jesuit Church at the end of the Ming Dynasty is mostly through the Silk Road.
The Jesuit Church went from the Silk Road to Haowangjiao,
then to the Middle East, and then to India.
Let's look at the two peak periods.
The first is the end of the Yuan Dynasty, the end of the 16th century.
The second is the second peak period after the Opium War.
In the early period, it was mainly the Catholic Church in Europe.
After the middle of the 19th century,
it was the new era of the Jesuit Church.
The real long-term and continuous impact
is actually more concentrated after the middle of the 19th century.
Now let's see how these missionary Chinese studies have affected China.
First of all, many of our friends online
are teachers and predecessors in the Chinese education field.
How did Chinese education become an independent subject?
Today, many people think that
after the Second World War,
it separated from traditional Chinese studies.
In fact, it may have started to separate earlier, at this time.
The original Chinese and Chinese studies,
that is, the synology we are talking about,
cannot be distinguished.
With the arrival of Luo Mingjian,
these people brought back a large number of Chinese classics
and translated them into Latin.
Then it spread to Europe.
We know that this is the Chinese heat of the enlightenment period.
The Sun King Louis XIV was very fond of Chinese culture,
especially the rise of rationalism.
They found that the distant Eastern Empire was godless.
They were very curious about the idea of ​​godlessness in Confucianism.
So at that time in Paris,
the Chinese hot trend was the fashion of the upper-class society.
So you have to wear Chinese silk, drink Chinese tea,
and discuss the Four Books and Five Sutras.
This is the rise of Chinese Chinese studies.
However, at this time,
because China and the West did not have direct contact,
Chinese studies at this time focused on the study of thought and culture,
and there was no need for actual language communication.
However, with the large number of Jesuits sent to China,
they actually began to come into contact with China.
These Jesuits had a need for preaching,
so they began to actively study Chinese.
Therefore, these Jesuits in China
began to independently develop language learning,
Chinese-language second language learning,
into an independent subject,
and made a distinction with Chinese studies based on thought.
For example, Gu Saifeng and Dai Suiliang,
who were the priests of the Jesuits,
began to write professional Chinese textbooks,
such as Chinese Introduction.
Next is the New Religion.
The New Religion I'm talking about
is the so-called Christian religion.
In the missionary history of the US Department of State,
as you are familiar with,
Wei Sanwei also published a ten-chapter text in English.
This ten-chapter ten refers to ten difficulties,
from the most basic words,
to the conversation in Chinese,
to the final reading material.
This is what makes Chinese studies
an independent subject.
This is the first impact.
The second impact is the development of Chinese-language language learning.
In our traditional Chinese primary schools,
as you are familiar with,
the study of Chinese characters,
is based on the study of Chinese characters.
The emphasis is on the character,
but the study of grammar has not been developed.
For Western Chinese-language learners,
especially those with Latin and Romance languages,
there is a huge difference in grammar.
It is very difficult for them to learn.
Even in the early days,
when they were reading literature,
the literature was very simple.
In addition to the grammar,
it was very difficult for them to grasp.
They even mistakenly thought that
there was no grammar in Chinese.
Recently,
the study of Chinese teaching history
has become more popular,
so a lot of information has been discovered.
Some of the information that you may be familiar with
is probably on my side.
There are some relatively new sayings.
First of all,
in the first book,
a Chinese-language book
written by a teacher from Laihua,
is written by Huankobo,
the father of the Taoism Society.
This book is actually dead.
It was because modern scholars
were studying the history of Chinese teaching,
and they found that
this book was mentioned
in the internal documents of the Taoism Society.
So it was designated as the earliest Chinese book.
In addition,
there is a book called
Huangjialue,
which is probably the first book
written in Chinese.
There are many scholars in the mainland
who have been designated
as scholars
from China
to France.
Huangjialue is probably the first book.
However,
this book
was written in France.
Secondly,
it was not executed.
In fact,
it was not widely promoted.
And is it written by Huangjialue?
There is still some controversy.
So I won't talk about it here.
I will focus on the research of
Western missionary language.
The second book
is probably the book
that has become the conclusion
over the past few years,
which is the book
of Wei Kuanguo's Chinese Literature.
This book is written in Latin.
It was written in Latin
until the beginning of the 20th century.
Of course,
it is now in English.
So almost all the early
letters in the church
are probably written in Latin.
He wrote this book
in Chinese.
This book is
circulated in the form of a manuscript.
His manuscript
still exists
in several versions.
Several libraries
in the church still have it.
One of the characteristics of this book
is that it discusses grammar
in the second and third chapters,
and for the first time
makes the difference between Chinese and Latin.
The difference between Latin and Chinese.
He also found that the characteristics of Chinese
are that there is no gender.
There is no gender.
There is no
gender.
There is no gender.
Let's take a look.
There is another book.
Ten years ago,
it was discussed
that Ji Wanguo's Chinese Guanhua Grammar.
This book is
the earliest
widely printed
grammar book.
It was also
a very popular
grammar book
in the 18th and 19th centuries.
What has a deeper impact
is the Chinese Zha Ji
written by Ma Ruose.
One of the characteristics of this book
is that the book was written
in 1728.
He had already first
studied the grammar of
Chinese and Latin.
In addition,
in the analysis of the grammar of Chinese and Latin,
the sentences he used
were a large number of sentences
quoted in the novel
.
At the same time, he noticed that
the words were divided into
real words and imaginary words.
He kept some local dialects.
For example,
when he quoted the Water Tiger Diamond,
he used a large number of Shandong dialects.
It is a historical
language
presentation.
It is a very real
grammar book.
Next,
let's talk about the impact of this book.
This impact is very direct.
We are all very familiar with
the first Chinese grammar book
written by Ma Ruose.
The author of Ma Ruose
is Ma Jianzhong.
It can be said that
Ma Jianzhong's writing of Ma Ruose
was influenced by the grammar book
of the Western missionary.
Let's take a look.
Ma Jianzhong himself was from Zhejiang.
At that time, he was called Dan Tu.
Dan Tu is the name of a school
in Xuhui, Shanghai.
If you are from Taiwan,
you probably know that
Xuhui High School
is the name of a school
in Luzhou,
Xinbei City.
That's right.
Xuhui High School
is the name of a school
in Xuhui, Shanghai.
It is a middle school
established by
Ma Jianzhong
in Xuhui.
At that time,
Ma Jianzhong was also
a member of Xuhui.
He was very familiar
with these French priests.
He studied Latin grammar
and wrote a book called
Ma Shi Wen Tong.
It is worth mentioning that
Ma Jianzhong's family
was Catholic.
He had a very famous brother
who later became a monk.
He was the founder
of Furen University
in Beijing.
Ma Jianzhong
was also a representative
from Europe.
Ma Shi Wen Tong
studied Chinese grammar
in a thorough way.
He wrote a lot of books
about the grammar of words.
He did a thorough research.
Ma Shi Wen Tong's book
was very helpful
in modern Chinese grammar
study.
It was influenced
by Zhang Shizhao's
Middle Chinese Dictionary,
Li Jingxi's
New Chinese Grammar,
Lu Shuxiang's
and Wang Li's works.
Next,
I would like to compare
the analysis
of the vocabulary
of Ma Shi Wen Tong's book.
The first book
is Wei Kuanguo's
Chinese Grammar in 1651.
As you can see,
he divided Chinese vocabulary
into nine categories.
We are all very familiar with it.
Next,
Ma Shi Wen Tong's Chinese Dictionary
has six categories.
What is special
is that
Wei Kuanguo
classified the Chinese vocabulary
into nouns.
The Chinese Dictionary
classified the Chinese vocabulary
into nouns.
Ma Shi Wen Tong
classified the Chinese vocabulary
into nouns.
He classified the Chinese vocabulary
into subordinate words.
He studied the subordinate words separately.
Let's look at
the book
which has become
Lu Shuxiang's
Chinese Dictionary
in the early 1980s.
He classified the Chinese vocabulary
into twelve categories.
He added the subordinate words
and the subordinate words.
We can see
that the Chinese Dictionary
which has been classified
for more than 300 years
is still based on
the earliest Chinese Dictionary
in 1651.
The third factor
is the appearance
of Chinese alphabets.
We all know that
the traditional Chinese alphabets
are pronounced in the opposite way.
They are pronounced
in the opposite way
in Chinese characters.
They are pronounced in the opposite way
This is the way
Chinese alphabets have been used
for a long time.
The Chinese alphabets
are classified into
the subordinate words
and the subordinate words.
Therefore,
it is very difficult
for a native speaker
to learn Chinese alphabets
or a non-native speaker
to learn Chinese alphabets.
After Li Maodou
came to China,
he first tried to
pronounce Chinese alphabets
but he failed.
On the one hand,
the Chinese alphabets
were changed
from the Ming Dynasty
to the Qing Dynasty.
At that time,
the Chinese alphabets
were introduced
from the south to China.
In addition to the dialects
of Guangdong,
the Chinese alphabets
were introduced
from the north to the south.
At that time,
the official language of Guangdong
was Manchurian.
Therefore,
the Chinese alphabets
were studied
in different regions.
The next one
is a heavy-weighted work,
which is
the work of
the father of
Genghis Khan.
He studied the books
of the Ming Dynasty
and translated the Chinese alphabets
into
the Western
alphabets.
He only used
25 alphabets
and 5 tones.
At that time,
the 5 tones
included the Chinese alphabets
so there was one more tone
than now.
Now,
let's look at
the Chinese alphabets.
This is the
Chinese alphabet
of Sirurmuz.
Although it is not clear,
it is presented
in a compass-shaped way.
The Chinese alphabets
were translated
in the way of
putting the sound
inside and
out.
Let's continue
to look at
how the Chinese alphabets
of Sirurmuz
influenced the development
of Chinese alphabets.
Sirurmuz's significance
is that
using Latin alphabets
to analyze Chinese alphabets
has always been
seen as a complicated
and difficult task.
It has a great impact
on the later
Chinese alphabets
such as Sirurmuz,
Sirurmuz,
Latin and Romance alphabets
had a big impact
on the success
of cutting alphabets
of Chinese alphabets.
Eulius Dirich,
the pope who came from
in the middle of the 19th century
was an American
who studied Chinese 싶은
We know that
Chinese characters are hard to learn.
He felt that
Chinese characters were
unreasonable.
So he wrote a paper
in the Chinese Newspaper
and he was the first to argue
that Chinese characters should
be replaced by Pinyin.
The reason he argued
was very intense.
First, he thought
that an excellent language
should be Pinyin.
He even said that
alphabets,
such as the Egyptian alphabet,
should be replaced by Pinyin.
He felt that
Chinese characters should be
eliminated from the
progress of language.
He also suggested
that Chinese characters
should be replaced
by Pinyin.
He said that
Chinese characters
are hard to learn.
Chinese children
should learn
because
Chinese characters
are hard to learn.
Wei Sanwei
agreed with this argument.
He continued to
argue in the Chinese Newspaper.
At the beginning of
the Qing Dynasty,
there were many
intellectuals
who recognized
the old China.
For example, Xuantong, Chen Duxiu,
etc.
Even Hu Shi
said that
Chinese characters
should be replaced
by Pinyin.
This led to
the famous
Chinese-Latin movement
in the early years of the Republic of China.
Of course,
the Chinese-Latin movement
did not succeed
in 2021.
Because there are too many dialects in China,
there is no way
to use one Pinyin
to represent all dialects.
Second,
there are too many homonyms in China.
In addition, there is a difference
between spoken Chinese and spoken Chinese.
Without Chinese characters,
there is no way
to express it correctly.
So Pinyin
did not replace Chinese characters.
However,
Chinese characters
were replaced by Pinyin
in the 18th century.
This is directly
due to the influence
of the Roman Pinyin
of the Western missionary.
Fourth,
missionary Chinese
has also improved
the status
of traditional Chinese literature.
Chinese literature
has always been
about poetry.
Poetry
can not be counted.
However,
the novelist
has always been
compared to the literati.
From the Chinese characters,
the author said
that the novelist Liu
is a hearsay.
He is not as good as Liu.
This idea
has been
passed down
from generation to generation.
The author did not
accept the novel.
He did not accept the novel
of Zhang Hui.
He accepted the short stories
of the literary world.
However,
he did not accept the four great novels.
Why?
Because he felt that the four great novels
were very vulgar.
However,
after the Western missionary
came to China,
he made a big change.
In French literature,
novels and plays
are very important.
The Chinese literature of France
started to pay attention
to Chinese novels and plays
very early on.
The missionary
also found that
the novels of Zhang Hui
and Baihua
were very rich in
folk customs
and life records.
Therefore,
the missionary
started to use
the novels of Zhang Hui
as a Chinese textbook.
In the book
of Ma Ruose,
he used the sentences
of the novels of Zhang Hui
as an example.
Let's take a look
at the book of Ma Ruose.
The French priest
of the Jesuit Church
named Andre Gaulle
translated the book
of Ma Ruose
as a textbook.
He translated
the book of Ma Ruose
as a textbook.
He translated the book
of Ma Ruose
as a textbook.
Ma Ruose
also translated
the book of Ma Ruose
as a textbook.
He translated the book
of Ma Ruose
as a textbook.
In addition,
the missionary
from the United States
named Wittema
translated the book
of Ma Ruose
as a textbook.
Wittema
translated the book
of Ma Ruose
as a textbook.
In addition,
the missionaries
from the West
also tried to
create novels of Zhang Hui.
For example,
Ma Ruose
wrote a novel
about Confucianism
with the purpose
of teaching.
The missionaries
from the West
were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
Especially,
the missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
The missionaries
from the West
were close
to the Chinese
and were interested
in the novel
of Zhang Hui.
I have some questions,
but I'd like to ask
them later.
I'd like to ask them later.
I think
I'd like to ask
questions
like
the question
of
Ning Shen.
Because
you mainly talk about
the missionaries from the West.
I'd like to know
how you define
the missionaries
from the West.
I'd like to know
how you define
the missionaries
from the West.
I know
some of them
are from different countries
and some of them
have different accents
and accents.
Do you think
their analysis
of Chinese
has an impact?
Because, as you said,
their main purpose
is to preach.
Their main purpose
I talked about
their interpretation
of the Bible
to help them preach
and communicate.
But before that,
because the Chinese culture
and language
flowed into
Europe
and they
read written language
and read written language
instead of conversation.
I'd like to know
because...
What's my question?
Because their purpose
is different.
I'd like to know
if this has an impact
on their Chinese learning
and analysis.
If you want
to read literature
and analyze literature,
the emphasis is different.
Is there a mismatch?
Next,
as you mentioned,
they've been
learning Chinese
in different places
for a long time.
As you mentioned,
there's a Shandong dialect.
There's a Shandong dialect.
Francesco Varo,
a Spanish missionary,
he read
the White Paper
in 1728.
It's a Shandong dialect.
So, I'd like to know...
He read it in Shandong dialect.
I'd like to know...
How does learning Chinese
affect their
Chinese learning?
How does learning Chinese
affect their
Korean learning?
They've an
we've an
We've an