Welcome everyone to today's TerraTalk.
We are very happy to welcome Dr. Wang Guan Zhong.
He graduated from the Department of Electrical Engineering in 2010,
and graduated from the Department of Electrical Engineering in 2021,
and received his Master's Degree.
During his Master's Degree,
he worked in coding,
and developed the non-equilibrium screen function,
which is NEGF.
This is also in his title.
If you don't know what NEGF is,
he will explain it to you later.
From 2014 to 2020,
he went to Purdue University, Indiana,
and received his Master's Degree in Electrical Engineering.
His main job there was quantum transport method,
which is the method of quantum transmission.
His main focus was on nanostructure and quantum transmission.
Currently, he works in Intel's TCAP team.
Let's welcome Dr. Wang Guan Zhong.
You can start sharing.
Let me share my screen.
Can everyone see my screen?
Yes, but you can't see the slides.
Okay.
Can you see the slides now?
Yes.
Let's follow the Tyrell tradition.
Please turn on your microphones,
and let's welcome Dr. Wang Guan Zhong.
Hello, everyone.
I will be speaking in English for the next few slides,
because the technical terms may change.
My target audience this time is...
If you're interested in this field,
whether you want to apply for a Master's Degree,
or if you want to know more about this field,
or if you want to use this tool,
my target audience is like that.
If you have any questions,
you can send me an email.
These works were done when I was studying for a Master's Degree at Purdue.
The funding sources were NSF and NCSA.
I also received funding from the Department of Education.
So I wanted to acknowledge that.
I also worked with CELBACO.
This work was done by Purdue's supercomputer,
which we call RCAC.
This is the result of the computation.
My topic today is optoelectronic simulation,
and I will go over from the semi-classical
to quantum transport,
my different perspective.
Here is my outline,
and I will go over the motivation,
and what's the method being used here,
and I will show some results.
In the methods, I will go over the semi-classical.
Here's a missing label here,
and go over to what's NEGF,
and what is a beautiful probe,
and the difficulty of including different processes,
a recombination and generation process inside the NEGF.
How do we do that?
I will show some results to show,
first, the importance of including these kinds of processes.
Also, I will do a comparison.
If we use a semi-classical way to do simulation
versus using quantum transport way to do it,
what's the difference?
And do a summary there.
So, why are we working on this project?
It's because what we have achieved so far as mankind,
because we have solar cell,
and also to harvest energy from sun,
and also we can efficiently emit light
through light-emitting diets,
which is like a really efficient way
to transfer energy from electricity to lighting.
And to push the boundary further,
we need to look into what other new materials are out there,
what different new structures we can optimize
like the current efficiency.
And so, for example, to improve the efficiency of LED,
we have these quantum wells,
and then you can see that when we have quantum well,
the carrier will like to stay there more,
and therefore increase the opportunity
to recombine and emit light.
And also we are looking to the novel new materials,
like, for example, different Indian composition,
or maybe some 2D materials,
and we're looking into these.
So, when we are utilizing all these different new materials,
new structures, and there are lots of quantum effects in it.
So, therefore, like the current,
and we know that the non-equilibrium Green's function,
this method, like it's solving Schrodinger equation
with using Green's function,
it's a well-accepted method.
So, I'm going to go over why do we need NEGF to do it.
So, what is optoelectronics?
And so, I think the best way to understand optoelectronics,
like it's just a simple PN diet we study in school, right?
So, it's usually a bipolar device,
where by bipolar, I mean, like,
there's electrons and there's holes.
And also there are carriers,
like they're in different equilibrium,
for example, electron,
and they're usually separated by a band gap.
That's why we use semiconductors.
So, having a band gap,
and we kind of segregate the carriers to two kinds,
and the electron is injected by the source, one side.
One contact, we inject electron here,
and the other one is like a hole.
And when they see each other,
and there's interesting thing can happen, right?
There are different processes there.
For example, there's like Shockley-Ree hole,
where electron and hole, they can recombine.
And when they recombine,
they can emit phonon, as known as heat, right?
So, this is like a wasteful energy.
When they recombine through the defects,
the heat is generated and nothing gained.
Well, the heat is gained, but it's not that great.
And there's also radiative recombination,
where when the electron and hole, they see each other,
and they can recombine,
and therefore, they can emit like a photon,
or we can see light here.
And the rate it happens usually is,
and there's like, because like,
for example, first one,
they need to see through a defect here,
and therefore, their proportion is like proportional
to the n-type or p-type,
because one carrier can come to the defect here,
and to wait for the other person to come,
and to recombine.
So, therefore, their rate is proportional to,
you know, either the carrier,
either the electrons or the hole concentration here.
But radiative recombination,
it's, you need,
the rate is proportional to the both of them.
So, you need to have a high electron here,
and high hole concentration here,
to make it happen.
And there's like also another process,
which is OJ recombination.
And this is like a three-particle process,
where the electron and hole,
they can recombine.
But instead of like emitting a photon,
it will kick an electron to a higher energy,
or the opposite.
It's either two electron with one hole,
or two hole with one electron.
But the result is like a waste of energy,
and the chance of doing is something like here.
And, yes.
If you have any questions,
you can ask directly,
or pause the video.
And the other part is a generation process,
where the electron hole,
at this place,
at this depletion region,
we can absorb the photon,
and like create an electron and hole pair.
So, all these processes are needed
to simulate an optoelectronic device.
So, that's what we need to cover,
when we are doing a modeling.
So, why do we need quantum model?
So, let's take a look at a simulation result.
And this is from this paper I'm co-author with.
This is like a simulation result
from a commercialized 3-5 LED.
And as you can see here,
this line here means the density of states,
and the color here is the electron density.
So, the contour line is the density of state, right?
And we can see that the electron is coming from the left side,
and occupying these states here.
And there are holes coming from the other direction.
This is injected here.
And they are going to be in here,
and they will recombine and emit light here.
So, we can see that,
if we really do a quantum simulation,
we can see that there is interference everywhere, right?
For example, all these pattern means,
if you treat them as particles,
it doesn't capture everything, right?
So, for example,
electron, they can tunnel through this barrier,
and through these interference.
So, we really need to make use of the quantum transport,
instead of the semi-classical way.
So, the current state of our tool to do this is to,
I mean, the current way,
I mean, before I published the paper, right?
So, before I was working on this,
the best way to deal with this quantumly
is also from this paper,
where we cut the domain into different pieces,
and then we call some of them the red part,
and also the green part.
So, the green part is like equilibrium.
And why are they in equilibrium?
Because usually the source is highly doped,
and then the drain is also highly doped region.
And when you're highly doped,
there's lots of carrier there,
and they will scatter a lot,
and the carrier there will be in equilibrium.
So, when you are in equilibrium,
we can put a Fermi level here,
saying, oh, this is the Fermi energy in this region,
and this is the Fermi energy,
and there's like Fermi level for electron,
Fermi level for holes in this region.
And there's also the pink part,
where we do, this is non-equilibrium region.
So, this is like the previous way of doing it,
where we do NEGF inside the pink region,
and we just put the Fermi level across here.
So, but this method has some defects,
where we cannot even calculate a simple p-n diet,
because a simple p-n diet,
we cannot really tell which region is non-equilibrium,
which region is equilibrium.
So, it's really hard to do quantum transport
in a p-n diet,
when we are trying to include
all the recombination or generation processes.
So, there are different flavor of quantum transport.
There's like ballistic NEGF,
there's like the one I mentioned,
we cut into different domain,
when we try to do the transport calculation,
and there's like the super expensive SE4,
but none of them can have been,
are able to deal with the p-n diets,
like with the recombination processes.
So, therefore, a new model is needed, right?
And also we can see that,
this is from a super old paper,
why the recombination process is important,
is because when you measure IV curve,
there's like different slope here,
and they are in the results
of different recombination process here,
which later on, I will talk more about that.
So, what's the available way to do,
to deal with carrier transport?
So, here's like a list, a roadmap,
like where you can pick and choose,
depending on your needs.
So, if you are,
so here, the axis,
y-axis here is the computational intensity.
So, I'm going from a super cheap,
super fast turnaround time,
computational cost,
like the semi-classical way,
and all the way to go quantum,
where we need to solve Schrodinger equation,
and using it on any GF methods.
So, I will first go over,
what's the Boltzmann transport equation?
And there are different way to solve it,
like the drift diffusion is the most popular way.
It's the first order,
I think, what is it?
The first order approximation,
not approximation,
but it's a simplification of the BTE,
the famous BTE thing,
and that's like we solve it drift diffusion,
and then we can also use Monte Carlo,
like statistically to gather results
for the BTE equation.
So, what's Boltzmann transport equation?
It's by saying that,
oh, there is a distribution function.
By distribution, we mean,
with the occupation of a different state,
and what does this mean?
Like, we want to ask,
what's the possibility of finding a carrier
at a particular location,
at a particular time,
with a particular momentum?
So, if we can,
for example, inside a device,
there's a different location here,
and for each location,
there is a,
I'm trying to draw this like a momentum,
so carrier with low momentum is here,
and carrier with higher momentum
is on the upper here,
and we are asking,
what's the distribution?
How many particles are in those states?
So, if we know this information
across time, across space,
and for different time and space
and different momentum,
we know this,
then the system is solved, right?
So, and why is this distribution useful?
Because from this distribution function,
we can get the carrier density, right?
Because if we want to ask,
what's the carrier density at this location?
Given the F at this location,
we can just do a sum
and know how much carrier is here.
And if you want to know,
oh, for your device you're working on,
what's the current
that you just do,
get their group of velocity
from the band structure
and you do a sum
with this distribution,
then you can get,
oh, how much current you are gaining
at this location.
So, it's useful
because we can get observable
from this distribution function.
And how do we solve this F?
And it's the BTE Boltzmann.
Boltzmann came up with this, right?
Like the Boltzmann transport equation.
It's the governing equation.
So, the equation is listed here.
And I will just try to show
how we understand different terms.
For example,
the first term means,
oh, if you have carrier
coming in, coming out,
the distribution here
will be related to that, right?
Because you have carrier
flowing into here or flowing out.
And the distribution here will be,
if you have lots of people coming in
and a few going out,
then the distribution here will be higher.
So, this is what the first term means.
And the second term means that
the F means the electric field,
the carrier experience in the charge.
And when you are,
when the carrier is experiencing
electric field, it will accelerate.
And it will change its momentum.
So, here we mean like that,
okay, given the electric field
at this location,
the distribution, you know,
it's related to
the distribution nearby.
So, distribution with a lower momentum,
with a higher momentum,
they can come in and out
because of the electric field
at this location.
And the last one is
if you have like, oh,
other collision inside a device,
for example, a phonon,
an electron can absorb a phonon
or emit a phonon and come to your
this place, if there's a possibility
like that, then this term is trying
to take that into account.
So, we have all this
and all combined. And they can be solved
really expensively by
doing Monte Carlo, by assuming
the distribution function and you start to
run it, oh, how many carrier coming in,
coming out from different momentum space,
then it's super expensive to do that
Monte Carlo. So, but if it's still
too hard, then you can simplify
this BT equation
to a drift diffusion equation,
which is saying that the
current at this place is proportional
to the carrier with the electric
field and the diffusion
with the density gradient.
So, this is, and the full derivation
is in this paper here.
People who are interested can go take
a look.
So, I kind of went over like the
semi-classical way where
the carrier and the device are
like particle-like and then
they can recombine
by solving
the drift diffusion equation and the continuity
equation. That's how we
deal with the
semi-classical way.
And now I'm going to step into the
Schrodinger equation and our
non-equilibrium Green's function.
So, we all know about Schrodinger equation.
It's like, it's
given a Hamiltonian of the system
that you can solve it and then to find
what's the possible eigenenergies
inside the system.
And the Green's function,
I still won't go into details.
I started to disappoint people here.
But like, I think
there are like really useful
material here and like really, I think
Professor Datas did a really good job
on explaining what
an AEGF method is with his
introductory material on
nanoHUB. So, it's all the information
and there's like a
famous book. You can reach out to me and I can
show you like
what's the book you need to read
into. But Green's function,
from our understanding, Green's function
is also
in an engineering term, it's like the response
to an excitation, right?
So usually, oh,
Poisson equation, the Green's function,
if you know the Green's function for a Poisson equation,
then you know, oh,
if you put a charge here, what's the
resulting potential you can get?
So the Schrodinger equation is similar like this.
So you put the H psi,
E psi all into one side
and then you can solve for the Green's function.
And the Green's function is that
if you multiply this
by excitation, then you know what's
the response you will get
inside this device.
So,
here, we will
first go into the ballistic
non-equilibrium Green's function.
So once you, so first you have this
Hamiltonian, and then you can get the
resulting Green's function. And then
by, so here
it's like the Hamiltonian here, and we can get
the Green's function. And using the Green's function,
there's like some key terms.
There's like the G lesser, which is the
the
this is proportional to the carrier
density. So it's like
here's the excitation you have in the system.
And you have like, using the Green's
function, and there's a Gr
and Gr dagger, then you can get the
what's the carrier distribution in the device.
So,
what the
NEGF does is that we are interested
in a part,
only this part of the device. And we are,
we want to say, oh,
we only want to focus on this small region.
And then the left,
we call it, that's a
contact, that's a lead. And we
don't want to care about the information.
It's an infinite,
going left and right.
They are periodically going left
and right. But we don't want to simulate
the entire universe. We only
want to focus on the transistor or the
LED we care about.
So, given this Green's
function, and then we can
for different contact,
if you are contact to the left, and then there's
like a left self-energy
and there's like a right side, there's like a
self-energy here. And with all this self-energy
on the Green's function, you can get what's
the carrier distribution in here.
And when they are in contact
with the reservoir of
a different Fermi level here
on the left side and right side here.
So, but the ballistic
and NEGF, there's no scattering.
So carrier will not scatter with
each other. So how
do we do
including all these scattering
terms in the
NEGF is like, there's a
popular method
that's called Butyprobe method
where it's proposed by Marcus
Butyprobe back in 1980s.
So it's a way to mimic
defacing, which means, aka
the scattering events.
So, we
will try, when we're
injecting the carrier into
the device from the left and right
side. So we're adding more
more these
reservoir inside the device.
So we're taking the electron out and
put it back in, take it out and put it
back in. So in this way, we're
mimicking like carrier
we can randomize the carrier
and the carrier's momentum will go around
and like you can see that
this is more closer to
the real world problem where the
device have scattering.
But this method
was only applicable
to unit polar device. For example,
if you only have electron here, it can only
simulate electrons
scattered inside the device.
So
my work, my PhD
was like to ask a question
whether we can modify this for
bipolar device.
Bipolar
means
when we have, so
can we put like two, when we are
we simulate electron and hole
separately like before, right?
We have electron coming in and electron
coming out and we also simulate the hole
whereas electron coming in, sorry, hole coming
in and hole coming out. And we also
include this probe here to extract
the carrier in, out of
the device and put it back in
and this
way, if we somehow take
the carrier out from
this electron and hole and that's equivalent
to semi-classically
how JIP diffusion model
the Shockley-Ree hole and different processes.
So using this
method, we can
cover
the processes I
mentioned in the optoelectronic device. We can
model Shockley-Ree hole, we can model
radiated, we can model OJ,
we can model all these
effects inside the
enhanced
electrical probe method.
So here is like all
the methodology I've mentioned
where from
cheap to expensive, we have like
JIP diffusion, Monte Carlo's
and the NEGF
and also
in the
NEGF we have like the
ballistical one and also the
what's the time now?
Do we still have time?
Oops.
Oh 540, sorry.
Let me put it back on.
Yeah, so we have like
all the different
methodology here and this is the one
I was mainly working on.
So carriers, they are
wave-like.
So for example,
from before, JIP diffusion and Monte Carlo's
each of the carriers, they are particle-like
and then we are solving
the current continuity equation.
For each location, there is like a quasi-Fermi
level, which means they follow Fermi
direct distribution
and
quantum correction with
artificial.
And there are way people
when using JIP diffusion, you can
couple it with quantum correction like
solving Schrodinger equation
in a certain region and then couple
them with a JIP diffusion and try
to mimic it.
You will have artificial boundary
condition.
When do we choose?
Which is the part we want to solve at quantum?
Where do we solve semi-classically?
So there's lots of confusion
if you are coupling that.
But using NEGF
like if it's
ballistic, it's not
really useful for
optoelectronic because there's no
recombination scattering processes and
there's like the way I mentioned, it's called
multi-equilibrium
way. So some part of it you
simulate, you assume
like there's like an equilibrium there.
But
this method, it requires
like
really, it only
works with, for example, quantum well structure
and inside here, we can
set it to be equilibrium and somehow to
have the carrier recombine.
But in this way, the new
proposed beautiful probe way
where the carriers are always
wavelength and we can have
recombination generation everywhere in the
device and we also can have scattering
consider and
you don't need to say
this part is equilibrium or the other part
is non-equilibrium. So you can simulate
the entire device without
artificial boundary.
And of course, there's the SC Born method
but that's like super expensive and
no one has, I would say
like no one has done like
a simulation like
LED kind of simulation
like with it.
And so later
next one, I will go
to talk about the results.
So first part, I will show that
the importance of recombination.
So here is a picture
showing, this is a structure
where electrons coming
again from the left side here and then
there's a band structure. There's a
band gap in between
this and I crop out in between
and the hole is coming to here.
So
there are two paths that electron
can, there's
a current conducting path, right?
So one path is the blue path where
electron come here and hole come here
and they will recombine and this
current, they can form a current path.
And the other path is the black line
where the carrier come in and can
jump over the barrier to the other side.
So there are two way that the
carrier can
that the current can form.
So here's a comparison with
or without this indium
gallium nitride. So when we form
the quantum well with a lower
band gap material here. So on the two sides
gallium nitride with a larger band gap.
With indium gallium nitride, you can shrink
the band gap and that's why we see this dip
here. And with this, you
can see that comparing the two
the recombination current is
much higher with a quantum well
because inside a quantum well, there's a
higher chance of
carrier here and because
we also know that
the recombination
is proportional to the carrier density
there, right? They want to see each other
they want to recombine. So the more they have
at each location, the more
they can recombine with each other.
So
here I'm trying
to show that
when we do any
gift calculation, when we include
the recombination here
this is a typical
IV curve and we can see that
this is a log scale
current, right? So when we increase
when we increase the drain
voltage, we are pulling
the barrier down
so there are more and more current can go
through to the other side. So
let's focus first on
the low Vd
side. So on the low Vd side
there, you can
see that there's still a barrier here. So
the black current, so the total
current will be, as I said before
there's like two parts. There's a recombine
the electron hole
they can recombine here for a
current path. And there's also the
thermionic current where the carrier can
jump over the barrier to the other side
so this is the two part. And when the
barrier is still high, we can see that the black line
is not in favor because it's hard
for the electron to jump out here. There's like
few particles here to jump out. So
the black part of the current is super
small. And
at this region
the recombination current dominates
so we can see that this is
the
distribution here.
And when we increase
the bias voltage
we're pulling the other side, the barrier down
so as you can see here
right now the black path is easier
the electron can zip through the device
and form a current path
so right now the blue one is
it's still large but
compared to the black one it's much smaller
so this is on off.
So when we include
NEGF, when we do
non-equilibrium Green's function
transport calculation, when we don't
have recombination, which current
do we get? We get the
we don't have
the blue line here so we're only getting
the black. And if we
using this method we're able
to include the recombination process
which means we get the red line
so we're pushing
the boundary of NEGF such that
we can simulate the device
from a black line to a red line
which is a really large difference if you look at
here and
if you look at the
before the threshold voltage there's a
huge current difference with or without
recombination and it
also further impact what's the
threshold voltage. The threshold voltage means
when is your device on
or off. So there's a small shift
here although on a
linear scale but with more recombination
the red and
also the black line will have a larger
shift and therefore a larger impact.
So it's really important to
include the recombination
in your device.
Can I ask a question here?
Yeah, sure.
Can you go back to your previous slide?
Yes.
Maybe
this is a bit stupid but I
thought
recombination
means you have
electron hole pair recombine
and I thought it will
lead to the emission
of phonon or emission of photon
and usually
I would think
recombination is bad
for the current but here you are saying
when you have
smaller bias voltage
the VT is smaller you
actually have higher recombination
energy, recombination
current. Why does recombination
contribute to a current?
To a current?
Or a current?
So there are different
recombination process, right? There's like
I mentioned like there's a
there's radiative recombination
and there's OJ recombination.
So they are all
the consequence of electron hole.
I mean OJ
is the radiative
in the shock wave hole is one electron one hole
and they disappear.
And the shock wave hole is
you emit heat.
Yeah, phonons.
And the radiative is like you emit
photon. And OJ
is like you kick another carrier
to a higher energy, right? So it's useless
too, right? So
not all. Okay, so wait, your question
is, but here
is showing the recombination is
the blue line here, right? So when
your lower VT is lower, when your
higher VT it's
higher.
But, sorry, what
was your question? My question is
I, okay, I
thought recombination
is bad for your, for the current.
Why?
It's bad because
it's
I think some, well
bad is kind of like a subjective, right?
I would call it bad if
I would call it
this is a bad device if most of your
recombination happens for
happen in the way, the shock wave hole way
or OJ, right? So the black
and the red is bad because they don't
produce photon, you don't
produce light, then why are you
recombining? So I think
bad is, okay, it depends
on which process you are
looking at, right? I think
the blue one is good because
I see, I see, because you want a photon
going, I see. Yeah.
Okay. Yes, yes.
Okay, and the relation between
okay, maybe this is
a bit specific, like OJ one
the radiative one and
the phonon one
black, blue, and red.
Are they always in this order?
Won't they cross
at some point if you have different lengths
of the, I think
this X means the size of your
Yeah, because it looks like
they always have red, blue, and black.
Do they ever
cross at some point?
I think I was showing
the interesting
question because I was showing
previously
they have different
relationship, right? So
this is an ABC model
where the
shock wave we hold there is proportional to
n plus p, and the radiative
is n and p, and then
the rate is proportional to n
squared p. So
I think if you engineer it
smartly, you can
control which one dominates.
But somehow in this scenario
the red one is always larger
but if you look at the equation here
it's n squared p
so if you make the p much
smaller, right now it's equally large
n and p are super large both in here
but the real device
I think is more complicated
and maybe in some
way, smart way, you can
shrink, make the blue
dominant and the other two
because relatively they are different, right?
In this case
the red are closer to blue
but here you can see that
the red and blue is farther away
or yeah
I think
there's some way
we can engineer it to make it
some area the blue one
will dominate, yeah.
Is there any other questions?
I have a question here.
So I guess
this case is simple enough
I guess this is probably
just your test case
but this case is simple enough
that you can also use semi-classical
way to do a simulation
so I'm just wondering
how do they compare?
So that's my next topic
it's like comparing on
this really small structure and then
we are using a semi-classical way and also
a quantum way to compute
and then I will show some comparison
here so I think that's the
that will answer your question.
Okay, great, yeah.
So the next one as the question has
elevated us
to this point, so I'm going
to talk about the comparison between the two, semi-classical
and quantum
and how do we compare, how do we make a fair comparison
yes, that's an important question
is that we use the same still
the same small, like the structure I was
showing here is like 20 nanometer
so it's a super tiny structure
and then I'm going to apply
semi-classical method, a drip
diffusion one and also
for the quantum way I'm using
this new method, the butycoprobe
with recombinant generation method
which is the tool our lab
used to work on in grad school
so if you guys are interested in applying for our group
email me and I can give
you more information
so how do we compare this
is that in all the transport
simulation
we're decoupling the transport part
with the part, like
electrostatic part, so we usually do a
self-consistent, we solve for the
where's the electron holes and given
the electron holes and they have charge
and therefore they will form a potential
so we will feed back the carrier
transport and plug it into Poisson
and get a potential and like doing this
like a hundred times or whatever
it's converging, so it's like self-consistently
solving, decouple the two
and solve the Poisson
and just keep on doing until it doesn't
change anymore and then we declare
this simulation is finished
it's converged
so to compare
it's easy because we can
just focus on this part and then for the
carrier we can choose to use
NEGF or we can choose the
semi-classical way of doing it
and when doing the semi-classical way
we also choose to
because Drift Diffusion, to solve these problems
they usually have another quantum correction model
where they are solving just
a confined Schrodinger
but NEGF is more like an open boundary
open boundary Schrodinger
equation, but like
for semi-classical
people, they usually will
couple it with a quantum correction method
which is solving Schrodinger
inside an infinite
quantum
so they will have boundary, but solving Schrodinger
only in that region and try to couple them
together
so the question to answer is
how do we
compare the quantum and semi-classical models
and here is
more of like showing
so the left side is using
the NEGF where
we will have a band structure, right?
we will have the band gap of
I think this is around
0.4 to
so galenitride is like 3.4
electron volts, and inside here
there is like a quantum well
so the actual
will be galenitride
and we assume that it is doped with 1E20
and there is like a region of galenitride
and that will have a smaller band gap
and also the galenitride, and this is like
the structure we are looking into
and in NEGF
we will provide like a
total energy
so the y-axis is the energy range
so you know
here are some states that can be
so here the color means like the density
of states, means like the carrier
can have a possibility to go in
there, but there is some portion of it
like brighter, which means
because of the interference, carrier
doesn't have a
even if you have carrier, it cannot go in
here, so that's what the density of states
means
the NEGF we can provide
is non-equilibrium throughout the entire
device, which means the carrier
doesn't have to follow Fermi-Dirac
distribution everywhere
also we can see that the states
is broadened, so because
you are in contact with the
external source, therefore
the state is broadened
otherwise, if you solve
this in the Schrodinger equation
it's going to be confined
like a
the states is like, you know, it's not
broadened, but here we can see that
for example, quantum well here, it's not a
compared to Schrodinger equation
it's a fixed energy level, because
you are in contact with the surrounding
therefore there is a peak here
and for the drift diffusion
we can see that
here
drift diffusion
equation assume that
in everywhere there is a Fermi
energy, right, and for this Fermi energy
follows the Fermi distribution
which means the carrier will
be Fermi distribution everywhere
with different Fermi energy
and also
we are solving the quantum
using this Q-well method
in ATLAS, which is solving Schrodinger equation
here, so that's why we can have this
red wave function
square here, so that's the wave function
form, and how is it solved? It's by solving
Schrodinger equation only in this
region, so we are defining
a region where we want to solve this
closed boundary Schrodinger
equation, and we are trying to couple this
to the drift diffusion methods
and there is like several parameters
for example, in a drift diffusion
you have ABC
parameters for the recombination
like the circularity hole, the phonon
the photon, and also the
other ones, the OJ, so there is
like the parameters for it, and we are using the same ABC
and
in drift diffusion, there is like a mobility
term, where for
NEGF is called self-energy, which is
the scattering rates
in the device, and that will, in a
semi-classical way, that's called the mobility
so we need to find
a corresponding, oh given this mu
what's the scattering rate in the device
and therefore what's the self-energy we are using
in NEGF, and
for drift diffusion
when you are, there is a density of
states, and you are assuming
you will
get a carrier, so there is
for different M
for different effective mass, you
correspond to different density of states, and therefore
carrier, for
NEGF we are using
we can support tight binding
different way
to describe this EK
relationship, so
that's the corresponding, right
we can also use effective mass, or we can use
tight binding method, or KRP, or
one-year functions
so the basis
there is a little bit different, in drift diffusion we can only support
so this is how we
couple them
so
I'm only going to show that
the direct comparison
from observable we can see
so for example, on the right side
this is showing
the solid line is the drift diffusion
result, and you can see that
this is the carrier density across the device
we have high electron on one side
and we have high hole on the other side
and they are penetrating into each
into the other side
and we can see that the drift diffusion
here is much lower
this is log scale, so it's like
ten to the fifth, the five times
smaller than the
quantum transports method, right
and the reason is
understandable, because
when you look into here
the electron, you know
the NEGF, you can
what is it like, the
when you bounce a ball to the wall, the semi-classical will bounce
back, but quantum
you can penetrate into the wall, right
so you can see that analogy here
where you still have some density
of states inside the barrier
where the semi-classical will just say
there's nothing, you bounce
into this wall and you will go back directly
so this is like the ball analogy
so that's why
when you're doing quantum transport
this carrier inside
here is higher, much higher
ten to the fifth time higher because of the
penetration here
but otherwise
the potential is pretty
matched here, but the carrier
difference here will cause you
to calculate the
recombination rate different, right
because you have higher density, therefore your
recombination rate will be
different, so that's why
the potential looks
the same between quantum way
and semi-classical way, however
the recombination rate calculated from
which is a post-process
using ABC model to predict
oh, what's the OJ
the photon and also the OJ related
process, there's a huge difference
at lower bias, you can see here
the quantum way
because you have more penetrated electrons
for them to recombine
therefore you have a much higher recombination rate
and for higher bias
they're pretty much similar
but small difference here
okay
and this case
before I was talking about a HOMO
junction where we're using
galenitride all across but with
different doping, and here is a heterojunction
where similar things
are done, we're comparing
the carrier
density and we can see that oh, there's
some difference here
right, like the semi-classical
we have a sharp discontinuity
probably because we chose
the boundary different but
which part should we solve Schrodinger
it's pretty subjective
so I'm putting
all the things here and seeing
that there is an impact
like with or without
diffusion like, or any
like what's the impact on carrier density
and here
trying to show the recombination with
in this heterojunction, we can also see that
because
drift diffusion coupled with
Schrodinger equation, therefore
we can see that the recombination rate after
doing this is pretty similar
so
I think this is like a
positive side about drift diffusion, it's pretty fast
and with coupling to like quantum
correction, it's matching
GF pretty well, so it's like
also kind of giving confidence but also giving
saying like oh, drift diffusion is not that bad
like you can still
quantumly correct it
with solving Schrodinger impartial
region
and here I'm trying
to show the I-V difference
for a homojunction device
so in a homojunction device, if you
measure the I-V curve, and here
the solid line is the drift diffusion, and the circle
is the quantum well, and we can see
that
the off current
there's like a larger difference
between them, and if you
have, if you compare the
heterojunction device using the
and there's some difference here
and there, but just like
providing the comparison here
and this
method, we can further
you know, solving, we're
enabling any GF to be able to
solve like
carrier generation, because we are
injecting the, we can
assume the light come in and
producing electron hole and
and give them, separate them
to generate current here, right?
So here's the simulation results like
using any GF, and this is like the
the first
the first tool that we can cover
all processes into, including
generation, and then to enable a device
simulation
So here
the summary, I kind of review
different carrier transport method
from BTE all the way to any
GF, and providing the references there
if you're interested, or can ask, email me
for more information, and this
is like, this work is to propose
a really generic
method for recombination
generation process inside the
any GF framework, so we're enabling
any GF community to
approach problem like recombination
generation, and we
show the importance, oh, for any GF
with or without recombination, what's the
difference, and why do we need it, and we
also benchmark against like GF diffusion
based TCAD tool, and to
see that, we can see that the charge is different
and with or without methods, and
also we can show that there's
tunneling and wave phenomena here
and I know
and lastly, if there's any
study group, or
want to discuss this, I think
it's very helpful to discuss
if you have any questions
or any questions
about this, you can email me
yeah, okay
is everyone still here?
okay, still here, so let's
first,
everyone please turn on the mic
to applaud, and thank the audience
so now,
do we have any questions?
that you want to ask
if you have questions,
just turn on the mic
okay
okay, I want to ask
a question that's not
that related
I'm curious
how long have you been at Intel?
about
a year
so
do you need
when you're doing these simulations
do you need to
communicate with the people doing the experiments?
some people
this isn't my Intel work, this is my study group's work
and Intel
yeah, I think
they'll communicate with
the people doing the experiments
for example, they have some data
you take this
simulation
when you're taking these
when you're explaining these simulations
and communicating with the people doing the experiments
do you feel like
there's a gap?
I think there is
but I think they'll
draw the problem to
yeah, it's not
if they're looking for you
they might think
this might be related
so for example
like
when you're doing these simulations
when you're discussing with the people doing the experiments
can you compare with the people doing the experiments?
or are there some
trends
when you're explaining the experiments
how do you
when you're discussing with the people doing the experiments
work with the people doing the experiments?
it's a bit abstract, I don't know how to explain it
for example
can you use these tools
to explain their data?
or can you provide
based on this data
maybe an improved direction
is this doable?
that kind of feeling
sorry, it's a bit abstract
I think it is
let me use Boban as an example
Boban's project
people might say
is it because of the recombination
causing the current to get smaller or more
if you make the defects level
bigger or smaller
I think it's more of a trend
if you increase the defects
can you see the curve
100% match the experiment data
but you might say
if this phenomenon
more defects, will my recombination rate get bigger or smaller?
you can experiment
experiment and simulate
I think a lot of problems
are not that
you need to model
to say it's really this phenomenon
you might observe
the current getting bigger
but you don't know why
you might say
you can make this adjustment
or add stress
there are a lot of things you can change
in simulation, there are a lot of parameters you can change
you might adjust the defects level
or adjust
all kinds of parameters
to confirm
I think this feedback
is quite important
to identify
if what you said is right
I think you can verify
if it's correct
another question
I know you are talking about
what Boban did
another question
after you joined Intel
do you think you are much better than Boban?
I think I'm much better
I feel
much better
so actually
I think this thing
is
already
considered
a simple geometry
but it can be
considered as a real device
quantity
after you joined
you will find
there are a lot of differences
it's just
the research field is different
I think the form
is similar
you mostly look at the paper
and see what model you can use
but I feel
in Boban's case
the professor tells you
what to do
it's more specific
but in the company
it's hard to say
I want to say
I'm also in the TK department
I'm working at TSMC
I actually
know a bit about this field
but now
maybe I shouldn't ask
my problem is
when I talk to Boban
he always says
you are right
these things
need to be discussed
I feel
it's hard
I don't know if Intel
feels the same
different companies
might have different
I won't
talk to an experimenter
I might talk to an intermediary
it's different
any other questions?
I want to ask
the simulation
looks simple
and
it looks like
using Boltzmann's
equation can be done
even though you need
some approximations
but
I'm thinking
the advantage of this
is it's more effective
on more difficult
devices
but I feel
in BTE
let's say it's particles
if it's particles
can you simulate
these details?
you can't
so if it's particles
you're missing a lot of details
but the result I'm showing
is that some drift diffusion
is a lot worse
some are similar
but
I mean
how do you know your future device
when it's particles
will you miss
some important details
I think BTE
can't be replaced
even in this small device
you can't say BTE is correct
did you say BTE or drift diffusion?
drift diffusion
you mean
Monte Carlo solve BTE
but even so
like interference
or tunneling
BTE
you can't figure it out
you need a lot of correction models
BTE is how to scatter particles
you need to calculate
you need to add a lot of calculations
but NEG
you throw the device in
the result is
low density of state
there's a pattern
but BTE can't figure it out
I see
but the pattern you drew
is this equilibrium?
like
this is
density of state
what do you mean?
density of state is
density of state under equilibrium
density of state and
is it equilibrium are separate
because density of state
doesn't have so many states
equilibrium means
you have a distribution function
Fermi-Dirac distribution
the bottom is 1
the top is 0
so given this density of state
you fill the Fermi-Dirac distribution
drift diffusion
means any device
is Fermi-Dirac
let me draw
let me see
which one is better
like this
drift diffusion
you have a Fermi-Level
this is Fermi-Level
your distribution is
this is 1 and this is 0
this is distribution
0 to 1
any position
is bound by Fermi-Level
Fermi-Level is lower here
my distribution is like this
to here
there may be some small changes
NEG means
carrier distribution
any place is not necessarily Fermi-Distribution
you are very free
particle you want to be higher
you want to be lower
your distribution may be like this
not necessarily Fermi-Distribution
but now we are bound by contact
in the middle of the device
is it
how much will the distribution change
your carrier is from the left
your left is Fermi-Distribution
right
this is Fermi-Distribution
but when your carrier
travel to here
will you change
you bounce around
bounce here
you may not be Fermi-Distribution
this is the advantage of NEG
you will not be limited by drift diffusion
you are bound
you have to distribute like this
understand
ok
any more questions
if not
I want to ask the last question
you are
in the second slide
you talked about
photon absorption
your photon absorption
is only in the middle
in the middle
junction
or the whole system
is affected by photon
this is a toy model
so I only hit
the green area
I should be
later I will publish another paper
but
I assume
only hit a certain area
from here to here
plus generation rate
how do you
deal with photon
I didn't simulate photon
because of photon
the electrons and electrons
will run out every second
so I didn't simulate photon
suppose photon is absorbed
one photon
you just
move it up
one photon
suppose
it moves up
so I assume
this band gap
is 3.2eV
or
I don't know
let's say 3eV
assume
a photon above 3eV
comes in
you can
split carrier hole
electron hole pair
ok
so you assume
electron hole pair is split
and start
simulation
ok, got it
any questions?
if not
let's thank
Guan Zhong
thank you
I'll turn off the recording