Hello everyone, I am the host of today's Taira Talk on September 18th, Hong Shih-an.
We are very happy to invite the Sky in the World comedy science team to share with you the spirit of science communication.
Like Taira, the comedy science team is made up of doctoral students or post-doctoral students.
They also want to promote the concept of science.
However, what is different from Taira is that they are more towards the public,
and they will share their life from a scientific perspective.
I have personally listened to their podcasts several times, and I think what they say is very close to the life of a graduate student.
I highly recommend everyone to listen to their podcasts.
They also run a clubhouse.
Without further ado, let's get into today's topic, the spirit of science communication.
Wallace, we'll leave it to you now.
Okay, sure.
The stage is yours.
What?
Okay, so I'm going to share my screen now.
Everyone has prepared a video.
Let me know if you can see it.
Yes.
Okay.
Thank you, Shih-an, for the introduction.
I'm one of the editors of the comedy science team.
I'm the screenwriter.
I'm very happy to have this opportunity to talk to you about science communication.
Seeing today's title, the spirit of science communication,
you may have a question.
What is the difference between science communication and science?
Why do we need the title of science communication?
Let's share our thoughts with you in the next hour.
Welcome to share your opinions.
First of all, let me introduce myself.
Okay, he can't go to the next page.
Okay, here we go.
I'm Liu Yuru.
I'm the founder and editor of Sky Interworld.
My nickname is Wall, so you can call me Wall Editor.
My English name is Wallace.
It's a long name, I know.
Sky Interworld started as a podcast and blog in 2006.
It's kind of like my personal thing.
I was originally alone.
When I went to the UK to study,
I was busy writing my thesis.
It's been a while since then.
I came back to Taiwan in 2019.
I joined the overseas talent bridge project called LIFT.
I met a lot of super cool overseas Taiwanese,
including Xiao Ji, Dou Dou, CBN, and so on.
So did Adam.
The most important thing is that I found this group of friends.
We are willing to make an impact
and do something for Taiwan.
Let's reopen the Sky Interworld podcast.
For more than a year,
we've been running Facebook, Instagram,
podcasts, and Clubhouse events on Sky Interworld.
We're very active on these platforms.
We have a lot of articles.
We have a podcast every week.
We also have a book club every month on Clubhouse.
We also have other editors
coming to play with us.
We currently have eight permanent editors,
including myself.
I'll be sharing with you later
Xiao Ji, CBN, CS, CBN, and Dou Dou.
Let me tell you about your locations.
Xiao Ji is in Milan, Italy.
CS is in the east coast of the United States.
Dou Dou is in Paris, France.
Adam is in the west coast of the United States.
CBN is in Switzerland.
Alan is in the north of Taiwan.
CBN is in the Czech Republic.
Most of us are postdoctoral researchers
or teachers at school.
Our articles are also posted
on different platforms.
For example, Science News,
National Daily, and World News.
I don't know why World News likes us.
Some of these events
have attracted a lot of attention.
Some people are willing to jump in
and join us.
For example,
a marine biologist
at the coast of Maryland.
He is a senior
in the US marine policy.
He is a senior.
A British citizen
will also join us
at Clubhouse.
Sometimes he will join our recording.
Last week,
Tyra gave a talk.
She is a senior
in the Netherlands.
She is a senior in higher education.
She is also a very important
source of advice and help.
The article and podcast
published by Sky in the World
are all from academic journals.
The content of the podcast
includes food and science,
interviews with people
who care about cancer development,
a doctor's seminar
for researchers,
and a fitness seminar
for everyone's health.
Adam is the host.
The content of the article
includes interesting research,
academic work,
environmental-related reports,
and support for cancer development in academia.
The purpose of the article
is to promote the scientific logic
and spirit of the article
through humor.
The translation of the article
will be different.
For example,
Michael Bonkowski
will be translated as
Michael Collision Driver.
Elizabeth Beak
will be translated as
Elizabeth Beak.
The purpose of the article
is to promote
the scientific logic
and spirit of the article
through humor.
In addition,
we hope that
everyone will pay attention
to the article.
Sometimes it will be dissed,
sometimes it will be praised.
The reaction is a bit two-dimensional,
but at the same time,
it also creates a topic.
The purpose of the article
is to promote
the scientific logic
and spirit of the article
through humor.
The purpose of the article
is to promote
the scientific logic
and spirit of the article
through humor.
We do not make any profit
by doing this.
Of course,
those who support us
will be very happy.
But we do not make any profit
by doing this.
Let's start with
the history of science.
In January 1665,
the French emperor Louis XIV
was called Colbert.
In order to honor
the Sun King,
he published the first
academic journal,
which you can see
in the upper left corner.
Its translation is
called The Scholar's Journal.
In March of the same year,
the Royal Academy of Sciences
also began a report on natural science.
It was the beginning of
scientific dissemination,
the beginning of scientific journals.
In the scientific field
of scientists,
they began to communicate
with each other.
At that time,
in Europe in the 17th century,
science was already developed
in the Roman era.
There was no need
to challenge existing knowledge.
Therefore,
many scientific experiments
and new ideas
came from science
as an entertainment activity
for the rich.
Why do we need money?
Look at the picture
below,
the boy and the girl.
The girl is his wife.
The experiment equipment
on the table in front
is made of glass.
The glass is so big
that it blows into
various strange shapes.
At that time,
it was very expensive,
so only the upper class
would play with it.
Of course,
such scientific dissemination
was only limited to
the upper class.
However,
with the rapid development of science,
science is no longer
just an entertainment activity
for the rich.
It will become a factor
that affects life in all aspects.
From the change of people's lifestyle
to the formation of public policy,
modern people need
scientific logic and concepts
to avoid becoming a bright world
that leads everyone
to become scientific journalists.
In Taiwan,
there is no such thing.
When you hear the word
science,
people think it's nonsense.
For example,
people are waiting
to hear some useless
British research.
I also watched the ad
of Vogue magazine.
I was very curious
about the science of fashion.
When I was teaching Vogue,
I thought
the word science
had been misused.
At that time,
I thought I should buy
a new dictionary
to see if the definition
of science had changed.
Because science
had been distorted,
several editors
from Sky Inner World
decided to disseminate
the concept of scientific life
in our lab
through various
social media platforms
to attract more
listeners.
At the same time,
we also care about
friends in the academic circle
and hope to share
the opinions of the editors
to help more friends
who are interested
in science and want to
learn more about
the science of comedy.
Hi, everyone.
I'm Xiao-Ji.
First of all,
if we want to make
science successful,
we need to let the general public
know what PhD is.
We need to know
what PhD is.
This is an introduction
from a professor in the US,
who introduces PhDs
every autumn.
I think this picture
is very interesting.
I think many people have seen it.
Let's recall it.
First of all,
you see a circle.
This circle represents
the knowledge of all humans.
Next.
You see a blue dot in the middle.
This is where we started
to learn about the world
We are in the middle.
Next.
As we grow up,
we learn more and more knowledge.
From elementary school,
high school, and university
to the university,
we start to have a specialization.
Our knowledge starts to go in a certain direction.
After the specialization,
we may have read a master's degree.
Finally, we decide to
get a PhD.
As our knowledge goes forward,
we have to face
the unknown.
As we face the unknown,
we work hard
to study
what others don't know.
After many years of struggle,
we finally have a new discovery.
Next.
As we move forward,
the knowledge of all humans
takes a small step.
This small step is
our life experience.
Next.
From our perspective,
we stand here
and look at
where the knowledge of all humans
is.
I think I have made
a big step.
Next.
When we look back,
we realize that
the knowledge of all humans
is very small.
So, the PhD is
right.
We may call it
Psychology.
I don't like the name.
On the other hand,
we are PhDs
because
we learned
how to
face the unknown systematically
and
learn new knowledge.
We can apply
this method
to other areas.
Even if we make a breakthrough,
we can apply this method
to other areas.
We must remember this.
If we forget that
what we learned is not only professional knowledge,
but also a whole set of research methods,
we will become advanced technicians.
We are just technicians
who know how to operate
strange machines.
Next.
When we do research,
we need to face the unknown.
We often say that we need to learn the ivory tower.
It seems that what we do
has nothing to do with everyday life.
Of course, we need to learn the ivory tower,
but why is it there?
It makes sense.
Next.
When we face the unknown,
no one knows the answer.
How can we find the answer?
We can only make assumptions.
We always make assumptions
and try to prove it.
We always end up
at the bottom of the theory.
Even if we can prove it,
we still need to apply it in our daily life.
There is a big difference between theory and reality.
For example,
I am doing diagnostic research.
We often say that
early diagnosis means early treatment.
Early diagnosis is a great topic.
I made a result.
This result
is a simple
example.
A week before a patient caught a cold,
I knew he had a cold.
So I went to my boss.
Boss,
I found something.
A week before a patient caught a cold,
I knew he would have a cold next week.
I can tell him
if he will have a cold next week.
My boss is a doctor.
He told me that
it is useless.
What if I have a cold next week?
I said yes.
There is a big difference between theory and reality.
Theoretically, early diagnosis
is a good thing.
But when we apply it,
there are more considerations.
Next slide.
Second,
we want to quantify science.
In order to quantify science,
we need a set of tools
to tell us the final result.
This set of tools is statistics.
Statistics is a very powerful tool.
But there is a limitation.
First,
when we do research,
we can't
study everyone.
For example,
if I want to study a patient,
I can't study all the patients in the world.
We may see a scientific article
about a breakthrough in cancer treatment.
We successfully treated this cancer.
If you read that article,
they successfully treated five patients.
Can these five patients
represent all the cancer patients in the world?
This is the sample
we got today.
Can the sample represent
the entire population?
Another example is
the presidential election.
Before the presidential election,
there were many polling stations.
Polling is a different
example of the same country.
This is the sample.
If the voters
support this candidate,
the result will be different.
Today,
the first point of statistics
is whether the sample can
reflect the reality of the society.
The second point of statistics is
when we do scientific research,
we can see the difference in statistics.
In short,
it tells you that
the result is very likely to be right.
In other words,
there must be a possibility that the result is wrong.
Even if we
make a very beautiful result,
there is no way
to be 100% sure
that the result is right.
In the development stage of science,
the key point is that
we can't know
whether we are right or wrong.
So when do we know
the result is right?
We have to wait
for different scientists
from all over the world
to test the result
in different ways
to make sure
that the result is right.
At this point,
we can apply the results
to our daily lives.
So today,
when we face the unknown
in front of the academic circle,
what we do
will really make a difference in our lives.
Most of the things
we do
cannot be applied
to our daily lives in an instant.
But when we finally
make a mature decision
to apply it to our daily lives,
we have to promote it to the public.
Let's move on to the next slide.
Today, we published an academic article.
What do you think
about it?
First of all,
academic articles require
very precise writing.
So today,
the sentence must be clear.
We can go back and read the paper
and still can't find the sentence.
The sentence is still in English.
When you translate it into Chinese,
it's even more difficult to understand.
But academic articles require accuracy.
You really can't delete a single word.
So it's a very painful reading experience
for most people.
Second,
academic articles have too many
special names and are very long.
So we start to abbreviate.
I don't even know
whether it's an abbreviation
or an abbreviation.
So for most people,
it's really hard to remember.
Third,
as I said,
when we write an article,
it may be overturned.
Even if the probability is very low,
the probability that I wrote
1% or 0.1% is not correct.
I can't speak slowly.
So we usually end up
writing that our research results
support the theory of A very much.
But at the same time,
B and C may also be correct.
At the same time,
we do not rule out the possibility
that D is also correct.
So basically,
these three sentences sum up.
In short,
if you see it,
you don't understand it.
If we let scholars
directly talk to the public,
there will be a second question.
First,
when we talk about science,
we become scholars.
Everything must be very clear.
Everything must be very correct.
So even the words we say
are almost the same as
the paper we wrote.
So the public may not understand
what they see or hear.
In fact, the level of understanding
has not improved.
The second question is
Captain
We have technical issues.
The second question is
because we are learning
science today,
it teaches us not to criticize.
So as long as we hear something wrong,
we immediately want to point it out.
We are trained to ask questions
that are very clear and correct.
Just like we talked about
in a previous podcast,
many people
start to get red
after eating seafood porridge.
Many people say they are allergic.
But in some cases,
they are actually poisoned, not allergic.
So you can imagine
that a friend came to me and said,
Xiaoxi, I just ate seafood porridge
and I'm allergic to red.
What should I do?
The point of this question is
But when my scholar soul
came up, I heard this question,
I just wanted to tell him that
you are not allergic, you are poisoned.
This is very accurate and important to me.
But this is not helpful
to the people who are asking for answers today.
So I think
when we are in contact with ordinary people,
we must suppress our scholar soul.
We have to be able to accept
that maybe this question is very broad
and not so accurate,
but it doesn't matter.
If we get the information
he wants to know today,
can we give him a simple
take-home message after the explanation?
After listening to a bunch of academic analysis,
he can still have a very clear
1, 2, 3 to follow.
And then
if we find out today
that he asked this question too broadly
and couldn't answer it,
this is usually the case.
Can we explain to him
how complicated this question is
so that the answer is not so easy?
So next time
if he encounters any false information,
just tell him so simply.
Maybe he can understand
that it's not that easy.
Because
this may not be true.
Because I know this thing is very difficult.
So in the end,
when we want to pass science to the general public,
the most important thing is
the skill of speaking and the art of communication.
This is actually very lacking
in our doctoral training.
But in fact,
in the future,
it is very important in life.
This kind of communication is not just internal.
We communicate with people in our lab,
with scholars in our field,
with scholars in other fields,
and even with the general public.
We all have different skills of communication.
There are even those above and those below.
I found something today.
How do I convince my boss?
He must support me.
In addition to my professional skills,
I also need to learn
the rules of science.
How do I pass this spirit
to the next generation?
So in the end, the most important thing is communication.
Speaking of communication,
let's give the floor to CS.
Have you heard my voice?
Yes.
I don't know how.
Okay.
CS can't come today.
He has a recording.
I'll play it here.
I'm going to share
with you
the starting point
of Sky in the World.
I'll share with you
the starting point of Sky in the World.
Sky in the World
has many hosts.
Everyone is in
almost different countries,
even different time zones.
Everyone has a different background.
In the interview
we invited,
in the interview
we invited
very experienced
professors
who are about
the same age as us,
but very good at teaching.
We also found a position
for seniors
who are
older than us.
Sometimes
through
Facebook fan page,
we also met
people who asked
if they should study in a PhD program.
Things like that.
This kind of
horizontal communication
between peers
and seniors
is a kind of
horizontal communication.
How do we
coordinate?
At the beginning of the sharing,
I'm going to ask
this question first.
It's on PowerPoint.
1 plus 1.
What's the answer
to this 1 plus 1?
Some people might think it's 2,
a very simple number.
Some people might think it's 2.
Or some people might think
1 drop of water plus 1 drop of water
is a big number.
Or 1 mouse plus 1 mouse
is a bunch of mice.
There are many answers.
When I first
joined Sky and World,
when faced with some questions,
my reaction was
2.
It's very certain.
There's no room for compromise.
In this world,
2 is the only standard answer.
Then,
I realized
that other hosts
have a different
reaction from me.
Why can they
ask questions
to so many people?
Today,
I started to
see how they
ask questions.
I found one thing
different from my experience.
What they think
is the connection
between their profession
and the question.
Or,
what's the connection
between their life
and the question
we're going to discuss?
It's a very special way.
When I started
to think in this direction,
when I removed
the standard answer frame
to the scientific question,
I also removed
the frame
from myself.
I stopped thinking
about the standard answer
or the pathway
or mechanism
it should follow.
I stopped
thinking
in a certain way.
I also removed
the frame
from others.
I think
they should
think in the same way.
But I started
to accept,
to discover,
to feel
their way of thinking.
I found that
the question became so interesting.
The question became so interesting.
In all sciences,
we introduce
history,
chemistry,
immunology,
or brain science.
We often introduce
very special foods
that people have never thought of.
We want
the audience
to feel
the same connection
between
their favorite
history,
science,
or
the life
they have never thought of.
Some people
like
special things.
It sounds
like
we can't find the answer.
But if we
find it,
it will be very rich.
This is what I want to say.
We should remove the frame.
We should remove
the frame
that has been
in the academic circle
for a long time.
We should think
how to connect
the theme.
We should
think through
other people's questions
and thoughts.
Why don't I have
other thoughts?
This kind of thought
is very good.
But science is a
subject that
we can think about
from various angles.
We should
communicate with each other
and
remove the frame.
What about the audience?
When we face
many seniors
or
when we become
their seniors,
do we
remove the frame?
Of course we do.
We remove the frame
because
there is
a gap between us.
Some people are up, some people are down.
Sometimes we are down, others are up.
Sometimes we become
other people's seniors.
Some people are up, some people are down.
In this case,
how should we
face the audience?
Do we
have to listen to
the seniors?
Do we have to
ask questions
or
ask our questions?
If we keep doing this,
we can't do the program.
We can't record the program.
We can't give a speech,
but we can't interview.
What we did
was
to remove
the focus
from the position
and
move to
the topic we wanted to discuss.
Whether it's a
science or
an interview,
the topic is neutral.
When we focus
on these issues,
we can jump
out of the
top-to-bottom
and
discuss a topic,
instead of
looking at what the elders
want to say to us.
It's not the same.
We can still learn
from the elders
in the interview.
When we discuss
with the elders,
we can
also learn from them.
However,
learning is not
about who
should learn, who should listen,
who should share, who should listen.
Instead,
this topic
is very interesting.
Let's think about
the starting point
for different people.
What would it look like?
In the interview,
we often
discuss
the topic
as
it sounds
neutral.
However,
it can be
exciting.
In this case,
we can learn
how to
understand
the atmosphere
and the process.
The most important thing
is that
we can
discuss
the topic
first.
Then,
we can
focus on
the topic.
This is what I want to share
with you today.
Actually,
we have heard about
frameworks.
Frameworks often
appear in our life.
I want to
remind you
that
we should
learn from
the elders.
Now,
let's welcome
Ren.
I want to
remind you
that
we should
learn from
the elders.
I want to
remind you
that
we should
learn from
the elders.
I am a health-related
scientist.
I am doing research
on sports.
We all know
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
Many scholars
are thinking about
how to
deal with
death.
This is my
evidence-based research.
However,
it does not
happen naturally.
I am from
the US.
NIH
did not mention
clinical trial.
From T0 to
T3 and T4,
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
I want to
remind you
that
it is not
a matter of
one or two days.
Before we look into
some of the
previous experiences,
we hope
that we can
invite
more
seniors
to share
their experiences
and thoughts.
Later, our audience
may gradually shift to
doctors or researchers,
researchers and employees.
However,
we hope that
the public
will be able to
see and understand
what scientific debate
looks like.
I know that
a lot of people
who study literature
or sociology
think that
scientific debates are
a bit deep,
but the jokes are funny.
I think that's enough.
I don't know if that answers
your question.
Is Alan speaking?
I just want to
add something.
Our team discussed
that we need people
with a literary background
or an artistic background
to discuss with us.
So,
we don't mean
to attack the literary community.
They can understand
these scientific things.
Absolutely.
Some of the people
we often collaborate with,
such as Clubhouse,
we have invited professors
from the Department of Philosophy
at the University of Miami.
This is a wonderful
field of study.
We can get to know
a lot of wonderful fields
through this platform.
We've never thought about
biotechnology or biophysics.
We've never heard of them,
but we've invited them
so that we can get to know
these different fields.
This is a part of cross-communication.
Scholars from different fields
communicate with each other
through this platform.
This is one of the things
we want to do.
This platform is very free.
In today's presentation,
the content is very free.
You can choose a topic
and go home to prepare.
You don't have to say
what you want to say.
It's a platform
you can use.
Any other questions?
I'd like to ask
a question about
what makes you feel
connected to the
Department of Philosophy.
I think it's about
choosing a boss.
I've been thinking
about
choosing a boss.
There was a talk
by Tara
from the Department of Chemistry
in Houston.
She said
she had prepared
a talk
about choosing a boss.
I talked to her
about it.
I think
we all have a common conclusion
that choosing a boss
is more than 50% by luck.
You've made
a lot of decisions
along the way,
but sometimes
by luck is a good decision.
I think
it's okay.
I feel the same way.
I think
the benefits of this platform
are quite interesting.
First,
I want to share
these things
so that people
on the same path
can have a better reference.
I also want to tell them
that if you make a decision,
it turns out that it's not a good decision
and it's not your problem.
It seems like
you have a lot of stories
to share.
You're welcome to join us.
Actually,
Sky in the World
has a good thing.
These people
have a lot of connections
in their interpersonal relationships.
We have some
internal information
about some
recruits
or job positions.
Editors
will share with each other.
If you join our team,
you'll hear a lot about
where to apply.
My job now
is to introduce.
Like you said,
sometimes you
accidentally throw it out.
Is there anyone
you know
who thinks it's suitable for this job?
Maybe some people
catch it.
Yeah.
Go ahead.
I just want to say
that I heard
the podcast
and I felt very allergic.
But there was a episode
about the clinical trial
and IRB.
I don't think it's right.
I really want to oppose it.
So I want to join this team
and discuss with you.
Yeah.
It's politically correct.
Whether it's an article
or a podcast,
we welcome people
to make mistakes.
We don't always
present our expertise.
So it might be wrong.
If people are willing
to make mistakes,
it's a discussion.
I think it's good.
I think science should be like this.
You present it
and we challenge it.
We present different opinions.
I agree with what you said.
I remember
listening to
the podcast
about how to choose a boss.
I'm very similar to Sinda.
It's like
a PhD student
or someone who
used to be a PhD student
will have
an interest
in listening.
If you think of
a topic you want to listen to,
you can throw it away.
Or you can join
our PhD chat.
I have a lot of
Facebook fans
who comment
on the topics
they want to hear.
We listen to them
and discuss them.
If you have
any ideas
or topics
you think
are worth discussing,
you're welcome.
You can also
ask questions
about your daily life.
For example,
what is sashimi?
Why can it be eaten raw?
Or what is cooked meat?
They can just throw it away
and we can
make food science for them.
Sounds great.
I have some
questions.
How do you manage the platform?
It sounds like
your audience
is the general public.
But sometimes
when it comes to
PhD topics,
it feels like
you have to be a PhD student
to want to listen.
This audience
looks like a PhD student.
How do you decide
in the middle?
For example,
what kind of audience
do you have?
Do you have a balance?
I'd like to know how you manage it.
The podcast part?
Allen, do you want to answer?
I was just kidding.
Please go ahead.
No, I'm just stressed
and bored.
You can continue.
We're all funny.
No, I'm just kidding.
For the podcast part,
we're quite
familiar with
the team.
We have a LINE group.
Every week,
once a month,
I'll organize the recording schedule.
For example,
we'll decide what to record
on a certain weekend.
We'll decide the topic
we want to talk about.
It's very simple.
For example, food science.
We'll throw the food on the table
and cook it into meat.
Or, for example,
we want to talk about
academic ghost stories.
We'll think about it.
Then,
during the recording session,
we'll have a chat
and talk freely.
We'll say what we want
to talk about.
Sometimes, the recording session
takes a long time.
But it's okay.
We can edit it.
For the audience,
we don't have a specific
target audience.
But I have
a separate target audience
for each topic.
For example,
for food science,
I'll talk about science.
For doctoral studies,
I'll talk about
those who are on the path
to become a doctor.
Or those who are already
on the path to become a doctor.
And so on.
For the gym,
I'll talk about
those who are
studying science.
Scientists
don't have much time to exercise.
But Adam will
tell everyone to exercise.
So, listen to Adam's lecture
once a month.
He'll tell you to exercise
for at least two or three days.
Just like me.
So, we'll use the theme
to distinguish our audience.
What do you think,
editors?
I really
don't care about
these things.
I joined the team
because I wanted to
be a rock band.
I was very happy
to join the team.
I've learned a lot.
We're all from different backgrounds.
So, for management,
I'm the leader.
For example,
Adam, Xiao Ji,
they all run
Instagram and Facebook.
So, they really
know
the behind-the-scenes
of the team.
Xiao Ji is amazing.
She's the big manager
of our Instagram.
I've been lost lately.
I'm addicted to mobile games.
Are you still playing
the mobile game?
Yes, I am.
We have to be scientific.
I've been wondering
if anyone is still playing
the mobile game.
Xiao Ji said so,
but our Instagram
has almost 1,000 followers.
It's been a long time.
If I'm still playing,
I should have 1,000 followers
last month.
I've been working lately,
so I don't have much time.
Otherwise, we would have 5,000 followers.
At first,
some people said
their social media
would explode
and 50 people would die.
We can't join.
We don't need to buy
anything.
Only 10 people will come.
I'm sorry.
It's a cold joke.
Before we started,
Jason told us
that Tyra's speech
would explode
sometimes.
But we haven't
encountered such a situation.
I saw a few viewers
turn on the camera.
Do you want to ask questions?
Yes.
Please ask.
Hello.
I'm a student
at Tsinghua University.
I've been writing
science fiction articles
and fan magazines.
I want to ask
if you want to write
science fiction articles
for the public,
how do you write
so that everyone can understand?
I think what I write
depends on
what you've learned.
I want to write
a story,
a fable.
You don't need
to feel burdened
to read it.
If you don't like science,
you'll want to read it.
What's your topic?
Which field do you prefer?
Animal behavior and neuroscience.
That's so cool.
I want to read your fable.
I can't write it yet.
I think this topic
is easy to use.
I think we can send
CS and V to read it.
I'm neuroscience too.
Don't ignore me.
Xiao Ji is also
neuroscience.
I write more
in writing
than other editors.
But other editors
also have free time.
How to
make a science fiction
story more vivid?
Can everyone
say something bad about someone else?
We're recording.
Let's cut it out.
We can't add anything.
Don't add anything.
We're not
doing a journal club.
If we want to present
an article to the general public,
the best way
is to use as many metaphors
as possible.
Use all kinds of metaphors
in everyday life.
You've already written a fable.
That's a good metaphor.
But sometimes
when I'm reading a story,
sometimes I can't
connect with
what I want to convey.
You have to be smart
to read the meaning of
self-discipline.
I can't read poetry.
It's useless
to write poetry.
So I think
you can use
metaphors in everyday life
to describe
the scientific facts.
For example,
DNA and RNA
will go through
translation and transcription.
You can say
it's a translation of the past.
There are too many
metaphors.
You can say
it's a dictionary.
it's a code.
You can say
it's a protein.
You can use
all kinds of metaphors.
Because you're writing
about a field
that few people write about,
you can use
innovative metaphors.
What do you think, Xiao-jin?
You sound like a writer.
I used to be a writer.
Maybe until I was 80.
I think
you can use
metaphors
like Xiao-jin said.
We have a lot of metaphors.
The second thing I think
is that you can
use images.
Xiao-jin is good at
animal behavior.
It's really interesting.
He said
animal behavior is like
two
ships
mating.
When mating,
the third mate
opened his hand.
You might think
it's boring.
When we observe
animals, it's boring.
When mating,
the third mate
might react in a bad way.
It's boring.
But if you think about it,
it's like a couple
fighting in the park.
They fought.
I told you to buy soy sauce,
but you went out to date.
When you use images,
it becomes interesting.
Everyone can imagine it.
Everyone can understand
what's going on.
When you bring it up,
you can talk about
what we see in biology.
It's interesting
and you learn something.
It's cool to share with others.
I think Xiao-jin is good
at using metaphors.
I run
Sky's Instagram.
Many readers leave comments
on Instagram.
They say,
they've never thought
they'd understand biology
or science.
But it's so funny.
After laughing,
I realized I understood.
It's touching.
It's like
a virtual science.
electrons,
atoms,
and positrons.
It's like chemistry.
It has to be perfect.
When there's a free machine,
it's like
when there's only one electron,
no one holds hands,
it becomes a mountain.
It destroys
your DNA.
It's a good example.
A free machine is a mountain.
A mountain will destroy a family.
A free machine will destroy
my body.
It's similar to
life.
It's far from the past.
But it's a strong example.
I think many people
can understand and catch up.
Yes.
This way
can be trained
in daily life.
Yesterday,
when we were in the LINE group,
we attended
Tara's speech.
It was a long speech.
I replied right away.
Of course not.
Have you ever seen a steak
only served with iron plate
and three-color beans
without steak?
Iron plate noodles.
Yes, iron plate noodles.
There's no main dish.
To be a staff member,
you have to attend an academic speech.
I told her,
we have a speech.
There are some metaphors
you can apply
and learn.
You can apply it
to your writing.
First,
visualize
something interesting.
Strengthen it.
Then,
connect your scientific knowledge.
There are some connections.
When the reader
or audience
receives a piece of information,
they will connect it.
It's easy to
form a memory.
How to strengthen the memory
is important.
My teacher was good at this.
She told me,
choosing a boss is like choosing a husband.
You have to be with him for years.
It sounds important.
She explained to me
P-Value.
We all have a P-Value
like a metaphor.
But how much
is the P-Value?
If you ask her,
she'll say,
how much is the P-Value?
P is 0.9.
It must be terrible.
If she's good at speaking,
she'll recommend it.
If the noodle is good,
you must try it.
It must be good.
It's different.
It's different from others.
When she said it, I understood.
It's not necessarily right.
It's right if you follow her.
That's a great metaphor.
Everyone said
a P-Value at the end.
You know it very well.
You can remember it.
Cool.
I want to read your article.
Do you post it on Facebook?
Or blog?
I'll put it on the wall
and post it
on Facebook.
What's it called?
V-Side is
the fan page of
Nervous Pig Tail.
She left a message.
It's Wen Qing Guan.
Yes, it's Wen Qing Guan.
V-Side is
like Tang Feng.
Anyone can be called.
Tang Feng likes us.
Can you share
where you
share your articles?
Chen Zhen You.
I...
I share it
on Facebook.
I post it
on my fan page
and post it
on Nervous Pig Tail
and
V-Side.
Mainly these two.
Can you post your fan page?
Can I?
Sure.
We're a
promotion platform.
If you want to promote something,
you can post your link.
Tell us your name.
Let's make a circle.
My brain has a mouth.
I think I've seen it.
Is it a mouth?
I thought it was a crime.
Is it Wen Qing?
That's too Wen Qing.
My brain is a original crime.
I have a like.
Cool.
When the fans recognize you,
they'll scream.
I want to ask
a similar question.
Chen Zhen You asked
how to
attract readers
in writing.
I want to ask
how to
attract readers
in writing.
I want to share
what you want to convey
as a scientist.
This is the problem
I'm facing.
When I meet someone
or want to flirt,
you can say
I'm not good at it.
It's normal.
You can describe
you're a physicist
or a physicist.
I'm a laser scientist.
I study light.
They'll say you're so smart.
Their mind
will be strong.
Don't tell me
your major.
You can feel
the wall.
You can't communicate.
I want to know...
Is your brain like this?
My wife is interested
in my research.
Wait, you have a wife?
I want my wife
to be interested.
His wife is his wife.
I want to know
if there's a way
to successfully
make
the other person
convey
what we learned
in science.
Is your goal
to talk about science?
Or is your goal...
I think
this is related
to your audience.
You can ask
other editors.
I think
my goal is
to convey
what I learned
to other people
with the money
I got from
the Nazis.
Tell your wife?
At least my wife
should know.
Or people
I meet.
I want to share
something.
My research
focuses on the elderly.
They have
an impression
that they're stubborn.
We have a technique
called
motivation interviewing.
You can't
directly...
If your audience
doesn't want to hear you
say something,
don't say it
directly.
CS shared
that you have to
connect to your topic
from their perspective.
You have to be related
to them
before they're interested.
Otherwise,
it's irrelevant
to them.
So,
it depends on
your language,
your attitude,
and your usage.
If you're talking to your wife,
you can
act cute.
You can tell her
that you want to share
your research
with her.
You're the one
I want to share
with her.
If you're just a passer-by,
you can
ask her about her background
first.
What's the connection
between your research and her background?
You can discuss it.
Sometimes, you have to
be interested in
the other person.
You have to be interested
in their background story
so that the conversation
can go on.
Do other editors
have their own
techniques or ideas?
Yes.
I think it's a good technique.
You can
ask the subject
about the field
they're interested in
and see if there's
a connection between
their science.
You can let them know
what they're interested in.
From a scientific point of view,
they can learn
about this field.
For example, my partner
likes Hermes a lot.
She likes the bag.
Do you know the difference
between Hermes' alligator
and the crocodile?
It's not the same.
The animal patterns
on the bag
are determined
by the genes.
You can connect
the fashion items
she likes
to the animal genes.
She'll understand
why there's a color
or a pattern on the bag.
Or she'll understand
the distribution of
the animals' origins
in different regions.
You can use it like this.
I think it sounds
interesting.
I'll give it a try.
Or you can
use a popular
catchphrase.
It's a scientific catchphrase.
Like,
I'm willing to
treat you like a red blood cell.
Your love is my oxygen.
For your love,
I don't even need my heart.
Red blood cells don't have cells.
It's the opposite.
You can tell her,
honey,
even if we're
the same age...
Honey, I'll treat your love
as if we're the same age.
We'll never be apart.
We're inseparable.
She'll ask,
don't you know?
These two things
are different, but we can't
separate them.
It's like us.
It's a scientific fact.
But you link it
to something interesting.
I think a lot of things in science
are romantic.
Like receptors.
I can only connect to you.
I can't connect to anyone else.
I want the virus to
take the AEC2
and connect to us.
It's painful to be
connected to the virus.
It's like being killed.
You said we can be separated.
Xiao Jing, you're being spied on.
What?
You're being spied on.
It's okay.
We don't need to get married
to the virus.
Who was talking just now?
Dou Dou.
Dou Dou is our immune specialist.
So,
if we talk about immune stuff today,
I'll get infected.
I was going to say
you were talking about being poisoned.
It's not like you'll
tell him you're poisoned.
It's just a possibility.
I'll be more aggressive.
When he's in pain,
I'll say,
you might not be poisoned,
but it's a possibility.
Please call an ambulance for me.
I'm not trying to solve his problem.
I'm just being a scientist.
I agree.
That's a good question.
I don't think I'll
really talk to
the general public
or people who don't
study science that much.
Yeah.
I just heard
Shilan say
you're doing research on physics.
That's really...
Is that how you say it?
I think
it's harder to...
That's a weird way to say it.
You're the one who thinks it's weird.
People think
what we do is deep.
What we do is...
It's just a lab.
It's just
putting together
capacitors and capacitors.
You're a welder
and a water pipe connector.
You connect all kinds of things.
That's all you do every day.
It's not as complicated
as people think.
I think it's complicated.
I think it's complicated, too.
Yeah.
I think it's because your field
sounds complicated.
You have to start with
simple things.
For example,
when I talk to people,
I'm afraid to answer
when people ask me about my background.
When I first came to Italy,
I wanted to make friends,
so I talked to people about
my background,
and they were like,
oh, I see.
That's usually the case.
When you're at a friend's party,
people ask you,
what do you do?
You answer, I do physics.
Then people start to change the subject.
So you have to be prepared.
Like the welder
you mentioned earlier.
He's a good guy.
It's not that it's difficult
when you hear physics,
but we're like welders.
We're all welding.
I'll answer,
it's not that it's difficult,
but I use my computer to analyze.
I'm just a nerd.
I'm a nerd.
This know-how,
do you have any questions?
You're welcome.
You can ask all kinds of questions.
Yeah, because podcast
is about all kinds of things.
It's not like we'll answer
all the right questions.
If you listen to our podcast,
you'll know that every time something comes up,
we all have different opinions.
It's a discussion.
Wang Yiting.
I don't know how to pronounce it.
Hi, I'm Yiting.
I'm a part of today's speaker.
I'm happy to be here
to teach everyone.
Is it Yiting?
Yes, that's me.
Yiting I met at a science activity.
I'm just curious
that I've been
listening to everyone
from the perspective of a spectator
and thought that
everyone's background is more
in the field of natural science.
As far as I know,
my field was
traditional natural science
in medical school.
Then I slowly
got closer to social science.
For example, social science
or some other
philosophical people
might have a chance to collaborate.
Of course, I can't claim
that I'm the only one.
From the perspective of social science,
they often do
so-called knowledge promotion.
In fact,
there are a lot of
social science-related things on the market.
For example, legal white paper.
Because everyone feels
that when we hear about
the problems of natural science,
for example,
everyone is quiet.
But in fact,
they also have similar problems.
Oh, I study social science,
and everyone is quiet.
In fact, I have seen
a lot of fans
who want to do
knowledge promotion
of social science.
I want to explain
some more complicated concepts to you.
I don't know if you
have any experience
in this knowledge promotion
or so-called science promotion
that other partners have discussed.
In fact, what we want to do is similar,
but our subjects are different.
I'm just curious about your experience.
From their perspective,
how does it work?
Or when you were running
a fan page,
did you see other examples
that they did well?
I want to take this opportunity
to learn more.
Maybe I haven't revealed it yet,
but I want to share it with you.
Do you mean
social science?
Social science,
for example,
psychology.
Psychology is actually quite common,
and I often write articles about it.
Maybe economics,
society, management,
law, and politics
are all social science.
In fact,
they also have some
demands
that they want to share with the public
to let people know that
what we do professionally
is not just in our own ivory tower,
but also wants to connect
with everyone's daily life.
I think they may also be looking for
a place for them to cut in.
As you said,
I can't think of
anything other than
legal dialogues.
But I know
there's a lot of
cultural knowledge
in the show.
For example,
linguistics.
I'm actually
inviting a linguist
to be the host of
Knowledge is Fun.
I hope he'll accept our interview.
Knowledge is Fun is a podcast
about culture and listening.
They also
worked with
the New York Times.
It's more natural science.
They have a series of
Knowledge is Fun,
including linguistics,
criminal psychology,
and so on.
Philosophy is also fun.
They also do some sharing.
What was the name
of the show before?
Philosophy, Philosophy, Egg Cake.
They do
a lot of philosophy.
I don't know much
about sociology.
But Lawyer Lv is good.
He talks a lot
about everything.
Do you have
any comments
or thoughts
you'd like to share?
I like the story.
I think it's
about history.
Yes.
It's so good.
You can see it on iQIYI.
I'm still watching
on Instagram.
Unless I'm really interested,
I'll look at the text.
But I think they're good.
They write about history.
It's a story.
It's interesting.
When I was in high school,
I don't know if you've seen
what history textbooks
I wrote in high school.
Why did I write
literary textbooks in high school?
And all of my answers
were wrong.
You're revealing your age.
I'm revealing my age.
The most painful thing
was that I thought literary textbooks
had a lot of room to explain.
It's just two or three words.
I thought maybe that's what they meant.
I was like, why would you think that?
Of course, I didn't have time
to discuss this with you in class.
But I think that's the way
you should learn history.
History is what people do.
A person may have a lot of reasons
to do this.
Why must it be like this?
Today, he wrote a non-human disaster.
Was he happy to write a non-human disaster?
Did he write a non-human disaster?
Or did he think he looked ugly?
Or did he think
it was too much to
deal with?
You don't know.
Why do you only have one answer?
Do you have any
suggestions?
Are you doing
research on this?
Do you have any suggestions
for us?
Because I also
had more opportunities to
get in touch with philosophy on Friday.
I used to have
very unfamiliar discussions.
When I started participating,
I thought that
if the mainstream background
was more
natural science,
people would have a way of discussing
and speaking.
But in the mainstream of
social science,
they would also have a way of speaking.
When I first participated,
I thought it was a new experience.
But after a few times,
I realized that
many things are the same.
It's just that
how do we make
what we think is important
but may be complicated
more interesting to more people?
I don't have many
suggestions.
I just think that
the experience of
exposing each other
is helpful to me.
I may see more opportunities
to get closer to each other.
So I'm just curious
if this is a future direction
of Sky in the World.
As you just heard,
we are now in the industry
where people call each other
the wall side.
Through this way of
increasing contact,
I think it can really help us
to understand more.
In addition to wanting to
let others understand our knowledge,
I think the experience
of teaching each other
is quite useful to me.
So I'm just curious
if this is also a future direction
that everyone is interested in.
It sounds like there is.
I just want to share this.
This is not the future,
this is the progress.
In our interview,
we will invite people from
different fields.
Of course,
we will invite people
from different fields.
For example,
we have interviewed
people from education,
such as Annie,
who was our guest speaker
last time,
and Dr. Yi Yang,
who is a professor of music.
He is teaching music history
in the US.
We will also invite people
from language studies,
or even people
who are not in the scientific field.
We have also interviewed
people like Maria,
who is a Chinese bride.
We have always been
trying to get in touch
with people from different fields.
But this is not
a scientific conversation.
Our research field
is very different,
but we all have to live.
So I will put this
topic in the interview,
because the interview
may be a topic
on how to plan
your life.
So when different
life plans
are shared by people
from different fields,
there will be different sparks.
Because we all have to live,
but we don't have to be
scientific.
So we use this sense of community
in our interviews.
I hope I have answered your question.
You mentioned that
if you want to join
the self-media
or spread the message,
the threshold is very low.
For example,
if we want to do a podcast,
we only need a computer
and a cell phone.
So we don't need
any equipment
The only difficulty
is the adjustment
in time.
That's because our team is big.
Sorry, our team is a bit big.
We need to adjust.
But if
we are a single person,
we have heard
that the podcast is a single person.
So if you are a person
and I want to share something with everyone,
you can.
I just thought that
if you are a college student
in the architecture department,
they also have their own podcast.
I forgot the name.
If you want to know,
you can find out.
I just want to say
hi to everyone.
You can communicate with Alan.
We are good friends.
We have a LINE group.
We talk every day.
We talk a lot every day.
I think
this is a very good direction.
Because we really
lack
certain types of scholars.
We lack a lot.
The physicist, please
agree to our interview.
Otherwise, we won't let you off the hook.
This is his.
Sorry.
You should
invite him to
an interview.
Let's help him discuss
how to chat with his wife.
After the interview,
we will let his wife listen to it.
It's very interesting.
But our audience
has a question.
Let's let the audience ask first.
I want to ask
have you ever thought
to promote your podcast
to high school or even high school?
Because you have a lot of skills.
Like protein
or bacteria.
Those skills
made me think
this is my high school knowledge.
If the school taught like this at that time,
it might
be more interesting.
I think
this channel is really interesting.
If I have a chance to promote
to national high school,
it might be very interesting.
Thank you.
That's a very good suggestion.
But we can't
control the audience's level.
But
I have tried my best
to find teachers
to interview.
I hope to attract
their approval.
Maybe it can be spread.
But
teaching at national high school
really needs to teach
the principles
or rules.
Because
we talk about
academic articles in the program.
So it might be
something that hasn't been decided yet.
It's possible.
So
I don't know
if I can understand
this program
without a solid basic knowledge.
I'm afraid that
they will fight with the teacher
after the Sky in the World interview.
Isn't it good?
Our education needs this kind of spark.
I think this is to convey to them
that something is not only the right answer.
Aren't these people doctors?
I think high school should
have a chance.
Because
the basic knowledge
like sugar,
or protein,
or fat,
I think they should
have a chance
to interact with the textbook.
I hope
high school students can come.
Our
Clubhouse
has a
host
twice in a row.
It's a textbook on Instagram.
It's three times in a row.
So
we hope to
get to know these people.
OK.
Thank you.
It's my first time to see you.
You look like
a grandpa.
My white beard.
Do I look like a grandpa?
Yes, your glasses.
You look like a natural
grandpa.
Mom's dad.
Adam, do you want to take off your shirt?
Or he can't recognize you.
I can recognize you.
On Instagram,
I saw Adam
showing off his muscles.
It's different from now.
Too many people. I'm not shy.
OK.
Sorry to interrupt.
I want to
comment from Taira's perspective.
You mentioned
many platforms.
I don't know
about them.
I've never seen or heard of them.
I want to say
from Taira's perspective,
we might want to
collaborate with these organizations.
We can try.
I don't know
if we should
organize
a group
to talk about
science or
knowledge.
We can
write down
the links
and see
who we can collaborate with.
The second comment
is
from Taira's perspective.
We have many PhD students.
They have
very professional
background knowledge.
I think
we should
collaborate with them.
We can find people
to interview.
I think
you can see
that Taira's team
focuses on natural science.
But there are
many branches in natural science.
And
there are many
areas I've never heard of
before.
So I think
you can dig
and protect them.
You can dig for resources.
I just want to say that.
How can we find
Taira's
contacts?
Are you the window?
I want to find
Taira's contacts.
Taira has a PR team.
I think our seminar team is too busy.
We have a PR team.
Xinda has a PR team.
You are familiar with it.
Yes.
I used to be in the PR team.
Then I
became
the president.
That's it.
You can
contact us.
Maybe we can
work together.
I think it's interesting.
I have an idea.
I just thought of it.
I don't have to agree with you.
Sleep on it.
Taiwan
has interviewed
Shanae.
She is the PI
for Taiwan.
They are
doing the same thing
as us.
They are also working on
scientific communication.
They are from the UK.
They are distributed in 5 or 6 different countries.