我們今天非常非常榮幸呢能請到建智來跟我們談談就是他在blockchain相關的研究
那在讓建智開始這個他的演講之前呢先讓我介紹一下建智
建智或是大家可以叫他Joseph是這個University of Waterloo的PhD student
他現在在的系所呢是Electrical and Computer Engineering Faculty of Engineering
然後呢在他來到這個University of Waterloo之前呢
他曾經在台灣就是帶領銀行的新創銀行團隊呢
這個做這個Banking System的這個程式設計
然後呢他同時有Collaborate跟Microsoft Taiwan Collaborate就是相關就是Medical System的研究
那他的這個Doctoral Research主要是就是今天的主題Blockchain
然後呢他除此之外他也對比如說IoT Edge Computing Security還有AI都有涉獵而且是非常有興趣
那除此之外在這個主要研究之外呢
他同時也有Volunteer在Mentor台灣的學生參加就是
Sorry申請這個全世界的這個PhD Program
然後他也同時也有
Sorry我看一下喔
Sorry我中文英文翻譯有點問題
我只用英文唸好了
Volunteer to mentor new graduate student in his department and the Taiwan Global Ambassador of UW's Office of Advancement
然後呢他非常鼓勵台灣的學生可以跳出舒適圈追尋他們的夢想
好那我這邊先關掉
今天劍之要給我們帶來的演講題目是
An Implementation of Fake News Prevention by Blockchain and Entropy-Based Incentive Mechanism
那麻煩大家現在把麥克風打開
因為我們的麥克風現在預設是關掉的
先把麥克風全部打開
然後我們用熱烈的掌聲來歡迎我們今天的講者為我們帶來精彩的演講
好那交給你了
Thank you everyone
And thanks 劍勇
I originally thought I use the Chinese to give a speech
But I promised my English workshop to give an English presentation
So I still use English to give my presentation
But if you have any question
Feel free to ask in Chinese or English
Both are fine
So I'm so glad to give you this presentation
It's about we use blockchain technique to come back with the fake news
But before into the research
I would like to introduce my background and to let you understand me more
So this is my background
Actually I'm born in Taiwan
And when I graduated, I worked in Taiwan for several years
And as you can see, I originally in Hsinchu
And then I go back to Taipei and do some software development
And then I go to the banks
Issan Bank and China Trust
And then before I joined UW
I collaborated with Microsoft Taiwan as a technical consultant
And my educational background is that
I'm a computer science master degree in National Taiwan Ocean University
And for this part is that I introduced that in my master thesis
We developed some facial recognition system
That you could input the sentences and your image
And then our system could to generate animation like you
And this animation can say some sentences
So it's pretty interesting
And as you can see right now
A lot of application like this published very famous
So yeah, it's a life is a joke
If we put this product on the market
Maybe I'm a millionaire now, right?
And if I graduated and, you know, for engineering students
Seniors told you, you could go to the Hsinchu to get a job
And then you can get a lot of stocks
Then you can retire very soon
So it was my dream
So when I graduated, I went to Hsinchu
But, you know, in that year, we met some financial crisis
So I came back to Taipei to do software development
And at that time, I was very interested in mobile development
And in that generation, in that year
The Microsoft collaborated with the Nokia to deliver the new devices
That's the Nokia and the Windows phone on the market
So I joined one company
We as a manager and a team to develop some mobile apps
As you can see, yeah, the interesting one is the repost
We transfer the Nokia's games
It's a Barbie game, right?
If you're a child, you use this app
You can change the process of the app to us in this games
We transfer it from the iPhone and Android system to Windows phone
And then we do some application
We do some applications for, you know, the care, right?
And tool for the Taiwan taxi and also for the easy taxi
All these applications, I was so excited that I did this application
Because, you know, in apps, if you are a programmer
The apps could give you a very straightforward feedback from customers
So it's very interesting
However, the life gave me another joke
Is that the Windows phone did not succeed at that time
So, yeah, after I did this job for more than one year
I found that, yeah, no, this job cannot help me to
Enough money for me to buy, yeah
So I joined to banks and to run the directives
Some financial products and we built a system
It's called the Muiris
And this Muiris is a very powerful system
At the banking operations
If you are a trader, you could use this system
To record any financial products in this system
And all the Taiwan, the first tier, the banks use this system
So I went to China Trust
And then I went to Hunter
Invite me to join Yishan Bank to introduce Muiris to their banks
And then when I finished this Muiris project
Yeah, we made a big project in Taiwan
Is that the Asian Pacific Organization came to Taiwan
They do some resource to how does Taiwan do
In the anti-money laundry, which is a fine system
And so when I, I was kidding that
So, yeah, I'm one of the Taiwan representative
The national teams in Taiwan is very honored for us
But it's really tough to do that
We need to finish it out of the requirements in a very short time
But, yeah, the final result is very good
And I also got a promotion in Yishan Bank
So far, it looks so good
So why I want to go study abroad
That's because that I was thinking about that
If I still stay in Taiwan, right
Maybe I could gather good jobs and to be promoted
Continue to be promoted
But, yeah, I was very
I heard about some great new technology skills
Or some new products from Silicon Valley
Or from North America
So it was always be my dream to study abroad
So I was so hesitate
But, yeah, I just to give myself a chance to do this
And so right now I was thinking about that
The thing is that if you have a dream
It only could stop you, it's just yourself
So I just want to encourage all of my friends
Or the participants or some young students in this meeting
You could to just to check your dreams
Or not to limit yourself
And so right now I'm here in Canada
So I saw a lot of beautiful things
But, yeah, the period is also
When I prepare for this study process
I met a lot of difficulties
But, yeah, it's worth it, I think
And, yeah, this is my
A lot of my motto is that
Actually adventure may hurt you
But monotony, which means that you always do the same things
It will kill you, kill you creative or other things
So, yeah, that's all my background introduction
So I will stop here for a while
If you have any question, you could ask me right now
OK, I think you have any question
Feel free to ask me and we can discuss more
And so I wrote some of my experiences in my blog
And some medium if you have
You could check it and to get more detail
If you also want to trust your dreams
Or you have some dream career
Or you could also find me on those pages
And, yeah, we could discuss more about your passion
And, OK, so let's get to our main research topic today
Today we're going to talk about
How to use the blockchain to prevent the fake news
Yeah, actually what is the fake news
It is a complete fabrication
Which means people to forge something
Or to mimic something
And they're very similar to the real
You are not able to confirm what the fact is
What is the real, what is the fact
And so what is the
Actually the spread of fake news
Is not in the long future
It happens right now
You could see this slide
In the left-hand upside
Is the U.S. stock market
In one day you could see the picture
It drops sharply
But why
Because at that day
The news says that the Trumps
The Obama was dead
But it's a rumor, right
But however the stock market to drop very sharply
By this fake news
And other examples in this slide
We all know that the Cambridge Analytic
They collect the users' preferences
And to make some news or articles
That you are interested in
And to affect your opinion in some specific issues
And also the Russian
They use some propagandas to affect the basis
The resource of basis
So all these are the current threat
To our society and democracy and the economy
Also in Taiwan
Taiwan is the same
Actually in the research
Taiwan is the most
We got the most threat from the whole world
We are number one
So it's very
Like I said
It's not a long
Not a threat in a long distance
It's the current
It happened currently right now
So why people invest in fake news
That is because they can get a lot of revenues
Based on the lower cost
Right now the cost of producing the fake news
It's very cheap
But if you can affect a big topic
Like the U.S. president election
Or some very huge topic
You could get a huge, huge revenues
So why not
Why don't we do that
If I can impact a lot of people
By very low cost
Actually the malicious people
Of course they will do that
And also the AI technology makes things worse
Because in my this slide
This is Jordan Peele
He is a U.S. actor
He collaborated with technology companies
They use the AI technique to
The deep fake technique to produce the video
And to let Obama to say some words
They want him to say
So AI make the fake news
To be produced more easier
And so
But in a traditional ways
Our research mainly focus on
To detect the fake news automatically
How we do that
You see this picture that
We have different algorithms
But mainly we use some machine learning algorithms
We find some clues
For example if you are the fake news comes in
And we find whether the IP address is correct or not
And its content has some
We use this or not
So we use some patterns to detect
And to decide whether this fake news is
Whether this news is correct or not
But like I said
AI makes things very similar to real
The algorithms does not have
Have the great performance right now
So some big companies like Google
Or Facebook
They begin to use some
Human beings power capabilities to
Help AI to check the contents
Authenticity
How they do that
They build some teams
They collaborate with the local professions
They have the ability to check the content
Is correct or not
And Facebook also did the same things
They built a team internal
And those teams will check some news
The authenticity
And to make your
Some news
When news push to your device
They will be real
And they will build some fake news
And in Taiwan
We also have one organization
And you could see that
It's the Taiwan Fact Check Center
And you could go on their website
And to see
They could check
They will check some news
And tell you this is correct or incorrect
OK
So I stop here
And for these solutions
Like Google or Facebook
Or the Taiwan Fact Check Center
Those are good solutions
But these solutions are
Are managed by a central organization
We don't know how they work
It's like a black box
If they did not do this job well
You did not know right
You just can trust them
So in our solution
We used decentralized solutions
Which means that we will form a team
Form a call
A lot of people
They are advisors
They will verify some contents
But this solution does not manage
By only one company
It's managed by everyone
Who joined this system
So this is our paper
And just accepted by DTN
2021 in November
So after the meeting
If you have more interesting details
You could
But it's not published yet
Maybe in December
So in December
You could check this content
In more detail
Ok so
I think we can get into the detail
So for
This work is from another paper
That invented by some researchers
In the UK
As you can see
In the middle of this architecture
There is a group
That we call the uprising actors
These are some professions
They have ability to check
The content is correct or not
And in that side
When the content creator
Is the content creators
Are people who create
The digital content
Maybe you are a writer
Or you are a photographer
And you make some content
And you could send your content
Into our system
And then those uprising actors
Will verify your content to check
Or your content is real or fake
And then they will send back to you
The uprising result
Then those uprising result
Will be saved in the
Blockchain network
After that
The right-hand side users
When it comes into our system
They could check the
Authenticity of the contents
From our blockchain network
So that's an overview
Architecture of the system
Our system's architecture
Is similar to this architecture
But in the following slide
I will introduce the differences
Between architecture and this
And this is interesting
Like I said
If we all rely on
Facebook or Google
To help us to check the content
How do I know
They do their job very well
Maybe they just have to
They did not do very seriously
So I still could still see some fake news
But in this system
You could to select the people
Or some authorities media
You trust
And then to get them
To be your oppressing actors
So for example
If in this case
I selected
One is the BBC
It's a media
And I also selected some people
Professor Smith or Mr. John
Maybe some celebrities you trust
If they say this news is real
You will trust that
So maybe for example in Taiwan
Maybe you are very
Trustful
If he say this news is real
Okay, I will trust him
So you could select these people
To be your trusted parties
And when the news comes in
We will call your call
A group of oppressing actors
They will give you the opinion
But is this news is correct or not
And so but
Why we need to use the blockchain
In the system
Why don't we just use
The traditional databases
We just accept the oppressing results
We don't need to use the blockchain, right
But actually blockchain
Has some characteristic
That if once your data
Is accepted in blockchain
You cannot modify that
Because everyone has one ledger
In their node
Is this not possible
To modify all the ledgers, right
And another case is that
If you modify the ledger
In only one node
It will be easier to be fine
Because we have some
Hashtag
In computer science
The hashpoint is that
For example, in my node
I have a hashpoint to point to your node
But if you modify
The hashpoint is based on your content
If you modify the content
The hashpoint will be modified
So it will be easier to be found that
Somebody modified the data
So blockchain will be a great solution
To maintain the correctness of the data
And we go back to give you some knowledge
How does the blockchain work
Actually you can see this picture
And if you have a transaction
In this system
And the nodes will compete
To try to verify it
And once this data verified
You will be set to the blockchain
That is in a button
We have some red blocks
And they are picked by the hashpoint
Right
So this is how the blockchain works
And then it's just
There are many, many blockchains right now
So it's a very simple classification
One is the public
And another is the private
Public means that everyone
And could to send a transaction
In this blockchain network
Like bitcoin
People know about bitcoin and all
But in private blockchain
Only people approved
Will be can send the transaction
Into the system
And so this private blockchain
Often be used in the corporations
Not for the public
And yeah so
And another
Since you need to know in blockchain
Is the proof of work
And proof of stake
What is proof of work
It means that
If we have a transaction
And we have a lot of nodes
Which node can record
This data into blockchain
And if you are proof of work mechanism
The nodes will compete
To solve a complicated math problem
And this process
We call it the mining
Right so it's a famous word
Or it's very popular to be heard
If you solve this problem
Then you get the right
To set data into blockchain
But yeah and the proof of work
Is right now the blockchain
And the ethereum used
And the proof of stake is that
Oh no we don't
To solve the math problem
We just use some stake
What does that mean
Is that if you want to
Record data into blockchain
You need to pay some fees
And if you pay higher
You will be get higher chance
To get the right
To be selected to get the right
To set data into blockchain
So these two solutions
Are called resist the hackers
Because in the proof of work
We want to control
Our right to record data
In blockchain
You need to control
More than 51% computers in the world
And in proof of stake
You need to pay more than 51% stakes
Then you will get the right
To record data
And then so you can see that
In blockchain actually
I think people heard about
One news is in Taiwan
That one day some people
Buy a lottery right
Then they collect a lot of people
People to buy the lottery together
But one man denied
He denied that
Said oh no this lottery
Only belongs to me
But if you use blockchain
The solution the problem
Will not exist
Because in blockchain
Everything will
Very transparency
And we could trust
Who did the transaction
So that's the one
The blockchain could support
Our daily life
Actually they can solve
A lot of things
Like if you're trying to vote in
Or to test some
The fishery or some products
The original prices of the product
By using a blockchain
And then in this system
You could
I would like to introduce
The hyperledger fabric
It's the blockchain that
Proposed by IBM
And this is the permission
Private blockchain that I said
It's for the companies
Not for the public
And how they work
You could see this flow
If you have a transaction
You could propose to
The execution chain code
The chain code is the smart contract
In the blockchain network
I think people will
Heard about smart contract
Often very often
And then the smart contract
Will check your content
To check is there any mistake
In your content
And then send back to you
And when you get a permission
You can send your
Submit your transaction
To the ordering services
And then the ordering services
Will to decide
How to record your data
Into the blockchain
And it's different to the bitcoin
The hyperledger fabric
Does not use the
Proof of work mechanism
Which means that
Then we don't need to spend
A lot of energy or money
To do the mining process
So it will be faster
And save energy
Than the blockchain
Than the bitcoin
So for this
In our paper
This is our main architecture
The main difference is that
You could see that
In the data persistent layer
Our blockchain
We use the hyperledger fabric
But in a previous work
That did not mention that
Which blockchain they used
Also we
How do you incentive
To let the oppressing actors
To do things well
We invented incentive mechanisms
To that people
Willing to do things very well
Not to produce some dishonest
Behaviors
And then our system will
Tell you that
If you send
The content creator
Send one content into our system
Our system will tell you
How much percent
This content is real or fake
Like this slide shows
The content is the
66% is real
And 80% is fake
And this opinion is from
The people you trust
In your trust list
So you could use this
Oppressing result to judge
This news is fake or not
And so this is our main floor
And we
We was
We refer to the history and that
In the beginning
Our system will accept
The participant to add some
So they will get
Some credit point
And then they can use the
Credit point to
Do some oppressing
And then we can get a trust score
And then
When we get a trust score
So we could
For example
In the previous
This example
Most of the majority thinks that
This content is real
So the minority
Why this minority
Think this content
Is fake
So our system will give reward
To those people
That are
Belongs to the majority
And to get the punishment
To people who are in the minority
Right
Because
All people are professions
Why you think this
Content is fake
Not correct
Not similar to the majority's opinion
And then before I get into
How to calculate the trust score
I want to introduce one concept
Is that
We call it entropy
And
Yeah, don't
Don't think it too complicated
I don't want to
Introduce some to
Academia or some to top
Concept
You can only see that
This concept is from the
Chemistry
And from
Yeah
Example is that
If you have a glass of water
And you put ink into water
The water will
The ink will
From one point
And will spread to everywhere
Right
So entropy is to
Measure this phenomena
All the things
Is it a disorder or not
If the entropy is high
Because
It means that
The things is more disorder
I could put here
And so
In this slide
You could see that
The red point
Is really, really similar to
You could imagine that
The one red point is one people
If their opinion are the same
It's just like the low entropy, right
They will
Stay together very closely
But if their opinion divergent
They will have high entropy, right
So their opinion will not the same
So
I will continue
Begin to tell you
How we calculate the trust score
And I will put some equations there
But you don't need to
To look very detail into equations
You just need to look at the numbers
Okay
But for this example
If we have five prices
And three of them agree
And two of them reject
So we could get that
The possibility of real
Is three divided by
Based on
This is the possibility
And this is three
Divide five, so it's 0.5
And p fact will be two
Divided five will be 0.4
And then we put this
The p real and p fact into this equation
Then we can get the entropy for this case
Will be 0.70
Okay
Just remember the number
And
Another case is that if we have
The four prices agree
Only one
Reject
You could get that
In this case, the people have the
More consistent opinion, right
So the entropy will lower
And in the example one
The entropy is higher
So our system encourage people to
Let their opinion consistent
So when the high
High entropy, our reward or
Punishment
Will lower
But in the
In the example two
Our reward and the punishment
Will be higher
So I will give you a table
And to show you how we calculate
The trust score
And so
If you remember the metaphor
I said before
In the beginning
This is of five people
And
Yeah, they have some opinions
In the specific news
And their initial stakes is that
A1 put 5000
Into the system
A2 put 1000
And then the total stakes is the 21000
And you could get the
The credit point or appraiser
And there is the 5000
To divide the 21000
So we could get the
Each appraiser's credit point
Of
Credit point of appraiser
Right
So it's just a simple
Simple math
Okay, so
We right now we have
Know how the
Credit point
Of the appraiser
And then
When they get
When the appraiser get opinion to the content
They could say that
Oh, I'm 100%
Sure that this news is fake
Or real or fake
But like A2
He could also say that
Oh, this content is a little bit tough for me to judge
So I just have the 70% confidence
That it is true
So our trust score
Will be the CPOA
To multiply the confidence
So you could see that
This SOA is the score of authentic
Is the all people agrees
And their SOA
The summation of the all the SOA
And here is the sum score of fake
Is the same as the score of authentic
And we also summation
All the people disagree
And the summation their SOA
To get the final result
So that's the trust
How we calculate the trust score
And then when we know the trust score
Like I said, our system will decide
Will reflect the reward or punishment to each appraisers
And we define that our basic reward
Is the total stake to modify the 0.1%
So in this case
Will be 21
And the basic punishment will be higher
More higher than the reward
Because we want to stop the malicious nodes
So the basic punishment will be total stake
Multiply the 10%
So it will be the 2100
And then the reward of the content
Which means that when once content comes in
And how many reward
We will reflect to all the appraisers
Who did their jobs
So our equation will be
We use the basic reward to modify
The value of the 1 to minus the entropy S
So you could see that in this case
We know that in our example 1
Our entropy is 0.97
So the ROC or POC will be 6.3 and 6.3 respectively
Okay
So then we know that the basic reward
And we know the reward of content
And the punishment of content
And how we reflect to each appraiser
And we will calculate the ratio of SOA
Which means that
For example, in SOA, we have the 0.66
And for A1, we will know that
There are 36% of the trust score
The score of authentic is come from
Is come from the appraiser 1
So we will use this ratio to reflect
The reward to each appraiser
And for the punishment is the same
We will know that
How you contribute to the trust of the fake
And then if you contribute
Or you occupy more percentage
You will get more reward or more punishment
Okay
So in here, you can see
We calculate the ratio of ROC and the ratio of POC
Which each appraiser need to be reflected
It will be added or be reduced
And then when we reflect it
You can see that for, for example, in for A1
The initial, its initial state is 5,000
And after state is the 5,000 point 23
So we could get all the after states
And then we can calculate the after credit point
So this is a cycle
When every content, when we finish the appraising process
We will have the new states and the new credit point
And then they will get ready to accept another content
And if any appraiser
Their credit point is close to zero
Which means that their stakes are heavy
They got a lot of the punishment
And their credit point
Their stakes is equal to zero
And we will go back to our main flow
The initial process that to accept
To ask this appraiser
Do you need to add more stakes
To continue to be the appraiser
So that's how
So we only finish the
I think that the most difficult part in our presentation
Is to calculate the trust score
And in this slide that we do some experiments
That to improve
To prove that our system could be a scale
On a lot of the users
You could see that
And in the left side
The picture shows that our system could
In our testing environment
We use the four servers
And the throughput is still goes well
But in our system
We set the contents
The maxima of the content is the eight megabytes
Because you could imagine
If we compress the content
For videos or some
We use the in-camera size
There is the technique
You could use the content to
As the input
And we have the output
It's a very short
Screen or some contents
And it will not to occupy a lot of size
So our limitation of the content
Would be the eight megabytes
And the right-hand side
The picture shows that
We all know that the computer system
Is rely on the fault tolerance
Which means that
If the main server fails
Our systems should still work well
You could see that
For example, you put a Facebook
One server crashed down
And you cannot use the Facebook
It's not good
So this is the right-hand side
The picture shows that
If we make some server failure
Our system still could work well
And the latency will not to increase very much
Okay, so I think we can get into conclusion
So yeah, so our system
I asked to summarize some take-home points
For all of you
Yeah, as you remember that
I've said that the AI technique
Is getting better and better
So the traditional algorithms
Does not get the great performance
To detect the fake news automatic
So if we use the human's capabilities
We will have a better solution
Than the traditional AI algorithms
But of course we could combine
The advantage for the AI algorithms
And the human-based capability
For example, we can use AI technique
To build the first layer of filters
And people can get into
To check the results, right
But the most important part
Is the blockchain network
Because it's decentralized
Not to manage it by only one companies
It's transparency
And very easier to find some data
It's being modified
And so in this experience
We know that our system
Is the architecture is peaceful
And we could
It has potential to be deployed
In thousands of machines
And the most important part
Is that our incentive mechanism
Offers this architecture
Commercial potential
You could imagine that to
If you are a writer
Or you are a photographer
You could use our system
To get some proof
That your content is real
And your reputation
Will getting better, right
And you are a journalist
Or you are some
If people doing a fact checking
And you can get reward from our system
So there is also
Then this will have
Get some commercial proof
And for building
This is the
Fact News Precision Systems
Okay
So that's for
It's a long presentation
So I'll stop here
And I'll tell you here
Is that this research is
Supported by Ripple
Is the World Wide
Payment Protocol
And also by
National Science and Engineering
Research Council of Canada
Okay
And also thanks my mentor
To give me
A lot of suggestions
And help when I
Study for and to
Find some research ideas
Or some
Know more people how to do well
In a PhD program
So I will introduce
Her Facebook
And
She wrote a lot of great things
For all of you who wants to
Study for or you have some
If you are women
That is the best
Facebook for you to check
So I put it here
And I want to thank
Catherine to be my mentor
And give me more
Help
Okay, so
That's all the presentation
And if you have a question
You could ask me right now
Or after the presentation
You could also drop me a mail
Or find me on
Or also
We will discuss with you
More detail or any questions you have
Yeah, thank you so much
So yeah, actually
So before we start our Q&A session
Please turn on your microphones again
So let's thank
Jianzhi for the very interesting talk
Thank you, thank you
Okay, so
I'm not sure, but I'm guessing that
Some of our attendees
Would like to ask in Mandarin Chinese
Probably, I guess
But, I mean, any kind of language
As long as you can communicate
That will all be fine
So, yeah
I'm happy to ask questions
Anyone?
Hello, hi
I'm Shanna
And I would like to know
Because I noticed that
Actually you have no experience
Studying abroad, right?
This is your first time
Yeah
How do you practice English?
Sorry, it's not related to your content
But I'm just curious
Yeah
Oh, yeah, it's an interesting question
Is that I think
I learned some English
Speaking practicing courses in UW
So, yeah, they gave me a lot of practice
To
Try to join
Reach some
Course master
The class near UW
So there's a lot of chance for me
Practicing English, yeah
Is that answer your question?
Oh, yes
And I heard some people said
That we should prepare
Maybe we should join the like
UHSL
It's faster than we prepare English fast
How do you think about that?
If I cannot reach the score
That my school wants
And did I need to apply for the language
UHSL first or
I just prepare English
And until I get a score
Get a TOEFL, pass the TOEFL
And then apply for the language school
Right
I think this is
Another interesting question
Actually, I will suggest that
It depends if you
I will suggest to prepare English
And try your best to pass the TOEFL
Or IELTS in Taiwan
Because if you
Go study abroad
And you go to some language schools
The cost is really
It's very high
And then it will spend a lot of money
But the most important thing
Is the but
If you
Sometimes
Some people are struggling
To pass the exams
So if you found that
You cannot concentrate to
Prepare for the exam
And you stuck on the TOEFL exam
And also the schools offer
Some opportunities that
They say you could go to the university
To take the language courses
And then you can get over
I would say you just go
Because the time is important
Do not to stuck one
One stage for a long time
I think that would be my answer
Thank you, Tom
Yeah, so I have a question
So if we go back to your title
I think you're saying that
This technique is mainly for
How do I say this
For deploying against fake news
But if you let the people decide
What will be the thing that they recognize
They basically just vote
Let's say Barack Obama just died
And if you let the internet vote
Probably 99% of the people will say
That's a fake news
But let's say objectively true thing
That cannot be voted to become a truth
In your system
How do you comment about that
Yeah, like I said
We trust the majority opinion
In our system
We have the reward and punishment mechanism
To make you to do the correct
And the honest things
Actually in all of the blockchain network
They have the specific incentive mechanism
To prevent from some malicious notes
So if you join our
We have two mechanism to prevent
This the notes to adjust to vote
Actually they will do their best
Because the first if they join our system
They need to pay for pay fees for
Like I said the stakes
So it's a cost
And then if we join system
And you did not do your job very well
You will get the punishment
And then eventually
You will be prohibited
To be the oppressors in our system
So our mechanism of incentive
Is core concept to incentive people
To check the content seriously
And to vote correctly
So if I understand correctly
Basically the assumption
That you are going with
Is that people generally have good intention
And they are answering
Based on their good intention
Regardless of the truth
So say Obama just died
Nobody knows
And they basically just like saying
It's not a good news
Because it's just not the thing
That is well established that I know
But it's true
So in your system
It's basically working against
Malicious information
But not exactly news
Can I say that
I could say how to define the bad news
Is that the content should be correct
So when you say Obama is dead
If it's not a truth
Our system will consider it is a bad news
But in my scenario
I'm saying what if he really just died
But nobody knows like 10 minutes ago
And I go out and say
Hey guys, he just died
That will be a fake news in your system
Because nobody knows
That's true
Yeah, you're right
But if you say Obama is dead
But nobody knows
I would say that
This situation is really
It's extremely
That's quite a situation news
Yeah, so I think
Because those oppressing actors
Are very capable to check the contents
So if they hesitate to give some opinions
Their confidence will lower
So the trust score of the agree
Authentic and the fact
They will be very similar
So our system will not treat it
In your case as a very tend to be real
Or fake, it will be a bad news
But we could give you an objective opinion
To check this content
I see
Okay
I do have some comment about the previous question
Just like
Okay
Okay, first, thank you for a nice talk
And for the tokenomics design
I think that's about how you make a dispute system
Because for now it's like a one-time votes
And you just get the result done
But if you see like
In order for the prediction market
Just like if you predict
And like whether Obama will die between like 2021
And people at 2021 votes
Maybe 3% of the voters enough to get yes or no
But if you don't trust the result
You can put your stake against that voting result
And then more people need to vote
If you stake like maybe 1% of the total token
Then all of the people need to vote
So I guess you need to kind of like refine
The appeal system or the tokenomics
Because I think the previous question is quite valid
Because you assume that like the majority vote
Will know the truth
But maybe it takes some time right
So but if you like you want to label the news in 10 minutes
And definitely well it's hard to get information
To propagate to like the society or the civilization
To get people votes and get the correct result
So I guess you just need to have a dispute system
I guess
Yeah, sure
But like you said
Yeah
If you want to get news in just 10 minutes
To see if it's correct or not
It will be difficult to achieve that
Because maybe like Elon said
The news is not just known by minority people
But yeah, for this case
I think for previous the current solutions
I think people will have
Like we have put more stakes
Or we can to introduce more
The sub-parties, the libraries
And we can ask their opinions
So our speed will get in faster
Yeah, well I do think this is a very interesting
Actually very valuable research
I'm just being curious
Yeah, so anyone has other questions
I have some questions
Do you really plan to launch this thing in a public chain
Because I was saying the past like two years
Hyperledger is not like really striving
And even though like the gas fee
And the transaction fee is an issue
For like Bitcoin in Syria
But for the new generation
Like high throughput blockchain
Also support smart contract
Then it will be a much better platform
I would say
Because well Hyperledger is definitely more
Like clean and more permission
But how to really scale the platform
I would say like public chain is still better
Than the permission chain
Yeah, actually you are right
We plan to introduce some
Digital tokens in our system
Because we need to get the reward or punishment
So Ethereum will be the one choice
That we consider to transfer
The Hyperledger to the Ethereum
And also there are other tokens
That invented right now
They have a great
Because the Ethereum and Bitcoin
Their speed is too slow
But there are lots of faster blockchain network
So we consider to
Yeah, like you said to transfer
From the private blockchain to the public
Okay, thank you for applying
Yeah, thank you
Okay, so one last time
Anybody has question
Okay, if not, please again
Really turn on your microphone
So let's thank our speaker again
That's a very interesting talk
Thank you, thank you everyone
If you have any question
If you also have any question, please