Thank you very much today, Zhang Fengxun, PhD candidate, can give us an online speech.
I am the host, Zhou Zhiqian, who is currently working at MD Anderson as a postdoc.
Let me introduce you a little bit about Zhang Fengxun's current education experience.
In 2009, Zhang Fengxun obtained his master's degree from the Department of Insectology at NTU.
In 2013, he obtained his master's degree from the Department of Ecology and Biochemistry at NTU.
Then, he spent a year at UC California Berkeley as a visiting student researcher at the Department of Environmental Science Policy and Management.
Then, he transferred to the University of Michigan to obtain his doctorate.
His major is the School of Nature Research and Environmental.
Now, he is already a PhD candidate.
We are very honored to invite him to give us an online speech.
The topic of his speech today is
How does Ominary influence the effects of consumer diversity on research prey consumption?
Now, let's invite Zhang Fengxun to give us a speech. Thank you.
Thank you for the host's introduction.
Thank you.
The topic of my speech today is mainly a framework for my PhD thesis.
And the results I have made recently.
It's almost done, so I hope I can get some feedback from everyone.
My overarching question is
How does Ominary influence the effects of consumer diversity on research prey consumption?
How many resources are consumed by different consumers?
Before answering this question, I would like to briefly explain to everyone that the topic I have made is
Biodiversity Ecosystem Functioning.
The question I want to answer in this subfield is
How does Ominary influence the functions of the entire system?
These functions are shown in this picture.
How many resources are consumed?
How many biomass are produced?
How are these functions influenced by the number of organisms in the system?
After many years of research,
we all think that
when there are more organisms in the system,
the function of the system will be higher and higher.
This is because different species have to live together at the same time.
They have to use different resources.
If the food I eat is different from the food you eat, we can live in harmony.
This is the concept of resource partitioning.
If it is a picture, you can look at it.
Assuming that the different X-axis on the right is a different resource.
For example, temperature or different pH of the soil.
The white circle in the middle is the resources needed by different organisms.
If different organisms occupy different resources,
they can live in harmony.
In addition to living in harmony, they can also use these resources more efficiently.
This is our consensus in the BEF subfield.
But there is a problem.
There are more than three-quarters of the research in this subfield.
It's all experimented with plants.
For example, in the picture on the left,
how many plants are there in the grass?
How many different kinds of grass?
How many organisms are there?
If it's in the animal community,
will we find the same thing?
The answer is,
Generally, we think that when the consumer diversity increases,
the ecosystem function should also increase.
But the pattern, the signal,
is not as obvious as in the plant community.
For example, in 2013, the Meta-Analysis
reported that it reviewed more than 40 studies.
More than half of them said that we did not see a positive correlation.
In other words, diversity does not have a positive impact on the function.
More than half of them said that we did not see a positive impact.
At this time, we will ask,
why is it like this?
Is it because animals and plants are different?
Don't they need to partition their resources to coexist?
Or are there other factors?
They don't need to partition to coexist.
This hypothesis is basically invalid.
Because it is impossible for two societies to use the same thing
and live well together.
It should be said that this case is very rare.
For example, in this study,
it is a very famous study.
It is in the seaweed bed.
The picture on the left is the seaweed bed in the sea.
There are different grazers on the seaweed bed.
You can think of it as different little prawns, little worms.
They will eat these seaweed.
They will also eat the algae on the seaweed.
As you can see,
when we have more grazers,
the overall biomass of the grazer can grow more.
We can also eat less algae.
For example, we still see diversity in the consumer community.
It has a positive impact on the function.
Especially the consumption of resources has a positive impact.
They also reported that
they saw this positive impact
because different grazers
tend to stay in different parts of the seaweed.
For example, this grazer will be in a shorter place.
This grazer will be in a straight place.
So they actually use different spaces.
In other words, they really use different resources.
So resource partitioning has a positive impact on diversity and function.
In other words, resource partitioning has a positive impact on function.
There is no problem.
But in fact, there are many experiments.
They said that animals not only eat the seaweed below.
Many animals actually eat other animals.
In other words, like humans,
we don't just eat plants.
We don't just eat meat.
We eat everything.
We are solid.
In other words, this meta-analysis
in the report of 2007,
it is a review of many food webs.
Many grazers measure their stomach content.
It really depends on what they eat.
They found that the vast majority of animals
are omnivores.
They are all solid.
The simplest example of a solid omnivore
is when we have a very simple food web.
Suppose there are only four species.
With two animals.
The simplest is called Intra-Cultivated.
For example, there is an animal that only eats
the resource below its stomach.
These species.
But there is another animal.
In addition to eating these resources,
it also ate the species that just ate the resource.
So this feeding link is the simplest omnivore.
So this is Intra-Cultivated IGP.
The simplest example of an omnivore.
When the omnivore occurs,
or when the Intra-Cultivated IGP occurs,
many studies have told us
that it will reduce the entire consumer function.
For example, in this study,
Grasshopper in this study.
What is this called?
What is it called?
Tooth bug.
No.
An insect that only eats grass.
I forgot what it's called in Chinese.
It's a pest.
Then it puts this pest
together with many other different animals.
See if these animals can eat this pest.
So in this experiment,
if there is no pest,
nothing,
only Grasshopper alone,
it can grow so much.
But if there are some pests,
some other consumers,
it only eats this grasshopper,
it can eat it very low,
almost none.
But if I put a lot of species in,
because these animals will eat each other
and eat each other,
so they eat less grasshopper overall.
In other words,
when the omnivore occurs,
or intragural predation,
a simple case occurs,
we will see that
consumer diversity
has a negative effect on the function.
So we can draw
a very simple memory map.
When resource partitioning occurs,
the consumer function will increase.
But when intragural predation occurs,
this function will decrease.
Consumer diversity
will have a negative effect on the function.
So in order to study
who is more important,
I asked a question.
My Ph.D.
The main question I want to answer is
resource partitioning
and omnivore,
these two things,
these two forces,
who is more important
to determine
animal diversity
and pre-consumption.
I have four ways
to answer this big question.
The first is
because I don't know
how omnivore,
I know it's probably negative,
but I don't know
how strong it is
to eliminate the benefits
of resource partitioning.
So I need to have a hypothesis first.
So the first step
is to make a mathematical model,
a theoretical model,
to help me
generate a hypothesis.
I can continue to do experiments later.
The second step is
I have a small experiment
in the lab
to verify that
the mathematical model
can really be discovered
in a biological object,
not just a mathematical calculation.
Then it seems like
I see something like this.
The next step is
because it was all in math just now,
it was all on paper,
or it was all just
in this kind of
well-controlled environment
in the lab.
So the third step is
I think the most important part
of this paper is
that I want to be able to
discover or not discover
this theory or experiment
in the wild.
This is how I can tell people
whether this is important or not.
Is this thing
important or not?
So the first step
is to make a mathematical model.
This mathematical model
is actually very simple.
I believe you all understand.
It's just a very simple
four ordinary differential equations
to describe the change in time
in a group.
Here we see P1 and P2
are the densities of a certain species,
or biomass.
The first one is that
their population growth rate
will follow this function.
Then this function
is actually a logistic regression,
but we don't have to understand it too much.
Anyway, it will grow.
There are two reasons for P1 and P2.
It will grow.
Then there are two zoomers,
which are two animals.
They will eat these two resources.
Z1 and Z2 will eat P1 and P2.
Then their consumption term
is described as their mathematical value.
Then here is a more important point.
I put a parameter S.
I use S to adjust
how much Z1 and Z2
are partitioned
or not partitioned.
So for example,
if Z1 is 1,
if S1 is 1,
Z1 will eat P2 completely,
but it doesn't eat P1 at all.
If S2 is 1,
Z2 will eat P1 completely,
and Z2 doesn't eat P2 at all.
Or in other words,
if Z1 or Z2 is 0.5,
if S1 or S2 is 0.5,
Z1 and Z2
will completely overlap their resources.
That is, half of their P1 and P2.
Next,
one of the consumers,
Z1, will be eaten by Z2.
I just described the simplest
example of an omnivore,
which is inter-game partition.
Z1 will be eaten by Z2.
So after having this model,
I can see these two parameters,
S1 and S2,
which will affect
how many resources are eaten overall.
I won't go into
the details of how to analyze this model.
It's just a process
of writing ODE.
Then,
the most important contribution
of this model is
to generate this hypothesis.
In other words,
when these two species
are in this state,
the overall resource density
will increase
with the intra-game partition,
which is the alpha just now,
and then decrease and then increase.
In other words,
this partition is completely different
from the intra-game partition
we thought at the beginning
or the omnivore
which will have a negative effect
on the consumer function.
It will eat more resources
when the omnivore is weak,
and then eat fewer resources
when the omnivore is strong.
That's why we see
this concave-up function.
This pattern is
no matter how high
or low my resource partition is,
I can see this function
going up and down.
For example, the intra-game partition
will let the consumer eat more resources
than the omnivore.
Now we have a hypothesis.
We are going to see
whether this math tells me
whether this pattern can be observed
on a real organism.
So I did a little experiment.
The first one is
my resource has
a bunch of bacteria.
These three are different bacteria.
Then there is
the first consumer,
which is the intra-game partition.
The first one only eats bacteria.
The second one
is the consumer
that eats bacteria at the same time
and eats
the other
consumer species.
So this is the
mathematical model
of the real organism.
I can't control
whether I want this one to eat more
or less,
so I have to adjust
or manipulate the
intra-game partition strength.
The method I use is
to take a net
and let the small
intra-game partition
that only eats bacteria
run around.
However, the big one
will be limited
to the small one
if it is observed.
Then I use this net
to adjust
the position
in the bottle
of the experiment.
I can adjust
how many
consumers
will be exposed
to the risk of being eaten by the big one,
which is how high
or how close
their contact probability is.
If this net
is placed in the middle
of the intra-game partition,
then the
big one is less than the small one.
But if this net is
only about 20%
of the space
for the big one
to move,
then the intra-game partition strength
is 20.
The above picture
shows that I cut off
the bottom of the glass bottle
and glued the net in
to make an experiment
jar.
After this
is done,
I can test this hypothesis.
I want to see
if the density of
the bacteria
increases
with the
intra-game partition strength
and decreases
with the contact probability.
After the experiment,
we can see
that there is a
concave fob.
When the intra-game partition
increases,
when the resource density
reaches an equilibrium,
when the population
does not change too much,
the bacteria density
will decrease first.
Next,
I want to explain
whether this pattern is
true or not,
and whether the mechanism
is like my mathematical model.
If I put the mathematical model
on this experimental result,
you will find that
this black dot is
the result of the experiment.
This curve is the density
predicted by the mathematical model.
You will find that they are quite different.
This curve and
these black dots
hardly explain anything.
They just have a concave fob function.
This pattern is qualitatively
correct, but
quantitatively is
not accurate at all.
I can't use my model to explain
the result I saw in the lab.
There is a very important reason
why I can't use
my model.
When I describe the intra-game partition,
I use a type 1 functional response.
This type 1 functional response
means that
no matter how many prey
come to me,
I will eat them.
This is actually
unrealistic.
How can we keep eating
and eating and eating?
Its function is a linear
upward. This is not a reasonable
state.
I don't want to use this function.
I changed it to a more complex
non-linear function.
It will have a sense of satiety
when it eats.
Even if a bunch of food
comes, it will not
continue to eat more.
This is called type 2 functional response.
It looks like this.
When I change this
functional response from type 1 to type 2,
my model prediction
will be closer to
the result of the lab.
Although it is not
exactly the same,
the explanation
can explain
about 70% of the variation.
Mainly these two points.
The lab observed that
it was low enough.
I don't know why the model can't
be so low.
Almost 70%
of the explanation power
is quite satisfactory.
We can use
this model that has been changed
to explain
what really happened
in the real organism.
The model of type 2 functional response
that has been changed
can not only explain
bacterial density,
but also explain
the density of
the other two consumers,
Intragalepra and Praetor.
It also explains about 70%.
The prediction function
is very similar.
We can use this model
to explain what really happened
in the organism.
As I said,
it is type 2 functional response.
When there is a little bit of
Intragalepra
and Praetor,
when there is a little bit of
Praetor,
the Praetor
is more nutritious
than the bacteria.
We can't see the bacteria.
The Praetor is bigger
and more nutritious.
For example,
if we eat a little bit of
meat,
in theory,
we will grow bigger and healthier.
Although there are vegetarians,
if we eat a little bit of meat,
a little bit of food,
we will grow more.
We can see that
Intragalepra and Praetor
really grow bigger
and eat a little bit.
So,
when there are a lot of big Praetor
and
a few small Praetor,
they can eat
more bacteria
overall.
However,
when the Intragalepra
is very strong,
the big Praetor will be full.
As I said,
the big Praetor
will be full.
When I eat a certain amount of food,
I won't eat
more food
because I am full.
So, when the big Praetor
is full,
it doesn't eat bacteria.
It doesn't need to eat bacteria.
The small Intragalepra
is eaten by the big Praetor.
The small Praetor is getting smaller.
The big Praetor doesn't change much.
So,
when the two Praetors
are eating each other,
the bacteria are very happy
because no one eats them.
So, the biological mechanism
behind this
is like this.
Because
there is
a satiated
functional response,
we can see that
weak Intragalepra
will increase overall consumption
and decrease overall consumption.
That is to say, it will reduce
the basal resource density first and then increase.
This is
what the lab
and math tell us.
This thing may happen.
But
in the paper ice
and in the lab's
good and perfect environment,
will this result happen
in the wild?
Will you see
the positive impact of resource partitioning?
Intragalepra will be positive first.
When it is very weak, it is positive first.
Then negative again.
Will you see this?
So I
need to use
more real data
to do this reality check.
So what I want to check
is that I need to know
the resource consumption
or
resource community biomass
will it really decrease
with the increase of consumer diversity?
That is to say, when I have
a lot of different animals
or different kinds of consumers,
will they really eat more
of their prey?
Will this
impact
when these consumers
eat each other
not so seriously,
but not so seriously,
will this impact increase?
And when people eat each other
and it gets more and more exaggerated,
will this impact decrease?
This is what I want to test in the end.
You can't see this pattern in the wild.
So my
first method is
I went to
find a big
data set. This data set
is the EPA in the United States.
Every
five years,
they will
go to every lake in the United States,
every state, every place, every lake.
He went to do a sample.
Then
after choosing more than 1,000 lakes,
he will measure how many kinds of
phytoplankton in this lake,
which is the basic
resource in the lake.
They are food. How many
different kinds of phytoplankton do they have?
How many kinds of phytoplankton are there?
How much biomass is there in total?
Next is their
predator.
This is the first
consumer in the entire lake.
It will eat
those small creatures
like phytoplankton.
It will also measure
how many of them are
diverse in density.
Then
in this data set,
the only pity is
that he didn't really measure
whether the
omelette is strong or weak.
He didn't do an experiment
to measure how many
phytoplankton or how many small
consumers are eaten by large consumers.
He didn't measure this thing.
Because there are too many lakes, he can't do so many experiments.
But he reported that
he saw this phytoplankton,
this consumer,
it will eat other consumers
or not.
Is it vegetarian, meat-eating,
it is solid.
So I use
this low plankton community
how many are
omnivore
as a
degree of omnivore proxy.
This is not very good, but it is
in this data
you can get
evidence
information.
Then there are other
water temperature, pH,
electricity,
other data.
So after having this big data,
I will test
this hypothesis.
The first is to look at
the relationship between resource consumption and consumer diversity.
Will this relationship
increase or decrease
with the omnivore?
Before I actually did this experiment,
in fact, three years ago,
someone had used this data
to do a very preliminary
and basic analysis.
He just put the
resource community of biomass,
how many resources are there,
to return to other factors.
Then I found
how many kinds of
resource diversity
and the
egg and phosphorus in the lake.
These three are the most important
effects of phytoplankton
biomass.
However,
as I just said,
this data set
comes from the whole of the United States.
In other words,
the lake in California and the lake in Michigan
will definitely look different.
But when they did this analysis,
they did not consider this matter.
He treats everything as the same.
So what he wants to see is an overall overview.
So in fact, there are a lot of
biological interactions
in the middle that
will be ignored.
So to test this,
to do my analysis,
I have to make their analysis
more complicated.
The so-called more complicated
is the first one,
because these lakes belong to
different regions,
belong to different ecoregions.
Everyone can think of ecoregions as
different ecoregions,
it means that there are different
large-scale biological,
chemical, geological,
and water-temperature historical factors
that cause this lake to be
fundamentally different.
So my first step
is to make this model
more complicated.
I added special heterogeneity
to this model.
In other words,
the model just now
estimates only one effect,
that is,
biodiversity.
Only one value will affect
the community biomass.
But now I make this effect
depend on different ecoregions.
In other words, I can make it
have different effects
in different ecoregions.
So maybe in California,
this is very strong,
but in Michigan, this may be very low.
I consider this randomness.
This is the first
complexity.
The second is
I really want to test my prediction.
I added open-ended speech richness.
And I made this effect
depend on another variable.
In other words,
this is a general return,
y equals ax plus b.
I just need to look at
how big or how small ax's a is.
I know what the impact of x on y is.
This is the most basic return.
But I don't want it now.
Community biomass equals
a factor called beta
multiplied by
open-ended diversity.
But this beta is
another response variable.
So this is the second hierarchy.
In other words,
my model is
not a plane.
It has many layers.
When it becomes many layers,
the original analysis method
can't handle this complexity.
So what I have to do is
Bayesian hierarchical model.
I didn't go into too much detail
about how to do Bayesian.
In short,
what I want to answer is
even if I measure this big data,
when I see the probability of
this effect,
and when I see
the effect of one variable
on the other variable,
what is the probability?
The data
is like I just said,
it will be measured every five years.
The last two years are 2007 and 2012.
In 2007,
I did
a full model.
I will do some model selection
to remove this
to see if it has
a higher or lower
ability to explain this model.
Or the probability is higher or lower.
After doing the model selection,
finally,
in 2007,
the best model is
the three variables just now.
They are all selected.
Specialty, Trojanity
are very important.
Let these effects depend on
special ecoregion.
And I also chose
another variable.
This picture shows
the posterior I just mentioned.
Even this data,
I see
what is the probability
of the effect of this variable.
That is the posterior probability.
So we can see
the three most important variables
are still selected.
But these three variables
are not a value anymore.
They come from a distribution.
Give me an ecoregion,
I can tell you
what the effect of these three variables
in that ecoregion will be.
Then there is a
very awkward position,
which is
Zofan's Diversity.
It seems to be important,
but it doesn't seem to be.
If you add it in,
you can increase
the model's posterior probability.
You can also increase
the model's ability to explain
or even predict.
But its credible interval
overlaps with 0.
In terms of statistics,
this is the story of 2007.
But by 2012,
this model has changed.
This model adds
Zofan's Diversity.
Zofan's Diversity is
an important variable
in the data of 2002.
It can help explain
the variable of Zofan's Community.
And this effect depends on
Omnivory.
But there is another awkward situation.
Although it depends on Omnivory,
adding it in
is helpful to this model.
But the effect of Omnivory
cannot be detected.
Just like
the awkward effect of
Zofan in 2007.
Adding it in is useful,
but I can't know
how much it is.
But overall,
these three variables are the most important.
Adding Special Issue Genuity
is also very helpful to this model.
Hello.
Can you hear me?
I missed the first five minutes.
Can we interrupt you
to ask a question?
Or do we have to ask at the end?
It's okay.
I have a question.
Because
these variables are
actually meaningful variables.
Like Total Nitrogen,
Total blah blah blah,
have you ever considered
combining these variables?
For example,
finding an eigenvalue
or linear combination.
Oh.
I can do that.
But if I
find its eigenvalue,
I will still lose
correlation.
Secondly,
the correlation between these variables
is not very big.
So I will just
treat each variable as an eigenvalue.
Oh.
Makes sense.
Yeah.
Nitrogen and Phosphorus.
This is a good question.
Nitrogen and Phosphorus
are highly correlated.
So in the model,
I let these two things
I put their covariance matrix
in the model,
but I didn't draw it directly.
Oh, I see. Thank you.
Hi.
Oh, I almost forgot.
So,
in 2007 and 2012,
the models we saw
were different.
Given 2007 and given 2012,
the most likely
explanation of these data
was different.
As time goes by,
I might see that
these variables are not important.
But how did they change?
Even this data,
because I only have two
snapshots,
and they are so far apart.
I don't know how they changed.
But there is one thing
I can point out.
In 2007,
the local diversity
was awkward.
It was on the edge.
But in 2012,
it was really
different from 0.
So,
when I dug up
these raw data,
I found that in 2012,
on average,
every lake had 8 different
low content.
Compared to 2007,
I don't know how this happened.
But if this happened,
it means that in 2012,
in recent years,
there are more animals
moving around.
With more animals,
it's easier to see that
different animals eat different foods.
Or they have a different impact
on the biomass of low content.
For example,
the effect of this variable
is easier to detect.
But in 2012,
in 2007 and 2012,
I can explain that
low content diversity
can be detected.
But other variables,
like Omnivore,
why it wasn't detected
in 2007 and 2012,
I don't really understand.
They are basically the same.
A lot of Omnivores are the same.
But in 2012,
it was detected.
In 2007, it wasn't.
Given this data,
I can't answer this question.
Lastly,
this is
the biggest problem
of Shrubster.
As I said,
the degree of Omnivore
is not measured.
It doesn't measure how many small animals
are eaten,
or how many overboars
are eaten by
plants and animals.
It's not measured.
It's a proxy.
It's hard to verify
because
it's a proxy.
I can't detect
the Omnivore.
Maybe it's because
Omnivore is too
unimportant.
Only in math,
or in a
well-controlled environment,
I can see this effect.
So when I go out,
it's not important.
It won't happen.
My PhD will know what I'm doing.
It's a sad
conclusion.
However,
to solve the Omnivore
consumption problem,
I have another
experiment.
I go to the lake
to get water
to feed these animals.
I measure
how many phytoplankton
are eaten by
small animals
and how many by large animals.
Overall,
how many phytoplankton
are eaten.
I can measure
the consumption
of phytoplankton.
It's the most important
response variable.
How is it affected by
zooplankton diversity?
How is this effect
strengthened by Omnivore?
In the experiment,
I measured
these things.
However,
it took too much energy.
I can only get
30 points.
I spent two summers
to get 30 points.
Let me show you
my experiment.
I
put a
boat on the
lake.
I drove the boat to the lake
to get water.
After I got water,
I put it back in the bottle.
There are animals
and plants in the bottle.
I left it in the lake
for a day.
I checked
how many animals and plants
disappeared.
However,
the first result
disappeared.
So I skipped it.
I can
share the results
with you later.
Let me show you
the animals
in the experiment.
Microzooplankton
look like
dinoflagellates.
There are also
small ciliates
in the experiment.
There are also large ciliates.
That's all for today.
In theory,
this experiment
is promising.
However, it is too labor intensive.
I can't
get a good result
from this experiment.
The sample size is too small.
I skip
the experiment result.
I will share
the results with you later.
Thank you
for your attention.
I will leave
my email address
at the end of the video.
If you have any questions
or suggestions,
please
leave a message.
Thank you.
Thank you,
for the wonderful
presentation.
Let's see if anyone
has any questions
about
Microzooplankton.
Let me ask a
naive question.
All your research
focuses on
phytoplankton
and zooplankton.
Can zooplankton
be applied
to larger
subspecies?
Large subspecies
are fine.
I can't
answer
this question
confidently.
I can't scale up
to larger animals.
It's complicated.
For example,
humans or
cats and dogs
are harder to
quantify
than
small animals.
It's hard to
systematically collect
data.
I'm not sure
if I can
scale up to
large animals.
If there's a system
that can measure
zooplankton and
consumer diversity,
this system
can be applied
to my framework
to see if
different systems
have different
effects.
Let me follow up
with a question.
Zooplankton
doesn't look
complicated.
It's just
eating and being eaten.
I'm thinking
that
when zooplankton
eats
phytoplankton
and is
being eaten,
doesn't it have
mechanisms
that make
zooplankton
eat phytoplankton?
I'm not sure
if I can
scale up to
large animals.
I'm not sure
if I can
scale up to
zooplankton
and eat
phytoplankton.
I'm not sure
if I can
scale up to
large animals.
I'm not sure
if I can
scale up to
zooplankton
and eat
phytoplankton.
I'm not sure
if I can
scale up to
large animals.
I'm not sure
if I can
scale up to
zooplankton
and eat
phytoplankton.
I'm not sure
if I can
scale up to
large animals.
I'm not sure
if I can
scale up to
large animals.
I'm not sure
if I can
scale up to
large animals.
And if I can
scale up to
a whole family.
If I can
scale up to
a whole family.
And if I can
scale up to
a whole family.
Because I'm not sure
if I can
scale up to
a whole family.
Because I'm not sure
if I can scale up
to a whole family.
Maybe the analysis
can help someone.
Because
I live in a small nature.
And my house
has withrawn
years ago.
So if
I do the analysis
I can scale up
to a whole family.
For example,
a pond can count
tens of thousands
of plants.
of individuals.
And animals
can count hundreds of thousands of individuals.
So the distribution
of variables
is actually
systematically dominant
but not statistically dominant.
Statistically uncertainty dominant.
I think so.
I don't understand
what you mean.
What I mean is
the number of
animals you count
is so large
that
there is no calculation
error.
The distribution width
mainly comes from
the difference in region
and year, right?
Yes.
We believe so.
For example,
the species
of phytoplankton.
I do one thing.
I verify
the species
of phytoplankton.
How to say?
I don't count
the number of species.
I consider
all samples
given sampling effort.
I can draw a curve.
Sampling effort
is x-axis.
Y-axis is species richness.
Given a sampling effort,
I can estimate
how many species
the sampling effort should have.
This curve
is calculated
from all data.
So
I assume
my sampling is
representative
to that lake.
I can't verify this.
But I count a lot.
This assumption should be possible.
I also consider
the sampling effort.
I don't count
the number of species.
I count a lot
and get a lot of species.
I count a little and get a little species.
I see.
Thank you.
Let me explain
why I ask this question.
A while ago,
I went to see
a group of researchers.
They were doing
microscopic sampling.
They said
it was hard
to calculate
the number of species
with human eyes.
If you know
the statistical error,
you can calculate
the number of species.
They developed a
video recognition method
to calculate
the number of species.
They immediately reduced
the error.
I was wondering
if you could apply this technology.
You said you counted
tens of thousands of species.
The statistical error of tens of thousands
is about 1%.
The width of the distribution
is more than 1%.
This means
the dominant bias
is different by region
and year.
It doesn't help you much.
I was wondering
if we could apply
a better method
of sampling.
You said
this method
was like
a machine
doing it for me.
If I look at it
with my eyes,
I need to look at
1 liter of water.
But this machine
is like a microscope
taking photos of me.
It keeps taking photos.
I can adjust the flow rate
and how fast or slow it is.
It's a bit like
the technique you mentioned.
This software is a bit like
It helps me expand my sample size.
Okay.
That makes sense.
The problem I encountered
in this field
is that
I can build
these curves
and detect these signals.
I have more than 1,000 data.
But when I
need to measure these feeding needs,
because I'm alone,
I can only measure
up to 40 data points.
The problem I encountered
is that the machine exists,
but the distribution
is zero.
So
it's a lot of trouble.
I see. So you really need
a lot of statistics.
I'm willing to
do research
in the wild.
I see. Thank you.
Thank you.
Any other
questions?
If not,
let's give a round of applause
to thank Zhang Fengxun
for his wonderful presentation.
Thank you.
Thank you, everyone.
This is the end of
the webinar.
The video will be uploaded
next week.
If you are interested
in more details,
or would like to contact
Zhang Fengxun
for a more in-depth discussion,
please do so.
Thank you.