Hello, everyone. Welcome to the Terra Talk on February 23rd.
We welcome our speaker today, Ms. Zhang Yan-yong.
Ms. Zhang is currently a Ph.D. student at the California Institute of Technology.
Let me briefly introduce Ms. Zhang's background.
Ms. Zhang took a Ph.D. course on spectroscopy at the University of Taiwan,
for which she chose to focus on fitting audiovisual instruments for her lab.
tabs into crystal and celestial physics,
as well as hardware devices.
Ms. Zhang is currently working on SuperCDMS at Caltech,
which aims to measure dark matter.
which aims to measured dark matter.
Ms. Zhang is currently working on SuperCDMS at Caltech,
What I mean is there are 30 spectrums in this list
There is a difference between the expected and predicted mass by GRAVITY
When it is
close to about the galaxy,
the material is able to spin faster than the prescribed velocity
when it is close to about the galaxy,
This means when it
is close to the galaxy, the force is much greater than the expected force
when it is close to the galaxy, the force is much greater than the expected force
It is able to maintain the orbit faster
If you have any questions, just ask directly
Sometimes, there are some confusion
Is this uncertainty too blue?
It looks like the blue line is very strong
The blue line indicates that it should look like this
And the red line indicates that it probably grows like this
But it says that the measurement allows to accurately measure if any location
can measure the distance between the crucible, solar system's velocity
each média indicates very low uncertainty
Okay, so this should be very accurate
Okay, so we know that
We found out that these planets rotate
Can I ask a question?
So you mean all the black lines are pretty accurate
The masses are not the same
The distribution is not the same
So you can imagine that there are 31 sets of blue and red lines
I just want to emphasize that it is getting more and more obvious when you get close to the periphery
It's too fast
It's so fast that it's weird
So at this time
You see this person called Vicky
He noticed this when he was observing the Small Magellanic Orbit
So he is the first to propose this
So there is actually a blue light cloud
I draw it up to tell you that there is something there
But in fact you can't see the blue light
There is a black hole, a light cloud
Dark matter
It is a mass
It is also radiating gravity
These things are symmetrical
Many people did not believe it until it was proposed
Vera Rubin did a very careful measurement
For many galaxies
This is a typical example
We can observe what we see
Its behavior
How much gravity affects it
Then we can see what can radiate gravity
How much can we really see
Then we compare the difference
Then we find that there is a part of the mass that we can't see
This is easier to understand
But in fact, dark matter has a lot of
There are a lot of different scales
It can be attributed to dark matter
What you see in the upper left corner
Is the rotation curve
Second, what you see in the upper right corner
All the light spots are a galaxy cluster
In other words, that a light spot
There are so many galaxies
It looks like a big universe
This is a simulation
The black part is dark matter
It makes the background of the universe white
If there is no dark matter in the universe
In this simulation
There is no way to form enough gravity to attract the matter
It is not heavy enough
So there are a lot of dark matter
It is closer to the cosmic web
Then the gravity will quickly suck in the visible matter
So dark matter can be explained well
If you look at the lower left corner
First, I want to say that the blue light cloud and the red light cloud in the lower left corner are added
The blue light cloud and the red light cloud in the lower left corner are added
There are not seen
Do you see the red part?
It means that it has observed X-ray emission
Do you see the blue part?
It is under the effect of limited sunlight
The equivalent effect of GANS
It is the opposite of GANS
The blue parts on two sides are soaked with GANS
The red parts are soaked with X-ray emission
In this graph, the two galaxy clusters clash
When they clash, the 2 clusters pass
We know that when these clusters collide
The closest cluster will generate X-ray
They look like two sprays of water
But there are two masses
They run far away
They don't interact
They don't interact with the matter we know
This is called a Bully Cluster
This can also give a very strong constraint
It is massive and it doesn't work
In the lower left corner
We can see the light blue and green
This is our galaxy
If we observe from the earth
This is the background of the universe
The red part is hot, the blue part is cold
This is the radiation of the universe
If I make this galaxy
2D Fourier Transform
You can see the shape of the light bulb
90 degrees, 18 degrees, 1 degree
0.2, 0.1, 0.07
What is the axis of gravity
Correlation
The heat is directly related between the two points
The chance is basically this
In other words, this blue and green
At about 1 degree
Or 0.7 degrees or 0.5 degrees
So its density will mainly appear at these angles
This is very interesting
We first have to ask how the universe's background radiation is produced
The background radiation of the universe is in the very distant early universe
When these lights are no longer with the very chaotic matter in the universe
After the Big Bang
It recorded the temperature of that location
What is the temperature
Temperature is the density of the location
Because the higher the density, the greater the pressure
The higher the temperature, the more heat, the more radiation
So we observe the distribution of the CMB map
How is the quality distributed in the universe
We can find one thing from this
To be so closely distributed
Like you see this spectrum
If only the quality in the universe we see now is not enough
We need more quality
They will first be crowded together because of gravity
Then their gravity will help lighter matter
It's like a right-hand corner map
The story is very similar
If only the matter we see is not heavy enough
To form the CMB map
Here we can tell us
There are many observations in the universe
The observed matter physics is basically particle physics
It's not consistent with gravity
A good direction is to think
Some things in our model have mass
We can explain it
This is dark matter
I will stop here
Do you have any questions?
It will be more technical
You can ask a difficult question
I want to ask a simple question
Do you know about the Fermi Law?
Want to know about Fermi Law?
want to know about Fermi Law?
Questions
Because some galaxies are large
It's curious, isn't this my job?
Isn't this my job?
Can you hear me?
Let me ask
Regarding the explanation
Because there is dark matter
It has weight but it can't be seen or observed
It's just an explanation
Is there any other explanation?
Try to explain this matter
And I'm very interested
But first, it's hard to do experiments in a short time
So I'm not doing it now
But I've been thinking
I told you that gravity is not wrong
It's just that there are some matters you can't see
The other best explanation is that gravity is wrong
Is this okay?
Yes, gravity is wrong
The answer is this
Why is gravity wrong is interesting
Because we always know
Quantum mechanics works very well
It can explain almost everything we see
Even if it can't explain
It can also be based on quantum mechanics
Give you a good model
Except for one thing, we have no idea
Is gravity
We can't quantize it
Then quantize can normalize
It becomes a good theory
So many people always think
Another good explanation is dark matter
Is a good example
Some very important and we don't know
In these places
It will be with the traditional gravity we know
Or quantum mechanics is incompatible
Of course, there are many ways to explain
We can talk about it later
But basically this is my answer
Gravity may be wrong
This is also a direction
Because I actually
Stay in high school and university physics
Let me feel like
Maybe it sounds like etheric
A little hypothetical
This is just a model
I agree
Thank you
Let's start talking about technical things
First of all, what you see here
Is what we know so far
Dark matter
Should say
On the table
Dark matter model
You see the lightest
That z is 10-
369 12 15
21 24
Small z is 10-24
Square EV
This is the quality unit
If you are not familiar with EV
EV is the weight of the electron
So it's so light
10-24 square electron weight
The heaviest
Can be so heavy
He can't use EV
He is 30 solar weight on the right
But we usually don't talk about
PEV
10-15 square electron weight
Obviously we don't understand this problem
Don't understand
We can build up
If you can imagine
These things in the range
May be a good model
And not ruled out
But the most important thing
You can see that there are two groups
A group on the right
WIMP
Hidden Sector Dark Matter
Hidden Thermal Relic
Asymmetric Dark Matter
Freezing Dark Matter
SIMP
On the left
Exia
Ultralight
What is the main difference
The main difference is
The heavier one
It will calm down
You can imagine
In the process of cooling
It will cool down
Stop at a point
Like a dot
In our galaxy
Like a planet
Rotate like a dust
Ultralight on the right
Is the best name
It's so light
Its material wave is very long
So long
It may be as big as a galaxy
So you can't define
It is a point like
Particle or wave
Or matter wave
So it has a very strong
Coherence interaction
Of course
In other words, it will not cool down
OK
But the point we want to talk about today
Is these particle-like
Instead of wave-like
So we will focus on today
This orange part
Is the so-called thermal relic
For thermal relic
Experts don't need me to explain
According to my explanation
In the process of cosmic cooling
It will cool down
Localize
Point-like
Then of course
According to our observations on astronomy
We can have some
Restrictions
These particles can't be less than
Can't be more than
Hundreds of T.E.V.
This is the range
OK
The next page is
How do we measure
What you see here is a
It's like a Feynman diagram
It's not a Feynman diagram
In other words, this chi or this big X
Is the dark matter
Dark matter
If they interact
They can produce two
Standard model
We already know the particle
Then they may shoot out
For example, Neutrino, Gamma ray, X-ray
Or Lepton
Or even proton
Then you can use some
Measurement of cosmic radiation
If something like this happens somewhere in the universe
It may shoot out to the earth
The particle we can measure
For example, Anitta, IceCube, AMS, Fermi
OK
If you look at the top of this picture
Collider is basically the opposite
You take the Standard Model Particle
With another Standard Model Particle
Then put it together
Then hope this one
Matter energy will become
What is that called
Dark matter comes out
Then I put a quotation here
If both come out as dark matter, you're done
You can't see anything
But in Collider, if it comes out as dark matter
The other one is not dark matter
Then you have to go through another behavior
To understand what that part is
Then this is probably what Collider is doing
What is LHC, Bell
Or even there are many experiments
It is Accelerator
It may not be Collider
It may be to take this beam and hit a target
Then hope that target can shoot something
That is also the concept
OK, today our focus is
Direct Detection
Direct Detection is this picture
Look up or look down
What does this mean
That is to say
Standard Model Particle
On the earth
We use it as a detector
Then there is a dark matter
Hit it
Then it bounced away
Then this time it was hit
Proton or Neutron or Electron
We use it as a detector
Will move, basically like this
It moves like a baseball
Then we measure this dynamic
Its concept is basically like this
The more famous one is
Liquid Noble Gas
Liquid Noble
It is a doping element
Turn it into a liquid
Or you can use Solid State
For example, semiconductor, superconductor, etc.
Then there are some people who use Cavity
But Cavity is usually not Thermal
So I won't talk about it today
Next page
Then we will focus on
So what is Direct Detection
You can see the picture on the right
Can I ask a question
You say
So
From the beginning
Everyone speculates that there is dark matter
This matter
It sounds like
Assuming
This gravity is right
Then
So I guess he must have
Some dark matter that I can't observe
So
Is it possible
Uh
In the last page
Those observations
Direct or indirect observation
The way of dark matter
I must
Is
Every way
Must rely on
The relationship above
To speculate the existence of dark matter
Ok
This is what I want to say first
What we are doing
Is hope
Except for this
We can really see
It's like a particle
Interaction
Instead of
Pure gravity
But the answer is
You are right
So far all the phenomena we have seen are
Only gravity
No one else
Why is it important
Other interactions
Understanding or restricting
Uh this model is very important
Important thing
Then I just said something wrong
That
I made a very stupid mistake
That is, the electronic quality is half MEV
Not half EV
Did I say EV?
Anyway, the electronic quality is MEV
Everyone will see
This quality is important
Ok, let's go back to the current projection
I have a question
I want to ask
Does anyone predict
How much is the distribution of dark matter
How is it
It is a
Now is
I can't imagine
It is
Dark matter is a
Particle
Such a thing exists
Then every particle
Has a certain quality
Or say
Any other way
To judge this dark matter
Is a group of things
That group of things
Various groups
A group of groups
Then each group does not necessarily have the same quality
Like this
Because now you look at your spectrum
It looks like a lot less
But it doesn't seem to say
If I have any
Prediction
Then it will be
A group of basic examples
Or is it a
Any group of quality
Any energy
Ok
The answer is we don't know
I can only tell you
Now the general assumption is
We measure the signal
Then we
Convert this signal to
Interaction
When these parameters
You now see the upper right corner
This picture
Dark matter
There is only one dark matter
Then the quality of the particle
That's the quality
This is the assumption
In many models
Dark matter can have more than one
Since there is more than one dark matter
Its quality will not be only one
So how it decays
Or how it interacts
Its scenario
But in order to be able to compare each other
Data
On the same basis
So now we usually assume
Dark matter has only one
Then we don't care what it is
We only care about its quality
Ok
Got it
Ok, let's go back to this page
In fact, I just told you a lot about this page
So how do we do it
In this galaxy
We built a detector on the earth
Then our solar system
Rotates inside
So we keep bumping into this
Our Milky Way
Dark matter
So it keeps changing
In other words, we are on the earth
With us as the coordinate
Is it okay?
This is our
If you are from this
Accelerator
This is our
Ok
You can see that there are three pictures below
Is dark matter
Dark matter
Sorry
With our
Normal matter
Neutron, proton, electron
Then run away like hitting a ball
This is the first
Its momentum transfer
Energy transfer
It's very simple
You just need to know how heavy the two balls are
Energy momentum conservation
The second one is more interesting
The second one is the picture in the middle
How to do it
If today
If there is a
Dark matter
With normal
We already know the matter
They will exchange each other
As long as they can
They have each other
This quantum number
Anyway, as long as they can
Conserve some property
They can walk around
Become another
What is hope
It becomes
Normal matter
Then we can measure it
The example you see below is
If today there is a dark matter like boson
Dark matter
It may have a certain chance to convert
The boson we know
Here is an example
Gamma
Gamma is the same as the electron
We can measure this
Photon out of nowhere
This is a dark matter signal
The third one
If dark matter
Is this A
If it comes in
This dark matter
It will decay itself
Two light
If your model
Usually we will find
You can have a process
If you help it
Supply another light
You see this B
It's usually a very strong magnetic field
You are crazy
Force it
I give you a foot
You go to another foot
So you can supply it
This magnetic field
It came in and measured the light
This is also a way
If you have this
You can do it
We are not a single channel search
We don't decide a channel
How it will decay
We put our detector
Then dark matter
We don't know what it is
But we know it continues to hit our detector
Then we see the signal
We go again
If it is this model
What would it be
So basically we are a bunch of models
Then interpret
What does it mean
What you see now
Is a very typical
Experimental results
That is to say
If I assume today
We want to look at dark matter
Nucleic acid
The contrast
What you see
Is the probability of action
You see down
The probability is getting smaller
What about the horizontal
Is this dark matter
How do I read
You assume a mass
For example, ETEV
Then you look up
Then see a certain line
Means
A conclusion
It's not right above this line
Why
Because if the quality of dark matter
Is this ETEV
Then the probability of action
Will be greater than 10 to the negative 44
Then I should have
In the size of my detector
And measuring time
See a lot of signals
But I didn't see anything
So at the level of confidence
I can say that it will never be greater than this value
Then I can assume that dark matter is a lot of different qualities
I can draw a line
Is the line you see
Is there a problem with this
It's okay
So basically
There are many lines
Each line is a different experiment
But
Every line
The gray dotted line
And then there is a grid
What does that mean
That's the sun
The sun is not always acting on this
This effect
We can't avoid
As long as we look at the sun
This is the sun's
Radiation
That
When your detector
I want to ask a question
That is to say, each line represents
Every experiment
It has a lot of models
It basically covers the model
No, this is usually one experiment
One model
Usually the data from the same experiment
Use different models to interpret
OK
Right
Anyway
Wait a minute
I'll answer the question first
What is the gray line
That gray line is when your experiment
When you get there
You will start to see the sun
Neutrino
And under the gradient
Under the gradient
You can't tell the difference between dark matter and neutrino
So you just
Basically
So that means
In this picture
When you put the rest
No white space
It means we
It's not possible to use
The method to detect
Unless you can distinguish
Neutrino and dark matter
The difference in signal
Otherwise you can't see it anymore
Yeah
OK
Any other questions
I have a question
I just don't understand
Is this line
Why is there a
Optimal
The mass
OK
I'll talk about this
Most of the lines are now
For example
Between 10-2 and 10-1
There is a
The deepest place
Why is it so deep
I'll talk about this later
OK
Sorry
I want to ask this
Is this a model-dependent
Search
Or is it a general search
Is it a model-dependent
Search or general search
Uh
In our field
Usually this picture
Model-independent
Search
Dark matter
With your nucleon
Elastic scattering
But
Literally
You still have some models
With nucleon
Elastic scattering
But
But this
So this picture is
Elastic scattering
And he has to assume one more thing
Dark matter has nothing to do with spin
If it has something to do with spin
You have to reduce the number of neutrons and neutrons
Because they will cancel
So that's a model
So to some extent this is not
Model-independent in text
But this thing is called model-independent
Because it is the widest
You can cover a lot of models
OK
Next page
If you put this here
This one is called limit plot
This range, take a look at it
What quality range
Throw it back to the model I just saw
You see it only digs that one
Little piece is called classical
WIMP
If you are doing high-performance, you will know
These things are all dug in
Weak scale
10 hundred times of weak scale
What is it
100 GeV to a few GeV
But this range
It's very wide
All these experiments are dug here
Sorry
What we want to do is ask a question
What about the other parts
What do we do
OK
So if you see this page now
I reduced the whole picture
Reduced to
This picture you see
Only the right side of this small piece
The gray part is where they are now
Digged
Then
The whole white one next to it
I didn't dig it all
Then I drew a lot on it
Various models
You can see it right away
The experiment they are digging
It's about 10 GeV to a few TeV
Basically they are very
Focus on this
Supersymmetric theory
MSSM
Then according to different adjustments
Its parameters
It can slightly adjust its range
But basically they are all digging
These things
But in fact, there are a lot of dark matter models
You can see
For example
10 to 5 GeV
There are still very good models here
And it should
So it should be Thermorelic
What we want to ask is
What about these models
You can see it now
I showed it
That is
What you see now
I zoom in to these
Places that have not been dug
The actual line is already dug
The actual line you can see
It's all CDMS
So I said CDMS is Low Mass Dark Matter Search
Very important and
It's basically a world-leading sensitivity
Experiment
If you see the long
This virtual line
Is already doing
Then probably in a few years
The result will come out
Simulation expected results
The best thing to see
It should still be SNOLAB
Except for this NewsG
NewsG is quite above
But its MassReach can reach
Is 100 MeV
Then if you see that dot line
Dot line is that everyone has some concepts
Then they use some
Basic physical way
To estimate the reach of these concepts
So there are actually a lot of people
Thinking about this
But this thing is also
WIMP Search
Continuous
LHC
Effective machine
This community
This high-performance community is thinking
If not WIMP
Not SUSY
How to do
I will talk about
How did these lines come
I will be very fast
Skip a big part
Because I talked about it for a long time
Recap
So what is Elastic Scattering
Basically what you see now
Dark Matter comes in and hits your detector
Then you can measure Recoil Energy
Next is to answer
The question just asked
What is Elastic Scattering
It is basically a momentum transfer
You learned it when you were at PuWu
How much energy has passed
It's four times the energy
Then multiply
This two
Hit and hit
The quality of these two particles is not even
If one is very heavy, one is very light
Hit down
The quality and energy will not pass
When will it pass the most
In these two hits and hits
When their quality is the same
100% will pass
This also answers the question
Why everyone digs
Optimal point
Because it is used to build
The particle of the detector
It's almost in that position
It's so heavy
It is the most sensitive
Is this okay
Everyone can see
If my model today
My particle is probably GEV
Nucleon
These boxes are probably GEV
More than 900
About 1000
In the position of the earth
Gravity
The speed of rotation of all particles
About 300 km per second
Put the number in
You will see the energy
Probably
An X-ray energy
Just a few tens of keV
But if
Today you put your
Model from this box
Change to electronic
It's very, very light
At this time
You get the maximum
Momentum transfer
Will come from
A very light particle
Let's imagine today
The quality of the electronic is probably MEV scale
Half MEV scale
If you hit your particle at this time
It's also half MEV or MEV
At this time you put the number in
Your maximum energy detection
It can be from about 0.1 to
100 EV so much energy
It's probably less than sub keV
Then even
You have the mismatch of the mass
The dark matter you came in is
100 MEV
Sorry
Compare this energy
If you today
There is a 100 MEV
Mass
The dark matter hit your nuclear
It's GEV
You can probably see
Sub to 1 keV
This kind of energy
So if we can use
This method and then measure such a small energy
We can start to measure very light particles
But if we go back to that page
If you have a dark matter as heavy as electronic
To hit your nuclear
It will leave us one thousandth of the energy
It's basically very difficult to measure
What do you mean by Coherent?
First of all, I want to explain what Coherent is
Coherent is
If you have dark matter today
The size of its wave packet
Probably
It's not the size of a nuclear
But the size of your entire atomic nucleus
The energy it hits
Coherent is smaller than
Nuclear binding energy scale
It's more like hitting the entire atomic nucleus
It's a hit on the entire atomic nucleus
All the nuclei
So the rate of this hit
You pick up this signal
The chance is with
How many atomic nuclei
The nucleus becomes positive
The wave amplitude becomes positive
So the probability is positive square
So the hit event rate
How many atomic nuclei
How many nuclei become positive square
But if it's electronic today
Because
Unless you can have an electronic
Bound state
Otherwise free electron
Or bound to
These electrons are far away
So you basically only hit one at a time
So there is no Coherent
Addition effect
OK?
Continue
As I said
If dark matter becomes photon
It will be absorbed by charged particles
So how much energy it absorbs
How much total energy
So recap
Low mass search
Basically called a few GeV
Or lighter
Basically you want to see very little energy
So you want your
Detector
Energy threshold
Very low
You can start to see very little energy
If you just go back to the picture
It has a deepest place
That place is usually marked
Its maximum energy transfer
But
Towards a smaller energy or lighter mass
Sensitivity
Suddenly shot very high and then there is no line
Because their energy threshold
Detector's trigger threshold is there
They can't shoot any smaller
So there is a very important idea
You have to have a very low
Threshold to measure very light particles
OK
Of course I just told you
There are a lot of new models
Dark sector, Asymmetric DM, Freezing DM
Blah blah blah
But how do we do this
Detector
Let me recap
We want to maximize
Momentum transfer
So if you want to measure light particles
The picture here
Asymmetric
Dark matter
Sorry
Blah blah blah
Dark matter mass
Asymmetric
Energy transfer, Momentum transfer
You see all kinds of different elements
Its peak
Different places
The lighter the element, the peak
You can probe lighter mass
Does this make sense
Electron recoil
It's the lightest
OK
Of course, in addition to this
You have to maximize energy transfer
You have to have very low noise
You have to have a very high signal-to-noise ratio
To be able to measure such a small energy
So you have to have sub-KEV sensitivity
Then if you want
Can measure
You have to have very, very good ability to
Shoot limit or you have to be able to see
Interaction probability
Or cross-section is very small
Then your
Fake event background event rate
Very, very low
OK, here I will quickly
Skip because I actually want to talk about the third part
Super CDMS
So what are we doing now
Sorry
I'll go back to that side
Is there a problem
No problem
Can you hear me
You said
In fact, my physics is probably only high school physics
But it sounds like
You assume
Dark matter particles
With normal matter particles
There are all kinds of different models
Then energy will be generated
So you measure this energy
Then learn that this
Dark matter
How much is the mass
Is that right
In this case
Suppose you do the experiment today
Then measured the energy
But this does not mean
That your assumption model is correct
Yes, you are right
So this situation
But this situation
Should still be able to get at least
Conclusion that dark matter does exist
So this experiment
The point is
Is to prove the existence of dark matter
Is this
I
The first is to prove the existence of dark matter
This is the most important
The second is basically
Under the same logic
What we are doing now
Basically no one sees dark matter
So we can keep
Some models propose
You should see dark matter here
You should see this sensitivity
You can't see it, we can remove them all
So we are actually
Narrow down the possible parameter space
Oh
Now the logic is basically like this
But you are absolutely right
If one day everyone starts
A certain cross-section
Then in a certain mass
Start to see the event
When dark matter is here
Think about it
How to measure these signals
To understand what it is
Ok
Thank you
What are we doing now
We are doing a time called cryogenic dark matter search
Cryogenic means super low temperature
What we are doing is like this
What you see now is this right side
It's a super thin or fold
Group of germanium
Its size
It's about 10 centimeters
Its thickness is 3.3 centimeters
Not kilometers, it's centimeters
So this is one you've never seen
Super big piece of germanium
Or silicon
You go out and buy wafer
It will never help you cut such a thick piece
But our detector looks like this
If you look at the left
This white line is dark matter
Knock on the atomic box and run out
Then see this blue one
It will dissipate heat
Then this heat dissipation
Because it is very, very low energy
It is very localized
Then at the same time
The electrons in your material
And this electric team
So it will shoot this red
Ok, this is the electronic electric team
So what are we measuring
We are measuring these electronic electric teams
At the same time we are also measuring phonon
We measured this phonon
And this electric team
We can see very, very small signals
Ok, the next page is talking about
Why do we have to measure at the same time
Electronic electric team
To measure phonon
If today
Particle is hit
That atomic box
It will be about 1 in 3
Its phonon energy
With ionization
Is the electric team
Energy ratio is about 1 to 3
Phonon is about 3 times
But if it hits today
Is that electron
100% electron
Its ionization energy
Is 100%
So there is a difference of 1 to 3
So if you see this picture next to it today
There will be a very obvious difference
So we can immediately identify
It is hit
Why is this important
Because if today
Is very heavy
It will not leave energy
It will leave energy
So you want to vary
This is a lot of energy
To hit the atomic box
Or we know
To hit the electron
So we have this ability
I want to skip this
So we are based on this ability
We made a detector
You see this big piece of crystal
There are a lot of small things on the surface
It is a super conductor
When it picks up energy
It will immediately from the superconductor
Turn into a normal conductor
In this fast
In the process of transformation
Its sensitivity is very large
A little bit of energy
Its electron will change a lot
So we can use this thing to do very, very precise measurements
At the same time, we also designed a very good
This
The distribution of electrons
In the lower right corner of this picture
If it is on the surface
Hit
Electrons and electrons will run to the same side
If you hit it in the middle
Electrons and electrons will be pulled to one side
Why is this important
Because most of the particles we already know
Relative to dark matter
It's easier to be blocked on the surface than in the middle
Because dark matter is the hardest to block
It will go to the middle
So the more to the middle, the more like dark matter
So we can do this
I don't want to talk about this at all
I just want to conclude
About this kind
Hit the nucleus or hit the electron
This kind of detector
In our expected detection time
We have 100% confidence
We can distinguish
Nuclear recoil or
Electron recoil
We can do a good job
Find dark matter
This kind of style
Dark matter search
In addition to this
We have another thing to use
This thing is called
HV detector
HV means high voltage
We are on this
Detector
Add a very large
This power plant
If it is released
Any free electronic electric team
It will be very fast
Speed ​​up
It's in this crystal
Middle speed
But the reason is that it can't exceed
So as long as it exceeds the middle speed
It is called heat dissipation
The meaning of heat dissipation
Is to create additional
Secondary phonon emission
So you add a big power plant to it
As long as you
Activate a free
Electronic electric team
You will get a lot of phonon energy
So
We can put very small
Enlarge to very large
So at this time
If your
Threshold is from your electronic
Noise
Our signal will be far greater than the noise
So we
Equivalent trigger
Trigger on specific recoil energy
Our threshold will be very, very low
We can lower the threshold by 100 times
If you give it 100 volts
This drift
The voltage
But what is his problem
Basically you are now
Electron recoil or nuclear recoil
You have completely lost the distortion
Electron recoil and nuclear recoil
But we can see very small energy
I don't want to talk about this
Basically just want to say
We have to build a big experiment
And then get it to very, very low temperature
Otherwise thermal agitation
Will keep creating thermal phonon
Ok
I jumped directly to the last page
Now everyone sees
There is a lot of radioactivity
What kind of money
What is this
Uranium
These things are all in our experimental environment
Then they will be radioactive
Is to shoot all kinds of particles
We want to make sure
All these elements are very, very
In our experiment
We can see
Just make sure that if there is really a signal today
I saw we have a lot of confidence
It will never be these impurities
Radioactivity
I don't want to skip this
This is basically to say
So we put all these
Background radioactivity
Then there is just said
IZ and HV detector
Germanium and silicon
Then put it on
You will see that in the end we can
Dig this piece
We haven't yet
This 2020 will start
It is expected to run for five years
You can dig this piece
Here is very sloppy
Is there a problem
Is this pink
This orange pink piece
Hey you say that again
Did you just detect all the detect functions?
Can you explain this place again?
Forget it
Let's talk about it at the end
It feels like it will be a long time
Actually, it's okay
This thing is what you think
Is
If you are today
I just didn't say if your dark matter
Hit the atomic box
There will be one-third of the ionization
One-third of the energy
Will also become a double pair
But if today your dark matter
It's 100%
If it's enough
Then these two scenarios
Will produce an electron and a double pair
That produces an electron and a double pair
Then I give it a high pressure
This high pressure will pull this electron
Accelerate to very fast
Accelerate to exceed its terminal speed
But when it exceeds the terminal speed
It must decelerate
Its principle is basically like this
It decelerates
It has to release energy
So basically
I don't care if I want to look at nuclear recoil
Or electron recoil
I'm starting to look at phonon now
What about the phonon I see
If today is nuclear recoil
It primary
There will be phonon
Then the ionization it creates at the same time
Pulled like this
There will also be secondary phonon
I look at nuclear recoil, I look at these two phonons
Phonon signal
But if today is electron recoil
I basically look at these electrons
After all were ionized
How many secondary phonons did they create
Probably like this
Is it clear to me?
Ok, keep going, thank you
Ok
This page
I want to skip
Ok, I'll just talk about this page
I'm starting to talk now
Sorry, I'm starting to talk now
So how do all these things integrate into the future
That is to say
We found one thing
I've been talking about it all the time
Today
If there is nuclear recoil
About one-third of the energy
You can still see one-third of the energy in ionization
Compared to your phonon energy
This thing
Probably right
Our best model now is called Linhardt
This is actually a half century old model
He explains
That is
The effect of electronic shielding on the atomic
Then you can see
One-third of this
I just talked about one-third of it
There is a blue line
This is the model
If you hit the energy
What is above 10 keV
It's all right
But below 10 keV
It's getting worse
But no one knows
Because no one could measure such a small energy
But now everyone can measure such a small energy
You have to measure very small energy
You can start detecting very small
Very light dark matter
So this thing becomes very important
So this is a very important direction
We are going to start studying
What is this ratio
This thing is very
Go hand in hand with low-threshold detector
Because you can't
You have to be able to measure such a small energy
Then you can start constraining this ratio
This ratio is currently
If you want to measure nuclear recoil
This is the highest level of certainty in your analysis
Then skip this page
The second one is
We can put this kind of high-voltage
How good is this kind of high-voltage detector
What about a recent paper
Stanford has a group
They made this little chip
This little chip is about 1 cm x 1 cm
This is 1 cm x 1 cm
Just as big as a thumb
Then its thickness is 1 cm
1 cm or half a centimeter
Anyway, it's a
It's a gram-scale small detector
So it can block the dark matter
The rate is very low
But it is super optimized
This high-voltage
Look at the design of the phonon detector
Then what do you see now
Is to see the picture on the right
There is a single peak
It's 0, 1, 2, 3
These peaks are all separated
What is this
There is a signal in this crystal
Created a single electron hole pair
Double, triple electron hole pair
It can see the quantized electron hole pair
So this is
You have to test
To use HV detector
Optimal sensitivity
You can start counting
Single electron hole pair
Created by detecting phonon
So you can see here
Its energy threshold is super low
It is 0.33eV
It can shoot
It only operates for one day
Within one day on surface
And it doesn't even have to go underground
To cover up those radioactivity
This is the one I'm going to talk about
You can see
If I can use this
Now everyone wants to use this
High voltage detector
In order to increase
It is offered tentest
You see the dots
Now there is a test called Sensai
It can do this
We think that Super CDMX can do
It can do
Lower than EMUV sensitivity
If we can optimize
It is the nature of HV detector
I want to skip this page
Next is that we can optimize
As I said, the phonon is a super conductor
If, It is very sensitive
As long as it picks up a bit of energy
It accumulates from the super conductor
So we can measure a great change in electrons
And here
When the plusion picks up the energy
It is the resistance of the virtual conductor
Now if the vector is a super conductor
If we connect it to the capacitor
It becomes a thermostat
So if the grand thermostat changes
It turns into the resonant freq
So if a as you can see on the map
Today if the cuper pair gets broken
If the cuper pair gets broken
and the impedance changes
The resonant frequency will be different
The interesting part is that every detector is small
So I can see the next page
This is super cdms snowlab detector
If you look at the bottom left
It has to connect a lot of small dds
It has to change the capacitor
It can make 12 pixels
Because even if the capacitor is 0
It is still small
So you have to connect a lot of dds
So you can see the signal
So it can only make 12 pixels
But if you look at the right picture
This is what we are doing in the lab
We use the way of super cdms
We can make every small square
So basically we are doing 80,100,200 pixels
So this technology has been demonstrated
The energy resolution is the same as the TX
It's very easy to do
It can save a lot of money
OK that is what we want to do now
There is also another aspect
What we kept talking about
We want to use it as a target
For dark matter
We can measure smaller energy
It's not exactly right
In fact, we want to do
We want to do
First, the primary target
But second
It picks up the energy it wants to measure
It must have an excited state to jump on
That's what we're looking at right now
Half brain
Except, there are more
For example, like
But the temperature will drift
Or like diamonds
These semiconductors have different bandgaps
Now a lot of people are thinking
Can we pick up more fancy materials
For example, gallium arsenide
These materials
To optimize the bandgap
We can pick up less energy
Another interesting thing is
Germanium silicon is a pure material
It has no polarization
But if there is gallium arsenide today
It will have a very strong dipole
So it will produce
I need to supply
I just said at the beginning
If I can supply a single particle
I can force it to keep running
There will be a very strong coupling
So materials like gallium arsenide
Axion-like particles or photon coupling
This is the first
But I can go further
Can I find
Smaller materials
For example, superconductor
Or superfluid helium
Now the bandgap is directly from
EV to mini-EV
You can measure very small energy
This is far future
If you look at the picture in the lower right corner
If you use scattering
Or EM absorption
What we are doing now
If you see the semiconductor in the middle
Or scintillator
Basically ionization
Traditionally the only thing that can be dug into WIMP
But in the future
Many people are thinking to use superfluid
Or superconductor as a target
This is also a direction
What did I say today?
Let me summarize
In the dark matter community
There is a paradigm shift
From classical WIMP
Everyone started to pay more attention to low mass dark matter
For example, in the EV scale
There may be Daryl, Neutrino
Or in the MEV, Dark Sector
There are many models that can be done
Traditionally, when doing WIMP search in dark matter
Everyone only cares about nuclear recoil
Because it's very heavy in that scale
You just want to hit the nuclear
You won't have a signal when you hit the electron
But now everyone is starting to pay attention
Electron recoil and nuclear recoil
It requires substantial improvement in low threshold detector technology
About this
I think it's fair to say
Super CDMX is the best
Basically, we have iZip
Can do ERNR discriminating
Tagging search
Or I can do
Ultra low threshold, ultra small energy search
Future
I want to be able to measure
More technology
Can measure smaller recoil
I want to have better calibration
To understand
How much ratio it has in NR
You can see ionization
What we can do now
Ionization quantum counting detector
I just introduced
In addition to measuring the change of electrons
Ultrasound sensor
Can also be used to measure the change of electrons
It has many benefits
The most important thing is
Eventually we want to measure
Thermorelic lower bound
Probably KEV
If I remember correctly
KEV
ER
Electron
Because I want to have a very light target
I can maximize my energy
Thank you
Um, do you have any questions?
What is this clip?
Oh, this is a very good question
Um
What is this
Um, I'm back
Is this a toy?
Yes, this is a toy
Look at the bottom right corner of this video
There is a called the particle zoo
If you google the particle zoo
It is a company
It has a lot of dolls
All we know
Hypothetical
Or all kinds of particles
Are made into toys
The black square is dark matter
All other people
It's all cotton
Only dark matter is sand
Because it is very heavy
That's probably the concept
But that's because it was a model
I think it can start to sand cotton
OK
Is this a business statement?
No, it's not
Should not be a business statement
It's a
I don't know if it's still running
It seems to have become a bit like a non-profit
It's a company that accepts people's donations
Because business is not good
It's cool to open a website
Sorry
Any other questions?
Someone asked first
Then I'll ask first
Zhang Youning
Everyone has their own opinion
What to measure
Different methods
Eliminate
Improving the ratio of information
Then your
Talk will talk about it
Do you have a
Value or a definition
Theoretical scientist
He said
If we measure something
Or when we get to a certain value
We call it measured
Or
Prove that there is a dark matter value
Up to 99.97
Have
Basically your question is
How do I define
Correct
The answer is
There are two ways
You actually don't know
Your background
What should it look like
What is the probability
If so
Is to put your background
This rate
Keep erasing
It's in you
Your experiment
Then according to your
The size of the experiment
Theoretically it should not appear
Any
OK
That
If it should not appear
Then today you measured it once
Then
I can tell you
What is the probability of it
But you measured 30
Then ask
How much confidence do you have
This is from another source
This is a very common statistic
Right
But the key to this whole thing is
You have to put your background
You can't see it at all
You will know when you see it
The second one
That is
If you have a background
Appearance frequency
Or for a certain parameter
Parameter you can measure
There is a certain understanding
OK
Then you have a curve
You can see what you see
In this parameter you can measure
Distribution above
OK
Then if there is
A big one
Beyond your model
You can't see it
You will have enough confidence to say
How much confidence it is
Is with
This distribution is not consistent
Do you understand
Did I explain
Um
I understand
Just
You just mentioned
How much
My understanding is probably like this
Um
Hey i think
After the noise
The rest is the signal
Then the signal is that I have measured
I'm just curious
Can you recognize the cup or
Uh
Things like
Hey
Uh
I think
I think this is the case
No one should know where it will be measured
But
Uh
What to do now is that you can measure
A pile of signals
Then these signals give you enough
Confidence level
This is definitely not
What we expect to see
Then this is the cup
Oh
This is the conclusion, this means that it is a new thing
By definition it is dark matter
Right
Because we don't know
Super cdms threshold
5 sigma
Uh super cdms
Threshold you mean
Uh you mean
Detection or you mean
Detector itself
Signal to noise ratio
Uh i mean you measured the signal
With the cup
Oh yeah yeah
If we are
Eventually we want to send
Uh we
Want to send
If we want to claim detection
5 sigma
But um
The problem now is
If we are today
Not so good
Or we are
Select material
Not so good
Not very clean
Eventually
What is it
4 events
You can claim
I saw an event nearby
But the confidence level is very low
Or you can say
Uh this thing will degrade my limit
But I assume that I made a mistake
Uh i don't think
In the future we will
Like we used to do
Is that we will say
Hey we see
Signal and then we are
Draw a contour on the limit plot
But this contour is 90% confidence
I don't think we will do this in the future
We used to do this
But we
Should be quite clear in the future
We will only say at least 25
Because 25 is your zero background
If you are plus on fluctuation
You should be square root
At least 25
We might say uh we claim
See something
Uh
Correct
Any questions
Uh i'm curious
Is you
After this device is designed
What kind of experiment is it
To do validation
Is to confirm this instrument
Indeed doing what you want
Want to do
Just do validation
Uh i don't know
How to say
Um ok
I think this can go back to the page I just skipped
Very very messy
That page
I thought it might be
High-performance experiment
Detector people will be more interested
So i skipped
Ok ok what do you see now
What you see now is
Uh let's just say
Let's take a look
Let's just talk about the picture on the right
The picture on the right
You see a lot of different colors
Dot
This is horizontal
What you see is
I'm on the front
And the opposite side
Electricity
The difference in energy
Ok so it's
It's a normalization
Ok
That is to say
The difference in ionization
Then what you see is
Phonon and ionization
The ratio is the one I just said
One third is nr
Ok so you see a lot of different colors
This color is actually added later
Then you see me now
Circle up there
There is a thing called california cf252
This is a radiative element
It will always shoot out the middle finger
We basically put a middle finger
Radiator
Put it on our detector
That middle finger keeps hitting
We think this should be the signal we want to see
It should look like
Because if today is
Anything else
It will act as a battery interaction
Whether it's gamma ray
Whether it's IR photon
Or electron
Its
It will be immediately
Will act as a battery
Block down
What you see at this time
It's not like your dark matter
Dark matter won't do this
So basically
What we are looking for is neutral particle
Then a very strong neutral particle
Will hit the atomic box
Then we think this signal
It's like we can see
Dark matter
So you see this california cf252
Is neutral source
So in other words, we can tag it next to it
It's background
This comes from a very strong
EM interaction source
That's led 210
So we're the same
Put led 210 on our detector
Then see these signals
Then find out
As we expected
Where the background should go
We basically do this
Does this answer your question?
Yes
Then I have another one
A more extensive question is
If I understand
You guys have been following up
Able to measure
Because it can measure lighter
Mass
But if you only use a single
It's usually neutral
Then its mass is
I don't know much about physics
But in my impression, it should be
So you can't confirm
Your instrument can measure
Mass
That's right
I have to say
Unless we have a dark matter source
Can calibrate our detector
Otherwise we will never know
What it looks like
But if we can do that
We don't have to measure anymore
So you're totally right
So there are some assumptions here
The assumption here is
We take our neutral to hit it
The energy it leaves
Energy is energy
It's not because it's from
Neutron to hit
There is a difference
So what we measured today
How much energy does it leave
Then based on this energy
Say OK
So the response I see in this energy
Is it the response I expect to see in this energy?
So basically
I don't care if it's neutral
But this assumption is like this
If you leave
For example, 1 keV
But this 1 keV comes from dark matter or neutron
In the end, your detector will have a different response
Then this will be different
This is a systematic
But this is the best we can do
Because we don't have a dark matter source
I think I understand
Thank you
I want to ask a question
That picture can be
There is a picture of Sigma vs Max
It's behind
Drawing a lot of different experiments
This
I just want to ask
Just assume
We want to do a new experiment now
Or maybe
Or improve other experiments
Do you have any suggestions
For example, because these lines
It's probably
For example, its peak is probably
It's around 10
So if we want to do something else later
For example, further
Or do other experiments
You will feel
For example, we want to prove
Of course, the further to the left
Or basically
For example, the part above the xenon
Is also the direction we can do
That is, if
If you want to do other experiments
This picture is basically like this
There are two directions you can go
Because this is a 2D picture
So there are two directions you can go
One is horizontal and one is vertical
Let's talk about what it means
It means
If you go horizontally
Basically you are in the probe
Different dark matter mass
If you go down
It's the same mass in the probe
But smaller
Smaller
Interaction cross action
No problem
But why do these pictures show
A straight line down
Then diagonally up a straight line
Triangle
This is probably the principle
Detector has its own noise
Below this noise
Then you are completely
Always noise
So you can't measure
You can only be above this line
That is Trigger Threshold
So that Trigger Threshold defines
The energy you can measure
In other words, it basically defines
You can measure the smallest particle mass
So this is the left one
Very sharp straight line
The right side is diagonally up
This is a log-log picture
So it's a log-log straight line
This basically means
You assume
The larger the particle mass
The less you see
So
Without seeing or seeing the same rate
The situation you can set
The weaker the limit
Because this principle is very simple
Because you know we are here
Is this dark matter
How much is the mass density of Halo
But mass density must be converted
To number density
To the mass
So the heavier the particle
The less
So hit your rate
Is 1 over m less
Do you understand
So the line on the right is probably
This means
First, I don't think
Different experiments
It should be said that the same experimental technology
Basically it is set
Where is its Threshold
So the super straight line on the right
It's hard to move
So if you want to change the line on the right
Basically you have to change
New technology
Not to say
How to get it
It can run left and right
It can only run up and down
Basically these lines can only run up and down
OK
Is it 1 over F?
No no no
Because this is the mass
This is the cross section
So that line basically means
Your Threshold is there
The gray line on the left
The line in the area is not
Which one
The picture on the right
The picture on the left
Is this
Yes
It should not be written on it
You can follow
I'll explain that later
OK
So I don't think
Use existing technology
It should not be said that I don't think
This is a recognition
Use the same technology
The bigger you can build
The more you use
The conclusion is
In the same time
In theory, you can block more
So if you don't block
You can set a stronger limit
But basically can't run left and right
Run left and right
Is to use different technology
So different technology
What is this technology
Is to reduce your Threshold
So basically what you can find
Is to find a way to reduce Threshold
OK
So in this picture you can see
The most obvious Threshold
The lowest is the light green
I point to this place
Why
I think the answer is different from others
If you go to track
The label
You will see
Aluminum SC
10mEV
What is that
Aluminum superconductor
Its bandgap is 10mEV
In fact, it is less than 10mEV
But its order of magnitude is 10mEV
It can slide over there
That
The rest you see
The light blue, dark blue
Dark green
What are these things
These are all semiconductors
So it actually has a label
What is silicon
Garlium arsenide
Silicon
They just take silicon
In a different way
Readout or readout or assembly
They are all over there
Then it actually has a label
Its Threshold
Let me see
Semiconductor Threshold is 10mEV
10mEV
I personally think
Go to a smaller Threshold
And the order of magnitude difference
Is to change the material
Now CEMS
I think we are already
Master
Semiconductor
Technology
Yes
So there may be
In short, it is
It depends on the signal to noise
The threshold of noise
So basically
Unless you change the material
It is unlikely to move
I think long term is to change the material
But is it possible to move
Yes, you can understand
What is your noise
You can understand what your noise is
Maybe you can reduce it
Eventually you can assume
If you are noise-free
Probably still around that
Can you reduce noise
Just in this group
Semiconductor experiment
Can you be better
That's about it
OK
You can ask
It doesn't matter
You continue
I just thought
Dark Matter Halo
Because you just said
It rotates in the universe
Then we can accept it
Does it have a number
For example, like Collider
Will it be here
It is with the earth
Our detector
Relative to this
Dark Matter Halo
How much is the luminosity
There is this number
This can be calculated
Let me explain
OK
What this picture draws
The solar system is here
Right
We know
The sun revolves around the Milky Way
How fast
Right
We also know
We observe
Our track
The quality of the package
How much is the quality of pulling us
Right
So we immediately know
How much is there
Missing mass
Can it be
But this is total mass
But if I do
The same thing
But I started from the middle of the reactor
Can I just make
How to say
Delta R
How much is it
Do I know
Every radius
Dark Matter Density
How much
Right
How fast
I know
How much
The only difference is
I don't know how heavy this particle is
So number density
You have to assume a mass
Basically depends on your model
But we actually know
What is this
Mass density
That's it
So that's model
Independent
But basically
But basically when we draw
Is to draw all the mass
A point becomes a line
I don't know how much this mass is
Every mass I draw
It becomes a line
OK
it is good
That should be the same
Thank you
OK
Time is almost up today
Do you have any questions
I have some questions
Can I ask
I have a little suggestion
I'm totally OK
Stay and ask questions
But because California is almost 9 o'clock
If the host wants to go home
Can go home
I don't know where you are now
Anyway
If you want to download it, you can download it
Anyway, the recording is over
Then we can continue to discuss
I am actually
I have one or two questions
but
I don't know if everyone has
That's it
Let's continue
I have a personal article
OK
Then I will stop the recording first