You can see it.
Okay, I'll start.
You know my name,
my name is Wang Zhu Yi.
The easier way to remember is
the sound of Zhu Yi and the chair made by Zhu.
I graduated from
the University of South California
last year
with a Ph.D. in Mechanical Engineering.
Today, I want to talk about
something related to my thesis
and my current research.
We have a framework
called Innovative Design Thinking.
It guides
designers
on how to design.
Today, I'll focus on
conceptual design.
I'll introduce
its background.
Conceptual design
has two phases.
One is concept generation,
the other is concept improvement.
I'll talk about it.
First,
I'll briefly introduce
my background.
Then, I'll talk about
some of the main
terms we're talking about
and what they are.
This is how I write
in Chinese.
It may look
difficult to read.
This is Zhu Yi, Wang Zhu Yi.
I graduated
from the University of South California
with a Ph.D. in Mechanical Engineering.
Previously,
I studied
light design
at the University of Taiwan.
When I was in college,
I studied
electrical engineering.
It may look
a bit complicated
but
it is
related to
system integration
and system design.
What I'm doing now
is a post-Ph.D.
research.
I'm working with
my co-director,
Stephen Lu,
who is doing
post-Ph.D. research
at USC.
I'd like to thank
Taiwan and USC
for their cooperation.
This is one of the
funding
for my post-Ph.D.
fellowship.
I can continue
my post-Ph.D. research at USC.
I also did
some administrative work.
The title sounds better.
It's about
designing product design
for students
and
maintaining
communication and
program.
I also had
a chance to teach
at USC.
I taught
two classes.
The first class
was
about
product development
and engineering.
The second class
was about
market
direction
and
how to
design.
The third class
was about
conceptual design.
I didn't teach this class
at USC,
but I'm going to
teach this class
at USC.
This is
today's topic.
Today's topic is
innovative design
thinking.
I'm going to focus on
conceptual design.
This is also
my specialty.
The so-called design framework
is a framework
that
doesn't tell you
how to do it.
If you follow
this framework
to design,
you can get
better results.
When we
talk about the framework,
we say it's
a prescriptive.
It's a bit like
the doctor's prescription.
It's based on your symptoms
and his experience.
He thinks this way
and you can follow
this and get better
results.
So we say it's
a framework,
not a prescriptive.
In this framework,
it might tell you
what you can do
at this stage
and what you can do
at that stage.
In fact,
this framework
doesn't just
focus on
conceptual design.
We don't have
a lot of time today.
My research
is also
focused on
conceptual design.
This is what I'm going to talk about today.
Before we get started,
I have a joke
to share with you.
Every time I
start a class,
I ask the students
if there are
five birds
on a tree
and a hunter
shoots a bullet,
how many birds
are still on the tree?
Does anyone
want to try to answer?
They all flew away.
I'm the one who
asked the question,
so I'll tell you
that there are three birds.
Why are there three birds?
Why are
these three birds
still on the tree?
In theory,
the shot should fly away.
Why are they still on the tree?
They were shocked.
Maybe.
But these three birds
are actually smart.
They are engineers.
But because they want
to pursue the optimal path,
they are still calculating
how to fly
so that they won't
be shot by the hunter.
So they are still calculating.
Because they are still calculating,
there are still three birds
on the tree.
The second question is
that there are
five birds,
three birds on the tree,
and two birds flew away.
What happened to them?
Did they
successfully fly away
or were they shot to death?
It's raining.
It makes sense.
The answer here
is that
they fell to the ground.
But why did they
fall to the ground?
They didn't faint.
Because these two birds
are actually managers.
They know
that the right decision
should be to fly away
or be shot by the hunter.
But because they are managers,
they have forgotten
how to fly.
So they fell to the ground.
This is a joke.
Engineers
usually
talk about
how to calculate
the optimal path
and how to
do the best.
This is to do
this thing well.
But sometimes
we forget that
there may be some
so-called
social reality.
We may have some
time problems
or some restrictions.
We have to make a decision right away.
To make a decision right away
is like a manager.
Their responsibility
is to make the right decision
and do the right thing.
But if
they didn't
make the right balance,
there is one without two,
and there is two without one.
At this stage
of conceptual design,
there may be some
things we will be ignored.
How to
do these two things
well?
In conceptual design,
we want to
discuss and give
a prescription.
This is connected to
product development.
In a
product development process,
it is usually
like this.
From the concept
to the final release
to the market.
Product
is something
to be sold in the future.
So we will consider
the social reality
and the market.
We will consider
global competition
or some
demand
and supply.
On the other hand,
there is a downstream part,
the so-called
reality.
This part is to consider
technology restrictions
or the current stage of
technology,
or how to
optimize,
how to
make this product
the best part.
So there is a so-called
upstream and downstream balance
that needs to be considered
in the process of product design.
The upstream part
is called
do the right thing.
Conceptual design is
to consider
the concept of
the design
between the two sides.
This upstream part
is the main part
of ISE 545.
AME 546
is the new customer
conceptual design part.
The other part
is to consider
the design framework
between the two sides.
The design framework
is the middle part
of ISE 545.
The design framework
is the middle part
of ISE 545.
The design framework
is the middle part
of ISE 545.
The design framework
is the middle part
of ISE 545.
So we don't
want to start
from the very top.
We want to
be good enough.
If there is a good
on-line design,
then the product
can be done
to reach the optimal
product.
So in fact,
in the design process,
we emphasize that
what we want to consider is
good enough, not
best or ideal.
Because
there are two sides to consider.
On the one hand, it's social reality.
On the other hand, it's plurality.
In other words,
we want to meet our goals,
but it has to be
operational.
So this is
what we will
consider
when designing
products.
A product design
from nothing to something
goes through
three main design
stages.
The first is functional design.
The second is conceptual design.
The third is technical design.
Functional design
is defined from
Cn to Fr,
which is the customer's needs
to the functional requirements.
These are the functional
requirements.
The functional requirements
go to the design parameters.
To put it simply,
DP is the concept
of design.
In this process,
there may not be
some actual numbers,
actual sizes,
or its geometric shape.
It is a conceptual design.
Then there is technical design,
which is to turn these concepts
into actual things.
There will be some process variables.
We
divide these four parts
into four domains.
In this process,
Cn to Fr, we call it functional design.
Fr to DP, we call it conceptual design.
DP to PV, we call it
technical design.
In this part,
we mainly focus on
conceptual design.
There are two phases.
The first is concept generation.
The second is concept improvement.
Why do we
talk about conceptual design?
Why do we do this research?
We know that
in the design process,
it seems that
there is no need
for rules.
It seems that
some creative things
can be created.
But in the process,
we found that
if you just do brainstorming
or have some ideas,
what if these things
can't be realized?
In conceptual design,
it is in the middle stage.
You have to find a way
to meet the needs of customers
or to attract
customers' interest.
You also have to
meet the
unfulfilled
demands.
In downstream,
you have to
be able to realize
the concept,
not just
empty thoughts.
In terms of profit,
you have to consider
the cost.
In this aspect,
conceptual design
is not that easy.
But it is also
an important phase.
In terms of
design,
it is in the early stage.
Generally speaking,
most companies
don't have
a concept
when they are
designing.
They have to find a way
to realize it.
It is a technical design.
But if you consider
the long-term
or new things,
from nothing
to something,
it is an opportunity.
For product development,
it is a very important phase.
In terms of
conceptual design,
if it is okay,
it is a good decision.
If you know
it is good,
it can be realized
in downstream.
It can have
low complexity
and good results.
But it is not easy
because it is in the middle.
It has to consider upstream
and downstream.
In the process,
it does not have
actual data.
It is not like
you have a prototype
and you can measure
on-board testing results.
How can we
make sure
the concept is okay?
We have to think about
how to make it
as ideal and practical
as possible.
We know
conceptual design
is from FR to DP.
First,
how does this FR come from?
This FR is
from functional design.
But this part
is not included here.
I will not
talk about
how to find this FR.
However,
the definition of FR
is very important
in terms of
how innovative
the product will be
in the future.
In my class,
we did not
talk about it
in conceptual design.
In this talk,
I will talk about
the concept of FR.
It is the
pre-process
of conceptual design.
It is a function
that we have to define
what functions
these concepts
must meet.
How do these functions
come from?
These functions
come from customer needs.
are defined
by designers,
not customers.
For example,
customer needs
often change.
Sometimes,
we talk about
observing
the emerging lifestyle.
In addition,
we talk about
need and want.
When the
functional requirement
is closer to
the basic needs,
the market
is larger,
but the profit
is smaller.
If it is closer
to the so-called want,
the profit is larger,
but the market
is smaller.
In the process of choosing,
we talk about
some strategies
when it comes to
functional design.
For example,
we talk about
triggering need
into want
or want into need.
We also talk about
different features
such as
kind of model.
Excitement feature
and time change
are discussed
in functional design.
However,
this talk
will not cover
this topic.
As I mentioned,
functional design
is an important
prelude to innovation
when defining
functional requirements.
Many things
need to be considered
when designing
functional requirements.
For example,
the phone holder
is a common
design,
but it is not
a good design.
Why?
Because
it is not
a good design
in California.
In California,
there may be
some restrictions.
Also,
California has
bad sunlight.
If you
have a phone
like this,
you will be told
that your phone
must be turned off
or can't be charged
because it is too hot.
There is another possibility
when designing
functional requirements.
For example,
if the sunlight is too strong,
the phone holder
should be placed
on the back of the phone.
However,
this is not a good design
because
the driver
will have to
look down
when driving.
Although it solves
A's requirement,
it does not solve
B's requirement
or other problems.
This is the design
of the phone holder
at the air outlet.
This is the design
of the phone holder
at the air outlet.
This is the design
of the phone holder
at the air outlet.
This is the design
of the phone holder
at the air outlet.
However,
there is a problem.
If
the phone holder
is sold in California,
if it is sold
in cold places,
such as
Michigan or Denver,
it will snow.
When it snows,
the driver
must turn on the heater.
However,
once the heater is turned on,
there will be a hot wind.
So,
the phone holder
will be too hot
when it snows.
So,
the phone holder
will be too hot
when it snows.
When the phone holder
is sold,
the driver
must turn off the heater,
and put the phone holder
in a storage bag.
The driver
must then
put the phone holder
in a storage bag,
and turn it off.
If the driver
is not turning on the heater,
the phone holder
must be turned off.
The driver
must then
put the phone holder
in a storage bag,
and turn it off.
If the driver
is not turning on the heater,
the phone holder
must be turned on.
The basic framework
of the process
is to
organize
the information
and make
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the
information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
after
organizing
the information
and SDG
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
and
making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
that,
and
make the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
and
make the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after
organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after organizing
the information
and making
the decision
after organizing
If it's not in there,
it's a synthetic proposition.
For example,
let's say
a bicycle
has two wheels.
A bicycle has two wheels.
This is an
analytic proposition.
The basic definition of a bicycle
is that it has two wheels.
This is an
analytic proposition.
Or let's say
a single man
is not married.
This is also an analytic proposition.
But if we say
that
if it's not in there,
it's a synthetic proposition.
For example,
if you go to school,
you have to ride a bicycle.
You don't have to ride a bicycle
to go to school,
but a bicycle is a method.
It's not in there.
This is a
synthetic proposition.
So,
through this synthetic
and analytic proposition,
we can change the interaction
and create the idea.
So,
the basic process
is that we need to do
a specified action
and then do an idea.
Then we integrate
the concept of the product.
Then we do
a validated action
and then we do
to form the concept formation.
This is the basic
part of the concept formation.
You have to follow
these four steps
to create a cycle.
Then you can go from
FR to DP.
For example,
our FR function
is to fly.
The specified action
is to lift.
There are some ways
to lift.
After the idea,
we use wings.
If you have wings,
you can lift it up
and then
we can create
a concept.
It may be an airplane
because the airplane
has wings.
It may be
a final concept
that can
satisfy
the fly action.
Because of this,
we can have a lot of solutions.
For example,
we can say
to fly, not to lift.
To lift, we can
use hot air to lift it up.
So we may have
hot air balloons
to make hot air balloons
to satisfy the fly action.
There are
different solutions
such as rockets.
If it is
wings and then
to lift,
it may not satisfy
the logic.
The concept is not feasible
if wings are not a part
of the balloon.
If wings are not a part
There are several
solutions
only by the cycle.
There are several solutions
Wings are just a part
of the airplane.
We can imagine
that a wing is not
a complete plane.
So, how do we get
to this point?
How do hot air
get to there?
You need to organize
the idea
so that you can
have a complete
plan and concept.
Then,
when you realize it,
it will be more
visible.
it will be more visible.
So,
we need to
use
the so-called hierarchy
to organize the idea.
We need to specify it.
We need to decompose it.
So,
the how-what
will be
different parts.
The different functions
will be more detailed.
Then,
after the idea
is created,
we will
combine it
with
the composition
to get
a concept.
So, we can
top-down it,
bottom-up it,
and complete it.
This concept
is not just a concept.
It follows
the logic.
So, you can know
the details.
What does this concept
contain?
What is the relationship
between these things?
For example,
this is because it meets
this condition, this function.
This is because it meets
this function.
Because we have this
so-called cycle,
specify idea,
integrate,
and then,
finally,
we have a concept.
But, we need to validate
this concept
to be sure
that this thing
can achieve this function.
Also,
we use
only some concepts
in this part.
We don't have data.
So, how can we
make the next step
to achieve
this concept?
We use
this dual hierarchical structure
to make
this
concept.
So,
the first step is
to decompose
this function
into
some small
paper systems
with different
paper functions.
Then, we find a solution
for each function.
Then, we integrate
these two concepts
to have a complete concept.
Then,
we verify
that this paper system
meets
our main function needs.
Then,
this paper system
may have some
actual limitations
or so-called
external limitations
and external conditions.
So,
when we decompose
this function,
we won't have
this paper system.
Then,
we can move on
to the next step
and make it more
geometric.
This paper system
is based on
the concept
we have already
developed.
For example,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a
thing that
can be moved
to support
and to move.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
transported.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Then,
if we want to
design something
that can be
transported,
we may want
to have
a support
and a thing
that can be
moved.
Recently,
we have been doing
a new material development.
Recently,
no one has done this
before,
but we have to
be responsible to our shareholders,
investors.
I think we may have some difficulties
when discussing these things.
How can we use
conceptual design
to convince investors
that we have reached a certain stage?
How can we use
this concept
to present a better vision
or show them
where the money is coming from?
After all, investors value
whether we can make money.
I understand.
Your question is
that you have a product,
but you want to
talk to investors
about how to make
investors accept
and invest in this project.
Yes.
This is my idea.
Conceptual design
is a place
where concepts
are generated and implemented.
You may want to
talk about
how this thing
can be
implemented.
In terms of investors,
conceptual design
is more market-oriented.
As I said before,
we may have
two pieces.
One is upstream,
the market part.
The other is downstream.
The upstream part
is the market part.
The downstream part
is the technology part.
Conceptual design
is in the middle.
You can consider
whether the product
meets the market demand.
Whether the so-called
functions
can make
consumers
want to buy
or whether
the market demand
already exists.
This can convince
investors to look at this part.
Because what they look at
is the upstream part.
The downstream part
is what you
develop
and do.
There may be some
practical difficulties.
Investors
don't care
about the specifications
of the product.
What they care about
is whether
the product can make money.
So,
we will consider
the concept part
which is more
market-oriented.
The function part
is more
market-oriented.
So,
you can consider
whether the product
has innovation
and market demand.
Whether
it has enough
competitors
or
market analysis.
It's like
what I talked about
in ISE.
It's about
functional design.
How to go from
functional design to
functional requirement.
I can't cover this part today.
But you can
talk about
some
main concepts
like
whether
your product
focuses on need
or want.
Demand may be
need or want.
But the profit
must be small.
If your product
meets the need
function,
your market
will be big.
But you must make
your product cheaper.
Then your profit
will be relatively small.
When we talk about
innovation,
we don't recommend
the product
meets the need
function.
People will want to
buy it.
Although
you are a new
founder or a new company,
your market
or market
is not high enough.
You may not have
enough
basic demand
but you can stimulate
people to buy it.
Your profit
can cover
the production cost
of two or three products.
Then you can
convince your investors
to invest in this product.
In addition,
we have the so-called
Canon Model.
You can see
that
it has some functions.
It has basic features,
performance features,
and excitement features.
In other words,
if we
want to
sell a smartphone
in this market,
we have to have
a camera function.
It must be able to
download an app
or have many functions.
This has become a basic feature.
Its performance
feature may be that the
resolution of my camera
is better or
the speed of my CPU
is faster.
The excitement feature
is a bit like
when they promote
their products
to their investors
or consumers,
they talk about
what's different
and what's special.
For example,
when they launch
the iPhone X,
they will talk about
facial recognition
and so on.
They must have
something that can
stimulate consumers
to buy.
This is something
you can consider
when talking about
regional issues.
For example,
in California,
this kind of thing
may not be sold.
However,
this kind of thing
may not be sold
in other states.
You can talk to
your investors about
these ideas.
For example,
if you go to India
or South Korea,
their direction is to
launch the iPhone X.
This is different
in different countries.
You need to know
where your target market is
and where your stakeholders
are.
You can talk to them
about this.
However,
this is a bit different
in terms of
conceptual design.
This concept is not
enough for you to realize
in the next phase.
However, it meets the needs
of the previous phase.
I hope I answered your question.
I think it's good.
I'm sorry.
It sounds like B2C.
I have a few more questions.
I'm sorry.
Can you talk about this later?
I have a NDA,
so I may not be able
to answer these questions.
I have a few more questions.
Is B2C and B2B
both practical
in terms of
conceptual design?
Or is there a difference
between them?
In terms of conceptual design,
B2C and B2B
are one part
of the design.
B2C and B2B
are one part
of the design.
When you design a product,
you can't just
consider
one part of it.
Your concept
should be
whether or not
the product
can meet
the customer's needs.
In terms of conceptual design,
it can be
B2B
or B2C,
but it's not
something
you have to
talk to
your investor about.
The design
is not
a functional design.
It's a design
that you have
decided
the customer's needs.
You've seen
the demand,
so you have to
make it happen.
But if you want to
make it happen,
you can't just
decide
one part.
If you want to
develop
your products,
there should
be actions
that are
recommended
for your customers.
For example,
there should be
a reflection
to improve
existing products.
This is the part of
conceptual design.
If there is
something that is not convenient to publicize,
this is my email.
You can email me.
Can you see it?
I don't seem to have it.
Stay there.
There is a
dialogue box.
I see it.
Hello,
loyal listeners.
Zhu Yi left
her email in the dialogue box.
If you need to contact her,
you can use this email to contact her.
At present,
we want to
be open
and experimental.
For example,
we can have a discussion
with the speaker
on the content of the speech.
We will
post it on Facebook
and
share it
in detail
to everyone.
We are still experimenting
and not sure
how to do it.
As you know,
it is almost completely
public on Facebook.
Some things
can be discussed
privately
with the speaker
and the interviewee.
If you are interested,
you can add me on Facebook.
My Facebook name is
the same as my name,
Zhu Yi Wang.
If you are interested, you can add me.
Okay.
Thank you.
Are there any questions?
Zhu Yi,
it's your turn.
Okay, thank you.
I want to vote.
I think
Zhou Ren should
introduce himself.
Why should I introduce myself?
I'm just a useless person
who stays in Japan.
No, no.
Zhou Ren is very good at studying.
He is studying at the University of Northeast China.
We often
have a chat.
I'm glad that it's you.
Their products
are slowly
being commercialized.
At least they are
on the track of practical use.
It's not like our products
are always
in theory and
hypothesis.
It's important to make money.
I think
most people can understand
what we are doing.
It's a process
for R&D.
For example,
let's say we are sure
this product is good.
It's not only neat, but also want.
How should we tell them?
Because manufacturers
want a clean product.
I saw the previous slide.
I feel like
if I tell them
how to develop
or what design concept
I think
it's a good way
to convince
investors.
Tell them how far we have come.
After all, we are R&D people.
Yes.
I think so.
We can talk more.
If you
think about investment,
it's about functional design.
I didn't cover it today.
But this part
I can share with you.
It might be useful.
Yes.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Any questions?
If not,
let's
give
a round of applause
for Zhu Yi
to turn on
the microphone.
Thank you.
That's about it for today.
Some places
in the city
are getting close to bedtime.
Yes.
That's about it for today.
The recording
will be posted
on Facebook
in three to five days.
No, no.
It will be posted
on Project Terra's
presentation link.
If you want to review it,
you can go back and watch it.
Okay.
Thank you, Zhu Yi.
Thank you, Ted.