Welcome everyone to today's Terra Talk, we are very honored to invite our speaker, Mr. Huang Shengfeng, to tell us about today's topic, Taiwan's international law positioning, the past, the present and the future.
I am very happy, because we have a long time in fact, there are no humanities or social science-related speeches.
Today, it is easy to invite Mr. Shengfeng, and Mr. Shengfeng is now in Edinburgh, he is 12 o'clock in the middle of the night to speak for everyone, so thank him very much.
First, let me introduce the background of Shengfeng. Shengfeng is the founder of Taipeng International Law, the founder of the Taiwan Voter Alliance.
He previously studied law at Taipei University and the Law Department of Taipei University, and then studied international law at the University of London, and now studies international law at Edinburgh University.
He is going to talk to us about the topic of Taiwan's international law positioning, the past, the present and the future.
A small reminder, if you don't turn on the microphone, you can't hear the applause, so let's turn on the microphone together, and thank Shengfeng for bringing us today's speech.
Hello everyone, I am Huang Shengfeng. Today I am very happy to have this opportunity to share with you some of the results of my research so far.
My research topic is Taiwan's international law positioning, the past, the present and the future.
At the beginning of the speech, I would like to share a sentence with everyone. This is what Albus Dumbledore said in Harry Potter.
Sometimes we must choose between what is right and what is easy.
In the end, it created today's situation. When we want to solve some problems in the future, we must continue to face many choices.
I don't know if the Taiwanese will choose the right choice or the simple and easy choice. I think this may determine our future.
At the beginning of this speech, I hope everyone can keep this sentence in mind.
Later, when I talk about the content, you can take this sentence out from time to time and think about it.
At that time, what did the Taiwanese think or what choices did the Taiwanese make in the end? What should we do in the future?
There are three main topics I want to share today. The first is the background knowledge of international law.
The second is the past and present of international law. The last is the future.
The background knowledge of international law is because most of the people who come to listen to my presentation today are not legal background.
So they may not know much about this aspect. I want to do some basic background explanation first.
Then I will start to talk about our internal topics.
First of all, we need to understand what international law is.
International law is the basic rule of law between political entities.
What is the political entity on international law?
Basically, it includes the so-called sovereign state.
The second is the so-called international organization, such as the United Nations, WHO, and WTO.
These are also political entities on international law.
The other is the implementation of autonomous units, such as Taiwan or Somaliland.
I put Taiwan in the implementation of autonomous units, not in the country.
This means that at least so far, under the definition of international law, Taiwan has not yet been recognized as a sovereign state.
Of course, everyone may have different ideas.
But from the perspective of international law, Taiwan is not yet.
Of course, I will say why it is not.
In addition, international law is the principle that determines the rights and obligations of the political entity on international law and its right to carry out its obligations.
The scope of international law is actually very wide.
Generally, when people hear international law, they sometimes feel that it is related to a place, a country, or diplomacy.
In fact, the scope of international law is very wide, including political, economic, military, and human rights.
For example, international relations, diplomacy, and business.
Then there is economic, import-export trade, currency exchange, financial transactions, and securities transactions.
In fact, today some people say that international law does not seem to have any effect.
In fact, if we want to implement import-export trade, or even if we want to study abroad,
or when you go sightseeing and need to exchange foreign currency, this is also related to international law.
Even now, some people may be in the United States, and then you can buy and sell securities and goods from other countries.
These financial transactions are all related to international law.
Then, for example, the military part, such as hand-to-hand combat, stop-and-go, how to end the war, military occupation.
Then, for example, the restrictions on nuclear and biological weapons.
For example, recently, the US withdrew the Semiconductor Missile Agreement.
These are all related to the military.
Then, for example, the human rights part, such as the right to freedom, the right to self-determination, the right to life, the right to transport, and the human rights law.
In fact, basically, we can say that as long as you have a connection with other countries, no matter what form of connection it is, it will be related to international law.
Hearing international law, there is often a reaction that international law is bigger and more powerful than fist.
However, it must be emphasized here that international law is not only bigger than fist.
Because if it is really bigger than fist, I believe that the biggest fist in the world now is the United States.
But even if the United States has such a big fist, it can't stop it.
That is, the wife of Palestine, she was born in front of the United Nations.
The United States is only one vote in the United Nations, in the General Assembly, and in the Security Council.
So it can't decide everything, although its fist may be the biggest in the world.
In addition, for example, China, of course, can't prevent the International Court of Justice from making a judgment against it.
Of course, at this time, some people will say that although it is said that it is not conducive to its judgment, China is still my heart and my tree.
But we have to think a little bit, that is, yes, that's right.
Although the Philippine was against the South China Sea part of the International Court of Justice, and then the International Court of Justice put China on it.
Later, the International Court of Justice made some of China's claims that there was no legal effect, that is, it did not have those rights.
Although China later decided not to recognize these things, other countries made such a decision because of the International Court of Justice.
So other countries, such as the United States, claimed that since the International Court of Justice believed that the right to claim did not exist,
then I followed the rules of the International Court of Justice, such as the International Ocean Law, and I exercised my freedom of navigation.
There are other countries, such as the United Kingdom, who are also exercising their freedom of navigation.
When other countries make a decision because of you, such as the International Court of Justice, and then let other countries obtain other basis on the International Law to exercise their rights, this is the effect of the International Law.
So what the International Law represents is to tell everyone that there is more than just a fist in the international community.
Because even if you have a fist as big as China, and then it is not willing to recognize the decision made by the International Court of Justice,
but other countries can still act according to the judgment made by the International Court of Justice.
At this time, even if China is dissatisfied, it can only look aside.
In this regard, I would like to let everyone know that the strong can set the rules, and the weak must comply with the rules.
The International Law is actually a decision made by the great powers and the strong to discuss and make a political decision.
The main purpose of the International Law is to allow different countries to solve disputes in a civilized and legal way, rather than a rapid war.
So in this case, we can know that the International Law is to some extent a bit like a structure on the balance of danger.
So in this case, even if it is a big country, it will feel that it is necessary to comply with the International Law.
Because if it does not comply with the International Law, other big countries may not comply with the International Law, and then it will be a mess.
In the event that everyone gives up their strength, it may be the end of the world.
For countries that are not strong, the strength is not so strong.
In fact, it is more important to understand what the rules are made by these big countries, and then to make good use of these rules.
Because in this case, you are not saying that you are bigger than the fist, you are a small fist against a big fist, you will win.
But if you follow the rules of the International Law, the rules of the International Law are a rule created by the power.
When you follow the rules created by the power to deal with other powers, you are like standing on the shoulders of a giant.
Although you may be a small person, you are standing on the shoulders of a giant.
The International Law is actually very useful, and in fact, for the weaker object, the greater the impact of the International Law, the stronger the meaning.
In fact, here I want to mention a simple example.
For example, after the founding of the People's Republic of China on October 1, 1949, it took 22 years and 24 days for it to become the representative government of China in the United Nations on October 25, 1971.
On October 25, 1971, the United Nations General Assembly Resolution No. 2758 was passed.
According to that resolution, the representative of China in the United Nations is the representative of the People's Republic of China.
So we all know that although the People's Republic of China came to Taiwan because of the civil war, and the so-called mainland China was controlled by the People's Republic of China.
But even though the power is so different, the People's Republic of China also took more than 20 years to enter the United Nations.
So it's not that it's really bigger than the fist. If it's really bigger than the fist, it should have entered earlier, and it wouldn't have waited more than 20 years.
Then again, like Palestine, it was after the independence of Palestine was announced on November 15, 1988. It took 24 years and 14 days for it to become a member of the United Nations.
So we find that whether it is a strong, stronger foundation of the People's Republic of China, or a very weak Palestine.
But after they were established, it took a long time for them to enter the international community, for example, to enter the United Nations.
So we know that whether it is strong or weak, the international law has a certain impact on them.
I am here to talk about the United Nations, because whether it is the People's Republic of China regime or Palestine,
they entered the United Nations today in accordance with the regulations set by the United Nations itself.
Of course, the regulations set by the United Nations International Organization also follow the regulations set by the international law.
So basically everyone follows the regulations of the international law. No one says that I have a big fist today, so I can listen to me directly.
Or that I am very weak, so everyone has to pity me. In fact, there is no such thing.
So I think that the international law has the greatest effect on the weak, which is to increase the competition with the strong, and then the political and legal defense.
In fact, this is especially important for Taiwan. I think that many people who come to participate today may have a nationality from other countries, for example, you may have a nationality in the United States.
Maybe you don't feel so strongly about this, but if you say that the nationality you have today or the place you are in is a relatively weak place in international politics or international relations,
in fact, you will feel that if everyone is just a fist, there is not much effect.
But if there is an international law as a backer, when you go to fight for some rights with others, you will have the opportunity to get what you want.
Can I ask a question?
You just said that there are three kinds of political entities in the world, the state, the WHO, and Taiwan or Somaliland.
Then you just had a statement that all interactions between countries must abide by international law.
I want to ask that the object of the international law is actually the country, that is, the ABC of the three A or ABC?
ABC.
So all three are required?
Yes.
Because I just said that the basic interactions between political entities in international law are regulated.
So the political entities in international law include those three things.
OK, thank you.
I think everyone has heard of the four elements of a country, namely territory, people, and government.
Then there is sovereignty.
For example, if you were educated in Taiwan, you would probably know the four elements of a country, namely territory, people, government, and sovereignty.
But I want to tell you that this statement is wrong.
The reason is that sovereignty is something that a country will have after it is formed.
So it is not a basic element that constitutes a country.
It is something that you will have after you become a country.
So if you say that sovereignty is an element that constitutes a country, this is a bit of a logical question.
Basically, it should be said that it is not the so-called four elements, but the characteristics that a sovereign country should have.
That is, in the Montevideo Convention on the Rights of the Nation, it talks about territory, people, and government.
In addition, there is the so-called diplomatic ability, which is the ability to communicate with other sovereign countries.
I particularly emphasize the ability to communicate with other sovereign countries.
And the important thing is that the sovereign country must treat you as a sovereign country.
When you communicate with the so-called official position, your diplomatic ability is truly recognized.
So in fact, a country, a very interesting thing is that the so-called sovereign country needs to have characteristics,
In addition to those entities that can be seen, such as territory, people, and government,
The other part of the diplomatic ability is actually directly linked to the so-called recognition part.
In fact, of course, some people say that you are or are not a country today, and you do not need other countries to recognize you.
But now the question is whether you are a country or whether you can play the role of a country.
In fact, it depends on whether other countries treat you as a country.
So whether or not you are recognized today is the key to becoming a country.
But to be recognized by other countries, to recognize that you are a country, is to allow you to operate like a country,
Or like a country, a basic prerequisite for connecting with other countries.
So in fact, when we have the so-called territory today, and the people have the government,
Then, with the diplomatic ability to be equal to other countries, you will have a so-called sovereign thing.
In fact, the form of sovereign performance is that it can control or manage the land and people internally,
Then you can have diplomatic relations with other countries.
So in fact, sovereign countries need to have these characteristics.
Basically, we can say that if it is a country, it will have these characteristics.
But having these characteristics does not mean that you are a country.
This is a bit logical, that is, if P is Q, if it is not Q, it is not P.
But you can't say that if P is Q, then if it is not P, then it is not Q. This logic is wrong.
OK, here is another basic knowledge.
That is, we have to distinguish between the so-called country, the government, and the regime.
The so-called country is a political entity with international law that dominates the national legal personality.
The regime is a political group with practical power and governance ability.
So if there is a group of people today and they form an organization,
Then that organization has practical control and can govern a certain place and govern a certain people.
We can say that the organization built by this group of people is a so-called regime.
Then there is another so-called government. The government is a government that can represent the country, that is, represent the country externally.
Then internally, it can govern the people and the land, and it is a regime that conducts diplomacy externally.
The distinction between this place and this place is very important.
Because if we put these three things together today, we will often have problems when we judge some problems.
Especially when facing the situation in Taiwan.
There are a few points here. The first is that a country can only have a government that represents the country, the so-called government.
The representative government is a regime that can represent the country.
So we know that the representative government is a regime, but this regime has another special nature, that is, it can represent the country.
In a country, there may be several regimes at the same time, and these several regimes are in the so-called representative government.
If there is such a situation, it is the so-called representative power struggle.
The most direct example is China, which is related to Taiwan.
From October 1, 1949 to today, the representative power struggle between the People's Republic of China government and the People's Republic of China government.
I also wrote the government here. In fact, we all know that they call themselves the government.
In fact, it is the regime of the People's Republic of China and the regime of the People's Republic of China.
They are fighting for the position of the Chinese representative government.
Which one wins will become the so-called Chinese government, the Chinese representative government.
The other is Venezuela. Venezuela just happened this year.
We know that the government of Maduro, and then there was a government of Guaido.
Guaido is a leader of the ruling party.
He thinks that the election of the Maduro government was problematic.
He does not recognize the election result.
In addition, Maduro's previous governance had a big problem.
There was a very big financial problem in Venezuela.
Guaido felt that he could not do it.
He appointed himself as the temporary president and established the so-called transitional government.
The interesting thing here is that the United States was the first to recognize that Guaido's transitional government was the representative government of Venezuela.
The Maduro government is not the representative government.
The interesting thing here is that other countries can choose which regime is the representative government of another country.
After their choice, they will follow their choice to deal with the government of this country.
For example, after the Maduro government decided to recognize Guaido's transitional government in the United States,
it ordered the U.S. diplomats to leave Venezuela.
The U.S. government's response is that we now recognize that Guaido's transitional government is the legitimate government of Venezuela.
Since the U.S. government is not the legitimate government of Venezuela,
the U.S. government's request to the U.S. diplomats to leave Venezuela is illegal.
The U.S. government does not recognize this request.
So the U.S. diplomats continue to stay in Venezuela.
This is actually a very interesting situation.
We know that countries have various characteristics.
Some of these characteristics are necessary, while some are not.
Let's see how these characteristics will change after the change.
First, let's talk about nationality.
Every country has a nationality, which is its name.
Of course, it can be changed, but its change will not affect its legal personality.
For example, if my name is Huang Shengfeng, and if I change my name to Lai Qingde, I will not become the former director of the Executive Yuan.
The same goes for countries.
After the country's nationality is changed, its national legal personality will not change.
A recent example is that Swaziland was renamed Swaziland in 2018.
Another example is that the Qing Dynasty changed its name to the Republic of China in 1912.
I say that the Republic of China was renamed.
You may think that the Republic of China was not founded by Sun Wen to overthrow the Qing Dynasty.
In fact, the Republic of China was founded by Emperor Xuantong of the Qing Dynasty.
Emperor Xuantong of the Qing Dynasty issued a decree of abdication in 1912.
In this decree, he announced that the Qing Dynasty would be changed from an imperial system to a republic system.
The Qing Dynasty would become the Great Republic of China, which was allied with the Han Dynasty.
Emperor Xuantong of the Qing Dynasty appointed Yuan Shikai as the temporary government.
The Qing Dynasty changed from an imperial system to a republic system.
The Qing Dynasty changed its name to the Republic of China.
The Qing Dynasty was later replaced by Yuan Shikai's temporary government.
Some people may not believe it, but I want to make it simple.
In the 6th year of the Republic of China, the so-called Xuantong 9th year,
there was a thing called Zhang Xun's abdication.
If you have read the history of the Republic of China textbooks, you will know the so-called Zhang Xun's abdication.
Zhang Xun's abdication means that the Republic of China changed from a republic system to an imperial system.
So Puyi ascended the throne again.
Let's think about one thing.
If the Qing Dynasty was overthrown today, if this country was overthrown,
and the Republic of China was a new country, how could you change it back?
It's just a simple change of a system, and then the name was changed and changed again.
If you are building a new country today, how could you change it like this?
In fact, it's not.
Because the Republic of China itself is the Qing Dynasty itself.
It just changed the system and changed the name.
So when Zhang Xun abdicated, because it was the same, it was able to return to its previous state.
So Zhang Xun's abdication tells us that the Republic of China is the same as the Qing Dynasty.
It's just a different name. It's just a different system.
This is actually the so-called renaissance constitution.
We can think of it this way.
In fact, this is the renaissance constitution.
The Qing Dynasty changed the name to the Republic of China.
Originally, the Qing Dynasty did not have a constitution.
Later, the Republic of China was changed to a temporary constitution.
It is the so-called renaissance constitution.
The renaissance constitution is no different from the constitutional constitution advocated by some people today.
So I found that if you change the name of a country, change its system, or make some regulations,
it will not affect the nature of this country.
Another so-called government.
If necessary, it can be changed.
Its change does not affect the national law.
Let me give you an example.
In 1928, China's representative government changed from the US government to the national government.
The textbooks of the Republic of China tell us that
Jiang Jieshi led the North and later unified China.
The North was successful.
In fact, the process of the whole North was the so-called Beiyang government, the representative government of China.
It was overthrown by the rebellious government.
That is to say, before the completion of the North,
Jiang Jieshi led the so-called national government.
In fact, it was a rebellious government.
After the rebellious government successfully overthrew the original representative government,
there was no other government in the Republic of China to compete with it.
So the national government became the representative government of the Republic of China.
Other countries originally came to the Republic of China with the Beiyang government.
Later, the Beiyang government was eliminated and replaced by the national government.
Other countries continue to come to the national government.
They are from the same country, but they still come from China.
They just come from different governments.
In fact, this is the meaning of the civil war in the Republic of China.
The civil war in the Republic of China is that the national government meets another competitor.
The system can be changed when necessary.
Its change does not affect the national law.
Here, we mentioned that China changed from a geological system to a republic system in 1912.
For example, France changed from a geological system to a republic system in the French Revolution in 1792.
We know that France is now the fifth republic.
In other words, after the French Revolution, it first became a republic system.
Then Napoleon came out to claim the throne and returned to the geological system.
So we know that a country's system can be changed.
Geological system, republic system, etc.
But the country is still the same.
Otherwise, we would not talk about the so-called French Revolution.
They are all from the same country.
It's just a system change.
In addition, there is the Constitution.
The Constitution is not necessary.
Because if the Constitution is necessary, we will find that there may be no country before the so-called military constitution.
In fact, it is not.
Because before the military constitution, all countries are monarchical systems.
There is no Constitution.
But these countries still exist.
Even to this day, they still belong to the imperial system.
For example, we have some chief states on the Arabian Peninsula.
These chief states are the imperial system.
They do not have the Constitution.
The Constitution is re-created and revised.
No matter how many times, it does not affect the order of the National Security Council.
Or change it.
For example, I can say that the French constitution is 17 times.
You may be surprised.
The French constitution is 17 times.
Re-created.
Not revised.
Re-created 17 times.
The latest constitution has been revised 24 times.
But we will not say that the French constitution is 17 times.
So France died and was born again.
Died and was born again.
More than ten times.
We do not think so.
It is still the same country.
So, the Constitution or the revision of the Constitution will not affect the national character.
In addition, there is the state flag.
The state flag is actually unnecessary.
No one stipulates that the country must have a state flag.
But that is a symbol.
So usually there will be.
To change it will not affect the national character.
The national anthem is the same.
Here we will start to enter the topic.
Taiwan's international law status.
Here we have to define what Taiwan is.
Taiwan actually has several definitions.
The most common is that
In the current range of the People's Republic of China regime.
Including Taiwan, Penghu, Kinmen.
There are other regions controlled by the regime in reality.
For example, Dongsha Island, Taiping Island.
These places.
The other is Guangyi.
That is the so-called island of Taiwan.
With its affiliated islands.
Then there is Penghu Island.
This is Guangyi.
That is the island of Taiwan.
With its affiliated islands.
That is not included in Penghu Island.
That is the island of Taiwan.
In today's briefing.
Unless I list Penghu at the same time today.
Otherwise, basically speaking.
This is Guangyi.
This is the island of Taiwan.
With its affiliated islands.
Then there is Penghu Island.
That does not include other places.
So it does not include Kinmen, Mazu.
And Dongsha, Taiping.
These places.
In fact, the past of Taiwan.
In fact, history is very long.
But because what we are going to talk about today.
It is relatively close to the modern history of Taiwan.
So I think I will.
Probably from Taiwan and China.
Began to be involved.
For example, modern China.
Let's start with less involved places.
But in this place.
We can take a look first.
This is the Qing Dynasty.
The emperor of the Qing Dynasty.
This is Emperor Yongzheng.
He said.
Taiwan has not belonged to China since ancient times.
The imperial examination of the God of War revealed the map.
This is the father of Emperor Yongzheng.
Also Emperor Kangxi.
In other words.
This place in Taiwan.
Until Emperor Kangxi of the Qing Dynasty.
To really enter the so-called map of China.
But before that.
Basically speaking.
Taiwan is not part of China.
So we know.
People's Republic of China.
Now claim that Taiwan is part of China.
The indivisible part.
Since ancient times.
We know.
In fact, many people do not agree with the facts.
In this place.
I think there are some points.
For example.
Because I'm talking about this now.
China is related to Taiwan.
And it is related to modern Taiwan.
So we jump directly.
Jump to 1662.
Is the part of Zheng Chenggong's defeat of the Netherlands.
Before that.
Is that.
Other western countries.
The part of the people of Taiwan.
The place has jumped.
In 1662.
Zheng Chenggong's defeat of the Netherlands.
We know.
The so-called anti-Qing people.
Later.
Not long after he came to Taiwan.
Died.
His son.
Zheng Jing.
Later.
Established the so-called Donglin Kingdom.
That.
Donglin Kingdom.
On the island of Taiwan.
Is.
More.
The Chinese side.
Is.
In fact.
In Taiwan.
More.
The beginning of a systematic degeneration.
Then.
In 1683.
In the 7th month of the Donglin Kingdom.
When he was at the Penghu Sea War.
He was defeated by the Qing Empire.
Then.
Surrender in September.
In October.
Enter the sea.
Enter Taiwan.
Then he surrendered.
So at this time.
Because.
The Qing Empire.
Then.
This.
The Qing Empire.
Emperor Kangxi.
Later.
Decided.
To take Taiwan.
Into the so-called territory.
Of course.
That is to say.
The Qing Empire itself.
In.
Defeated.
Zheng Chenggong.
After the Donglin Kingdom.
Is.
To take Taiwan into.
This.
The territory of the Qing Empire.
Inside.
They also have a fight.
But later.
Anyway.
After a fight.
So I still decided.
All right.
Let's take Taiwan into the territory.
But.
No active management.
Then.
In 1867.
This.
The so-called United States.
The Rovahao Incident.
That is.
The United States.
Uploaded.
He is.
In the east.
Here.
Then.
Later.
Accidentally.
Into.
This.
Taiwan's territory.
Then.
As a result.
Later.
Many people were fired.
That.
Living.
Living people.
Run.
Go to the Qing Empire.
A small report.
As a result.
The Qing Empire said.
Then he.
Do not care.
From this place.
You can see.
One thing.
That is.
For the Qing Empire.
The so-called deep.
He does not think.
Is his own territory.
That is.
He can't control.
The place.
He thinks.
That is not actually his territory.
So.
It's not his territory.
Within the scope of things.
It's not.
He can manage.
So.
We can see from this place.
That is.
The Qing Empire.
Basically.
What is his position?
On this island.
He can control.
What is the position of the scope?
That.
The United States.
Of course.
Very angry.
Ah.
That's good.
Since you don't care.
Then I'll do it myself.
So.
The United States.
He himself.
Send troops away.
To Taiwan.
So.
This is the U.S. Marine Corps.
Just.
Landed in Taiwan.
Then.
To this.
The native of the Taiwanese people.
Just.
Fight with him.
As a result.
Since defeated.
Lost.
This.
Now this is.
The U.S. Marine Corps.
Everyone knows.
Hey.
Almost everyone hears it.
Wen Feng.
That's it.
Hey.
This.
Is very powerful.
But they lost to this.
The native of Taiwan.
So.
You can know.
The native of Taiwan.
Really.
Very arrogant.
So he.
The United States.
These.
The Marines.
Attack the native of Taiwan.
Return in the rain.
Later.
Three months later.
Just.
In Langqiao.
With the head of the 18th Division of the Taiwan Army.
This.
Zhou Qidu.
He fought with him.
Then.
He signed the so-called.
Alliance of the Southern Xia.
Then.
Officially ended.
This.
Luo Fahao Incident.
Then.
This Alliance of the Southern Xia.
Basically.
That is to say.
In the future.
If there is a ship.
In case of.
What kind of.
When the shipwreck happened.
Then.
If they say.
Raised a.
What label.
For example.
Raised a red flag.
Then.
The United States.
This.
Is.
A kind of agreement.
That.
From this place.
We can see that.
This.
The United States.
With.
The aborigines.
They signed.
Such an agreement.
But.
Signed such an agreement.
Is it representative of.
This.
The Taiwan Army 18th Division.
They.
In the eyes of the United States.
Is.
A country.
In fact, this.
To put on a question mark.
Just.
Because in fact.
This is the US government.
They are with.
Under the international law.
Modern.
The sovereign state.
The same.
Can sign some agreements.
Sign some agreements.
So.
Even if it is.
Signed such an agreement.
It does not mean that.
At that time.
The United States.
Is.
This.
Taiwan Army 18th Division.
This piece.
Recognize it.
Is a country.
But what we can be sure of is.
He thinks.
He is with a regime.
Is signing.
Just.
Because he thinks.
He can control that place.
A regime.
And then.
In.
After more than a year.
This.
Li Xian.
Again.
With that.
Zhuo Qidu.
In China.
The customs tax officer.
Under the witness.
Signing a memorandum of understanding.
That's here.
I'm talking about.
Under the witness.
So we know that.
This.
This Chinese customs.
The official.
He is just a witness.
He is not the party.
So we know that.
In this case.
It is a very.
It's a very.
It's a very very memorable.
It's a very memorable.
In this case it's a very interesting thing.
The United States and.
With this.
The representative of the Manchen family from the south of Taiwan.
Signed with him.
This thing.
China's third-person role.
challenged
Be a witness.
China's third-person role.
Not be a person's character.
Not be Person's anime.
It can be seen from this that it means that China does not really believe that that place is his territory.
Then there was an event at the peony bazaar in 1878 lecture.
Many people know.
It is.
Liu Lib LA.
OK.
It is happening for thevious reasons.
It is happening for vicious reasons.
After it, the land was villagers encountered with native people.
Then some language, culture Military politics is lost.
Then some peko FF Escaped by battle.
At this time,
In the imperial State of Japan,
during the great British competition with the King
toward the imperial State of the New Republic.
Theren commander of the Imperial Japanese Palace
Recently, he Roosevelt asked
The one who killed the King of Taiwan
You are not the King of the Empire
You are not the king of the empire
The great New Empire not to
The great New Empire
King's imperial reuse
King's imperial rebirth
The great New Empire said
This is a self-degraded rebirth
In other words
The great New Empire said
These people can't control
So we found that
It's the same as the Roosevelt incident
The attitude of the great New Empire is like this
The attitude of Japan is OK
Well, since that's the case
You think these
The place where the rebirth is located is not your territory
Then you can't control these
Then I'll take care of it, right?
Because I think the Great Japanese Empire said
I think the King of the Empire
It's also my territory
So I want to protect my territory
So I'm going to punish
These rebirths in Taiwan
So Japan sent troops to the so-called five main regions
Five main regions
So later
Japan, of course, sent troops to attack
Mutan Temple, Kaosifu Temple
And then
After defeating these aborigines
He camped in that place
For the Great Japanese Empire
It's actually a very embarrassing thing
That is
You are the Great Japanese Empire
You go to this island of Taiwan today
You have to go
For your
The fishermen of the King of the Empire
Go to
It's OK to achieve justice
But after you go there to fight
You stay there
No
Because he
The Great Japanese Empire still thinks that
The island of Taiwan is mainly his
Although Japan is there
Stay there
What do you think
So the Great Japanese Empire later
To find a way
To get rid of these things
So later
Through the intervention of the British Empire
Then signed the Beijing Treaty
After that
It's agreed in it
After that, these places on the island of Taiwan
These rebirths
The Great Japanese Empire has to find a way
To restrain
In fact, to some extent
This also means that
Britain is here
It's a statement
All right
People in these places
Basically
Or you have to manage
You have to manage
I think it's a bit like admitting
The place where those rebirths are
In fact, it is still the territory of the Great Japanese Empire
So people in these places
You have to manage
such
In 1885
The Great Japanese Empire finally
Established it in Taiwan
After two years
Officially assigned to work
As a result
It didn't take long to establish
Ten years later
Nine years
Then the Jiawu War happened
On March 23, Japan
One of the Penghu
Japan has occupied Penghu
So in the so-called Jiawu War
Penghu is actually
Involved in the war
But Japan
He has an army to occupy Penghu
Here I want to mention
In the past
Just before
Before World War I and World War II
In the International Law
Basically during the war
If you are in the war
This one
For example, the enemy occupied
His opponent's country
A piece of territory
When there is an occupation
Usually after the war
The part that was occupied
May be cut off
So in fact, Japan
On March 23, he occupied Penghu
Is meaningful
That is to say
Japan wants to say
He wants to eat Taiwan and Penghu
So anyway
On March 23
He sent the army first
To occupy Penghu
Later, when signing the contract
There is a big bargaining chip
Can ask the Qing Empire to give up Penghu
Here we can take a look
That is to say
The Qing Empire was in 1772
The scope he controlled
It's actually very small
In other words
After the Qing Empire
After he solved the Kingdom of Dongning
In 1772
The scope he actually controlled
It's still very small
Still limited to the original
The scope controlled by the Kingdom of Dongning
By 1884
Then in 1884
The Qing Empire
The scope of control is relatively large
Just now
Does anyone want to speak?
It's okay, you can continue
I'm sorry
OK
In 1772
The Qing Empire
The scope of control on the island of Taiwan
Is very small
Then in 1884
His scope of control is relatively large
But we found
In the middle of the island of Taiwan
Is mainly the mountainous area
The Qing Empire
Basically uncontrollable
But actually we see
This 1884
The Qing Empire
The scope he controlled
Actually in the eastern part
For example, in the so-called
The part of Beinanting
May be a little bragging
Because actually
The Qing Empire
In the middle of the east
His ability to control
Not so strong
Then in 1895
This
The Treaty of Maguan
The Treaty of Maguan was signed on May 8th
Then the Great Japanese
In terms of international law
The Great Japanese Empire is
According to this Treaty of Maguan
To obtain the Qing Empire
The rule of law in the Taiwan Strait
Then
After a few weeks
I said it was not really
To establish an independent democratic country
Then this is also particularly emphasized
It's not really independent
Why do you say that?
Because
In fact, Taiwan is a democratic country
Some people see Taiwan as a democratic country today
I think this is the Taiwanese claim
Independent
Is a pioneer
Then there is also the belief that
Is now going to restore the country
What is the restoration of Taiwan's democracy?
But the Taiwan Democratic Republic is actually
When it was established
In fact, it's just a delay
That's just to say
Some officials of the Qing Empire
Then there were some
Some scholars at the time wanted to say
They want to say
Announce independence as soon as possible
Then
See if there are other countries to intervene
Then let Japan
There is no way to put that
Taiwan and Penghu
Become its territory
Because we know that in the Treaty of Maguan
The original part of the Great Japanese Empire
Except for Penghu, Taiwan
Including those places on the Liaodong Peninsula
As a result
There is the so-called Three Kingdoms Intervention in Liao
So actually at that time
Some officials in Taiwan
There are some scholars
They are thinking
I will announce independence as soon as possible today
Then maybe other countries will intervene
Then Japan will put Taiwan and Penghu
Into the Qing Empire
So there is such an idea
So even the Taiwan Democratic Republic
Even that year
Its year is called Yongqing
You know that this is
Always loyal to the Qing Empire
So in fact, the Taiwan Democratic Republic
It's really not
It really means independence
So in terms of international law
After the establishment of the Taiwan Democratic Republic
Basically speaking
There is no country to admit
No other country
Admit the existence of this country
Everyone can see it clearly
No one wants to
Take advantage of this
So in terms of concept
Taiwan Democratic Republic
Is on the mainland territory of the Great Japanese Empire
Taiwan's rebellion
The so-called Taiwan Democratic Republic was established by the rebellion
That's about five months later
This is the end of the military suppression
So the Taiwan Democratic Republic was destroyed
And then this
By 1910
The Great Japanese Empire began to use force
To annex the territory of the aborigines
Then I say here
Use force to annex the territory of the aborigines
Then in this place
It's a way to conquer with force
Before World War I
Is to conquer with force
Is to wage war
Use force to conquer the territory of others
Then expand your own sovereignty
Territory
In international law
Is legal
Before this
Before World War I
This is legal
But after World War I
Such behavior
Basically speaking
It is deemed illegal
That is because
To avoid the country
Expand the territory by force
Anyway
Is Japan
The Great Japanese Empire
He is using force
To conquer
Can legally expand the territory
During the period
He used force
To annex the territory of the aborigines
Then he used this
The so-called Five-Year Li Fan Plan
Is to use force to conquer
By January 15, 1915
The Five-Year Li Fan Plan was completed
It was announced to end on the 20th of the same month
This is the so-called Taiwan Islands
Out of the city
That is to say
On this day
Taiwan Islands
Every inch of land
Is his true sovereignty
Belongs to the Great Japanese Empire
So we know
Actually this
Taiwan Islands
The Great Empire
He gave it to Japan
In fact, it does not include the so-called
Central Mountain Area
Then there is the eastern part
That is Japan
After he used force to conquer
He really got a complete
Taiwan Islands
Conquered sovereignty
In 1943
This
Later
After the island returned to Japan
It's been a while
Then this
The Second World War broke out
That
On October 23, 1943
The so-called Kairo Airstrike
Then it says
The Taiwan-Japan War will return to the Republic of China
Then on July 26, 1945
The Wade Declaration
Then it says that the Kairo Declaration
Must be implemented
August 15, 1945
The Great Japanese Empire
This
The emperor of the Japanese
The Great Japanese Empire unconditionally surrendered to the Mongols
I think
Ok
Then let's jump back and see
This 1895
I just said before
I said that the Qing Empire
He
In that
The 1884
That one
He said he was on the east side
The part of the Northern Land
Say that part is a bit bragging
why
You see, in 1895
When the Great Japanese Empire
The range it can control
Not including the east
That is actually very interesting
That is to say
Because this place actually represents
Originally these places were all
The Great Japanese Empire can effectively control
Should be able to
Effectively transfer to Japan
But actually for Japan
He said in 1895
He is on the east side
He still can't control
That place is the aboriginal place
But in 1920
Found the island of Taiwan
All included in the Great Japanese Empire
Set up this administrative plan
Japan also effectively governs
So we know that
In fact, the sovereignty of the entire island of Taiwan
In fact, the Great Japanese Empire
Is the first one
A country with sovereignty over the island of Taiwan
OK
I just talked about this in 1895
August 15, 1945
This
The emperor of the Great Japanese Empire
Is to announce the surrender of the Five Straits
Then on September 2
The Great Japanese Empire
He signed the surrender document
The surrender document
It is a ceasefire agreement
That is to say
After signing this
Everyone will fire each other
So this is just a ceasefire agreement
The purpose is to end the battle
Then the same day
The same day
Chief of the Allied Forces
Commander Michael Arthur
He ordered the Great Japanese Empire
Issued what he issued
General Order No. 1
Inside
He agreed that
The representative of the regime of the Republic of China
According to the arrangements in the order
In China
Not including Manchuria
Then in Taipeng
Then 16 degrees north to north
French Indochina
Accept Japanese surrender
Then
Let's take a look
Someone just said in China
Then Taipeng
Then 16 degrees north to north
So I found out
He is a division list
So it means
Taipeng is not part of China
Then China
It does not include Manchuria
Then why is it planned like this
Because at that time Manchuria
Is handed over to the Soviet Union
To be responsible
Then go to surrender
Then occupy
Then October 25, 1945
This is Chiang Kai-shek
He sent the representative of the surrender
Chen Yi
To the Taipei Public Security Hall
Hold the Allied Surrender Ceremony
But he held this
When the surrender ceremony
He did not say that this is
The Allied Forces came to surrender
He said this is called
Taiwan restoration
That
At that time he
The Republic of China regime
Here in Taiwan
Established a
Occupation agency
It's called
Taiwan Provincial Administrative Officer Agency
Add the three words of Taiwan Provincial
That because
Actually this
At this time
Taiwan is just
Allied Forces
Military occupation
That is to say, it is not really
Return to the Republic of China
The sovereignty did not really
That
Taiwan Provincial Administrative Officer Agency
In fact, it represents the Allied Forces
To Taiwan and Penghu
Occupation
But because
The Republic of China is thinking
Anyway, that
The Cairo Times said that
Taiwan and Penghu
After Japan surrendered
Will return to the Republic of China
So he just
A little bit like
Before and after
Five tickets after getting on the bus
So he just
Established the so-called
Administrative Officer Agency
Then add Taiwan Provincial in front
That goes with that
Taiwan Guangfu
That
January 12, 1946
The Republic of China regime
He issued
Administrative order
Then restore Taiwan Penghu
Well-known
Republic of China nationality
That
Britain and the United States
In this place
He protested
He said because of Taiwan Penghu sovereignty
At this time
Still belong to Japan
So you have to say
Britain and the United States are clear
He said there was no Taiwan Guangfu
This kind of thing
No 18
December 15, 1945
No Taiwan Guangfu
This kind of thing
Taiwan and Penghu sovereignty
In 1942
Still belong to Japan
So they said
You can't be in the Republic of China
Just like this
Directly to the occupation
People's nationality
But the Republic of China
He continues
I do what I do
So anyway
He still does
But in international law
In fact, at that time
Taiwanese people
Taiwan and Penghu
Residents
They
In international law
He still has
Still have
Great Japanese Empire
Is the nationality of Japan
But at this time
They have one more
The so-called Republic of China nationality
So at that time
Taipeng resident
Double nationality
Everyone has two nationalities
Then
On February 28, 1947
Then all the way to the same April
On February 28, the Great Lusha
This thing
In fact, here we can know
Say
In fact, here
What happened
It's definitely not the government
With his name
Is a national government
With his people
Conflict
It's not the case
The situation here is
A
Occupation
In
Occupation of the victorious country
On the territory of the defeated country
The act of slaughtering the people of the defeated country
This is definitely not what
It's not an official-civilian conflict
This is
Cross-national slaughter
Because after the February 28 incident
This
The people of Taiwan are of course
For this
The regime of the Republic of China
Very dissatisfied with the situation here in Taiwan
Then they also made a request
Request that the governor-general of Taiwan province
Require him to be re-elected
Become the provincial government of Taiwan
Because he thinks
Chen Yi is like another
Like the Governor-General of Taiwan
That
The regime of the Republic of China
Later on April 22
When it was
Re-elected the provincial government of Taiwan
That
On May 17, the provincial government of Taiwan
Officially operated
Then in front of this
I want to talk about it
Re-elect the governor-general of Taiwan province
Re-elected
Re-elected the provincial government of Taiwan
This is actually
The requirements that the people of Taiwan put forth
This is the requirements that the people of Taiwan put forth
It means that the people of Taiwan
At that time
They think they are
Citizens of the Republic of China
And don't think they are
People occupying the land
So they will make such a request
So to some extent
It means that I am Chinese
So
So this is actually a choice
This is a choice
The result of this choice
Caused a big problem
OK
On May 17, 1947
The provincial government of Taiwan officially operated
On October 1, 1949
The government of the People's Republic of China
Witness
I don't want to talk about witnessing
Because actually in this place
What really happened
Is not to establish another country
But another government
That also started on this day
On October 1, 1949
China
There is a two-party regime
There are two regimes under China
Republic of China regime
With the People's Republic of China regime
These two regimes
Began to fight
Who is the representative government of China
That has been fighting to this day
Keep fighting to this day
Still fighting to this day
Some people may think
No
Now the government of the Republic of China
Isn't it the government of Taiwan?
Where is he fighting this thing?
In fact, there is
Why not
Because we look at this before
In 2017
Panama
He changed to recognize the People's Republic of China regime
Is the Chinese representative government
Of course, Taiwan is writing here
What is Taiwan-Panamanian diplomatic relations?
But we look at that time
Republic of China regime
What does his Ministry of Foreign Affairs say?
He said
Republic of China regime
Between Panama
The diplomatic relations between the two countries
More than a century
How does this century count?
When did it start?
Counting from 1910
This is very interesting
If the Republic of China regime is not China
How could you
If it's really Taiwan
How could you be with Panama
More than a century of diplomatic relations
Because in 1910
Taiwan is the territory of Japan
So it's impossible for Taiwan to establish diplomatic relations with Panama
So in 1910
It must be China
And the point is
In 1910
The Republic of China has not appeared yet
Still the Qing Empire
So we know
The Republic of China is the Qing Empire
So he just counted like this
Then the Republic of China is China
So from here we can know
The Republic of China regime says itself is Taiwan
This is actually a big question mark
Republic of China government
Until now
It's still so determined
In fact, the Republic of China regime
It's all like this
Look at him
There is no diplomatic country
China
This thing
Take it from him
There is still China
Where is this attribute
OK
it is good
On December 8, 1949
Because of this
Domestic relations
Do you have any questions?
No no
I don't have a question
Let's pause here for a moment
Just to this
Before the establishment of the People's Republic of China
Because there are a lot of historical facts here
quite a lot
Let's stop here
Before the establishment of the People's Republic of China
Does anyone have any questions?
Do you want to ask?
I can ask
You say
I just
I am a historian
Then I also read some
Some questions about international law
Then of course
I haven't talked about the key part yet
Is the 1952 Sanhok Agreement
I look forward to how you will interpret that thing
But I think so far
I heard a question
Is that when you first defined the international law
There are three
It was just mentioned by Yan Yong
Then you put Taiwan in the third
He is just a full-time independent unit
Instead of a country
If your definition is like that
In fact, you are still discussing
That is to say
You try to put the regime of the Republic of China
Kick out of Taiwan
Then think that the people of Taiwan can decide for themselves
The government of the Republic of China is just one of the exiled regimes
That is unreasonable
Because of your own
Your own
The original assumption is that Taiwan is not a country
If your original assumption is like that
That is to say
Taiwan can't get out of the Republic of the People's Republic of China
Can't skip the Republic of the People's Republic of China
Then talk to yourself
I can be independent
What can I do about this
Do you understand
Do you understand the mistake
Ah, I think you
This inference seems a bit strange
Because why would you go to the Republic of China
There is no way to escape
It has nothing to do with him
Yeah, yeah, yeah, because I just heard it
The feeling is the first one
The first step is to say
I want to make sure that we are on the same page
You think Taiwan's current situation is not a sovereign state
Right
That's because it's all the way down
The result is that Taiwan is not a country
So I will
That is
I just said earlier
Why is Taiwan not a country
I said I would talk about it later
Oh, so
It's not that I make an assumption first
No, no
Is that I push it all the way
Because in the end it will be made
I will tell you that the whole way
There will be a conclusion
And the conclusion is
Taiwan is not a country
But Taiwan is really a
A place of independent operation
So I put this thing on
That is to say, this is
A political entity mentioned in the International Law
Something that will appear
Because Taiwan is really a political entity
Participating in international society
It doesn't matter if you continue
Because of that 1952
The San Francisco Treaty
I think it's more critical
I think
How to explain that
Because I think it's quite interesting
Because I'm talking about this here
The point is
Taiwan's sovereignty belongs to who
Because Taiwan's sovereignty
Our sovereignty
Because it says here
Here
Taiwan's sovereignty is not yet
Belong to any
Still in Japan
Actually, I think this question is good
But that's why
The reason I stopped here
This is what I will talk about later
So before this
About any historical events
Do you have any questions?
Because what Kiki said
With the next thing to talk about
Because that will be answered later
That will be answered later
I'm sorry
The part where someone left a message
Let me read it for him
I want to ask
Why is the Kinmen Mazu not in
In your definition of Taiwan
This will be talked about later
Will be talked about later, right?
But actually I will say
A simple truth
That is
Because the Kinmen Mazu
Never been
Conceded by China
The Kinmen Mazu has always been in China
So its historical direction
It's different from Taiwan
From 1895
There is a big difference
Yes, it was in 1895
Taiwan and Penghu were conceded to Japan
So these two places
After the defeat of Japan
The problem of transfer
It's different from the Kinmen Mazu
Because the Kinmen Mazu
It is inherited by the Manchurian government
The Republic of China government
Then the Republic of China government
Later became an exile government
So come to Taiwan
The Kinmen Mazu
Its sovereignty has always been
Belongs to the Republic of China government
But Taiwan
Because in 1895
There was a regime transfer
Is to transfer to Japan
Then after the defeat of Japan
Gave up this land
So Taiwan and Penghu will have problems
Kinmen Mazu has no problem
You secretly finished my thing
Do you want to come and talk
But anyway
But I think this place should be a little bit
Because I'll talk about it later
Because it's not actually
Sovereignty does not belong to the Republic of China
But belongs to China
Let's put it this way
Because when
We are talking about this part of sovereignty
Sovereignty belongs to
It must be a country
The Republic of China
It's actually in
People's Republic of China
Sovereignty appears
A state of two regimes under China
When
At this time
Actually the problem is
That is to say
That part of the territory
Anyway, the territory of China
Always the territory of China
But
Unless there is
Unless there are other changes
The status of the transfer of territorial sovereignty
But this
Republic of China regime
With the People's Republic of China regime
These two regimes
Who is the representative government of China
This is the problem
But Kinmen and Mazu
Always
Always belong to the territory of China
In other words
Republic of China
It's not a
It's not a separate
People's Republic of China
country
They are a
Two regimes in a country
Two
Who is the representative government of the government
regime
So it's always been like this
Always in this state
So
Kinmen has always been the territory of China
That's also because of this reason
So it becomes
Kinmen has always been tied to China
Taiwan and Penghu
There is a situation of leaving China
Now it's actually going to be discussed later
Taiwan and Penghu
Did you go back to China
Did you go back to
Become part of China's territory
This is actually
International law
Top
Issues to discuss
I think everyone is asking questions
It's almost time to break the meme
Otherwise, let's continue
Yes, let's continue
OK
it is good
That 1949
Then we know that this
Because of the international war
Then the Republic of China
The regime of the Republic of China
He passed the executive committee meeting
Decision
Then move the central government to
Taipeng
Become an exile regime
That actually
The United States
These countries
A little bit
Forget it
That is to say
This one
It was announced
It was said that Taiwan and Penghu
Anyway, sooner or later
Return to China
right
that
I don't care about him
In case it is said that Taipeng
If it is said that in case
That
If the CCP eats it
You just admit it
But later because of the Korean War
Just
American attitude
There are some
This
The attitude of the anti-communist country has changed
They think this
This communist country
They are now
To expand their power
That way
It's already
The country itself
Own
The uprising between the people
Or the form of revolution
In addition
There is also this
Is to use force to invade
So they think
This is unacceptable
No way
In this place
I think the communist country
Must be used
In a more powerful way
To fight him
So at that time
They just
A conclusion
That is to say
Taiwan and Penghu can't fall
Communists
So at that time
They just
Maybe a
The so-called Taiwan Strait
Neutralization Declaration
At this time
He actually said
That is to say
Taiwan and Penghu
This part of the sovereignty
This question
This has not been decided yet
This has to be solved
Wait until
After signing a contract with Japan
Then decide
That's what they think
Or wait for the Korean War
After the end of the Korean War
Decide again
But later
Of course
There are some changes
That
On September 8, 1951
Japan and 48 allies
Members
Signed the San Francisco Treaty
At this time
When signing the San Francisco Treaty
China
There is no
Signed
Of course
A very important reason is because
In the end
China
Which regime
To represent the government
To represent China
This
Allies
There is a dispute between the members
Like the United States
I feel like I have to ask the Republic of China to come
Like the Soviet Union
He felt like
There should be the People's Republic of China
regime
Everyone is arguing
Irreconcilable
So in the end
China is not
No
Signed the San Francisco Treaty
But in the San Francisco Treaty
There is a special
Part of China's power
There are some
Some
Conditions
In the second B of the San Francisco Treaty
He is clear
That is to say
Japan gives up the right to Taiwan Strait
Rights and demands
This is a complete
A way to give up the sovereignty of the Taiwan Strait
Ok
But he did not point out
Who is the owner of the sovereignty of the Taiwan Strait?
So this is in
The so-called status of Taiwan is not set
This legal basis
The basis of the International Law is completed
Before this
For example, on June 25, 1950
Taiwan's status is not set
This position comes out
Actually
Because at that time
In fact, Taiwan and Penghu
Taiwan's sovereignty belongs to Japan
Just say
At that time
In fact, Truman meant
That is to say
Taiwan and Penghu
The status of the future
Not sure yet
That's just
This is in the San Francisco Treaty
Inside
In the second B
Directly put
The status of Taiwan and Penghu
Is not set
This legal basis
Set it up
So through this treaty
Inside this clause
Inside Japan
Then there is no designation
Who will accept
This one
Let Taiwan and Penghu
The final disposal
In a
Uncertain state
On the International Law
Taiwan and Penghu
The status is in an uncertain situation
In fact, in the San Francisco Treaty
It's not just Taiwan and Penghu
It's like this
There are others like
The West Shaanxi Islands
The South Shaanxi Islands
Then
And Japan
There were some at that time
There will be some
Tendao Islands
Kuye Islands
These places in the south
In fact, they are all in the same form
To standardize
So basically
All belong to the so-called status
To a certain state
Unless later
There are other special disposals
Taiwan and Penghu are not
OK
The second F below
I told you
He said to Mingding
The part of the South Shaanxi and the West Shaanxi
Japan is also in the same way
To give up
So this part is
Japan gave up
The sovereignty of these places
Absolutely give up
That was in 1951
On November 19
Japan's Yuren Emperor
According to the request of the Japanese Cabinet
To complete the certification of the San Francisco Treaty
Then I'm here
The reason for this particular point
Because
To some people
I'm still arguing now
That is to say
Taiwan and Penghu sovereignty
Still belong to Japan
That
Their claim is
Because of that
The San Francisco Treaty
Is
Signed by the Japanese government
Not the Japanese emperor
Signed
So it doesn't count
Then I'm here
Special mention
That is to say
The Japanese emperor has already certified
San Francisco Treaty
So he has already recognized
So the San Francisco Treaty
To give up the Taiwan-Penghu sovereignty
The Japanese emperor has already recognized
So Taiwan and Penghu sovereignty
No longer belong to Japan
That
In 1952
On April 19
Japanese Justice
Sorry
You say
Can I ask a question?
You said here
Hey
San Francisco Treaty
China has no money
Then my question is
That way
Does this contract still count?
Or is this kind of contract
Is to
Big
I don't know how to
How does this contract work?
If there is one
From Mongolia
This contract is still valid
Thank you
OK
it is good
Let's talk about it now
San Francisco Treaty
It actually means this
because
The purpose of the contract
Is to end
The state of war between countries
So in San Francisco Treaty
Inside
Every signed country
Every signed member
Are the countries that have fought with Japan before
So San Francisco Treaty
Actually
Although it is Japan
Signed with so many countries
But actually
He
What I really want to say is
This
48 countries
Have signed a contract with Japan
That
The effect of this contract is
Happened in Japan
With
Between each signed country
Is the effect of individual establishment
Individual establishment effect
So
It's the United Nations
Not a
It's not like a company
Something like a judge
It is a
Individual
Gather
So it's like
When we sign a contract
San Francisco Treaty
Effective in Japan
With
Every
Signed
Between countries
That did not sign
That's the contract
It doesn't work for that country
But it won't affect
Signed
The country with the contract
Efficiency between Japan
and so
In this place
San Francisco Treaty
Itself
When it works
Is
All countries that have signed and approved
This contract is effective
That
Not because
Which one
San Francisco members did not sign
Then the whole contract will be invalid
Or there is no way to work
because
The international law
Basically speaking
Between two countries
Established
one
It's a contract relationship
So
Will not be affected by another country
Is there a contract
Unless they are in today
In the contract
Directly say
Must have someone
To sign
Approve
This
The contract is effective
Otherwise
Basically speaking
Established in
Every
Signed between countries
Any other country
No money
Does not affect the efficiency of the contract
In fact, in this place
San Francisco Treaty
That
San Francisco member
Not only China
The Soviet Union did not sign
The Soviet Union is actually today
Have not signed a peace treaty with Japan
Peace Treaty
From the Soviet Union to today
Have not signed a peace treaty with Japan
That
Wait a minute
Because I don't quite understand
What is the contract for?
Is to end the war between
End the war between the country and the country
The state of war
Then there is
Determine the compensation between countries
So
I can understand
So this contract
As long as Japan unilaterally recognizes it
From each country
Can complete
No country
Does it matter to sign?
No
Signed country
To end
The war between him and Japan
If you don't sign
War
Will continue to exist
So
So that means
China is now
Theoretically still
In the state of war with Japan
No
Because we haven't finished the history
Sorry
Because you don't have to sign
You want
You can sign another contract with Japan
Contract
In other words
Not just able to sign
This kind of contract
Every country
Because
Just say we are so
For example, if there are 50 people today
Right
Fifty people fight a group
Then
Fifty people fight a man
Then this person
With everyone
Everyone makes an agreement
Some people say
We use this set today
Use this set of rules
This condition
We
I made an agreement with you
In fact, he said this set
Condition
I am not satisfied
I want to talk about it again
Yes
So that's the state
You can also
With those countries that do not sign the agreement
In another contract
To end their
The state of war
Not just able to sign
Not
When you
Between two countries
You want to end the state of war
Just sign a contract
But
In the case of so many countries
Can
You can have
For example, 50
Fifty
Allied soldiers
You can sign with Japan
Is
Between 1 to 50
Between
This contract
To end this state of war
But if
For example, like here
There are 48 members
Decided to sign a treaty with Japan
That
It's these 48 countries
The state of war with Japan
Just based on the treaty to end
Ok
Then the rest did not sign
They just
In addition, use other ways to end
Maybe it's a contract
Maybe it's in other forms
For example, some are
What to publish
To replace
The same
To achieve that goal
But we are talking about
48 countries
48 allied soldiers
Signed with Japan
In the end, only 45 were approved
That
In addition, there are those three that are not
They are actually later
Also use other ways to contact
The state of war with Japan
Correct
This is
It's quite interesting
That is to say, this one
Maybe someone will say
Is the allied forces coming together?
No
That is
Countries
Just gather together
But he did not stipulate that
Must be consistent
Then all the same action
To count
No
Each country
Is an individual right
Individuals can go to Japan to sign a treaty
This is a country with its own
That
Because of that
Uh
There is another one
This participant
He has a question
That
That is
China did not sign a treaty with Japan
And so on
This question of Taiwan
I think
This discussion is probably
Probably answered this question
Because we are a little late now
That
Uh
Let's
The user's question
If he feels that it has not been fully answered
After the speech
Ask again
Then talk about the parts that have not been answered
OK?
Then you end it first
OK
That user
Sorry
That
Because China later
Signed with Japan
Ha ha ha
OK
it is good
That
April 19, 1952
Then of course
Posted that
Private message
That message said
Taipeng resident
The expiration date of the TPP Treaty
Japanese nationality
That
TPP Treaty
April 28, 1952
So
From that day on
Taiwan and Penghu are no longer Japanese territory
Then the sovereignty is in an uncertain state
Then
Taipeng resident
He is no longer Japanese nationality
No more Japanese
Yes
Now there are some people in Taiwan and Penghu
There are still Japanese nationalities
This is not always understood in international law
Then let's talk about this thing now
Is
China signed a contract with Japan
That is
April 28, 1952
On the day the contract came into effect
Japan and the People's Republic of China
Signed the Sino-Japanese Treaty
What about this contract
Because Japan was there
He is
Recognize the People's Republic of China as the Chinese representative government
So at this time
The effect of the Sino-Japanese Treaty
Is to end the war between China and Japan
So although China did not sign the TPP Treaty
But
He signed the Sino-Japanese Treaty
So it's still the same
Then there is a point
In the Sino-Japanese Treaty
Article 2
He clearly stated
The two sides admitted that Japan had given up Taiwan in the TPP Treaty
Taipeng
The complete sovereignty of the South China Sea and the West China Sea
That's it
It's over
This is about territorial
The part of Taipeng's sovereignty
That's it
Nothing else
In fact, in this place
This second article also means
The People's Republic of China
Basically through the signing of the Sino-Japanese Treaty
He admitted that in the Sino-Japanese Treaty
Arrangements for Taiwan's absence
In the fourth article
This includes all the treaties between China and Japan before December 9, 1941
This also includes the so-called Maguan Treaty
There will be a question later
But I will mention
Article 10
Taipeng residents and his descendants
As a citizen of the People's Republic of China
But here you have to pay special attention
This is a citizen
You are not
Take you as
It's called a citizen
So in other words
In fact, Taipeng residents and his descendants
For the regime of the People's Republic of China
Actually not his citizen
He just took it as his citizen
In law
The Sino-Japanese Treaty was enacted on August 5, 1952
it is good
Then I just said before
He signed the Sino-Japanese Treaty
Article 10
The absence of the Sino-Japanese Treaty before December 9, 1941
All the treaties
Including the Maguan Treaty
Will Taipeng's sovereignty return to the People's Republic of China?
That Japanese side is very straightforward
It seems that in 1964
The Taiwan Treaty Bureau said directly
Jumped over
We just said
Such a treaty as Taiwan's abandonment
That is to say
Complete the abandonment of Taiwan
Once achieved the purpose
After that, it will only be effective in form
Because this is
A treaty that has been executed
Even if abandoned
Abandonment in form
The event that has been executed
Unable to return to the state of non-execution
In other words
The Maguan Treaty abandons Taiwan and Penghu to Japan
Abandoned
Completed
It's over after the transfer
After that, even if the Maguan Treaty is abolished
Taiwan and Penghu's sovereignty
Will not return to the Republic of China because of this
This is the basic principle of international law
Because it is based on the requirements of legal stability
Of course, why is this?
Because
Because in fact, between the international
Sometimes in the past
Often because of some war
There is a problem of territorial partition between each other
So the territory is partitioned
If it's just between two countries
It doesn't matter if you fight
Sometimes it will be related to the third country
Or even the fourth country, the fifth country
In this case
Your territory
A piece of territory may be partitioned in the middle
Turn around
Turn a few hands
If you are in the back
For example, if the A country and the B country fight
Then partition a piece of land
Then fight a few battles
Then the land was later transferred to the F country
Then if later
Between the A country and the B country
If the treaty on this piece of land was abolished
Assuming that you can make the territory return to its original state
Isn't the territory in the hands of the F country now?
How do you return to its original state?
So this is to say
Because it is based on the principle of legal stability
So like this
You have already
The territory has been partitioned
You can't say
Because you restore today
That is to say
This treaty
The previous treaty was abolished
Then restore to its original state
and so
After the Maguan Treaty was abolished
Then Taiwan and Hong Kong
Returned to the Republic of China
This statement
It's not correct in law
It doesn't make sense in international law
But this is one of the sayings of the Republic of China
And then in 1954
The Republic of China signed with the United States
Sino-US Joint Transparency Treaty
What about the treaty?
It was abolished on March 3
March 3 next year
Article 2 of the Treaty
Taiwan and Penghu are listed as
Territory controlled by the Republic of China
In the English version, it is Territory
In fact, Territory is mainly in this place
Is a region controlled by a regime
In the Chinese version, it is translated as territory
This is a hint of sovereignty
In fact, the Republic of China
Do things like this in many places
In fact, it's just a field
Just say where you actually control
It's not about sovereignty
Sovereignty belongs to you
But the Republic of China
He will do it in translation
Then make you feel
Yeah, does that mean sovereignty?
Belongs to the Republic of China
In fact, the United States is also very clear about this
So they are in
The Senate approved the treaty and said directly
This treaty
Will not change the status of Taiwan's legal status
Uncertain state
On December 5, 1971
The United Nations General Assembly resolution
The Republic of China regime
Listed as a representative of the Republic of China
But this resolution did not mention
Taiwan and Penghu belong to
Then expelled from the United Nations
Is the regime of the Republic of China
Not Taiwan
So someone said
Taiwan withdrew from the United Nations
This is not the case
Because Taiwan has never been
Never entered the United Nations
The Republic of China entered the United Nations in 1945
Then the Republic of China
At that time he was China
Because at that time
The regime of the People's Republic of China did not exist
Is the regime of the Republic of China
Is the government of the Republic of China
Then in 1972
On September 29, Japan changed
The regime of the People's Republic of China is the government of China
So he did not memorize the Sino-Japanese Treaty
In this case
For Japan
Taiwan and Penghu residents are no longer regarded as citizens of the Republic of China
But residents under the Taiwan Autonomous Region
In fact, this later
Extended all the way to
Just recently
We have heard some news
That is, like Japan
Now Taiwan is in Japan
If he wants to register
Or what other registration
His birthplace
Something like that
You can write Taiwan directly now
Instead of writing China
So this concept
Just came out
OK
Then in 1979
On January 1, the United States changed
The regime of the People's Republic of China is the government of China
On April 10, the same year
Taiwan Relations Act was signed
Expired on January 1, 1979
But the purpose is to maintain
Non-official relations between the United States and Taiwan Penghu residents
Then it also admitted that
The United States originally recognized the Republic of China
This thing
Now it's the Taiwan Autonomous Region
And this Autonomous Region can be replaced
Look at the part of Jinma
This award is
The point is that these places
Jinma has always been the coast island of mainland China
Then he is different from the legal status of Taiwan Penghu
Because the biggest difference is
Never been cut
Then there is no
This one behind
The dispute on the territorial settlement treaty
So Jinmen Mazu
It's always the territory of China
Then the UK is the same
Can I ask a question?
Just go back to the Sino-Japanese Treaty
I agree with your point
You said that the defeated country
Because he surrendered
So he signed the treaty
Then put the original
The original territory
Must give up
Transfer to
Give up this territory
That means
This territory will be returned to
Originally he
Occupied that country
I agree
But my question is
If according to this logic
Why did Japan sign the Sino-Japanese Treaty with the Republic of China?
When he signed the treaty
He is with all
The 48 countries that won
All signed
I said I gave up Taiwan Pengjin
I give up every one
With the United States
With France
He has such a clause
Or he is only
For the Sino-Japanese Treaty signed with the Republic of China
He also mentioned
I give up the sovereignty of Taiwan Pengjin
Then in the treaty
There is already
Including Japan's abandonment of Taiwan Pengjin
Part
So he is now
Between Japan and the Republic of China
In addition
This thing is because of China
Because at that time
China because of the issue of representative rights
So there is no way to sign
Sino-Japanese Treaty
But the war between China and Japan
Still have to end
So Japan is with
The Chinese representative government he recognized
Signed this Sino-Japanese Treaty
There is a very important part in this
Is to say
Is the part about Taiwan and Pengjin
That part about Taiwan and Pengjin
He is here
Especially with the Republic of China
Signed this thing
To say OK
Both sides admit
Japan has been in the Sino-Japanese Treaty
Did you give up this part of the sovereignty?
That's it
So actually it should be said
That is to say, for Japan
He is with all the countries
About Taiwan and Pengjin
Part of the territory
The conditions are the same
It's all Japan
Gave up the sovereignty of Taiwan Pengjin
It's all the same thing here
I have a
I have a metaphor, OK?
Because I think you are
It seems to make sense
But there is a little bit of no sense
I said it was a common sense
Suppose there is a pair
There is a
There is a person who went to rob
A robbed B's child
And then a few years later
B retaliated
Then B
He has a bigger fist
He won the war
And now
He wants to deal with this now
The thing about the kid who was robbed
He signed a contract
Then according to your statement
It's a bit like A signed
Signed this contract with B
In the contract
He just said he gave up this kid
He didn't say this kid
Must belong to B
I think you gave me this
The logic of the deduction is like that
So what I mean is
So why did he follow
So the first thing is
He signed this thing with B
A and B have such behavior
Is a
A has been established in a
Under a very special relationship
The two of them will do it again
A contract like this
No, there is no special relationship
Because in fact they are all
They are all
There is a war with Japan
So for Japan
He just wants to solve this problem
So I have to sign this
Basically
The content of the Sino-Japanese Treaty
Originally
Basically the Sino-Japanese Treaty
I think
Let's leave this question
Let's discuss it in the last Q&A
Because this is more like a question of interpretation
This is not an objective fact
Just answer it
Because I think
In fact, the objective fact is also very simple
Basically
For Japan
Sino-Japanese Treaty
Why did he sign this thing
Because actually the original Sino-Japanese Treaty
The original draft is not like this
The original content of the Sino-Japanese Treaty
In fact, it is not much different from the Sino-Japanese Treaty
But then I found out
Why repeat these things
Because in the Sino-Japanese Treaty
Article 26
It directly says that Japan
In the Sino-Japanese Treaty
For example, within two years
You can sign with other countries
That is, the content of the treaty is consistent
Some other contracts that are similar to the content of the treaty
To end the state of war between each other
So for Japan
He signed this with the Republic of China
Because Japan is not only signed with the Republic of China
He also signed with India
And with
And some other countries
Also signed contracts
But when signing these contracts
In fact, it is
It's like adding up
Some of the things in the Sino-Japanese Treaty
So for Japan
He just didn't sign the Sino-Japanese Treaty
Or signed the Sino-Japanese Treaty
But no approved countries
In addition to signing the treaty
And then go
Officially confirm the state of war between each other
That's it
That
The current situation is that
Because now there is a point
Japan signed with the Republic of China today
This thing
With Japan
He signed in the Sino-Japanese Treaty
He just said
I have already made it very clear
China also admitted
This is the arrangement of the Sino-Japanese Treaty
Republic of China
He also admitted
This is how the Sino-Japanese Treaty is handled
He can't do it here
Further processing
In fact, it is the Republic of China
I admit
That's it
The result is like this
I can't handle it anymore
Because Japan and the Republic of China
He can't sign anything else
Because Japan has given up
In fact, he has given up
He just told the Republic of China
He told the Republic of China
I have given up these things
You can't ask me for anything anymore
I can't give you anything
So the Republic of China said
OK, I admit
I admit that you have given up here
OK
I can't ask you for anything
You can't give me anything anymore
In Japan
Through this form
Off the hook
For example
Yes, I am already in the Sino-Japanese Treaty
I have already given up on the sovereignty of Taiwan
To the world
Then
It's not my business anymore
None of my business
Then I signed with the Republic of China today
Make it clear
Although this place is now occupied
But I have already said
I have already given up on this thing
I have already given up
It's none of my business
You can't ask me for anything
So this is actually the effect of the Sino-Japanese Treaty
That is
This kind of blood
Is to let China
The Republic of China can't do anything with Japan
The Republic of China can only admit
OK
It's over like this
The situation is like this
In fact, the Republic of China also thinks
The status of Taiwan is not necessarily better
It's not because of the Sino-Japanese Treaty
Signed like this
Then I felt
Taiwan is like this
Then I went back to him again
Of course
How he talks to the Taiwanese
That's another thing
But the Republic of China is very clear about this
OK
That
So I say this conclusion
This part of Taiwan and Penghu
This is the first place in the law
The ownership of sovereignty is not decided
Does not belong to any country
But this is also special
Taiwan and Penghu are basically
Basically speaking
Before giving up in Japan
Sovereignty belongs to Japan
But it is the colonial territory of Japan
So basically speaking
After World War II
The so-called international consensus
The colonial territory is basically
To give the people of the colonial territory the right to self-determination
So from this perspective
Taiwan and Penghu
In its original status as a colonial territory
He has the right
Taiwanese citizens have the right to decide to return
That part of China
The regime of the Republic of China did not get it
The People's Republic of China regime
So he can't claim
By inheriting the Republic of China
To obtain this sovereignty
Some people claim that Taiwan and Penghu
Sovereignty now belongs to the United States
But the United States is just one of the allies
There is no international document
Hand Taiwan's sovereignty over to the United States
So there is no such thing
Someone else said
Taiwan's sovereignty now belongs to the allies
This is also a joke
because
The allied forces only carry out military occupation authorization
That's the same thing in the Sino-Taiwan Treaty
Japan just gave up
Did not say that the sovereignty was transferred to the allied forces
So Taiwan and Penghu sovereignty
It will not belong to the allied forces
Someone else said
Taiwan's sovereignty belongs to the people of Taiwan
But in fact, territorial sovereignty
Only the country can claim
and so
Can't mix with national sovereignty
The current status of self-determination is
The Republic of China regime
Under the authorization of the allied forces
Established occupation self-government institutions
Taiwan's own authorities
Occupying
In governance
That allied force established
The Republic of China established this occupation self-government institution
At first it was the so-called Taiwan Provincial Executive Office
Later it became the Taiwan Provincial Government
Then later
Because of a series of new provinces
After the Dong Province and the Jin Province
The main functions and roles
Basically
Have been taken over by the central government of the Republic of China regime
So we see
It was originally the Taiwan Province
The so-called Taiwan Province of the Republic of China
Later, Taipei City became the Executive Office
The Executive Yuan directly managed
Later, Kaohsiung City came out
And now it has become a six-capital city
That basically
Some of these from the Executive Yuan of the Republic of China
These so-called Executive Offices
Basically equal to the Republic of China
It has taken all its governance
In their own hands
The Taiwan Provincial Government
Basically speaking
Already
Degraded
And now
The personnel has been reorganized to the National Development and Reform Commission
So in fact, the whole Taiwan
Now the whole governance
It's the Republic of China regime itself
In operation
OK
That's basically the part of the Ma group
The rule of law has always been China
What about the governance part?
It's the Republic of China regime
It's the Chinese regime
One of the two major regimes
China
The Republic of China regime
Now it is governed
So that's the way it is
That is
To show off
It's China
It's two regimes
The two regimes have their own jurisdiction
Different ranges
These are all belong to
Mainland China
Hong Kong and Macau
The Ma group is the so-called Chinese territory
The part of the sovereign territory
That's another piece
It is the Allied Forces that authorizes the Republic of China regime
Establish the Allied Forces Occupation Organization
Then come to govern
Taiwan and Penghu
That is currently the status of the sovereign
That governance
The power comes from the Allied Forces
All the way down
That is to say
The Allied Forces were the victors
The victor
The victor is the loser
Occupy the territory
And then because of the loser
After giving up the territory
but
The final disposal of its territory is not certain
So people still maintain
A state of continued management
So this is the current legal status
Of course this is my research
That
Maybe someone has other different opinions
But basically
This is from me
I personally from the perspective of international law
The results of my research
OK
Then
Taiwan is a country
In fact, this statement
Some people think it is already
Some people say that in 1949
Taiwan is already a country
but
This is a problem
That is to say
At that time, Taiwan's sovereignty was still Japan
How do you use Taiwan to build a country
This is a very strange thing
Another year
On October 25, 1971
Also represented China in the United Nations
So if you say you built a country in 1949
That one
If it's not China
How do you represent China in the United Nations
And another thing is
With him
Build a country with China
Still regard it as China
At least before October 25, 1971
The United States was before 1979
Right?
Still think
It represents China
It's all China
Then there are people who claim that
After giving up because of Japan
Taiwan
Then it becomes an unoccupied territory
So you can occupy an unoccupied territory
Then it becomes its territory
But now there is a problem
That is to say
On the International Law
For the so-called unoccupied land
There is a strict requirement
Now the so-called unoccupied land
It is the so-called uninhabited island that can claim to occupy the unoccupied land
Or no one
Long-term residence
That place
That place will become
Unoccupied land
Appropriate object
Then we know that
In fact, Taiwan and Penghu
In fact, there are millions of people on it for a long time
Millions of people now live on it
Then there are social
Social life
Organized operation
There is economic life
So it won't be
It won't be an uninhabited island
So you can't use it
The sovereignty of the unoccupied land
The Republic of China regime
Has not yet announced the establishment of a new country
So it's all the same
Same as above
It's all the same in the United Nations
Some people say that in 1971
The Republic of China was kicked out of the United Nations
After the founding of the country
This is also very interesting
In fact, it is still the same
It has never been announced
Has not yet announced the establishment of a new country
Then
In fact, the Republic of China regime in 1979
After being kicked out of the United Nations
The so-called Republic of China
In fact, there are many countries
Admit that he is the representative of China
Right
Like the United States
It was only changed in 1979
Panama
It was only over in 2017
Right
So there are many countries
Think he is the Chinese regime
So he never established
A new country that is different from China
Never did this thing
It's all the same
Then someone else said
In 1996
The presidential election of the Republic of China regime
So the founding of the country
This is also very interesting
Still the same
The same questions are all the same
Another one is
The candidate did not say
Announce the establishment of a new country
In 1996
The presidential election of the Republic of China regime
Li Denghui was elected
Li Denghui
At that time, the Chinese Kuomintang was the chairman
Then we all know that the Chinese Kuomintang
Is a regime that advocates unification
So the chairman of a regime that advocates unification
Elected president
How could you
Because he elected the president
Then establish a country
This is also incomprehensible
The other point is
You can't choose
The president of the A country to establish the B country
Is there such an example in history?
Then someone else said
The Chinese Kuomintang did not work before
Then change to the Democratic Party
Then someone said
In 2000, 2004, Chen Shui-bian was elected
Basically the same as before
Chen Shui-bian was elected
He did not advocate the establishment of a new country
The other important thing is
In 2008, Ma Ying-jeou was elected president
If today
Chen Shui-bian elected the president of the Republic of China
He will represent the establishment of the Republic of Taiwan
Today, when Ma Ying-jeou was elected president
What about the previous Republic of Taiwan?
Is there such a thing as extinction?
So this is a very strange statement
It is impossible for you to say
Which one to choose
To be the leader of a certain regime
To establish another country
That is incomprehensible
Then someone said
Because there is no complete governance
So Chen Shui-bian has no complete governance
So that doesn't count
In 2016, Tsai Ing-wen took over
Taiwan is the same
It's all the same in front
These are all the same problems
Have appeared
In addition, by taking over
To establish another country
There is no potential
Then this is what I just said
Panama changed its name to the People's Republic of China regime
The Ministry of Foreign Affairs of the People's Republic of China is still talking about
The two countries are more than a century apart
So even if Tsai Ing-wen's regime
Tsai Ing-wen as president
This regime of the People's Republic of China
He is still
The same relationship with other countries
All the way back to China
Relations with other countries
So it won't be another country
So Taiwan is not a country yet
Then this situation is more direct
For example, the so-called diplomatic countries of the People's Republic of China
This is Fan Ligang
There is that website below
This is actually
On the official website of Fan Ligang
The national flag of the People's Republic of China is written on the side of China
Now many people say this is the national flag of Taiwan
Then another example is Honduras
It's the same
China
Taiwan is written behind
What does Taiwan mean?
Is China equal to Taiwan?
China on Taiwan
China in Taiwan
I don't know
China is in Taiwan
China is Taiwan
I don't know
He used this form to express
Then another like Guatemala
It's the same
He also wrote like this
So this is actually
You know he
Taiwan's current state
Other countries
Even the diplomatic countries of the People's Republic of China
When dealing with Taiwan
He still has no way
Take the piece of China
So if you want to say
Taiwan is already
A sovereign independent country
That has nothing to do with the country
You will find that in fact
Not so much
OK
In the future
What should I do?
How to build
Actually I want to say
Sorry
We can end
In Taiwan's current history
Is the current international law positioning?
Because it's too long
Yes
OK
Then let's go back
You just wrote a line of red paper
Taiwan is not a country now
This page is good
OK
Sorry
I want to interrupt you
Because today is really too long
I think this is a very conclusive conclusion
Just take away
Based on international law
Taiwan is not a country now
If we have a chance
You can
We are looking for you to talk about this
The last part
That is
I'm sorry
It's okay
This thing is really
I originally wanted to
It's complicated
I originally wanted to cut it short
I found out
It seems to be impossible
OK
Before we start asking questions
Still the same
Please turn on the microphone
Then we applaud again
Thank you, Shen Feng
Thank you
OK
Do you have any questions?
Or comment?
Because I just interrupted
There may be one or two questions
That can be discussed now
Does anyone want to mention it?
That Sino-Japanese contract
Yes, but he
Because after he finished asking
It's been a long time
Maybe there is an answer
Let's just ask
Who else has any questions now?
Do you want to mention it?
Just based on
After listening to everything
Is there anyone who wants to ask a question?
OK
That means today's speech
I can ask
OK
You say
In fact, it is
In the count
Two
PowerPoint
I already have a little lost
You are here
For example, on this PowerPoint
It says
Is Taiwan already a country?
Your Taiwan here
This territory
The people on this territory
Republic of China government
Democratic Progressive Party government
What is Taiwan here?
This Taiwan
In fact, it is not
Democratic Progressive Party government
Those things
But just say
Now in Taiwan
Is this piece
Taiwan
With the island of Taiwan
With the surrounding area
With
Penghu Islands
On this piece
These lands
With the group
The group of people above
With the above
The current governance
That regime
With this
Wrap it up like this
This piece
This thing
Is it a country?
Is this territory
This people
This above
Governance
Government
This government
This regime
I'm not talking about the government
Is the governing regime above
Will he
Is he
Is it
Can this be regarded as a country?
Is it a country?
Is it a country on the international community?
Then you think
It's not a country
The reason is because of this territory
And the people above
Still undetermined
The territory is undetermined
Because the territory belongs
Which country does it belong to?
Unknown
The territory is undetermined
Then above this
Republic of China regime
Above this
Republic of China regime itself
He is the Chinese regime
If he says today
If it is to be determined
If it is a country
He is also a
He is just China
He won't be
And there is no
China with air sovereignty
Because
Air sovereignty does not belong to any country
So even if he is a country
Republic of China regime
Even if it's a country
He is also in China
As a fugitive government
In Taiwan
Because
The country he represents is China
Not Taiwan
Because
Taiwan and Penghu's sovereignty
Does not belong to him
Of course, Taiwan and Penghu
Is being governed by him
That's right
but
He is not
His territorial scope
Does not include Taiwan and Penghu
So now this
A state
That is to say, Taiwan and Penghu
Now govern his
That regime
Does not have
He is not a
A country
As a government
To govern
He is not a
A territorial form
He is just a
Manager role
And his role as a manager
Is
In 1945
Under the auspices of the Allied Forces
What happened
So now the situation is
I'm talking about this part of Taiwan now
The main thing is
The part of the land and the people
The regime above
Because of his
Chinese regime
And China
Never got
Air sovereignty
This matter
Will become
He has no way
With Taiwan and Penghu
This part
Just become a country
Because
There is no territorial relationship between the two
He is a
Actually in
A state of governance
That
There is another one here
That participant has a question
But in
I'll ask him later
Because he is typing
But before asking
I have a little comment
To tell everyone
Just
I want to use
Shen Feng and Kiki's conversation
As an example
Project Taira's purpose
Is to make it possible
In different parts of the world
Because Kiki is actually in California now
Shen Feng is in Edinburgh
I personally think
You can have a good conversation
From different points of view
Create a good study of Taiwan
That
Because I happen to know both of them
So if you need
Leave the other party's contact information
You can ask me
Or
On Project Taira's website
There should be members
A personal page
Can find a way to contact
Then I really strongly
You should continue to communicate
Ok
This is my comment
Sorry
What is the direct relationship with the researcher
But
This Liu
He is Liu
Say
That old national law
How can Taiwan and Penghu be considered a country?
If Taiwan and Penghu finally broke up with the Republic of China regime
Do you have to break up with Jinma?
Then I think this is
The part I just cut off
right
Yes yes yes
Please continue
Pick a few
Just for this question
See how you answer
Ok
Then we will
Take a look
So you see
This thing still wants to talk about it
Ok good
That means everyone is very interested in this topic
Yes yes yes
Because the key is here
You know the current state
Of course you want to solve the problem
right
This is very normal
Anyway
Actually
How does Taiwan become a country?
In fact, I am talking now
You want to be a country
Your purpose is to become one
Recognized by the international community
A political entity that is willing to recognize the status of a country
So the point is
You have to follow the rules of international law
Don't give birth to some other weird things yourself
Ok
That is to say, like these
What I just talked about
Those
What I listed before
All the way to 2016
What is the previous administration
These international law
No potential
So basically it doesn't make sense
What else
There are some
Prove self-reliance
Self-reliance
These are all
All involve the constitution
I think it's from the constitution or the name
This is what I said at the beginning
There are some national characteristics
How do you change it
It won't change its essence
So today
No matter how you change your name
No matter how you make a constitution
It doesn't matter if it's abolished
Will not affect the Chinese regime of the Republic of China
Taiwan is not a country yet
You can't build a country through constitution
You have to build a country first and then constitution
The other point is
Taiwan's strength
Of course there is no way to make international rules by yourself
So it's according to the rules
According to international rules
In the international rules
There are rules in international law
One is the right of self-determination
So the right of self-determination
The constitution of the United Nations
Then the civil rights
Civil rights and political rights
International Convention
Economic, social, cultural rights
All mentioned the right of self-determination
For Taiwan
The most important part is to decolonize
Because I mentioned earlier
Taiwan is the former colony of Japan
In fact, in principle
Taiwan as a former colony
It should be
Under the context of decolonization
The right of self-determination
And then build your own country
In the U.N. Congress
In fact, the U.N. Constitution itself
It has
There is a direct regulation
To this decolonization part
Decolonization is the U.N.
One of the main goals in the Constitution
In addition, the U.N. Convention
It also mentions
No. 1 and No. 4
Say
In the non-intellectual territory of the territory of the jurisdiction
Or other
Without reaching the territory of independence
Steps must be taken
Then everyone
Help these democracies
Be able to enjoy complete independence and freedom
So this is also the right of self-determination
The part of the U.N. Convention
In the other U.N. Convention
No. 1, 5, 4, 1
It mentions
When the right of self-determination is exercised
Non-intellectual territory
That's what it says
In order to achieve independence
These parts of the territory
Can be achieved in the following way
Complete self-determination
First, become a sovereign independent country
Second, become an independent country
Or join an independent country
The so-called sovereign independent country
Needless to say
Just become a country
In addition, become an independent country
This one
In fact, you are also a country
It's just that you may have some rights
Some rights on sovereignty
You just give it to other countries
Help you to execute
For example, like
The United States used to have some
According to the U.N. Convention
Regulations on deportation
Then give it to the U.S.
Some of the Pacific Islands
Some islands
After they became independent
They decided to be
To become a free party in the United States
That is to say, they put some rights
Just give it to the U.S.
Maybe it's the diplomatic part
Maybe it's the military part
They might even be
Use the U.S. dollar
Something like this
But these countries themselves still have
These still have national rights
The other one is to become an independent country
So for Taiwan
The choice after that is
In fact, it is in the context of colonization
Execute self-determination
When it comes to self-determination
There are these options
If Taiwan wants to become a country
That is, when it comes to self-determination
Choose to become a sovereign independent country
What about the current state?
In fact, it is important to say
First define Taipeng as
We are now under the arrangement of the Allied Forces
Members of the Allied Forces
For the Allied Forces
The occupation of the occupation
Occupation in governance
So they belong to
Not yet reached an independent territory
If you go through the UN
If the UN resolution 1514
The UN member states have the obligation
To assist Taiwan in gaining independence
But to be honest
Taiwan has never advocated this way
So we have always advocated
We are already a country
Then ask people to let us join the United Nations
In fact, through the original
I just talked about the United Nations
The right to self-determination mentioned in the Constitution of the United Nations
Then the United Nations
Then the other conventional signatories
They have no reason to deny
Taipeng's right to self-determination
Then you exercise
The right to self-determination is the same as the right to self-determination
In fact, the United Nations member states
There is no way to deny the effect of self-determination
So if Taiwan wants to become a country
In fact, it is very important
You use Taiwan as the host
The identity of the pre-colonial
Then combined with the international
Under the consensus of colonization
Confirm the self-determination of the colony
According to international convention
Then ask the United Nations member states to recognize
This one
I personally think this is the most
The most feasible route
This is definitely more than
Now you claim that Taiwan is already a sovereign independent country
But you are clearly now
It's a Chinese exile regime
Then you said you want to join the United Nations with this identity
Will be more effective than that
Because other countries will see that
You are the Chinese regime
I can't admit you
He is in the People's Republic of China regime
Choose one with the Republic of China regime
OK
So that is to say
In fact, this place just now
In fact, everyone has already talked about it
If you want to enter the United Nations
This is actually
I think there is something
Let me talk a little bit
Entering the United Nations is not the necessary procedure to build a country
Some people say
What does Taiwan have to enter the United Nations
To prove that you are a country
In fact, many countries
I didn't join the United Nations
For example, like Switzerland
I joined the United Nations in 2002
No other country has ever thought that you
Switzerland was not a country before 2002
Right
He is still a country
that
So
You said you want to join the United Nations to build a country
This is not right
You have to build a country first
So
You don't have to join the United Nations after building a country
The basis of this sentence is the International Law
Because this is the question of building a country
But it doesn't matter if you don't build a country and you can't join the United Nations
It has nothing to do with the International Law
It is the rule of the United Nations
No, because the United Nations is
As I said earlier
This is the United Nations
Because the United Nations is an international organization
He himself
The requirement of becoming a member is to be a member
Yes, this is his internal rule
He is not part of the International Law
You have to say he is not part of the International Law
In fact, it should be said
He set such a rule in accordance with the International Law
That is to say, because the United Nations
In fact, it is based on the United Nations
An international organization established by the Constitution
OK
Yes
So we can only talk about it now
We can only talk about it now
That is to say
Members of the international organization
What kind of identity do you need to join
Is the international organization
His
For example, a document like this
How to write in such a document
How to decide
It is not stipulated that this person must be a country
To join the international organization
But this rule
Is the rule of this international organization
It was set out in accordance with the International Law
I see
Ok, that one
Because his question just now is
What should be done to uphold international law
He said it could be
But we are basically talking about
How to become
But basically
He turned out to mean the same
How do you become
How does it count
So you answered the first question
Let's talk about the second question directly
That is
Taipeng broke up with the Republic of China
Do you have to break up with Jinma?
Oh yes
But Jinma
But Jinma, he can
They can also exercise self-determination
What is self-determination
That is
It should be said like this
That is, Taipeng, you can
Can be self-determined
Become a sovereign independent country
Right
What about Jinma
Of course it can
Because I just mentioned it here
What about Jinma
Basically
Taipeng
You follow the international law
Under the context of decolonization
Exercise self-determination
Then establish a sovereign independent country
This is the way Taipeng wants to go
If you want to be a country
This road is
I think
Personally, I think it is the best way
But part of Jinma
Because his sovereignty belongs to China
So what they need to do is
Independent
To separate from China and come out independently
Then separate from China and come out independently
Then you have to have a
Chinese regime
To hold such an independent meeting
So Jinma
He said
Want to
If you want to be with Taiwan and Penghu
That is, Jinma's resident
He followed the regime of the Republic of China
Hold a self-determination meeting there
Then decide whether to be independent from the Republic of China
Then after independence
Then see if he wants to
Become a country here
Or to join
The new country established by Taipeng
This is their choice
But what I have to say is
Jinma people
Do they want to be with Taiwan and Penghu
This is a question mark
This is a big question mark
I think sometimes it is like this
We think they seem to want to be with us
We seem to want us to abandon them
Abandon them or something
But in fact, Jinma people may not think so
They may not think at all
I am Taiwanese
They may
They should basically admit that they are the people of the Republic of China
No problem
The citizens of the Republic of China are OK
But do they think they are Taiwanese?
Do they want to be with Taiwan?
This is sometimes a question mark
Because you see some news
Jinma people seem
They seem to think they are Chinese
The ratio is higher
Of course we have opened the way for everyone
There is a way to go in international law
They hold an independent meeting
See if they want to be independent from China
Then move to another country
They can do
The other point is that if
Jinma people
They can't get through the independent meeting
Let Jinma become
Taipeng
Become the same country as Taipeng
His people
He can also be planned
Become the citizens of this new country
In fact, many Jinma
Jinma people
They are actually living on the island of Taiwan now
May be there to get married and have children
Then buy a house or something
So for them
Maybe most of the time they are in Taiwan
Maybe they think
Maybe it will become the citizens of Taipeng
No problem
If they don't want to
They can also be the people of the Republic of China
Is a foreigner
Continue to stay
In fact, the subsequent disposal
There are legal means
It can be solved
Just
It's just that in international law
If we want to
If you want to deal with this issue
You have to separate
Because there is no way to solve the problem together
If you put it together
You just mix it up
The unsettled
With those who belong to the territory of China
There is no way to do it together
Because when it comes to processing
The rules are different
So you have to deal with it
Must be divided
But will it be together in the end?
That depends on
I would think
It depends on the wishes of the Kinmen people
I don't know if they want to be with Taiwan
OK
So for the second question
Basically the answer is the first
Yes
Have to break up with Kinmen
The second is
But Kinmen can be based on
Is the context of decolonization
Make their own self-awareness
Kinmen is not the context of decolonization
Because Kinmen has not been colonized
OK
Kinmen they
Because they are independent
They are directly separated and independent
Taiwan and Penghu
Taiwan and Penghu are decolonized
Kinmen is separated and independent
That is to say, separated and independent from China
Just like Scotland
Separated from the United Kingdom
Quebec is separated from Canada
OK
Kinmen independence is such a form
Different from Taiwan
That
Liu said thank you for the detailed explanation of the speaker
Then I think
Come here today
Also cover you
Last
Sorry
The part that was cut off by me
Most of the cut
I just finished talking
OK
Ok
We are here again
Applause
Thank you for the speech brought to us by Saint
It's already two o'clock in the middle of the night over there
Thank you very much
Thank you
That
Everyone is me
I want to stop recording first
But you are welcome to continue discussing
OK