Hello, I'm Ted. I'm very happy to be here today. I'd like to welcome Chen Junjia from the University of Amsterdam.
This is his last year at Pomeranian. Yay!
I've known him since he was in university. He's also a student at the Electrical Engineering Department.
I'm very happy to have someone with me to talk about physics.
Junjia is studying Atomic Physics.
I've done a little bit of it in the beginning, but it's a lot different from what I did in IELTS and BEC.
I think BEC is very cool in physics.
You've been in this field for over 20 years now, right? How long have you been in BEC?
It's been over 20 years since 1995.
Yeah, okay.
But it's been a long time since people wanted to do it. It was only made in 1995.
Junjia's topic for today is Steady-State Ultracold Cesium Near Quantum Degeneracy.
He's talking about the application in CW atom lasers and clocks.
His lab is one of the latest quantum flagships in Europe.
So maybe we can hear some new things and see what Europe plans to do in this area.
I won't say much more. Junjia, please get ready to start your speech.
Thank you.
First of all, I'd like to thank Jianyuan for giving me the opportunity to introduce the topic I'm doing.
First of all, I'd like to make a correction. What I'm doing is Strontium, not Cesium.
Strontium is a 2A element.
The purpose of our experiment is, as I said in the title, to achieve a steady-state.
In principle, the ultimate goal is to achieve a continuous atomic laser.
Of course, before you reach that ultimate goal, you have to reach the Bose-Einstein connection in the first phase.
This is something that hasn't been achieved yet.
In principle, our lab hopes to challenge it.
As I mentioned in the title, the ultimate goal is to achieve a steady-state.
In principle, we are already very close to quantum degeneracy.
Of course, we haven't reached it yet.
But in principle, I will briefly report on our current progress.
Of course, I will also mention some applications of CW, Atom Laser, and CLOX on the technology we have developed.
The title is of course our lab, our overall experimental setup.
Let's take a look.
Of course, we have a step on the experiment.
In principle, we have used some of the cooling mechanisms of CISPOS.
I will briefly introduce it in the next speech.
First of all, this is the outline of my talk today.
I will briefly explain who we are, where we are, and why we want to do these things.
Next, I will briefly mention the technologies we use, such as laser cooling and BEC.
In principle, I will mention two applications that I am more interested in.
Atomic clock and atomic interferometer.
I will introduce STROMCM.
In principle, I will also introduce the so-called laser cooling STROMCM to Bose-SanSan condensate.
Next, I will introduce our entire experimental setup.
The three main results are, for example, Ultra High Phase Space Density MOD.
And how do we achieve the principle of Steady State Unity Phase Space Density.
Next, of course, I will introduce one of the cooling technologies we have developed, CISPOS Optical Lattice Decelerator.
Next, I will give Outlook.
First of all, let me introduce myself.
My master's thesis was originally done in Taiwan.
My master's thesis experiment.
In principle, my experiment is to achieve a full optical Rubidium Bose-SanSan condensate.
It is also because of this factor that I am interested in laser cooling.
So when I applied for a doctorate class,
Because when I was a soldier, the English exam preparation was not going well.
For example, I did not pass the TOEFL exam.
Then I thought I would come to Europe to do it.
At that time, I read some papers when I was studying in the master's class.
I know that there is a good team in Innsbruck, Australia.
At that time, I thought I would try to apply.
Then I applied to Rudy Green's lab.
At that time, the group I applied to was originally a strong team.
But then my little boss,
In principle, it is our actual boss, Florian.
He later applied for a teaching position to move to Amsterdam.
So I will come to Amsterdam to do it.
There is a very interesting historical source in Amsterdam.
This person is called Joke Worven.
In principle, at the beginning of BC,
When you want to achieve the Bose-Einstein condensation,
Ordinary people have not yet considered the elements of the EA group.
They want to achieve the Bose-Einstein condensation in hydrogen.
Joke Worven, in principle, his lab in Amsterdam
Is to do hydrogen cooling.
Then I want to achieve the Bose-Einstein condensation.
So, in principle, we have some in Amsterdam.
This kind of laser cooling historical source is right.
Of course, we moved from Australia to Amsterdam.
It's also a toss.
In principle, this is our good team in Amsterdam.
First of all, let me introduce what Bose-Einstein condensation is.
We all know that in principle, W1 material,
In principle, you can have the nature of the wave,
You can also have the nature of the particles.
Of course, it depends on your temperature conditions.
To determine some of the characteristics of your wave field.
Of course, we know that under higher temperature conditions,
In principle, O-nitrogen behaves more like a particle.
When the temperature drops,
The relationship between W1 and O-nitrogen tells you that
Its wavelength will gradually increase.
Then you start to use some fluctuations
To describe some of the behavior of your particles.
Of course, the closer you get to your condensation temperature,
The wavelength of your O-nitrogen starts to overlap.
Then you are more and more unable to tell the particles.
Finally, of course, in theory,
When T equals zero, you will reach a so-called
Bose-Einstein condensation state.
The picture is basically tested by the MIT team in 1997.
That is to say, they realized that
Let two Bose-Einstein condensations interfere.
In the experiment, of course, they first realized a Bose-Einstein condensation.
They divided an O-nitrogen into two.
So in the end, two Bose-Einstein condensations were formed.
Then they let it interfere.
Then you will see a very obvious
Interference of the particle wave.
After BC was realized,
First of all, it is a particle wave.
If it is a particle wave,
In the experiment, of course, they will think
It's like a laser.
They tried to achieve some
Demonstration of particle laser.
You can think of it as
In principle, it is an optical cavity.
All the atoms are in a so-called cavity mode.
You try to get this particle wave
After the particle wave comes out of the cavity,
In principle, they realized some of these particle lasers.
Of course, the current technology in the experiment
In principle, it can only achieve
There is no way to achieve a continuous particle laser.
In principle, you want to achieve a continuous particle laser.
Of course, you need some
You have to achieve some first.
First of all, you have to have a continuous BC.
To achieve a continuous BC,
You have to have some continuous cooling technology.
Continuous evaporative cooling
Or some continuous trap loading
In principle, many people in the past 20 years
Try to realize it.
Of course, in the end, they still haven't achieved
The ultimate goal is a continuous particle laser.
In principle, this is still a very difficult thing.
The reason why it is so difficult is because
For example, the conditions for BC to be realized
In principle, we all look at this so-called optical cavity density.
You can think of it as
For the water in the fish tank
Under low temperature conditions
It may have already thawed.
In principle, in the process of cooling
Its density conditions may already
There is no way to achieve the so-called
To achieve the state of BC condensation
First of all, we know that BC condensation
It has this optical cavity density
It has to reach the condition of greater than 2.6
Its degree of freedom depends on the relationship with temperature.
So we know that first of all, my density has to be high enough.
Then my temperature has to be low enough.
But under conditions of high density
Assuming that your density is too high
In principle, the atom will have a so-called
Loss mechanism
In principle, it is a so-called three-body recombination.
It will form molecules
In principle, it is a
Do you understand?
In principle, it is a loss mechanism.
We know that in principle
The density is almost on this scale.
It is 10 to the 14th square
So it means that your density cannot be too high.
If it is too high, your three-body recombination
In principle, your atoms will form molecules.
So your density is almost controlled at 10 to the 14th square.
That gives a contrast
In principle, in your air
In principle, your density is almost 10 to the 19th square.
So you can say
In principle, we are doing cold matter
When the cold atom is studied
The density of the atom group we are talking about
In principle, it is thin
It's 10 to the 14th square.
To reach this Bc condition
Its corresponding temperature is almost at this level.
1μK to 10 nK level
This is a very cold principle.
That is to say
That's why it's called an ultracold atom.
Because it compares with other temperature scales.
Our cold atom is almost in this range.
Compared with other Earth's room temperature conditions
300K here
We are at about 7 or 8 numbers
A temperature condition below
The current realization
In principle, it is because of the restriction of cooling technology.
We can only achieve the so-called
The so-called Maltese-Boson condensation
You need to have the first stage of laser cooling in the experimental technology.
Then evaporate the cooling
When you reach Bc
You try to put the atom group inside
After the alcohol comes out
Of course, you will later
After using up the atom group in the trap
Then you have to do another experiment.
Re-create the Boson condensation
So on the experimental technology
You can only achieve the so-called Maltese-Boson condensation.
Of course, the continuous Boson condensation
Or continuous material laser
Has always been in the field
A goal that everyone wants to achieve
But even after 20 years of effort
There is still no way to achieve it.
Has not been achieved yet
Of course, we use laser cooling in the experiment.
Then I will briefly explain
Some mechanisms of laser cooling
First of all, the atom
First, we know that the atom interacts with the light.
Take a look
Sorry
First of all, the atom is electrically activated.
There is a principle
Resonant light
It absorbs a light corresponding to the quantum frequency.
The atom will be activated
Then there will be a transfer of momentum
Of course, after releasing the light back to the atom
There will be a transfer of momentum
The principle of laser cooling is based on this mechanism
To interact with the atom through light
To do a deceleration action
Of course on the experimental level
Through this mechanism
We want to take the atom from
For example, this is our source
You throw a piece of metal into the oven
Heat it up
It will be vaporized
Of course, vapor pressure corresponds to
For example, you heat it up
For example, on our experiment, we put it at 500 Kelvin.
So it's basically
Sorry, 500 degrees C
Then it will have a corresponding 500 degrees C
The speed distribution of Boltzmann distribution
How to interact with the atom through light
To decelerate this speed distribution
In principle, on the experiment
We also use a so-called Zeeman Slower
Zeeman Slower is mainly through
Atomic under magnetic field conditions
It is a connection to the magnetic field
Change
On the principle of our laser
In the picture, you see the principle
On the experiment, we will go around a circle
Create a T-magnetic field
This T-magnetic field
It corresponds to
When my light and atom are in this position
Corresponding magnetic field
It creates
It meets the conditions
It interacts with the atom
It has a momentum shift
It decelerates
So the atom is decelerated
Then in the next position
Because my magnetic field has a T-magnetic field change
I'm in the next position
My magnetic field conditions
To find a way to maintain this
Light and atom interaction
Under constant conditions
My atom group
After this Zeeman Slower
After a deceleration
In principle, in the back
Can put my entire atom group
Its speed distribution
That is to say, a deceleration action
The principle of this experiment is
The overall experimental structure
For example, I have an oven
Is my heating
Heat the metal block
Area of ​​generating steam pressure
Then this is my Zeeman Slower
Then finally
I want to be in this place
Do a state of atom capture
This is just a general
A standard
A pulse-injection-like
I'm just making an example now
Let's take a look
In the experiment, of course, we finally
Is in
Do an atom capture
Let's take a look
Sorry, don't jump
That just said
After the atom capture
The technology used in the atom capture
For example, the last area
Will put the so-called six lasers
Six lasers in space
In principle, you can put
Atomic group in all directions
Do a deceleration action
Of course, in the experiment
We add a magnetic field
To be able to do a so-called
Spatial confinement
Then I'm here in principle
Just skip it first
In the principle of laser cooling
In the next step
It is necessary to enter the evaporation cooling
The reason is because
In the process of laser cooling
Your laser cooling will have a so-called
Laser cooling corresponds to a
Cooling temperature limit
The cooling temperature limit
Mainly you can understand it as
When all your atoms
After being cooled
It will get higher and higher
But because
You are absorbing the cooling light
The next step is to release the cooling light
Release a spontaneous emission
Then the light released
Because the density of the atomic group is very high now
It may be further
It's a bit like heating the atoms around you
The reason is because the density is very high now
So it corresponds to a
Laser cooling corresponds to a
Cooling temperature limit
So in principle
At the end of the experiment
After this laser cooling step
Will do an evaporation cooling action
The evaporation cooling action
General technology now
Of course there is the so-called magnetic field
Is to put the atomic group
Put it in a magnetic track
Or light
Did you use light in the experiment?
Let me explain a little bit
What is the overall mechanism of light?
We all know that the atom
There will be one in the power plant
Will be polarized
Then this
It will have a spontaneous
Electric dipole
In principle
Suppose I use light today
To produce a so-called
AC electric field
Then my atom in principle
Will be
Induced dipole moment
In principle, its power plant is produced by light
Then he knows
Because of this
In the light field
Its dipole moment
In principle, it will
Because of the power plant
Sorry
For example, we are using light now
To produce a light field
That light field because
In principle, the light field
I produce this
Trap his
It is determined by its intensity
That is to say, I assume
Today light is a Gaussian beam
It has an intensity distribution
In principle
This dipole moment
To induce
In this light field
For this intensity distribution
You will have the so-called
Assuming
The atom is in the light field
Suppose I have this light today
For it
If I am a
Redshift
It means
I assume my wavelength
Than the wavelength of the light I use
If the wavelength of my atomic quantum frequency
If it's still long
We call it
In principle, it is called
In this light
In principle
This light field is called
Red Dipole Trap
In principle, it is said
My atom will be concentrated
To a higher intensity
Area
Compared to
Assuming the wavelength of the light I use today
If the wavelength is still short
The overall
The characteristic of the light produced is that
My atom will be concentrated
The lower part of the intensity
That
Just a little bit here
Demonstrate
Atomic group
Some interactions with light
In the experiment, of course, we are
After generating the so-called magnetic light
Open my Red Dipole Trap
Then it is
In principle
You will see
The atomic group is
Leaked into the Red Dipole Trap
That
This is just to show that
After opening the Red Dipole Trap
I go
That is
Just open
0 ms
10 ms
20 ms
That my atomic group
One
Atomic group
Leaked into the Red Dipole Trap
One
Behavior like this
In the experiment, of course, we reached
That is to say, the atomic group
Leaked into the light
Then we need to evaporate and cool in the light
That evaporate and cool
The concept is very simple
After the hot atom leaves
Overall
The remaining atoms will go through again
One
Thermalization process
At the end
Of course, the overall temperature will drop
That
Evaporate and cool
Next
When the temperature is getting lower and lower
After reaching the critical temperature
You will see one
Atomic group
The process of phase transformation
That
Here
Is a
At the end
Evaporate and cool
Then the radiation freezes
One
This is a whole
A phase transformation
One
Demonstration
That
In
Evaporate and cool
He
How do you judge
Your substance has passed
Is already
Reached the evaporation and cooling state
That
In the experiment, we will
Through
Uh
For example, I am looking at this
Atomic group behavior
That
For example, we are now
Here is the
Uh release
Then the atomic group will be in the gravity field
It will fall under the conditions
That
Let's do an image action
Atomic group
In principle, it assumes
If it is still thermal gas
He is in
Uh
You will see that in principle it is a
Isotropic expansion
One behavior
That
Assuming he is today
If it reaches the evaporation and cooling state
That
In principle, you will see a
So-called
Anisotropic
Expansion behavior
That this is with
You can understand it
That is to say
Uh
For example, if you have a
Elongated
Cloud
That in
He is in
After you release the
He is in the gravity field
Falling
That
He was originally
Strong
Strong confinement
On the axis
His
He is stronger
So he will
In the process of release
In principle, it will grow faster
He will have
It also leads to
He will have this
So-called
Anisotropic expansion
A phenomenon
That this is
In principle, our
A smoking gun
That is to say
As long as we have reached BC
That in principle
We are going to
Find this
Anisotropic expansion
To determine that we have reached
The state of BC
That of course
BC was realized for the first time
That
Next
In 2001
I got the Nobel Prize
That
So far
Uh
Someone
Have a question
Want to ask
That is to say
I'm just a little bit
Laser cooling
That
So far
Someone has a question
Hello
I want to ask
That
You will be sure
It's you
Inside this
Or your BC
How many
Or how many
For you
Because
Sometimes there will be
He is like
His number should be
It's all changing
Uh
So
I
Uh
Of course
We experiment
For example, you see this picture now
That we are
Do
Uh
Assortment imaging
It's basically
To go back
How many of its atoms are there
Like this
This picture
Uh
Of course I can't guess now
But
Almost
Look at this condition
There are about 10 5-quarters
10 6-quarters
The number of atoms
On the experiment
Of course we will
Will calculate
But
Uh
For example, we are now on the experiment
I want to reach the continuous Bohr's law
Can be imagined
At the beginning
The number you reach
Not so much
It's possible
10 3-quarters
10 4-quarters
So
But he has a corresponding condition
That is to say
Uh
The number
Also with your
The temperature of the ring
It has something to do
That is to say
You have to reach
So many
Uh
Bohr's law
Your
You have a corresponding ring temperature
That's right
So
On our experiment
Of course, we have to find a way
Condition
That is to say
I want my system to be able to
Cold to such a low temperature
That
At that temperature
How much density do I have to reach
To have a way
To cross that
Condition of phase space density
Greater than 2
That is
Uh
N lambda 3-quarters
Greater than 2.6
This condition
In principle
I'm going to adjust this
Density
With temperature
That whole person
To have this
Satisfy this condition
I have a way to
To reach the Bohr's law
So
Uh
I don't know if this answers your question
Hey, it's okay
You go ahead
We
I have some questions later
I'll ask you again
OK
Technical questions
I'll ask you again
Hey, hello
That one
The one in the first video
It's gone
It's your head now
Oh really
Hey
Do you see your desktop
Or am I seeing yours now
OK
I see
It's okay to continue
OK
Uh, I have a question
Let me introduce us
That
OK
Uh, sorry
I just want to ask
That is
Uh
What is it called
That is
You want to produce
CW
The
Bose Einstein Converter
That is
You can let that Bose Einstein Converter
Keep going
So
My question is
That is
Under what circumstances
Why won't it last
OK
How long does it last
How long
Let me find the video
Uh
How long
In principle
On top of time
Is
You mean
It has an infinite duration
What I just said
It has a time limit
That time limit
Yes yes
Yes, that's right
That time limit
In principle
It depends on your experimental technology
You have to go through the laser cooling first
And then the next step
Evaporate and cool
Finally reach the Boltzmann fission
That
But in principle
Your entire system
You will have a
Uh
Loss
Or you're doing atom
Outcouple your atom
Outcouple your atom from your BC
After your atom comes out
That you
In the end
You still use up all the atoms
So that means
You're in the experiment
Re-create the Boltzmann fission
So that's because of this
Restriction, so
In the experiment
You will
You
Your Boltzmann fission
Or your atom laser
Is
There will be a
Uh
It's a soldering
Because you're going to run out of atoms
That experiment
Is to achieve
That is to say
Continuous
Your Boltzmann fission
Boltzmann fission
Continuous
That side
That is to say
He basically
Assuming I
If I keep
What do you mean
If it's
That is
That usually we
The last step is
Outcouple
That BEC
Then you can measure
Correct
That if
You keep outcoupling
That BEC
Just
Won't it be there all the time
Uh
Is because
You have to know
In vacuum
He still has a so-called
Background collision
He
Your
You have a BEC
He's in
Under vacuum
In your
Inside the trap
He will still
There is a
Background collision
A loss caused
In principle
You can imagine
His lifetime
In principle
Under the best vacuum condition
It's about 30 seconds
Uh
After 30 seconds
Your atom
In principle
After a series of
Background collision
In the end
It's gone
So
On the experiment
You have to start again
Re-create
A wave
Out of vacuum
So
OK
Yes
There is a
Background collision
Result in
You have a whole
A loss
Uh
OK
Good to know
it is good
Thank you
That
On the experiment
We are doing strong
Strong
With
Uh
Different elements of the 2A group
Of course, he has two
Add electrons
That
It corresponds to the electronic connection
Different from the 1A group
In
He has so-called
Singlet
With triplet states
That
First of all, we all know
In the 1A group
You make these atomic keys
That is
In principle
He will meet
Some so-called
Selection rule
That
In the 2A group
Because he has a triplet state
That
Atomic keys from singlet to triplet state
In principle
Not satisfied
Selection rule
That is to say your
Delta s
Not equal to 0
In principle
This is
Selection rule
Not allowed
But of course
Because
Some
Coincidence mechanism
For example
In this 3P state
He
He and
This state
1P1
In principle, there is a coincidence
That
In principle
He will indirectly
With
Ground state couple
To
So he
Overall
This key
He
Still allowed
That
But the answer he corresponds to is
Because he
Uh
He corresponds to the key
Is allowed
But he corresponds to the width of the line
Relatively narrow
That
This is
A level scheme of strong
Then we see
For example
In
First left is
Singlet state
Right is triplet state
That
Singlet state inside
This
Is what we use
Mainly laser cooling
He corresponds to the width of the line
In principle, it is
30.5 MHz
That
Triplet state is our second stage
Laser cooling key
That
His line is relatively narrow
Because I just mentioned
Is
He
Selection rule
This is a
Forbidden transition
But
He
In principle, it is
He corresponds to
In principle, he
In principle
Not completely forbidden
So he corresponds to
Is a
Transition of the width of the line
He corresponds to the width of the line
Transition
He is on the laser cooling
Allow you to reach
Lower
Cooling limit
So
Use this
Uh
To do laser cooling
He can reach
A lower temperature
That
He has some
Features
This
Metastable state
I will introduce later
I am
We use it
For example
Uh
In general
Poisson
Inside
He can be used
Accumulate my atomic group
That is to say this is a
Lifetime
Long
State
I can put the atom
In principle
Concentrated in this state
To do
Uh
Accumulated action
That
His
Ground state
Mentioned here is that
No
Magnetic
Electronic
Magnetic Moment
So
My
Atomic atom
Originally in
I can't use
Because he doesn't have
Magnetic Moment
So I can't use
Magnetic to capture him
Also limited to say
Is
I have to use light in the experiment
Instead of magnetic
That
This is the reason
He doesn't have
Magnetic
Magnetic Moment
That
Current stage
Strong
The experiment
In principle
Uh
I'm here
There are many principles
For example
Ultra cold
Inside the atom
Want to
We have it in the lab
For example
We want to do
Ground state
That
There is also a strong
Two molecules
And
For example
Now
Very
Red
For example
Quantum gas microscope
Want to
In principle
We want to do
High resolution
That is to say
High resolution on the experiment
One
Uh
To observe the atomic group
Some
Uh
Experiment
Or say
For example
Use magnetic atoms to do atomic interference
And
The next thing I'm going to introduce is
Use magnetic atoms to do superradiant laser
That
There are many
I'm more interested in
For example
Let's do the atomic group
That
We all know now
Atomic group
Now use color atoms
To do
That
Uh
Time definition
That
In fact, this is with color atoms
Hyper
Uh
Ground state
Hyperfine state
To do a
Uh
Time standard
That
Color atoms
Ground state
Hyperfine state
Transition
Almost
In
Uh
Gigahertz level
It seems
There are
More than nine gigahertz
That
Of course
We all know that
Some of it
Uh
Then I'm on the right side
A list of
Relationship
We know that this
His
Accuracy
In principle
Is with
Screen
His uncertainty
Is related to his frequency
That
From this relationship
We know that
Your center frequency
For example
Ccm
It corresponds to
The frequency is in the gigahertz level
That
Of course they are on the time
I hope to put this frequency
The higher the higher the better
Because
This way
This one
His
The error can be
Or
His
Uncertainty can be smaller
Because you imagine
For example
I put
He from gigahertz
Back to
Terahertz
That
This one
The denominator is super big
That he overall
I
Error of hertz
Corresponding to an uncertainty
His
Fraction is smaller
That
In addition, we know that the number is in principle
The more atoms, the better
That's why the experiment
The glasses are in the light
This piece
They want to go from gigahertz
To
Light to push
Push to terahertz
That of course
Uh, the first one
Light
The candidate is, for example, ion trap
Because ion, for example, ion
He has some
Ion corresponds to
Uh, for example, clock transition
That is to say, you can
Uh
He corresponds to the clock transition
Can be used as your time standard
But
Uh
The first generation of ion trap, of course
He trapped an ion
So in this number
He is relatively
Weak
That's why
In
The new generation, of course, other people have other proposals
For example, to do optical lattice clock
Of course he is
The more traps, the better the atoms
That optical lattice clock
He also uses atoms
Also use the atomic clock state
In terahertz level
And then he has to trap a lot of atoms at the same time
Go to this
Pull up
That overall makes the whole
Uh
The accuracy is higher
That
So state of the art
Of course it is
The night army in Gila
What he achieved now, of course, is
The Fermi gas clock
Uh, Fermi gas clock
That of course
His this
Now on the experiment
Uh, the principle is
Almost at 10 to 18
10 to 18
Of course this is
This is listed here
The night army
He
In his speech, it is often mentioned that
Assuming that he can achieve it in today's experiment
One
Uh, Fermi gas principle is
There are 1 million atoms
That his
Uh, he has a way to reach this
Uh
Accuracy in light
A value of 10 to 20
At the same time, of course
In Gila
They also have another one
Uh, the approach on the experiment
For example, it is
James Thompson, his super radian laser
The principle is
Uh
Generally, we
In the experiment of the night army, he
Atoms are his
His
A substance of detection, of course, is
To find a way
He also has to go through a local
For example, he wants to do a very good laser
And then through this laser
His
Made of atoms
So the atom as a whole
In his experiment, this is a
Uh
He needs a very good clock laser
And then to probe his
Uh
What is it called
Atoms are his
Absorber
Just
Atoms are his
A substance of observation
So the overall
Your light is a so-called passive
Clock because you are
You have to use a very good
Laser to observe your
Sample
James Thompson's approach is basically different
He just wants to let the atoms
Go by yourself
Release the light of this clock transition
His experiment is
Put the atom
Put it in a cavity
Then let him
A super radian effect
That's the last
The light you come out of
In principle
Uh
It's determined by the atom
Not by you
Cavity conditions
To decide
So the experiment
He is now
Make a
Super radian laser
That
Because this super radian laser
He is basically
Clock state
3P0
His
Uh
Minihertz
They are now
Super radian laser
That
They are the same
Two experiments
To make a
To measure
Super radian laser
How accurate it is
So
James Thompson put his
Super radian laser
Optical lattice clock
To make a
Beat note
To measure
Uh
His super radian laser
Conditions
Of course they are now
About 10 to 15
That
James Thompson
He also wants to do
Super radian laser
That
On this number
Push down three
That means
Usually in this kind of light
Uh light experiment
You have to measure his
Uh you do the points
That is to say
You measure light
You
Uh
In principle, the accuracy
The longer you measure
Uh
The higher the accuracy is
In the light
In the experiment
If you do it in a row
You
In this super radian laser
You are one second
In principle, you can reach 10 to 18
One of the four
Conditions
That means
James Thompson gave himself a metaphor
For example, you put this light
His super radian laser
You are
Uh
In principle
Assuming that the conditions of CW
You can reach this level
That is
Of course another
Uh
The application of double-sided tape is of course
Used on atomic interference
Then we all know that atomic interference
Uh
It can be used to measure your acceleration
It can be used to measure the gravitational field
It can be used to measure
Uh
Your rotation
In principle, it has a very high accuracy
That
In the experiment, of course
His
Sensitivity
With
You in your
For example
You can
On the basis of the atomic group
You let him do
The longer the time
Or your
Your two atomic groups
Just
The greater the distance
Your sensitivity will be higher
So
Now on the experiment, of course
They take this thing
Want to do
For example
Or
Gravity wave detector
First of all, I must say
This is the atomic interference
One of them
Quite interesting application
But I don't do this myself
I can only say
On the basis of technology
Tell you a little bit
Now there are principles
In this regard
There are other teams doing
For example
On the gravity wave
On the detector
Atomic interference
In principle, he has a way to make up
Other gravity wave
Detector
For example, now
There is a LIGO on the experiment
His detection wavelength is here
That next
Proposed
Lisa to sit in space
In principle, his detection wavelength is here
There is actually a gap in the middle
This gap can be in principle
Atomic interference to make up
His advantage is
We all know gravity wave
He's going to measure this
Chirping
When two
He finally
For example, your gravity wave
Source, he finally
In the process
Your measured gravity wave
In principle, the frequency will be higher and higher
But
You experiment
At this frequency
If you have a detector
His advantage is
You can
You are in a gravity wave
Before the event
You can go through
For example, our atomic interference
After measuring the signal
He can go first
Position in space
Let you know
For example, your LIGO
You can expect
There will be a gravity wave
You can measure
Of course
Through this atomic interference
Because he's in
The frequency he corresponds to
He
Measured gravity wave
The lifetime of the event will be longer
For example, he is
0.01 hertz
To 10 hertz
So you basically
You can
He corresponds to
For example, you measure
The event
It takes a few months
He means
In the measurement process
In space
The source of your gravity wave
That
Of course you can
With other
For example, LIGO
Then
It's on some satellites
It seems to be measuring
Electromagnetic wave
Of
The principle
It means
You go to measure this gravity wave
Of
You can match other
Detector
So reach the so-called multi-messenger
One
Measurement
Of course you have to be able to do multi-messenger
It means
You have to know where he is
Those detectors on the satellite
For
Measure in that direction
So
Atomic interference
Can provide information
Of
Of course
At Stanford
Do some
Of
They first built a 10-meter
Atomic interference
That
Of course they also reached the so-called
Of
The material wave
Can reach 54 cm
That
That means
They also achieved some
On both sides
Some early experiments in the gravity field
For example, in this experiment
Their
In principle, your atomic group
Is
He went to throw different heights
That he experimented
In principle, here is a
For example, an 80-kilogram
Piece
Then
They went to measure this
Throw the atomic group at different heights
To scan this
In principle
Gravity field
This result
In principle, it is a
Demonstration that your
In principle, you can measure
A change in the gravity field
Of course
Of
Their next experiment
Of course, I want to scale up
I want to do, for example, 100 meters
Then
They want to do it with a private atom
Because private atoms
Some
In the past
For example, he first had a
That he experimented
He can reach
Higher accuracy
So
This is a private atom
In the next few years
On gravity
Detector
A
Competitive application
That
Then we experimented
Then we do
Our ultimate goal is to do
Then
We have a way to produce
The so-called
Continuous
Assuming we have a way to produce
Continuous Boson-Einstein connection
Continuous
In fact, on the experiment
We also have
Continuous
So this is
Mainly in our
Want to do
Several plans
That
I think I might be a little too slow
A little
Speed up
Then we experimented
Just mentioned
To achieve continuous
Laser cooling
That just said
Laser cooling and evaporation cooling
On the experiment
Not compatible
The reason is because
Laser cooling has a laser cooling temperature limit
That next stage
You just want to put the atomic group
To
To the
Put the atomic group to
For example, we use the
Inside and then inside
Evaporation cooling
At the same time you want to
Turn off the laser cooling light
The reason is because the laser cooling is used
Originally
Resonant light
At the same time
In the cooling process
Resonant
That is to say
Resonant light
If there is a way
If there is a way to stimulate the atomic light
That
Your atomic principle
Is constantly heated
So in the evaporation cooling process
We must turn off the laser cooling light
That
Of course
That is
You can't do it on the experiment
To achieve a so-called continuous
A
Because these two cooling steps are incompatible
But
In 2013, our lab
The principle is
Did an experiment
That
There is a way to achieve
That is to say we are completely
No evaporation cooling
We only rely on laser cooling
To achieve Boson-enzyme condensation
That
Of course
Here is the introduction
We put it on the experiment
That is the so-called transparency beam
I just talked about the laser cooling
The source of the cooling limit
Because
When the density is higher
Your laser cooling light
In the process of re-release
It will heat up your atom
That
In the experiment, we go through this
We call it transparency beam
We find a way to let the atom
To my laser cooling light
In principle
Become transparent
That is to say, my atom can't see my laser cooling light
That
Through this
Transparency beam
A little trick
Then we have a way to achieve
Only by laser cooling
To achieve Boson-enzyme condensation
That
Its mechanism is actually quite simple
That I am now
In principle
In the film
In my light well
That
At the same time
I have my laser cooling light
Is in this
Um, use this
Laser cooling light
That its laser cooling
The cooling limit is in principle
Corresponding to
Doppler temperature
In principle
Doppler cooling temperature is about
180 nK
Doppler temperature is about
About 500 nK
So
Its laser cooling light corresponds to
The temperature limit is actually very low
So
My group of atoms in principle
In the light well
Through laser cooling
Can reach
Almost
1 uC
That
That's why
To reach such a low temperature
Mainly just mentioned
Those
Um
Your
Atoms will still have this
Reabsorption of light
Being heated
The state
Of course, we use this
Transparency beam
Let me
Excited state
This light is in principle
Address my
Excited state to another state
That
The reason for this light
Because of this light
My excited state
Its state is
So-called
AC star shift
That
Because of this light
My atom is in this
Position
It
Uh
Excited state
Light shift
So
It can't
In principle
My light will not
Interact with this atom
Interact with the group of atoms in this position
That
Of course we are
My
The group of atoms is in my dipole trap
Then
Right
What you see is the distribution of the group of atoms in principle
Let's say I open my
Transparency beam
I'm also doing
Uh
Imaging
Because
Sorry
Let me say it again
This
Absorption imaging
Transition
You can see the overall distribution of the group of atoms in principle
There is one in the middle
In principle, the density is higher
Because I have this
Dimple relationship
Now I open my transparency beam
Because
In this position
It
Excited state
Light shift
That is to say
Shift
So my
This beam of light
In principle, in this position
There is no way to interact with the atom
So you are doing the same
When imaging
Use this beam of light
The group of atoms is in this position
It
It's with this
This beam of light is in principle
It's not fair
So it's in principle
In principle, there is no way to interact with those atoms
So you are in
You can't see it in the image
That
Of course, the experiment
Through this
You can imagine
My laser cooling light
In
Reservoir
It continues to cool my laser
That
In
Dimple
Because of my
Transparency beam
Protect my atom
So in principle, the atom
Will not be these
Light
Do not interact with these lights
That experiment
Laser light is constantly
In
Reservoir
Then
At the same time
In my dimple
If you don't interact with these lights
That my
In dimple
The density is high enough
The temperature is low enough
He has a way to form Boson
That's why the experiment
On the right side of the picture
In principle
We hit it in the experiment
Through
Laser cooling
To achieve Boson
That whole process
We did not do an evaporation
Cooling
That
This experiment
When this experiment is completed
Of course we want to go further
The so-called continuous
Atomic laser
Because now
To achieve Boson
We are completely free
We completely skipped the evaporation
Cooling
That experiment
To achieve the so-called continuous
Atomic laser
That
Of course
Just introduced
That is to say
On the experiment
My laser cooling evaporates
That experiment
Of course
I am evaporating
In the process of laser cooling
I just ignored
That is to say
We do laser cooling on the experiment
There are two laser cooling stages
First of all
In principle, there is the first one
The so-called blue mark
That is to say, use this laser cooling light
To do the first stage of cooling
Then
Use this
Thinner light
To reach a lower temperature
That
Then
This Transparency Beam
In principle, it can protect my atom
Let it
Not interact with this laser light
But on the experiment
We still need
The first stage of laser cooling
To accumulate my atomic number
To reach a lower temperature
To reach enough atoms
To do the second stage of cooling
That is to say
There is a two-stage laser cooling
Step
And my
Transparency Beam
Only in the second stage
It works in the laser cooling process
But on the experiment
We still need the first stage
Laser cooling light
So
Next
We are going to do
Continuous
Uh
Polaris
Or continuous atomic laser
The second stage
Uh
Light we can pass
This Transparency Beam to protect my atom
But
The first stage of laser cooling light
We experiment
In principle, it is
Let
Uh
In another space
Go to
Finish my first stage of laser cooling
Then the atom
In principle
To the second space
To achieve my so-called continuous
Polaris
Of course
This is our experiment
Is
After the atom came out of the oven
The first stage
Uh
What we use is what we just said
Do the first stage of laser cooling
Next
Then
In this chamber above
This 30
Megahertz
To do
Uh
After the atom came out of the oven
My atomic number is essentially
To
The following chamber
Go
To achieve my
Continuous Polaris
That space
In this area
In principle, it is completely
Uh
With my first stage of laser cooling
The space is separated
That experiment
In the middle of the chamber
Of course there is also this
Uh
In principle, it is to avoid some
Scattering light
Scattered blue photon
Go to the following chamber
That
First of all
This is our general chamber design
That
We are
Just do
All the first stage of laser cooling
Achieve
The atomic number is running
To the following chamber
That
In the following chamber, we are essentially
No blue light at all
We use the so-called
Uh
To reach a lower temperature
Of course
We want to have
Uh
We first achieve
First make a
After that
The atomic number is essentially
In because this
Is a 2D
So it's on the axis
In principle, the atomic number can be
Run up and run down
The atomic number running down
We are
In principle
Through a molasses
To cool
Let the overall atomic number
Uh
Increase
That
At the same time we are
It's a bit like
Put two blue push pins
To
Avoid the atomic number
Run up
You are
In
The following chamber
Atomic number
Relatively higher
That
Uh
As I just said
But we have to achieve a series of
4BEC and
In the atomic laser chamber
We don't need blue light at all
That
The red light used is essentially
Corresponding to
Uh
On the surface
Because it is
Only 7.4 kHz
The bandwidth
Corresponding to
In principle, only
About
Gravity acceleration
So it's actually a very
Inefficient
Speed reduction
Of course we are
In principle
Put this
7.4 kHz
The bandwidth we want to do
Frequency broadening
To make it overall
Acceleration
That is to say
To have a way
Uh
For example, I'm from the top
Chamber
The atomic number it corresponds to is a
6 mps
A
Speed limit
That
Of course we have reached
Uh
At least the first stage
In practice, we can't reach
Steady state red mod
That steady state red mod is essentially
The first one in practice
Through
Continuous
Use
7.4 kHz bandwidth
To achieve
A mod condition
That it
In principle
We have just reached
Uh
First
I just started talking about it
We have a way
In space
In different spaces with different
Laser cooling
In this framework
In principle, it is realized
Blue laser cooling on the top chamber
Red laser cooling on the bottom chamber
A condition
That
Of course
In practice
We put
Mod center
Pull
Uh
Side by side
The main reason is because
If you make a mod here
He will still see
Blue scatter light
So
Through
My
Mod center moved to the side
After
Can reach a lower temperature
On the experiment
At the same time, of course
I'm here
On this condition here, I reached one
On the experiment
Continuous
One
Atomic sample
On the experiment, I tried to
Produce a pulse-like
Scatter light connection
Then use this
To measure
My lifetime
The point is
I have a BEC here
Then I use this BEC
Then at the same time I turn on my blue laser cooling light
I'm going to measure my BEC lifetime
Then through this step
I'm going to make sure
In this experiment
I'm here
He won't be
This place
Laser cooling light
That
We're going to measure his lifetime
Almost unchanged
So
So in this experiment
We're sure
My experiment
My
The origin of this place
Will not be above me
Blue laser
Cooling photon
Then we try to
Characterize my
A condition
Then we found out that
The mass produced here
Its space density
With all the previous
Experiment to compare
We have a principle
100 times
That is, we compare
All the previous
Steady state
Compared to the conditions
Our mass
At least 100 times
The increase in the number of space density
This is our principle
The first piece of paper
Junjia
Hello
I'm sorry because it's a little over time
You probably still
How long are you going to talk about
Because we usually talk about an hour
Yeah
Take a look
So if you feel
I think everyone is by the way
There's something wrong with you
To a stage
If you think it's a paragraph
That's it for today
Let everyone come
Please ask questions about your content
Like this
Okay
I'll talk about it for another ten minutes
In principle
Because in the first experiment
We reach the principle
100 times
The increase in the number of space density
But
We still can't do it in time
The wave is very condensed
Then we have the second experiment
In principle
Is
In principle, we have a red mark here
Then we
Put the red mark
Continuously exposed to our DiploTrap
Inside
My principle
Is that you can run through
On the right
A DiploTrap
One condition
Then
He also continues to use
After these tricks
We have a way
A continuous
A loading
Then finally
In this place
This is my
I want to produce my one here
SteadyStateBEC
In SteadyStateBEC
In principle
We have to use this isotope
To realize
In principle
To reach
We have now reached
The condition
That is far from our goal
In principle
We are now in the same number
So
Of course we are now
The next step is to hope
Of course
We now have a new way to cool
Because
In terms of here
I have a Zeeman SlowerBeam here
Is our one deceleration mechanism
Then we found that this deceleration mechanism
In principle
It will heat up again in the experiment
The source here
So
We have
Develop a new deceleration method
In the new experiment
In principle, we are going to use this new deceleration method
I hope I can go further
Try to put this
The density of the phase space
Increase
In the end, of course, I hope I can reach
Continuous BC
So
I think I may have talked too long
In principle, this is our current state
So
To do a brief summary
In principle
In our new experiment
We hope to reach
In space
Separate these two different cooling
Laser cooling
Step
In the experiment
We have a new experiment
We built a new experiment
That reached the first stage
High Phase Space Density
A condition
And then try to realize
Continuous
In principle
DipoleTrapLoading
And finally reach a
Space density
A state
I just talked about
In this part
Deceleration mechanism
We found
There is a heating effect on our atomic group
So we
Try to develop new
That is to say different
Deceleration mechanism
In the new experiment
Hope to try to break through this
The density of the phase space is now
A bottleneck
Once
In principle, we have a way
Achieve continuous
Deceleration
That's about it
Hello
Power
Did you hear
Hello
Ok
Thank you for the speech
That
Now
Is there anything about the speech?
No problem
Welcome to open questions
How many people are there now?
Just
There are about nine in the peak period
I think
It's a bit too hard
to talk about it later
Then
I think
Everyone wants to hear
There are some applications
in the middle
Like you said, like gravity
That
Or other things
What are the conditions
that need to be met
You say you are close to them
Almost the same number
How long do you expect
Will be completed
Or within two or three years
Is it like this?
In principle, our experiment now
Of course it is
Put
New
Speed ​​limit
Applied to the experiment
That
In principle, I will do it again
Then this time
My speed limit
Instead of using
Radiation pressure force
I will use it now
My new speed limit
That
Briefly introduce
My new speed limit
In principle
Is me
Let the atom go
I am on my excited state
To produce a
Potential landscape
Then once my atom is
After being stimulated
Its energy
Is through this excited state
Potential landscape
It's climbing this
On the excited state
A process
To take the energy
So this is
In principle, it is my new speed limit
That experiment
I hope I can avoid this
Speed ​​limit
To heat up
My atomic group
But at the same time
It won't
To affect
I
Atomic group
A temperature
So the new experimental principle is
I hope to prove this as soon as possible
That is to say
My new speed limit
It won't affect me
Final
This is in
Atomic group inside
Then because it won't heat it
So hope
Also in density
Temperature conditions
Under the conditions
To achieve my continuous
Potential landscape
That
At least two more experiments
About two months
That hope
In principle
Almost tested
That
Is to be able to
Try to answer this question
Under the new speed limit
I have no way to achieve my
Continuous potential landscape
Thank you
Hey, can I ask another question?
Is a little
More
General
That is
Why did you choose
Is this strong?
And you just mentioned
Use his
Red number
That
The use of
The same number of conditions
Is
Here
There are different numbers
For example, strong
That
You have to reach bc
You
Your
He has one
At least
This
Decide
There is no way
Uh
Go
Do effective
Thermalization
Because you have to do
Your
To do a heat balance
Condition
That
Because his
Very low
So he
Can't see each other
So
Your cooling process
You don't have a so-called
Heat balance
So when you're cooling
He's hard
Uh, the first one
It's hard to go
The second one is
So low
And it's almost negative
In fact, there's no way
Uh, stable
So in practice
Even this
His
Very high
But because of this
He's not a
Easy to reach bc
The same number
So that
That's too high
So he's easy
Once he's
He's
He's too high
He
In principle, the heat balance is too fast
And then
It can even cause heating
That
He just happened to be
A very friendly
That
So in practice, we're going to
Want to achieve
That
Uh, why
The main reason is also
Mainly because
Um
He
The first stage
Laser cooling
So I can do very effective
Laser cooling to
Fast
Uh
Accumulate atoms
Because he has his second stage
Laser cooling
First
Width
It won't be too narrow
So I can still use it to do some
Uh, uh
The first one is wide enough
So I can do laser cooling to very low temperature
That
Can reach very low temperature
Because of that 2013
We
Laser cooling to bc
It's a mechanism of transparency
Go
To achieve the so-called full light
Laser cooling
Uh
Boomerang
Completely skipped
The step of evaporation and cooling
So that experiment
The double line becomes
The most likely
Achieve continuous
Boomerang
A element
So in principle
So we will choose private atoms
Mainly because of our experiment
Is
Start with private atoms
So
This
There is a reason to choose him
Ah
Is it
The 2A group
All can
Up and down
Everyone uses private atoms
That
Is there a heavier one?
Also
If you can't reach it
Change to a unified group
You can do it
Or maybe
There is no way
A lot of people doing AMO
Looking at the laser
Can you get used to it?
Or can you buy it?
Your question is
First in the second step
Try to answer
Laser cooling to bc
You have to find a way to make your atoms
A transparent mechanism
In this experiment
Is through a
In our transparency
To let the atom
For this light
Be transparent
But in space
We have to find a way
To put the atom
From the oven stage
Cool to have a way
Uh, there are two
The steps of laser cooling
Assuming
If you use other 2A elements
Cover the atom
His
Transition
Its bandwidth is 350Hz
That he actually
Doing this
Atom
If you use the atom
Your
Transfer
Difficult to achieve
That is to say
If you want to do this
Transfer
Difficult
7.4kHz
It corresponds to
If you use the atom
350kHz
350Hz
Almost
Not too scattered
That means you're hard
Efficient deceleration
You almost can't
For
You cover the atom again
It's hard to decelerate
That is to say
Somehow
In a sweet spot
Hello
Hey
Other questions
Hello
Other people
If you don't have any questions, you can ask now
Otherwise, our speech will end today
Hello
Please turn on the mic
Let's give a round of applause to Junjia
Okay, only me left
Sorry
Because I asked some small details
I'm afraid everyone is getting impatient
Thank you
Junjia, next time we'll discuss other questions with you
Okay
Okay, thank you
Junjia, go to sleep
It's a bit late, it's 3pm
Okay
Good night
Bye
Thank you for watching!
See you next time!
Translated by Hua Chenyu English Subs