Hi, everyone. Welcome to TerraTalk.
Today, we are honored to invite Wu Xinmei, who is studying in Yanhu City, Utah, to talk about today's topic.
Today's topic is Studying the Recharge Cycle of the Old-Faith Geyser with GANS Seismic Arrays.
Xinmei is currently studying Geology at Utah State University.
She graduated from the University of Utah and came to the U.S. for her Ph.D.
Last year, or this year, she received her Ph.D. from the University of Utah.
Today's topic is Studying the Recharge Cycle of the Old-Faith Geyser with GANS Seismic Arrays.
Today's topic is a little bit different from the previous one.
This time, we are going to talk about the introduction of the previous topic.
Our lab mainly uses seismic data.
In recent decades, earthquakes have not been the main source of data.
Today, we are going to use seismic data to study the Old-Faith Geyser.
The Old-Faith Geyser is located in Yellowstone, Utah.
The Old-Faith Geyser is a periodic geyser.
Today's presentation will focus on the Old-Faith Geyser.
The Old-Faith Geyser is located in Yellowstone, Utah.