Thank you everyone for coming to this talk.
We are very happy to invite Dr. Lin Shujing from the University of Columbia, UBC, Canada.
Dr. Lin was trained at the University of Zhongshan Medical University,
in the Department of Radiation Science and Imaging.
After graduating from this university,
he obtained the qualification of a Radiologist of the Republic of China.
However, he was very interested in academic research,
so he later completed a master's degree from the Institute of Brain Science at the University of Columbia.
After the master's degree,
he also served as a research assistant at the University of Yangming,
Rongzhong, Taipei City Hospital, and Jiaotong University.
In 2012, he went to the University of Columbia, UBC, Canada,
to start his doctorate in Neuroscience.
He graduated in 2018.
Today's talk is mainly about his doctoral thesis.
I am very happy and grateful that he is here to share with us.
This talk is about the connection between the functions of the brain and neurodegenerative diseases,
as well as the connection between cognitive functions.
Let's welcome him with a round of applause.
Can you turn up the volume?
If not, let me know in the chat.
I can do it here.
You can? Okay.
Thank you for the introduction.
What I am going to talk about today is basically what I did in my PhD thesis.
The structure of today's talk will be based on the order of the chapters in my thesis.
The title is a bit long.
Let me explain.
The title of my thesis is called Advanced Neural Analysis of Resin-stained Functional Connectivity
to Probe Exactive Functions in Parkinson's Disease and Multiple Sclerosis.
In simple terms, it is a way to look at the connection between the functions of the brain and cognitive functions
in neurodegenerative diseases.
Let's move on.
I wrote seven chapters in total.
The presentation will follow the order of the chapters.
In the first part, I will put the first and second chapters together.
The purpose of putting the first and second chapters together is to give you a brief introduction,
including the symptoms of these two diseases and their clinical symptoms.
I will also put the second chapter together
because the second chapter is purely about behavioral studies.
So it will give you a more comprehensive introduction.
The third and sixth chapters are related to fMRI.
In short, we used different methods to analyze Resin-stained fMRI data.
We got different measurements.
On the one hand, we want to see if these different measurements can be used as biomarkers
to clearly distinguish between patients and normal people.
On the other hand, we want to see if these measurements are related to fMRI.
The seventh chapter is summary.
Let's move on to the first and second chapters.
In the first chapter, we will briefly introduce Parkinson's disease and multiple sclerosis.
These two neurodegenerative diseases are the main structure of the whole paper.
Parkinson's disease is more familiar to Taiwanese people.
It is a neurodegenerative disease,
which is common in men and older patients,
for example, about 50 or 60 years old.
Another type of multiple sclerosis is called multiple sclerosis,
but it is more common in slightly younger women.
It is more common in Europe and the United States,
such as the United States, Canada, and North Europe.
It is also common in Taiwan, but relatively rare.
The picture on the right is a brief introduction.
The basic cause of multiple sclerosis is that the nerve on the left is a nerve tree,
and there is a bulge on the outside called the myelin.
The structure of the myelin is attacked by a killer T cell,
so it is a kind of autoimmune disease.
This attack will cause the transmission of the nerve signal to slow down or cause some errors.
On the clinical table, we can see that there is a problem with the coordination between the head and the eyes,
and the patient's walking will be more unbalanced.
There are also a lot of visual problems,
and the patient often says,
oh, I'm very tired. This is called fatigue.
There are also some cognitive function disorders.
Another Parkinson's disease is more common.
The main cause of the disease is that the neurotransmitter in the brain is not enough,
and this neurotransmitter is called dopamine or dopamine.
In normal people's brains, you can see this picture.
This black part is a neurotransmitter that produces dopamine,
and this part is called the subcentral nigra.
You can see that it's very dark here,
but in Parkinson's disease patients, these black things are gone,
which is the death of neurotransmitters that produce dopamine,
which leads to insufficient concentration of neurotransmitter.
For example, we often hear tremor,
and there is a problem with sleep, and there is a problem with walking balance.
In addition, there are also some cognitive function disorders.
So you can see that PD and MS are two very different diseases,
but they both produce cognitive impairment.
According to clinical evidence and previous literature review,
MS produces the most cognitive functions,
including executive function,
and Parkinson's disease visual memory.
PD is also an executive function,
and most people will have these problems,
as well as walking memory and visual spatial abilities.
In addition to the clinical evidence and literature review,
we are also very interested in whether these cognitive function disorders
are related to the severity of their clinical disease or other factors.
So in the second part, we did a simple analysis.
We use Canonical Correlation Analysis,
abbreviated as CCA,
to see if their cognitive function performance
is related to other clinical data.
Let me briefly introduce what CCA is.
It is a multivariate statistical approach.
The main purpose of CCA is to find two pieces of data.
Let's say we have two pieces of data, U and V.
The purpose of CCA is to find these so-called weights.
These weights will let us know
what kind of linear combination will make U and V the most relevant.
In other words, CCA finds this weight,
and then we can infer
whether X1 is the most relevant,
or whether Y2 is the most relevant.
In the second part of the study,
one of the data is the demographic on clinical data,
such as the severity of the disease or age.
The other piece of data is the performance of cognitive function.
We did some tests,
and then we took their scores to make a set of data.
Let's take a look at the results on PD.
As we said, the purpose of CCA is to find linear combinations
to make these two pieces of data the most relevant.
So here you can see that
these two pieces of data are indeed very relevant.
The relevant factor is 0.9.
One of them is demographic on clinical data,
and the other is cognitive function.
Because we put gender in it,
all the variables are...
Wait a minute, it's not out yet.
All the variables are positive,
and the positive loading is related to the male.
All the negative loading is related to the female.
And then, if all the variables are the same,
for example, positive loading,
they are both positive.
If negative loading occurs,
This means that if this number goes up,
the other numbers related to it will also go up.
So let's take a look now.
In general, the result tells us that
in the case of PD patients,
if the male is also in a more serious state of depression,
it has nothing to do with cognitive function.
But let's take a look at the following.
In other words, women with higher education
have a longer period of education,
which has a lot to do with most of the better cognitive functions.
These are a series of tests we tested.
Actually, this is not what we tested.
This is a database called PPMI.
If you are interested, we can discuss it later.
They tested a lot of different cognitive domains.
In principle, the higher the number,
the better the cognitive function and the better the response.
So you can see that women with higher education
have better cognitive performance.
As for MS, let's take a look.
This is the data we received.
The same thing.
The positive loading is related to the male.
If the negative loading is related to the female.
Let's take a look at the cognitive function part.
These two are TMT, trial making test A and B.
Basically, it's a test of attention,
and executive function.
What you can find is that in women,
you can see that if it's a woman,
negative loading,
these two tests will perform better on women.
At the same time, we have another set of different cognitive functions.
Here, you can see that if it's a male,
it will be related to EDS.
EDS is an indicator on MS Clinical.
The higher the EDS value,
the more serious the disease.
On the other side,
it's the Wisconsin Consultant Error.
In other words, the higher the EDS value,
the more serious the disease,
the more mistakes it makes.
On the other hand,
for women,
their performance will be better.
You can see that these two tests are closely related.
So,
here is a conclusion.
We have categorized the same and different cognitive functions
of PD and MS.
For the same function,
we find that gender is a very important factor,
whether it's PD or MS.
Especially for women,
their cognitive functions seem to be better.
On the other hand,
for PD,
the higher the EDS value,
the better the cognitive function.
We can use the so-called Cognitive Research Theory
to explain this.
In this theory,
the longer the EDS value,
the more protective it is.
So, if a person has been educated for a long time,
he may get sick later in life.
The early education
may not be able to protect his cognitive function.
In addition,
we also found that
in the case of PD,
at first,
we were surprised to find that
the clinical indicators of PD
are not related to cognitive functions.
One possibility is that
the clinical indicators of PD,
which is similar to MS EDSS,
but we call it UPDRS,
are actually evaluated
based on the symptoms of the action.
It is also possible that
the neurotransmitters
related to action
and cognitive functions are different.
In addition, in the case of MS,
we can see that
the more serious the disease is,
it is related to the worse cognitive functions.
As we just mentioned,
it made more mistakes.
Okay,
this part is purely about
the fact that
there is no FMI involved in behavior.
Next, we are going to talk about FMI.
As we all know,
if you have a little bit of research on MS,
Functional MRI is a non-invasive method.
We can use this non-invasive method
to study the human brain
or the activity in the animal brain.
And we usually take this material
for a period of time.
Most of the data we use
in this study is racing state,
which means that we require the victim
to lie in the machine,
close their eyes,
and don't think about anything special.
This is called racing state.
This method is actually
more feasible in clinical trials,
because many of the victims are patients,
and they can't cooperate with you
to do some tasks.
For example, you may have to
respond to a case,
which is a little difficult for patients,
especially patients with Parkinson's disease.
In addition, even if it is racing state,
the victim did not do anything.
It still relies on the activity of the brain
to communicate a lot of cognitive functions.
Then,
I will explain the so-called
functional connectivity here.
In other words,
because this word often appears in the back,
for example, we get the racing state
fMRI data.
What we need to analyze now is to look at
its functional connectivity.
Suppose you are interested in
many different brains today.
The so-called functional connectivity
is the signal of fMRI in these brains.
Are they related to each other?
I'll just use a picture to explain.
It may be easier to understand.
Suppose you have a brain today,
and we are interested in three areas.
We call it Region of Interest,
which is called RRI.
After some preliminary processing,
such as the difference in time,
or the difference in head movement,
we get these fMRI data.
It's a bit like
getting these fMRI data
is to get the fMRI signals
of these three brains.
Then use some statistical methods to calculate
whether the fMRI signals between
Brain 1 and Brain 2 are related.
If they are related,
we will think that these two brain areas
are connected to each other.
In addition, there are many
different ways to calculate.
The most common is
Pairwise Correlation.
There is also Partial Correlation
or Mutual Information.
There are many ways to calculate.
There is no limit to this.
It depends on how you use it.
The most common thing we see is a matrix,
a color-coded matrix.
If you are interested in this,
it means that
RRI1 and RRI2 are highly related.
It means that
RRI1 and RRI2 are related.
We know that they are connected.
In conclusion,
even if
we are in a resting state,
we can still use this kind of data
to observe
its functional connectivity
and then study
whether these functional connectivity
are related or not.
Next,
since we want to study
cognitive functions,
especially Exciter Functions,
because both PDS and MS
are prone to
Exciter Functions.
So we did some
literature review.
We found that
these are the brain areas
that are most related
to Exciter Functions
You can see that
most of the connections
are Frontal Parietal Region.
It means that
Frontal Parietal Region
and Exciter Functions
are related.
PDS is the same.
Frontal Parietal Region
and RCP are also related.
In addition,
there are connections in the opposite brain area.
So we have a conclusion that
the so-called Long Range Connection
is very important
for Exciter Functions.
The so-called Long Range Connection
is a cortical-to-cortical connection.
Just like what we said here,
Frontal to Parietal.
Next,
what we just observed
is very similar to a model.
This was proposed by
Melvin Cohen in 2001.
They believe that
there are three components in Exciter Function.
The first one is Input.
Input is the transfer of
sensory information to
the internal state.
The internal state is in the Prefrontal Cortex.
These signals are transferred to
the Prefrontal Cortex for processing.
After processing,
the Prefrontal Cortex transfers the signals
to the Output Component.
The Output Component
is in the subcortical area.
The Prefrontal Cortex
is in the subcortical region.
The Output Component
and the Subcortical Region
must cooperate with the
Motor Cortex
to execute the
processed signals.
It is very important
to study the cognitive functions
as well as
how different brain areas
work together
and cooperate.
This is the main goal
and architecture of the paper.
That's all for today's presentation.
We have already explained
the first and second chapters.
We will move on to the
FMI section.
The third chapter is
focused on connection.
However,
I found that
the third chapter is too long,
so I will skip it for now.
We can discuss it later.
The fourth chapter is
static brain organization.
The fifth chapter is
dynamic functional connectivity.
sliding window approach.
We will put together
the fourth and fifth chapters
to see if
these measurements
are related to
clinical indicators or cognitive functions.
That's the conclusion of the seventh chapter.
That's all.
Now we are moving to
the fourth chapter,
the FDIL section.
Does anyone have any questions?
Let's get started
with the fourth chapter.
The fourth chapter is
the Brain Organization section.
The so-called
Brain Organization
is to study
how the brain
is organized.
There are several main principles.
First, we see
Functional Integration,
Functional Segregation, and
HUB Structure.
I will use a picture to explain.
As you can see,
there are many dots and lines.
Each dot represents
a brain region in our brain,
the RRI.
Each line represents
the connection between
the two brain regions.
We think they have a connection.
The picture on the right
has many different colors.
Each color represents
the individual community.
In other words,
this region
will form a network
between each other.
The so-called
Functional Integration
represents
how well
the neural signal
is integrated
globally in the brain.
It is a community
that crosses different colors.
On the other hand,
Functional Segregation
represents how well
the neural signal
is integrated
in the individual community.
So, Functional Integration
and Functional Segregation
are the opposite.
One is in the community,
the other is across the community.
Finally, there is a concept
called HUB Structure.
Let's look at
the middle dot.
As you can see,
the HUB Structure
has more dots than
other dots in the community.
This means that
the RRI is very important
in this network.
It plays a central role.
So, we think
it is a HUB Structure.
At the same time,
it has many different connections
than other dots.
HUB Structure Integration
and Segregation
can be obtained
through Graph Analysis.
So far, I think
Graph Theory
is a good way
to integrate
Functional Connectivity.
As we mentioned before,
after you get
the correlation matrix,
you will have too much information.
At the same time,
if you have hundreds of RRIs,
you don't know where to start.
So, Graph Theory
is a good way
to tell you
whether your network
is integrated or segregated.
In addition,
you can get many
different Graphical Measures
through Graph Theory.
Each Measure
represents a network feature.
These Measures
can be connected
to cognitive functions.
So,
these are the research
done on normal people.
As for the disease,
we also did some
literature review.
Overall,
we can see that
Graphical Measures
are not different
from normal people.
It is possible that
Graphical Measures
can be biomarkers.
In fact,
we have connected
Graphical Measures
to Cognitive Functions
to show the difference
between normal people
and patients,
so that
we can connect
the difference
to Cognitive Functions.
Ok,
let's talk about
Material Methods.
We have two cohorts,
PT and MS.
PT and normal people.
As for MS,
when we were collecting data,
normal people
and patients
are not age-matched,
so I put all MS in
to see if their measurements
are related to Cognitive Functions.
We call it
Brain Behavior Analysis.
In addition,
we took 18 MS
and 15 normal people
to do a t-test
to see if
our measurements can be biomarkers.
In addition,
in terms of data,
PT has
Overall Cognition,
which is a Modular Cognitive Assessment.
In addition,
there are tests for different Cognitive Domains,
such as
Visual Special Ability,
Learning,
Working Memory,
Excitement Function, etc.
In terms of MS,
we can divide it into
Working Memory,
Processing Speed,
and Excitement Function.
At the same time,
we also did a questionnaire
to measure their
Depression,
Anxiety,
and Fatigue.
As I mentioned earlier,
the most important thing in GraphQL
is points and lines,
i.e., ROI and Connection.
We have 68 ROI here.
As for Connection,
after retrieving the FMR signal,
we do Partial Correlation,
which is
Partial Correlation Matrix.
Here,
we consider it as Functional Connection,
so we have points and lines,
and we can do the following analysis.
We use Brain Connectivity Toolbox
to do Graph Theory.
It is a free download of
ManLab Toolbox.
You can download it online.
As for the GraphQL Majors,
we can divide them into
Global Majors and Nodal Majors.
In Global Majors,
there is a number
for each subject.
This number represents
the characteristics of the brain
globally.
For example,
Global Efficiency,
Pathline,
Rich Coop,
Coefficient,
Modularity,
and so on.
I won't go into details
of each number.
In short,
they represent
Functional Segregation
and Functional Integration.
Nodal Majors
Here,
I mainly use
Betweenness Centrality
and Local Efficiency.
represents that
the higher the value,
the more important
the RRI is in the network.
Local Efficiency
represents that
the higher the value,
the higher the Functional Connectivity
of the RRI.
If the value is different
in patients and in patients,
it may become a biomarker.
The so-called Brain Behavior Analysis
uses correlation and regression
to evaluate
if these measures
are related to cognition.
Let's look at
the results of PT.
There are no differences
in Global Majors.
However, we find that
Local Efficiency and Betweenness Centrality
have significant differences.
Let's look at the picture.
This is the result of
Local Efficiency on PT.
You can see that
there are a lot of
dots on the right.
Each dot represents
an RRI.
We have a total of 68 RRIs.
These orange dots
represent that
these RRIs are actually
increasing in PT.
This is Local Efficiency.
In PT,
these RRIs
actually increase
their functional connectivity.
It's a bit different from what we usually think.
Let's look at
Betweenness Centrality.
These blue dots
represent
that their Betweenness Centrality
is decreasing.
In PT,
these numbers are relatively low.
RRIs like
Superior Frontal Cortex
or Parietal Cortex
represent that
these dots are
the Hub Structure.
In theory,
these dots are very important.
However, in PT,
these RRIs
are not that important.
Interestingly,
these two RRIs
on the right are
Local Clearance Accumbance.
These two RRIs
are more important in PT.
Their Betweenness Centrality
is higher.
We think that
this might be related to
Compensation or Adaptation.
We will explain it later.
This is the result of t-test.
In the next part of
Brain Behavior Analysis,
we will do Correlation and Linear Regression.
I can tell you that
you will not see any result.
As for Correlation,
there is an SDMT,
Symbol Digital Modality Test.
It mainly tests process speed.
It is related to
Global Efficiency and Pathline.
Let's take a look at the graph.
Let's take a look at this one.
Global Efficiency
The higher the number of Global Efficiency,
the better the neural signal
is integrated in the brain
in different communities.
Unexpectedly,
the higher the number of Global Efficiency,
the better the neural signal
is integrated in the brain.
It is related to
poor cognitive performance.
The graph on the right
is related to
Global Efficiency.
The higher the number of
Pathline,
the lower the number of Global Efficiency.
These two graphs
tell us the same thing.
The higher the number of
Global Efficiency,
the lower the neural signal
is integrated in the brain.
It is related to
poor cognitive performance.
Let's take a look at
MS.
MS