Hello everyone, and welcome to the Terra Talks on April 27th, 2019.
Our speaker today is Dr. Zhang Changming,
who is currently working as a postdoc at Technical University of Munich in Germany.
Today's theme is Photoelectrochemical Solar Field Production, Progress and Prospects.
Changming did his undergraduate degree in Technical University of Munich,
and then went to UC Berkeley to do his Ph.D. and postdoc.
He is now doing his second research in Germany.
We are very happy to welcome Changming to give us his latest speech. Thank you.
Thank you, Yu-Tung. Hello everyone.
Can I speak like this?
Yes.
Sorry if my speech is a bit laggy today.
It's 5 a.m. in Europe,
and I'm having my first cup of coffee,
so it might be a bit slow.
If you have any questions,
please feel free to interrupt me.
Looking back at the previous theme,
it seems a bit too broad,
but basically today I want to share with you
some of the results of the past two or three years.
From our perspective,
we need to use a lot of energy.
According to statistics,
the average energy consumption per year is 18 terawatts.
Of course, as technology advances, the number will continue to increase.
It is estimated that in about 30 years,
this number will increase to 60 terawatts.
This means that we need to find a source of new energy.
So far, most of this energy has come from so-called fossil fuels.
Of course, we have been burning fossil fuels,
which means that we keep putting carbon dioxide into the atmosphere every year.
We can also see that this is a project by UC San Diego.
They started tracking the concentration of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere from Hawaii in the 1950s.
We can see that in 2015,
this concentration has officially broken through the 400ppm level.
Of course, this also causes the so-called global warming problem.
In order to solve this problem,
it means that we need to find a source of new energy at the same time,
and at the same time avoid creating more carbon dioxide.
This means that we need to find some energy that does not emit carbon dioxide.
A very ideal choice, of course, is solar energy.
For example, here we can see that on the surface of the earth every year,
the input energy of solar energy is 120,000 terawatts.
This is far more than what we need.
So in recent years,
we also know that solar energy devices are increasing all over the world.
But so far, it's about 300 to 400 gigawatts.
So there is still some time to go on the energy of the device.
But we can also predict that there is a problem.
The source of solar energy is not a very stable source.
It is related to the weather and the season.
So we need to have a way to store the excess solar energy.
In this regard, there are usually two directions.
One, of course, is the so-called development battery.
I won't talk about most of this today.
It's not my own field.
But in another part,
in addition to storing energy by battery,
my field is how to store the excess solar energy by chemical energy.
How do we do this?
Basically, our goal is to convert solar energy into fuel.
Our first method is the so-called electromagnetic method.
It's two parts.
No matter what method we use to generate electricity,
the excess electricity is generated by electricity.
Then we can make an electromagnetic cell.
Our battery is here.
We can put a blower in the positive and negative poles.
For example, in the positive pole,
where the oxidation reaction occurs,
we can oxidize water into oxygen.
In the negative pole, we convert water into hydrogen.
This hydrogen can be stored.
Then it can be used as fuel.
Whether it's solar power,
or the source of the electric car with the fuel cell.
This method is purely electromagnetic.
To do this,
for example, to decompose water into hydrogen and oxygen.
In thermodynamics,
we need about 1.23 volts.
This is the most basic requirement.
But in fact,
no matter what chemical reaction we have,
there is a so-called kinetic barrier.
We have to overcome this barrier on both sides.
In fact, we need about 1.7 to 1.8 volts
to do the so-called water-soluble reaction.
This is one approach.
The other approach is to combine these two steps into one.
We directly convert light into fuel.
How do we do this?
For example, we can put an N-shaped semiconductor
in the positive pole.
When we put the N-shaped semiconductor into the water,
there will be a shocky barrier on the interface.
So its shock absorber and conductor will go up.
After absorbing light, we have electromagnetic current.
Because of the band bending,
the current will flow in the direction of the solution.
This current can be used to
do the oxidation reaction,
to oxidize water into oxygen.
This means that if we do it this way,
we need 1.7 to 1.8 volts.
The voltage depends on
the band gap of the semiconductor.
In terms of experience,
the light voltage can only do
up to 70% of the band gap.
This means that if we want to use the same semiconductor
to provide voltage for the solution of water,
we need a semiconductor with a voltage above 2.5 eV.
This means that most of the light in the solar system
is not easy to use.
We can also improve our approach.
We use different semiconductors in the positive and negative poles.
For example, in the positive pole,
we use a N-shaped semiconductor with a slightly larger band gap.
Then we can do the oxidation reaction.
After the short-wave long-wave light is absorbed,
the long-wave long-wave light can still pass through.
We use a smaller band gap.
At this time, we use a P-shaped semiconductor.
So its light electrons will run in the direction of the solution
to do the oxidation reaction.
This is the bottom layer of the semiconductor.
In this way, we can choose the most optimized band gap combination.
We can use most of the light in the solar system
to produce enough light voltage
to produce the so-called CO2 photoreduction,
which is more difficult
whether it is to produce hydrogen or the recently more popular,
which is to convert CO2 into chemical fuel.
So my research focuses on the so-called photoelectrochemical
solar energy conversion.
Today I will talk about
an example of a P-type photocastle.
I will also introduce some N-type photoanodes.
We want to find a suitable light-electrode material.
How do we define the efficiency of a photocastle?
How do we find a photocastle with high efficiency?
Basically, when we develop a photocastle,
we define its efficiency
based on how much light current we can get.
For example, this is our photocastle in the middle.
We can apply different potentials to the photocastle.
Then we measure how much current we have.
We can carry out this experiment
without photocastle or photocastle.
The gap in the middle is the so-called light current,
which is to convert light into current.
Because there is current, it means
that a circuit is formed between the entire furnace and the photocastle.
This means that there is a chemical reaction
between the furnace and the circuit.
Of course, the higher the light current, the higher the efficiency.
Basically, the intensity of the light entering the photocastle
is defined, because it is the radiance of the sun.
It is about the intensity of the global average.
So the light entering the photocastle is fixed.
If we analyze this way, the light current we get
is related to the three efficiency factors of our material.
The first efficiency factor is the efficiency of the photocastle.
Of course, the smaller the bandgap, the stronger the photocastle's ability.
There will be more electromagnetic waves
under the same photocastle.
After the electromagnetic waves are generated,
they need to move to the easy interface.
During this process, there may be so-called recombination.
The electromagnetic recombination disappears.
This means that it will reduce our efficiency.
So in order to have high charge separation efficiency,
we need our material to have a better carrier transport property.
Finally, when our electromagnetic or electromagnetic waves
reach the surface of the photocastle,
they need to do a charge transfer to the photocastle
to carry out our chemical reaction.
But these reactions are usually slower
and have a connected barrier.
So we will also have some efficiency losses.
Because these electromagnetic or electromagnetic waves
will stop at the surface
until there is enough time for the chemical reaction.
During this waiting time, there will also be so-called surface recombination.
In addition to these factors,
we also hope that our material does not require
a too expensive method of synthesis
or does not require some very rare elements.
It will be a little cheaper in terms of production cost.
Another point is that
these inorganic materials hate water very much.
It is very different from the water that humans or animals need.
These inorganic materials,
especially when you add a voltage to it in the water,
it is very likely to decompose or be unstable.
In order to do this,
we ultimately want to make this technology
into a large-scale mature technology
that can solve the energy problems of humans.
So we hope that the cost is low,
it is stable and efficient.
So we can take a look at our current
so-called solar cell
some more mature semiconductors in this field,
such as silicon.
It is efficient enough.
We also have very mature technology
that can do large-scale mass production,
but it is unstable in water.
The so-called tribozoic semiconductor is also very efficient,
but it is basically unable to do large-scale mass production at present.
They also have stability problems.
So my own research and
many people in the academic world are currently studying the so-called
metal oxide.
These are easier to manufacture
and at the same time quite stable in water.
But a big common problem is that
these metal oxides are undergoing
so-called energy conversion.
The efficiency of this application is
very, very different from silicon.
Our goal is to find out why
the efficiency of these metal oxides is still so low.
After understanding these reasons,
we hope to use these knowledge to guide us
to find a new material
that can meet these three needs at the same time.
So in the first part, I will
use this example,
the so-called copper iron oxide.
It is a P-type photocasol.
Then in the second part, I will
mention some so-called copper vanadium oxide
as a photogano.
The so-called photocasols
are a P-type material.
After it is absorbed, it is easily
re-reacted on the surface.
Basically, most oxidants are N-type
because it is easy to have so-called oxygen vacancy.
This is a native N-type defect.
So it is a bit difficult to find P-type oxidants.
The most common P-type oxidant is
sulfuric acid or copper oxide.
This material has actually been studied
in the field of solar cells quite thoroughly.
In terms of solar cells,
it can also have a pretty good efficiency.
But the problem is that
we want to do photoelectrochemical energy conversion.
In the water, this material is very, very unstable.
It means that it will die in five minutes.
The reason for the death is that
we can see that its conduction band is mainly
copper 4s orbital.
After you light it up, the electrons in the conduction band
will convert a copper to a metal copper.
It means that in a very short time,
our oxidant will gradually be converted to metal.
So how do we improve this material?
One way is to add a second metal.
These are some common examples.
The advantage is that
because we still have a copper in our material,
these oxides are still native P-type.
Another advantage is that
after adding the second metal,
we can adjust our bandgap.
Either push the radiance band up
or lower the conduction band.
In this way, our bandgap is reduced.
We can use solar cells more efficiently.
Another advantage is that
after we change the character of the minimum conduction band,
we can reduce the chance of restoring the copper.
We can make the material more stable.
So the first topic I want to talk about is
copper iron oxide.
It looks like a very attractive material.
Because no matter copper or iron,
there are a lot of elements in the earth.
So the cost is very low in production.
The structure is here.
There are six oxides in every three iron atoms.
So it's a composite structure of the surface.
Copper is a linear composite structure.
It's basically a layer-by-layer structure.
Basically, if you look at the literature,
there are many different ways
to composite this material.
But there is a very interesting way.
Hello.
I can't hear Tom's voice right now.
Did you accidentally mute yourself?
I just got back.
Okay.
I just had some...
Can everyone see the screen now?
I can see it now.
Okay.
Can everyone see the screen now?
I can see it now.
Okay.
Did you cut off from here?
Yes.
Okay.
So basically,
if you go back to the literature,
there are several different ways to composite copper iron oxide.
The first way is called Sol-gel synthesis.
It's basically a spin-coating method.
You can see from the image of the electronic microscope
that it's a pretty tight film.
The blue data here is the so-called C-V curve.
That is to say,
under different voltages,
how much light current do we have?
It has this up and down jump
because sometimes there is light,
and sometimes there is no light.
So the gap in the middle is the so-called photocurrent.
The blue one is the so-called action-reduction reaction.
That is to say,
we put a lot of oxygen in copper iron.
Oxygen is also an easy-to-restore molecule.
So we can see that
this material can effectively restore oxygen.
But if we want to make it HER,
so-called hydrogen evolution,
which is to restore water to hydrogen,
we don't see how much current there is.
That means the surface of this material
is not very efficient for so-called hydrogen evolution.
We also found that
the main problem is
when you put this material in the water,
there will be a surface hydroxide layer.
The electron will be trapped in this layer
instead of being transferred to the water to produce hydrogen.
But the interesting thing is
you can also synthesize this material in the so-called electromagnetic way.
From the surface map of the electron microscope,
there are a lot of these small nanoparticles.
That means its surface area is getting bigger.
At the same time,
the materials made by electromagnetic method
are not entirely pure carbon iron oxide.
It is easy to have so-called copper oxide,
the second oxygen bucket in it.
This material is not only
compared with the previous SOLDIER,
but it can also be used
for CO2 photoreduction, which is theoretically more difficult.
Our CO2 is a very stable molecule.
Why are there so many differences in the activity
compared with the previous SOLDIER?
We can see here that
the morphology is basically very different.
And the purity of the material is also very different.
So the first goal is to
make a controllable synthesis method.
We can adjust the purity of the material
while maintaining the same morphology.
In this way, we can determine
whether the source of this activity
is the activity of the material itself
or the activity of the secondary phase.
The method we have is
Reactive Sputtering.
We have two targets, copper and iron.
We can have two negative targets.
We use argon plasma to hit the target
and deposit the material on the substrate.
In this way, we can make a large-scale,
easy-to-produce scale.
For example, we can easily make 5x5 cm2.
But in the industry,
it is easy to scale up to tens of centimeters.
We can also adjust the ratio of copper and iron in the material.
The middle is the ratio of copper and iron.
In 1 to 1, we get a very pure carbon dioxide phase.
We can see it from X-ray scattering
or from Laman-Campbell scattering.
It is a very pure material.
But when we add more iron,
we can see some secondary phase.
We can identify that it is mainly oxidized iron.
On the other hand, if we put more copper in,
the secondary phase we see is 2 plus oxidized copper.
After we have this series of materials,
we can make some more large-scale comparisons.
Whether it is the photoelectrochemical performance
or the material used to identify its optical properties,
its carrier transport properties,
or the electronic structure of the material.
First of all, in the so-called photoelectrochemical performance,
we do the same measurement first.
This is not the so-called hydrogen evolution.
We add this sodium persafate.
This is a so-called electron scavenger.
It means that it is also easy to be restored.
If you still remember this tetrahedron,
we add a very easy-to-be-restored thing in the solution.
It means that we assume that the last charge injection efficiency
is very efficient, which is basically 1.
We can see that we get about 1 mA per cm2.
So much current.
But if we don't add this thing,
it means that we want to do a hydrogen evolution.
Our current density is reduced by about 20 times.
This is the so-called pure material.
If we look at the material in this series we just had,
in the case of the electron scavenger on the left,
the density of the current is basically the same.
But on the right, we can see that
in the case where the copper ratio is higher,
the density of our current is obviously higher.
We can see that there is also another peak in the CV data.
This peak means that there is an additional oxidation reaction in the material.
If you still remember,
these more copper samples are actually non-pure oxidized carbon dioxide.
From this data, we can deduce that
especially in the lower right corner,
the higher current for CO2 reduction
is actually due to the oxidation of copper as a catalyst.
So no matter what,
our copper dioxide is just a catalyst.
On the surface, it can't restore CO2.
But when you have an excess of oxidized copper,
these oxidized copper will first be restored to oxidized arsenic or metal copper
to act as a catalyst.
Next, we're going to do a light quality measurement.
We're using the so-called spectroscopic isometry.
We can analyze its absorption rate.
We can also do a tau analysis.
We find that it's an indirect semiconductor.
The bandgap is about 1.43eV.
Its direct bandgap is about 3.09eV.
But as we said earlier,
our light current density is about 1mA per cm2.
But if we look at its bandgap at 1.4,
it can actually absorb a lot of light.
If we compare the light we absorb
with the ratio of current we get,
that's our conversion efficiency.
If we calculate this efficiency,
it's actually less than 10%.
That means after more than 90% of the light is absorbed,
we can't take it out of the semiconductor interface.
That means a lot of recombination occurs.
This recombination,
when we look at these new oxidizing materials,
it's a very common and the biggest limitation.
This is mainly a comparison.
The gray one is the so-called photosymbol diffraction.
That is to say, we measure the absorption of the material.
After the material absorbs light,
we convert the energy of light into heat.
We can see that it has a very fast sharp onset.
The red one is the so-called photo-to-current efficiency.
Its onset is also in the bandgap,
but its increase is significantly slower.
That means in visible light,
at 500 to 800 nm,
in this visible light area,
a lot of light can be absorbed,
but it can't be used as a photo-to-current.
At the same time, in the sub-bandgap,
we see a relatively small absorption peak.
We will come back to discuss what this is later.
We say that these oxidizing materials,
especially the common limitation of super-resistant oxidizing materials,
is the so-called bulk recombination.
Why is it like this?
If we look at these super-resistant metals,
we look at its band structure,
its 3D orbital is not fully filled.
If we use the general band theory to look at it,
it should actually be a metal material.
Why are these oxidizing materials a semiconductor,
even though it is a super-resistant material?
That's because these electrons have strong interactions with each other.
That means that because of these interactions,
our metal 3D band will split into the so-called sub-band and sub-band.
At the same time, we have oxides in the oxidizing material.
So depending on the oxygen 2P band
is in a place with lower energy
or a place with higher energy,
we can have these two types of insulators.
One is the Moharber insulator,
which means that the sub-band and sub-band are all metal 3D.
Or the sub-band is metal oxygen 2P
and the sub-band is metal 3D.
No matter which type,
in these oxidizing materials,
because they are, how to put it,
compared to the traditional silicon or 3-5 group semiconductors,
the characteristics of these oxidizing materials are that
although they are also semiconductors,
but our electrons have to pass through them.
Because these oxidizing materials are more ionic,
we have,
so the electrons have to jump around in different atoms.
For example, in this case in the upper right corner,
our electrons have to jump around in different metal atoms.
And the electrons have to jump around in different oxygen atoms.
This means that our electrons are very localized.
In the process of localization,
it will also change the structure of the metal around it.
It means that the structure will be a little different.
What does this affect?
It means that their mobility will be worse.
Just like in ordinary silicon,
it doesn't have this localized electron problem.
It's like going for a walk in the wild.
Basically, no one will stop you.
You can go wherever you want.
In these oxidizing materials,
for example, there are a lot of people in Simending.
If you want to go to a place,
it means that the people you want to go to
have to leave a space for you to go there.
It means that in the process of walking,
the environment around you will also change with you.
Of course, the mobility will be much lower.
We think that these oxidizing materials have poor charge mobility.
At the same time, for this reason,
we have a lot of bulk recombination.
How do we prove this hypothesis?
At the beginning, after oxidation,
the electromagnetic electron localized
to produce the so-called polaron.
This process is very fast.
So we want to use the so-called
phantocyclic contraction absorption
to observe this phenomenon.
Basically, a very typical measurement is like this.
First, we use a very short pump pulse
to produce an oxidized state.
Because the oxidized state
has a different electronic arrangement from the machine,
so its absorption of different light will also be different.
We can use the second probing
to measure the difference in absorption
of different oxidized states.
We can change the delay between the pump and probe,
so that we can follow
how it relaxes after producing the oxidized state.
But this method is basically
applied to the liquid state at the beginning.
We found that we are now
studying solid materials.
So in addition to the so-called transmission,
we also have to consider reflectivity.
This means that we have to measure
the so-called transmission, transmission,
and transmission reflectivity at the same time.
I skipped some details,
but the point is that
if we measure transmission and reflectivity at the same time,
we can return to the so-called differential absorption.
In the case of solid materials,
we can see this kind of
first-order or third-order
differential signal.
This is because different absorption oscillators
are either produced by shift
or oscillators by broadening.
This is how we used another material
to build this analysis.
Back to our carbon monoxide,
this is our transmission absorption data.
We can see that there are many changes
in the area near the interwebbing gap and the interwebbing gap.
At the same time, in the sub-webbing gap,
that is, in the infrared part,
there is a very flat absorption.
This is the so-called free carrier absorption,
which means that after being absorbed,
the free carrier absorption will appear in this area.
This free carrier absorption is actually very short-lived.
In about 1 picosecond,
this signal disappears.
At the same time,
for example,
near the interwebbing gap,
there is a relatively long-lived excited state.
We think this is indirect evidence that
our free carrier localizes
and produces a polaron state.
This means that after 1 picosecond,
we don't have a real free carrier,
but a polaron.
These polarons can still be charged transport,
but their mobility is relatively much lower.
Next, about the so-called electronic structure,
we first have a cooperation,
using the DFT plus U method to calculate,
to calculate the electronic structure according to the crystal structure.
The middle part of 0 is the Fermi level.
The low energy part on the left is the so-called valence band.
We see that from the calculation process,
at the top of the valence band,
the closest to the valence band edge is
mainly the copper 3D electron.
The lower part is the oxygen.
The lower part is the so-called iron 3D.
In the conduction band part,
there are two bands, iron 3D.
The higher part is copper.
We want to do an experiment to verify the calculation structure.
The first experiment is to use the so-called XPS.
It means that we use an X-ray
to isolate the valence band electron.
According to the analysis of these photoelectron's
kinetic energy,
we can return the binding energy in the material.
We can see that there are four peaks.
The two peaks at the top are
similar to the copper in the calculation result.
The next two peaks are
similar to the oxygen and iron.
You may ask,
why does the ratio in the experiment
look different from the calculation?
That's because in the experiment,
the ionization cross-section of the X-ray
is different for different elements.
In our experiment,
the ionization cross-section of the copper
is much higher than that of the oxygen or iron.
This explains why in our experiment,
the intensity of the two peaks at the top
is much higher than the other two peaks.
We can also use the so-called X-ray emission.
That means we also use the X-ray,
but now we isolate the electron.
Let's see how the electron of the valence band
returns the binding energy.
In the process of returning the binding energy,
we will emit an X-ray beam.
We can analyze the beam of the X-ray beam
to get the distribution of the valence band.
Here we see that in the oxygen,
the K-edge X-ray emission,
we also see four peaks.
In this process,
because we are looking at the co-level excitation of oxygen,
of course,
when the valence band is returned,
what we see is that
more electrons are returned from oxygen.
That's why we see that
the intensity of the peak in the middle is higher.
This is the valence band.
The conduction band,
in the calculation process,
we see that the two lowest conduction bands are iron,
mainly from the unoccupied iron orbital.
We use the X-ray absorption spectroscopy.
In this method,
we measure from the co-level
to the unoccupied conduction band level.
Then we can change the input X-ray energy
to see how much light can be absorbed.
We can compare.
For example, in oxidized iron,
we see two peaks.
This is because
for iron,
it is also a triangular iron.
There are six ions around it.
It is an octahedral structure.
So we can see that the 3D orbital of iron
is split into 1G and T2G levels.
In carbon monoxide,
we also see these two peaks
at the same energy.
At a higher level,
we find a new peak.
According to our calculations,
this may be produced
from the same unoccupied orbital.
We can also do this calculation.
This is also done with DFT,
using the many-body X-ray absorption calculation.
We can almost reproduce these three peaks.
We can also choose
from the calculation results.
These three different peaks
correspond to different final states.
We can see that the first peak
is the non-bonding state of oxygen and iron.
The second peak
is also the anti-bonding state between oxygen and iron.
The highest energy peak
is the anti-bonding state of copper and oxygen.
This means that we not only
verified that our calculations were correct,
but also that the two lower peaks
were contributed by iron,
while the highest peak was contributed by copper.
We can understand how different peaks
or different conduction bands
interact with each other.
How do we verify this?
We can combine the different X-ray spectrums
into the so-called
Resonance in Elastic X-ray Scattering.
Basically, we use different X-ray spectrums
to stimulate an electron
from the core level to the conduction band.
But we can also change the energy of the injected X-ray.
We can analyze
the X-ray emission
from the valence band.
What are the different changes?
This is also done in the advanced slide source of Berkeley.
Our sample is placed here.
We have a green X-ray.
We are analyzing the energy of the X-ray emission.
If you still remember,
two slides ago,
we said this is the K-H X-ray emission of oxygen.
The middle peak
is the contribution from oxygen to P
in the valence band.
The so-called RIGS data
is the same measurement,
but we change the different excitation energy.
The diagram looks a bit complicated,
but the X-axis is the same X-ray emission.
The Y-axis is the different excitation energy.
When we change the excitation energy,
the shape of the X-ray emission changes a lot.
In the first part, we can see the emission onset.
When we increase the excitation energy,
it moves to a higher energy level.
This means our material is an indirect semiconductor.
Why?
In our direct semiconductor,
the valence band maximum and condensation minimum
are in the same K-space.
When we increase the excitation energy,
the X-ray emission moves to a lower energy level.
But in the indirect semiconductor,
the valence band maximum and condensation minimum
are separated.
When we increase the excitation energy,
the X-ray emission moves to a higher energy level.
This is what we observe here.
At the same time,
we can see some other changes.
For example, when we emit at these two peaks,
we can see that the peak at the low energy level is more obvious.
But when we move to the third peak,
we can't see this peak.
Instead, we can see another sharp peak at the high energy level.
This means that when we emit at this peak,
we are emitting at an unoccupied copper state.
This means that our X-ray emission
will have more copper 3D characters in the valence band.
In other words, when we emit at two low-energy peaks,
we see our own emission and lower-energy iron 3D emission.
But when we emit at the third peak,
which is the so-called unoccupied copper state,
we will see more copper 3D emission.
This can explain the different changes we see.
This means that we not only know
that we are an indirect semiconductor.
The bandgap is 1.4 eV.
We also know that our valence band is copper.
Our conduction band minimum is iron.
This is a so-called metal-to-metal charge transfer semiconductor.
We can also do a similar measurement at the so-called iron L-edge.
In this method, we see that
X-ray emission and excitation energy are closely related.
In this method, we can see that
the first diagonal line is the so-called elastic scattering.
This means that it is the same energy as the X-ray emission.
So basically nothing happens.
But in the parallel direction,
we can see that there are two or three diagonal peaks.
This means that no matter what X-ray excitation energy we use,
we all have a fixed energy loss.
This is the same principle as our optical Raman scattering.
In Raman, this fixed energy loss tells us
what is the energy of the lattice vibration.
In this technique, this fixed energy loss tells us some different information.
How do we explain it?
We can also compare these different X-ray emissions.
This is not absolute X-ray emission energy,
but how much energy loss there is in the following.
In other words, we use a diagonal method to align these emissions.
We see that there are three fixed energy losses.
The first is about one electron volt.
That is, no matter what energy we use to excite,
we lose a fixed electron volt.
Why is this?
This is the configuration of our ground state.
It has five electrons and a high-spin configuration.
When we do an X-ray excitation,
we have a cold hole.
So we have an electric current at 2P.
We have an extra electron in 3D.
When it returns to the final state,
it can return to its original state.
That is, there is no energy loss.
Or it can return to a quadrilateral state.
This means that this energy loss is equivalent to
a spin from our ground state.
This electron volt energy loss
represents a TD excitation energy loss.
If you remember,
when we measured the absorption of light on both sides,
there was a small peak at the South Bank.
It was at about 1,200 nanometers.
If you convert it to the energy scale,
it is actually an electron volt.
This means that in practice,
we can actually observe this very weak absorption.
Then there are two other fans.
What is the reason for this?
This is also the so-called intermediate state.
At first, we put an electron in the iron conduction band.
Then we have an electric current.
This intermediate state is actually coupling with other intermediate states.
That means that when it returns to the final state,
what we see can be a charge transfer from oxygen to iron,
or a charge transfer from copper to iron.
When they return to the final state,
the energy difference from the initial state to the final state
will reflect the energy loss here.
The first one we see is about negative five to negative six electron volts.
Compared with our calculation results,
it is a charge transfer from oxygen to iron.
The energy loss in the middle is about two to four electron volts.
It is actually several peaks coupled together.
If we compare it with our optical absorption,
we can see that there are three peaks.
If we compare them,
they can basically be put together.
That means that the energy loss peak in the middle,
which is about three electron volts,
is mainly due to the charge transfer from copper to iron.
This energy loss can also be compared with our optical absorption.
In conclusion,
we used the Reactive Spotter to prepare this series of samples.
We can separate the so-called impurity phase and morphology.
We learned that
carbon dioxide itself does not have CO2 reduction activity.
This activity is mainly due to the fact that
when we have more copper,
the oxidized carbon dioxide acts as a catalyst.
We used a lot of different X-ray optical methods
to understand its electron structure.
We found that its valence band is mainly of copper 3D nature,
and the connection band is of iron 3D nature.
This means that
if we look at the structure of the metal,
we can see that it is a layer by layer structure of copper oxide or iron oxide.
This means that if we can control the direction of the growth of the metal
on the magnetic back,
maybe we can more efficiently separate the electrons and electrons
by using the Reactive Spotter.
If we can control the direction of the growth of the metal in a regular way.
Okay, I think it's about time.
Do you have any questions about this part?
Thank you, Chang-Ming, for the wonderful speech.
I'm going to stop the recording here,
and then we can start the Q&A.