Thank you, Dr. He Wei-Ching, for giving us an online lecture.
My host today is me, I am Jay Chou.
I am currently working as a postdoc at MD Anderson Cancer Center.
Today I will introduce some of Dr. He Wei-Ching's background.
Dr. He Wei-Ching received her master's degree from the Department of Life Sciences, National Taiwan University, from 2004 to 2008.
She then received her master's degree from the Institute of Zoology, National Taiwan University, from 2008 to 2010.
After receiving her master's degree, she worked as a research assistant at the Department of Life Sciences for one year.
From 2011 to 2017, she received her Ph.D. degree from the Department of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology at the University of Michigan.
After receiving her Ph.D. degree, she is currently working as a postdoc research associate at the Center for the Mechanism of Evolution,
and a postdoc research associate at the Biodesign Institute, Arizona State University.
Today, I am honored to invite Dr. He Wei-Ching to give us an online lecture.
Her topic is Understanding Biology by Replaying the Type of Life, Experimental Evolution of the E. coli as an Example.
Let's welcome Dr. He Wei-Ching to give us an online lecture.
Thank you for the introduction, and thank you, Tara, for giving me the opportunity to share my recent research with you.
I am a biophysicist, and my main concern is to study the diversity of life, how it evolves, and how we can predict the evolution of life.
Today, I am going to share with you some of the experiments that I am doing in the lab, using E. coli as a model species.
I am a postdoc at Arizona State University.
We all know that biodiversity is very diverse in this world.
This problem also confuses many biophysicists.
How do these biodiversity evolve?
Normally, many biophysicists go to the wild to observe these different forms of life, and then try to find some similarities with the different environmental factors in the wild.
Can you explain how these diversities evolve?
However, such research is usually difficult because there are too many environmental factors in the wild, so sometimes the researchers do not know which one to look at.
Therefore, it would be easier for everyone to study the evolution of biodiversity in a situation where there is a better control of mutations.
In this situation, the famous ancient biologist Stephen Jay Gould wrote the book Wonderful Life.
This book mainly talks about the evolution of biodiversity related to the Cambrian explosion in the Berger scale.
More importantly, he proposed an experimental idea in this book.
In other words, if you can see so many diversities on Earth, we will begin to think about whether the biodiversity in the biological world is a natural result of evolution or just a random result.
To distinguish whether it is a natural result or a random result, an experiment may be helpful to explain this.
If you can press a button to wash away the previous biological evolution process to the very, very beginning stage, then you keep pressing the play button,
and every time you press the play button, you will see if the biological evolution will have the same result.
If this happens repeatedly, it means that the diversity we see is a natural result of evolution, not a random result.
At the time of this idea, he said in the book that he was very sad, because in fact this kind of experiment can only be thought of, and there is no way to do it.
However, in recent years, due to the development of experimental technologies in the laboratory and the progress of various molecular technologies, many people have tried to do so-called experimental evolution in the laboratory.
In the process of experimental evolution, we can repeat many times of evolution and do it in a better environment.
The most famous experimental evolution is Richard Alensky's E. coli long-term experimental evolution.
This is Richard Alensky and his E. coli long-term population.
He started doing this experiment in 1988, and so far there have been more than 60,000 generations.
He put the E. coli in the Glucose Minimum Media and passed it on to the new media every day.
When he started this experiment, he had a total of 12 parallel populations, so he repeated the evolution process 12 times.
Over the course of more than 20 years of evolution, his laboratory sent a lot of documents to introduce what happened to his E. coli.
In his reports on different phenotypes and genotypes, he also found different levels of repetition.
For example, in all of his populations, he saw an increase in fitness and even an increase in cell size.
He argued that this may be related to nutrient acquisition.
However, in all of his populations, he only observed that half of the population would evolve to a higher rate of mutation.
What he found more novel was that in all 12 populations, there was one population that evolved to use another chemical in the environment, citrate, as a carbon source of nutrient composition.
At the same time, he also observed some parallelism on genotypes, which means that some mutations are easier to detect than other mutations.
At the same time, he also saw that within this population, they began to form population structures.
However, after these discoveries, we have to ask, because he was only doing this in the same environment.
If we want to fully understand how to predict the results of a mutation, we are not sure whether the phenomena he observed only occurred in the environment he started or in the bacteria he used.
What is more important is that there are many different types of evolutionary forces in the process of mutation.
Different evolutionary forces have different types, some of which will lead to de-mutation, some of which will lead to evolution, and so on.
If we want to better understand the predictability of mutation, we will want to understand that these different evolutionary forces are related to different types of mutations.
In the process of evolution, there are many different forces that will result in evolution.
The most famous is the natural selection. The natural selection will lead to deterministic results, and the deterministic results will lead to deterministic results.
In the process of evolution, there are many different forces that will result in evolution. The most famous is the natural selection.
The natural selection will lead to deterministic results, because if your genotype is higher than the fitness of other genotypes, the genotype will spread faster in the population.
However, evolution is not only the natural selection of a force. Many other forces are also very important, and they play a random role.
For example, mutation is the most basic force of evolution. Without mutation, it is basically impossible to produce a new shape.
Another force is recombination. Recombination allows different species to get a new combination of genetic material.
Another force, genetic drift, will also cause random changes.
Here are some examples of genetic drift.
Basically, genetic drift is the change in the frequency of genetic material in the evolution process of life.
You can imagine that there are some unpredictable factors in the evolution process, such as natural disasters that cause population size changes.
Interestingly, if the population size is smaller in the genetic drift effect, the genetic drift effect will be stronger.
Sometimes it will be so strong that the natural selection effect is overshadowed.
The following two graphs are simulation results.
This graph simulates the frequency of genetic mutations as the number of generations increases.
If there are only 20 individuals in this group, you will see that after the 10th and 20th generations, the mutation may jump from the original 0.5 frequency to 1.
This means that the entire population has this variation, or this variation is gone when the frequency of its variation becomes 0.
However, if the population size is 2000, you will see that the frequency of its variation is very small.
What is the significance of this in evolution?
It is because sometimes, as we just said, in the evolution process of the population, it may encounter some natural disasters or other environmental changes that cause the decline in the population size.
So there is a very famous example of genetic drift called the bottleneck effect.
As shown in this graph, if the population size is very large at the very beginning on the far left, then the balls of different colors seem to be different genetic variations.
At the beginning, the genetic composition may be very consistent.
However, when the population size begins to decline, you can imagine that only a small number of balls are drawn from many, many balls.
At this time, the genetic composition will change significantly.
When the population size decreases more and more, the frequency of genetic variation will change even more.
For example, in the end, you will find that the red part has gone from 20% to 70%.
Because there are different forces in the evolution process, we have carried out a lot of different experiments in the Lynch Lab where I am now.
We want to test whether the evolution forces of different species will change the evolution results.
In particular, we pay special attention to the impact of the mutation rate and the population bottlenecks.
In addition, we also want to try to see what would happen if the experimental evolution was carried out in a more complex environment.
In the previous Lynch Lab evolution process, the environment was relatively monotonous, with only glucose as its carbon source.
In our experimental design, we first chose a more complex cultivator, the LB cultivator.
In the LB cultivator, there are many different amino acids that can be used as the source of carbon.
In addition, we do not use the tracing bottle for experiments, but use the lynch lab for experiments.
When doing experiments in the lynch lab, you can imagine that there may be some differences in the degree of T in the entire lynch lab.
For example, the concentration of oxygen may be higher at the top and lower at the bottom.
We use this method to make the experimental environment more complex.
In addition, we want to know the impact of the mutation rate on the experimental results.
Therefore, we tried to use different genetic backgrounds to carry out the experimental evolution.
We used the MUTEL gene in the wild type LB cultivator.
Previous experiments have shown that if there is this gene, the mutation rate will increase by 150 times.
The reason for this is that MUTEL is a very important molecule in the mismatch repair, as shown in the figure on the right.
That is, when there is a mismatch in the DNA, for example, G should not be paired with T.
When this mismatch is detected by MUTEL and MUTX, it will recruit MUTH and other pathways to do DNA repair and put the correct pairing back.
This is why the mutation rate will increase by more than 150 times after MUTEL is deleted.
At the same time, if it is in the usual wild type environment, you can imagine that its mutation rate is very low, about 10 to the minus 10 per base per generation.
At the same time, we also used different dilution factors in the experimental setup.
We have just introduced the start of different genetic backgrounds.
For each genetic background, we also tried three different bottleneck sizes.
Next, I will use small, medium, and large to represent different bottleneck sizes.
But the actual dilution factor is listed here.
If it is the smallest bottleneck, there will be one-tenth of the population entering the new tube from the old cultivator to the new cultivator tube every day.
You can imagine that only one-tenth of the original population size will enter the new tube.
If it is medium, it is one-fourth of 10.
The strongest bottleneck is one-tenth of 10.
Because we want to see if the results of different bottlenecks are repetitive,
we have eight repetitions in each genetic background and dilution factor treatment.
This experiment has been carried out in Lynch Lab for three or four years.
Today, I would like to share with you the results of the 900th day dilution.
The first question is, after 900 days, is their adaptability better than before?
To answer this question, our strategy is to do a competition assay.
The logic is quite simple.
At the beginning, we took some of the evolved population and some of the ancestor population.
After putting them in the same tube and mixing them, we immediately measured the ratio between them.
After 24 hours, let them compete with each other inside and then measure the ratio again.
In this way, we have the later ratio and the earlier ratio.
By comparing these two ratios, we can know how much the fitness of the evolved population has improved compared to the ancestor population.
Then we do this to different parallel populations of different treatments.
This is the result of the experiment.
On the x-axis, we have some different treatments with different numbers.
Different treatments, such as whether the population bottleneck size is small or large,
or whether the genetic background is the high-transmission rate of MMR- or wild type, are listed above.
The y-axis is the fitness improvement relative to ancestor.
We measured at least three populations for each treatment,
and at least three replicates for each evolved line.
This result shows that after doing the two-way ANOVA test,
we found that different genetic backgrounds did not have a significant impact.
But the bottleneck size has a significant impact.
From this graph, we can see that if the bottleneck size is medium or large,
the fitness improvement is actually very small, much smaller than the small population bottleneck.
This is calculated.
Because we see the fitness improvement, we want to ask if the genetic material changes are consistent with the fitness changes.
During the experiment, we did a high-throughput sequencing every 100 days.
After doing the high-throughput DNA sequencing,
we used the Briseeq software to derive the allele frequency.
Briseeq was developed to map the Lenski Long-Term Experimental Evolution software.
After the map was derived, we measured the amount of mutation for each time point.
The amount of mutation was used to add up the derived allele frequency.
In addition, because the population bottleneck size is different in different treatments,
it is possible that the bacteria that pass through the evolution process are different in generation.
During the experiment, we found that no matter how small or large the bottleneck is,
it can grow back to the maximum possible number of the population in one day.
So we use this to estimate the generation number of bacteria.
The smallest 1 over 10 dilution factor is calculated to be about 3.3 generations per day.
The largest population bottleneck can reach 23 generations per day.
After obtaining these data, we plot them on this graph.
On this graph, the x-axis shows the number of generations,
and 1000 is the unit.
The y-axis shows the number of mutations.
SNP stands for Single Nucleotide Polymorphism.
We take the average between different parallel experimental evolutions.
You can see that the amount of mutation is very linear.
Next, we want to compare the different treatments.
Is there a difference in the speed of accumulation of the number of mutations on the gene?
The B in each treatment graph is the regression slope.
If we compare the MMR minus, which is a higher mutation rate,
with the wild type, which is a lower mutation rate,
and compare them with the same population bottleneck size,
the MMR minus is higher.
However, the higher MMR minus is only 4 to 20 times higher,
less than 150 times higher than the initial mutation rate.
If we compare the different population bottlenecks,
we will find that the higher the population bottleneck size,
the lower the accumulation rate of mutations on the gene.
Can I ask a question?
Sure.
The MMR mutation rate is 150 times higher than the wild type.
Yes.
Is there any experiment that can prove that the MMR minus
has a higher mutation rate than the wild type?
Is there any experiment that can prove that the MMR minus has a higher mutation rate than the wild type?
Yes.
First of all, they look similar, but the Y-axis is different.
I forgot to mention this.
You can see that the Y-axis is 10 times higher than the wild type.
Although the mutation rate looks the same on the graph,
the MMR minus mutation rate is 10 times higher than the wild type.
The MMR minus mutation rate is 10 times higher than the wild type.
Is there any experiment that can prove that the MMR mutation rate is 150 times higher than the wild type?
Yes.
At the beginning, when I was talking about the MMR minus genetic background,
I didn't say it very clearly.
In fact, 150 times is the result of the experiment.
I guess I will talk about the method of experiment testing in the next slide.
The method of experiment testing is the so-called universal accumulation experiment.
We call it the mutation accumulation experiment.
In the process of this experiment, we will raise these bacteria in the same way.
But in the process of raising, we give it a very strong bottleneck.
That is to say, every time we pass it on, we only pick one colony to pass on.
So you can imagine that unless the mutation kills the bacteria,
otherwise all mutations can be retained in the bacteria.
In the process of this mutation accumulation experiment,
it is passed on for more than 60 days with only one colony left every day.
In this way, you can know how many new mutations have occurred after 60 days.
Then the new mutation is divided by the number of generations and the mutation rate is obtained.
The mutation rate mentioned in the first slide,
For example, the 10 to the power of 10 times per base pair per generation,
is measured like this.
In today's presentation, we have used another faster way.
We will discuss this later.
At the same time, we are also using the mutation accumulation method
to measure the evolved mutation rate.
Indeed, as I mentioned earlier,
there is a very intuitive explanation,
that is, the mutation rate dropped during the evolution process,
and our data also shows this.
This is what I just explained.
In the experiment process,
there is another group of experiments to measure the evolved mutation rate.
This is the so-called mutation accumulation experiment.
There are many parallel experiments.
The point is that every time we transfer,
we lose a very, very strong population bottleneck.
There is probably only one group.
Then we have to try to keep all the mutations.
So after this process,
we can imagine,
we can use host-genome sequencing to see how many mutations there are.
Then we can measure the mutation rate.
This kind of mutation rate should be the evolution rate of the genome.
If the following things are correct,
first, if the mutation rate has not changed,
second, if there is no subpopulation structure.
Because if there is a subpopulation structure,
it will limit the number of mutations in each new genome
to the extent that it cannot spread to the entire group.
So the evolution rate is also reduced.
In addition, we have to assume that
if all the mutations do not kill the bacteria,
it has no effect on fitness.
Because in the previous paper,
I have measured the mutation rate of MAR- and wild-type.
Then in this picture,
I drew it on the virtual line.
That is to say, the virtual line means
if the assumption was established before,
that is, the evolution rate has not changed,
then all the mutations have no effect on fitness,
and then there is no subpopulation structure,
then we would expect to see
so many mutations shown on the virtual line.
But we can see that
in the virtual expectation
and the actual color line observation,
the actual evolution rate observed by MAR-
is lower than the virtual line.
On the other hand, the wild-type is actually higher.
So there are some different hypotheses
to explain this.
Hello, I have another question.
Is the virtual line and the actual line
experimental environment completely identical?
Yes, they are all LB.
And they are all column-shaped bottles.
Yes, this is a bit different.
Because in the MAR-experiment,
the method of transmission,
because we have to pick the single colony,
so it is done on the side plate.
This may be a bit different.
I see.
Yes, so there is a possible assumption that
the MAR-line has a lower mutation rate,
while the wild-type has a higher mutation rate,
which may explain this.
This picture is mainly to say
that the phenomenon we just saw
is not caused by one or two lines.
If I draw the slope of each line,
you will find that they are actually quite consistent.
For example, in the MAR-line,
each block is a different parallel population.
Then you will find that they are all lower than the virtual line.
The virtual line is the expected rate in the MA-experiment.
In the wild-type, each one is higher.
So the average phenomenon just now
is not just caused by one or two lines.
It is a very broad phenomenon.
Another interesting point is
if you look closely,
in the wild-type background,
the smallest is the small dilution factor.
You will find that there are two or three points
where the outlier is divided into two groups.
This means that
during the evolution process,
the two points at the top,
the two parallel populations,
may have evolved a high mutation rate
compared to others.
In the method of measuring the mutation rate,
in addition to the MA-experiment just mentioned,
there is another method called the fluctuation test.
This method will be faster
because it does not need to go through
several months of generation and cultivation.
In the end, there is no need for high-throughput sequencing.
But it will be less accurate.
The principle of this fluctuation test is
if the line at the beginning
is antibiotic-sensitive,
then
if it encounters antibiotics,
these will die.
Like these blue and black dots.
Then,
if we start cultivating
the same group of bacteria
with different tubes,
you can imagine that
they will each produce a new mutation
because they start to reproduce themselves.
In the process of reproduction,
they may get a new mutation.
In these new mutations,
some of them will cause the bacteria
to gain the ability of antibiotic resistance.
In this picture,
there are those white dots.
Then,
after several generations,
after a period of reproduction,
we will put the bacteria inside
on the plate of the antibiotic cultivator
to calculate
how many colonies there are.
This means
how many new individuals
have antibiotic resistance.
We can compare different bacteria.
If more colonies are found
at the end of the test,
it means that
the potential mutation rate is higher.
So,
the method of
measuring the mutation rate
is to use
the reprimising antibiotic
to measure.
Then,
we took some
clones that had just evolved
to do the experiment.
Then,
we also did the
ancestor test.
We also did the
ancestor mutation rate test.
It is worth noting that
the mutation rate here is not the previous
per base pair per generation.
It is a mutation rate
related to antibiotic resistance.
However,
we can still compare the relative changes between them.
We found that in the MMR-line,
the ancestor mutation rate
is actually
about 10 to the power of 6.
However,
in the Evolv-line,
we found that
the mutation rate is reduced
by about 20 to 40 times,
as shown in the figure.
However, in the wild type,
this phenomenon is not obvious.
You can see that their
error bars are basically overlapped.
Or,
in some cases,
the mutation rate is very large.
So, we think
that the wild type mutation rate
may not have much change
in these lines.
The change is relatively small.
However, in the ML-line,
the mutation rate is low.
This may be
one of the explanations for the phenomenon.
Of course,
this is just a few lines.
We are currently measuring
more lines.
Another possible factor
is the stop-population structure.
The stop-population structure
is actually
what the researchers
in the Lynch Lab
found before.
They found that
if the environment of the tube
is used,
it is easy to cause
a mutation.
It is a bit like
what is shown in this picture.
At first, the bacteria
may be in a plantonic state,
which means that
it can incubate inside.
However, after the mutation,
some bacteria may develop
and form a biological membrane
on the surface.
In this case,
it will cause
a difference in the structure of the group.
Previously,
in the long-term
E. coli evolution
of Richard Lenski,
they developed
the Hidden Markov Model
to see
how the
stop-population structure
in the population
changes.
He used
the Hidden Markov Model
to assume
that
different mutations
in the population
may be in different clades.
He assumed that
there is a major clade
and a minor clade.
The Hidden Markov Chain
assumes that
a mutation
can change
the frequency
in the basal clade,
major clade,
or minor clade
in the basal clade.
On the left,
this is a very complicated picture.
He used
the Hidden Markov Chain Model
to identify
some mutations,
as shown in the above picture,
that can
successfully spread
to the entire population
by increasing
the allele frequency
to 1.
However,
these mutations
may have
substructure evidence
in the population.
I did the same
analysis of the
Markov Chain Model.
I used
the analysis
to estimate
how long
the two
mutations
in the basal clade
and the minor clade
and the major clade
can be observed.
In this picture,
there are different
population bottlenecks
and different genetic backgrounds.
The histogram
is the distribution
of coexistence time.
We found that
ML-
tends to
have longer
clade
and
is marginally
significant.
It is possible that
the ML-
bottlenecks
make the population
structure
more likely to occur,
which causes
the evolutionary rate
to be less than
the initial
ancestor mutation
of the
ML-
clade.
Next,
we are going to
look at
the nature selection effect.
When we look at
the nature selection effect,
we tend to look at
different pore mutations.
Different pore mutations
have different
perception of
nature selection.
Different DNA
sequences
produce different
protein sequences.
We call some mutations
synonymous mutations.
This means that
although the DNA sequence
changes,
the protein sequence
does not change.
For example,
in this green example,
G becomes A,
but it is still glycine.
Because it changes
in the first place of the codon,
the original glycine
becomes arginine.
So you can imagine that
if this non-synonymous mutation
causes a change in the amino
acid sequence,
this mutation
may cause
a stronger nature selection
because it changes the protein sequence,
which will negatively affect the protein function.
In the analysis,
we only focus on
non-synonymous mutations,
which may cause
a change in the protein function.
Then,
we need to detect
this parallelism mutation.
The method we use is
G-score.
Here is a simple example.
For example,
there are
gene A,
gene B,
gene C,
and then
there are six replicates
in the experiment.
Then
each gene may have
ten
non-synonymous sites.
If
this parallelism
does not favor any gene,
like the example here,
there are two, two, two.
Then
we can calculate
this G-score will be zero.
So when the G-score is very low,
it means
that no gene
is particularly easy to be mutated.
But the following example
shows that if a certain gene
is easy to be mutated,
such as gene A,
like this example,
there are also six mutations in total,
but these six mutations
only occur in A,
but not in B and C.
If these six mutations
occur in A,
the final result
will make the G-score very high.
That is to say,
the high or low G-score
can tell us
whether certain genes
are particularly easy to mutate.
There are some different
biological meanings
to explain the higher G-score
we see.
For example,
if a gene
has a relatively strong
beneficial effect,
it is easier to be retained
in the selection.
Then it may show
a higher G-score.
It is also possible that
there are a lot of mutations
in that gene
that have beneficial effects.
But in addition to
beneficial effects
and natural selection-related results,
it is also possible
that there are different mutations
in different genome regions.
Therefore,
in order to
really observe
the effect of natural selection,
we only consider
fixed mutations.
The so-called fixed mutations
are those mutations
that have spread
throughout the entire group.
Such mutations
are usually not just
a bias,
but they can spread
within the group.
Another point is
how many total
non-senitive mutations
will affect
the G-score itself.
In this picture,
if we simulate the G-score
and start with some different numbers,
you will find that
the higher the number
of G-scores,
the higher the G-score itself.
Therefore,
when we compare,
we can't just observe the G-score.
We also need to use
how many mutations
to simulate
and compare the value of observation
and the value of simulation.
So this picture is
the result of gene-level parallelism.
The triangle part
is the actual observed
G-score.
The histogram part
is the simulation part.
Based on the simulated distribution
and the observed value,
we can calculate the Z-value.
The Z-value
tells us
how significant
the gene-level parallelism is.
The higher the value,
the more significant it is.
In this result,
we can see that
first of all,
the MR-value
has more gene-level parallelism.
It may be because
the mutation rate is higher,
so it may be able to
search for more mutations,
resulting in a stronger selection effect.
At the same time,
we can only see
if a single gene
shows a strong G-score.
This picture
is the result of
the statistical test.
So we have listed
some different genes
that show
an effect on
gene-level parallelism.
Then we can
analyze
the special
clustering function
of these genes.
We have obtained
several possible candidates,
such as those with special
enzyme activity
or those
related to
transcription regulation.
Interestingly,
some genes
are identified
as being
gene-level parallelism.
For example,
FinH, FinE, FinB, FinG
are all related to
type I fibrillate structure
or regulation.
In E.coli,
type I fibrillate
is related to
stress response
and mobility.
Perhaps these genes
can help
E.coli
to grow.
After identifying
these genes,
our next goal
is to test
whether these genes
can increase
E.coli fitness.
We also detected
some nucleotide-level
parallelism.
This is
the nucleotide-level
parallelism
distribution.
X-axis
shows
how many nucleotide
mutations can be seen
in different parallel
experiments.
There are also
different population
bottleneck sizes
and different genetic backgrounds.
We also found
nucleotide-level
parallelism.
In other words,
mutations
such as point mutations
can be observed
in different parallel
experiments.
These are
potential
and important
adaptive mutations.
This also
provides
a target
for verification
in the next experiment.
For example,
we can make a point map
to map these nucleotides
to see if they are
really increasing
in our
experimental conditions.
In short,
we tested
many different
genetic backgrounds
and different
population bottleneck sizes.
We tried to
understand
whether the different
phenotypes
in different
genetic backgrounds
or in different
stronger bottlenecks
can also show
parallelism.
Will the level of
parallelism change?
The results show
that
although the
level of
parallelism
is lower than the
genetic background,
the rate of
mutation
is lower
than the genetic background.
This may be because
most mutations
are not good
for the individual.
If the
mutation rate is
high,
the
mutation rate
will be
affected
negatively
by the
genetic background.
Maybe
the
effect of
genetic background
will make
the
mutation rate
lower.
We also found that
the MR-
line
tends to
evolve
population
substructure.
This
part of the
hypothesis
may be because
the evolution
of population
substructure
may
require
different
types of
mutations
to
cause
different
mutations
in the
population.
Different
mutations
in different
places
may have
different
collaborations.
For example,
in
biofilm,
some
individuals
may secrete
nutrients
that
may be
needed
by other
individuals.
If the
total mutation
rate is
higher,
different
individuals
may
have
this
collaboration
related
mutation.
However,
although
the
MR-
mutation
rate
is higher,
it
does not
cause
the
population
fitness
difference.
A
stronger
bottleneck
size
will
reduce
the
fitness
evolve
rate
and
the
genome
evolve
rate.
In
addition,
we can
also see
the
genotypic
parallelism
above.
Whether
it is
gene level
or
single
nucleotide
level,
these
provide
us
with
experiments
to
see
whether
these
genes
or
these
mutations
can
make
the
large
intestinal
bacteria
more
adaptable
in
LB.
In
this
experiment,
we
are
testing
different
mutating
forces
and
related
factors.
In
fact,
there are
many
different
replay
life
tape
experiments.
Panel
A is
the most
basic
experiment
with
many
parallel
genes.
But
there are
also
other
proposals.
For example,
in the
process of
evolution,
you
take
different
evolution
results
from
different
times
and
see
if
each
evolution
point
has an
effect
on
each
evolution
process.
You
move it
to another
environment
and
see if
the
first
evolution
has
an
effect
on
the
second
evolution.
In
addition,
there are
more
professional
evolutions
trying to
bring the
environment
closer to
the
real
world.
For
example,
there is
a
lot of
time
to
add
interactions
between
different
species.
For
example,
some
put
the
sperm
and
algae
together
to
co-evolve.
There
is also
a
more
popular
way
to
make
the
environment
closer
to the
real
world.
At
the same
time,
we as
evolution
biologists
want to
improve the
predictability
of evolution
models,
but
the
analysis I
did
was
very
linear.
We
saw
evolutionary
outcomes,
and we
used
regression
or statistical
methods
to see
whether
these
factors
have
prediction
power.
This
is my
top-down
approach.
I see
outcomes,
and I
want to
correlate
them
with
different
factors.
I
think
this
is
my
bottom-up
approach.
For
example,
I
start
with
biophysical
or
biochemical
properties,
and if
I know
how
each
mutation
affects
fitness,
I
will
get
the
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation.
I
will
get
the
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation,
and
the
results
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.
The
fitness
distribution
of
each
mutation
will
be
the
best
possible
outcome.