Hello, everyone. I'm Jason Hong.
I'm the host for today.
Today, we're honored to have two postdocs from the Japanese Institute of理化學研究所, RIKEN.
One is the founder of TAIRA, Ted Chang.
The other is Xu Chengxuan.
Ted Chang is a postdoctoral researcher at the Center for Emerging Sciences.
His research focuses on the interaction between light and light-emitting ions.
Chengxuan focuses on theory.
His research focuses on the interaction between spin-orbital interaction and Latin geoliquid effects on nanostructure.
We're honored to have them here today.
Today's topic is 2-Dimensional Electron Gas, 2DEC, Electronic and Application.
I'd like to ask Ted Chang to introduce 2-Dimensional Electron Gas.
Can you hear me?
Most of the audience is muted.
If you have any questions, please turn on the microphone.
There's a line on the right side of the screen, which means you're muted.
You can also leave a comment in the chat box on the right.
Hello, I'm Ted Chang.
Today I'm going to talk about 2DEC.
2DEC stands for 2-Dimensional Electron Gas.
We use semiconductors to generate different heterostructure materials.
We can also do some interesting experiments by adding some processes.
Later on, Ted Chang will talk about how to use 2DEC to generate heterostructure materials.
I'm going to talk about how to generate 2DEC.
We're going to talk about how to generate quantum dots.
In quantum dots, we can trap a single electron.
In this experiment, we're going to measure the direction of polarization of light.
The result is a single electron.
We can also generate entangled photons.
This is a technology that has been around for 20 years.
We can generate entangled photons and spins.
Let's talk about 2DEC.
Why do we want to enter 2DEC?
In fact, in 3D life, the phenomenon is different in 2D.
This is a very special example.
In 2D space, it is not possible for an animal to live in 2D space.
Why?
Because this dog will be separated by its digestive tract.
Dogs in 2D space are not likely to exist in 2D space.
Because the physical conditions in 2D space are different, there will be different phenomena.
What method do we use to observe 2DEC?
Let's talk about how 2DEC is generated.
We will also introduce some basic characteristics of 2DEC.
If we have different semiconductor materials, which phenomenon is the most important to characterize the good or bad of these materials?
From 2DEC, we will introduce how to control the production of electrons or even a single electron in the material.
How does 2DEC interact with a single electron?
This is a diagram of 3 different materials.
The left bottom corner is the material of gallium arsenide and aluminum gallium arsenide.
The band structure of these two materials is different.
The band structure on the left is the material of gallium arsenide, and the band structure on the right is the material of aluminum gallium arsenide.
When the two materials are stacked together, a quantum well is generated.
In the middle of the quantum well, the Fermi energy, which occupies the highest electromagnetic field, can be adjusted.
The material of gallium arsenide can move freely in the 2D space.
At the same time, different materials can be used to make similar 2DEC.
Later on, we will introduce gallium arsenide.
In our lab, we are also working on silicon and silicon germanium, which are also heterostructures.
In this material, we will focus on the characteristics of gallium arsenide.
The main thing is that we hope that its mobility is basically the higher the better.
Mobility is also related to a lot of things.
Usually, the mean free path is very long, and the scheduling time is very short.
In this material, we will focus on the phase coherence lab, which is the interaction between electrons.
We hope that the interaction between electrons will be better and better.
Of course, it is different for different materials.
But basically, our main concern is mobility, mean free path, and scheduling time.
Gallium arsenide is a very mature technology.
Now it can grow to tens of millions, which is no problem.
Of course, there are many limitations in other materials.
The impurities in the middle of each layer may not match.
So in this aspect, its mobility will be reduced.
In contrast, its mean free path and scheduling time are not so good.
Next, we will talk about how to use mature manufacturing technology to make special components from 2DEC.
This picture looks very old.
Indeed, this is a paper published in 1996.
It uses gallium arsenide with a similar structure.
So it has gallium arsenide, aluminum gallium arsenide, and gallium arsenide, which are different doping materials.
It can add electrons up and down.
So it has a dot in the middle, which is a 2D artificial atom.
Because its electrons can only be confined to this layer,
we used to think that our electronic architecture has a lot of S, P, and D domain.
But it is S, P, D, and L in three-dimensional space.
But in 2D, its S, P, D, and L, its orbital angular number is different.
Because of the discovery of 2D artificial atom,
we created a periodic table for 2D artificial atoms.
The elements in this table are very interesting.
It is named after the person who discovered this phenomenon.
Our group, Tarucha, is in the upper left corner of the periodic table.
There are many famous people in this table.
This is one of the researchers of Mariana Fermi.
In addition to using the H method to describe different elements,
there is another method that is commonly used now.
It is to put an electrode on it.
For example, in 1988, they started to put an electrode on 2D.
The current from the left to the right is a quantized conductance.
When passing through the channel, the wave function can only be confined to these directions.
So the conductance is quantized.
This is a picture of its side.
When you apply voltage to the electrode below,
the lower the voltage, the narrower the channel below.
At the same time, it also controls the height of the level.
This is how it produces quantized conductance.
Sorry, sometimes it doesn't work.
Oh, yes, quantized conductance.
Next, we will slowly enter the topic.
Recently, everyone has been discussing quantum computing.
How to use quantum dot or quantum confine in the direction of quantum,
and how to use quantum dot to produce quantized conductance.
This paper was written by Chen Xuanhui's boss in 1998.
How to use quantum dot to produce quantized conductance.
Basically, the concept is that when we apply voltage to the electrode above,
there are some electrons below that can only stay in this area.
This is because it is confined to one end, so it is in quantum dot.
How to use quantum dot to produce quantized conductance.
Apply different voltages to the gate in the middle,
so that the interaction between electrons becomes stronger or weaker.
So that it has the effect of exchange.
Next, let's move on to my real experiment.
This is our dilution fridge.
Our components are placed on a chip on the dilution fridge.
The real size is about 1cm x 1cm.
As long as you apply voltage to the electrode above,
you can control the production of quantum dot.
For example, this is an SEM graph.
The quantum dot produced here is produced in the electrode confined here.
Its size is about 100nm.
In addition to producing double quantum dot,
the same device can also produce single quantum dot.
When the voltage in the middle is not so high,
the whole space can let the electrons stay in the middle.
In this place, we can measure its conductance.
It is like a horizontal line.
When the voltage in the middle increases,
it produces a stability diagram.
Next, I will talk about how our experiment is going.
The optical part is producing entangled photons in the left half of the graph.
Entangled photons are basically two different nonlinear crystals.
One is producing double quantum dot,
and the other is producing entangled photons.
When we measure the polarization of the photon on one side,
we measure the spin of the electron on the other side.
Is the electron spinning up or down?
This is a work from five years ago.
When a single electron is produced,
it is related to the direction of polarization of the photon.
When you produce a circular polarization with different velocities,
it produces different traces of electrons.
Next, we will talk about how to use the irradiated light
to produce a single electron.
How do we measure the direction of the electron's spin?
Next, we will measure the direction of the electron's spin from horizontal to spin up or vertical to spin down.
This is to use the electron and hole pair produced.
We use the light hole instead of the heavy hole.
This method allows us to produce different spin directions from horizontal to vertical.
How to do spin readout?
We use a method called spin-to-charge conversion.
We hope that the spin-up and spin-down are different.
How do we do this?
We use a phenomenon called Pauli Spin Blockade.
If you know the Pauli Exclusion Principle,
you will know that if the electron spins up or down on both sides,
it will not be able to move from the left to the right.
This is our basic way of doing it.
In the experiment, we let the quantum dot on the right have an electron.
The blue star represents 0 and 1.
0 and 1 represent the charge state of different quantum dots.
When another electron is produced, it will enter 1 or 0.2.
If the electron is produced in the opposite direction,
it will spin left and right.
When the electron is produced in the opposite direction,
This is how we measure the direction of single spin.
This graph also describes the phenomenon I just described.
If it is in a different direction of spin,
its trace will be different.
This graph also describes the phenomenon I just described.
How do we produce an entangled photon?
This is a very mature technology.
Because the quantum dot moves,
the light in the two circles will move in the opposite direction.
The light in the two circles will move in the opposite direction.
If you measure the polarization of the light in the two circles,
it will be an entangled state.
Next, we measure the light.
If the light receives the two signals at the same time,
it means that we have an entangled photon and an entangled spin.
This is the result of our experiment last year.
It produces an entangled photon and an entangled spin.
This is the end of the main experiment.
Here I explain how 2D Electron GANs is formed.
Usually, the quantum dot is produced differently.
Some products are self-assembled quantum dots,
because the structure of the golden frame
has a defect, and this defect becomes a quantum dot.
Compared to us, we use predetermined electrons
to apply different voltages to produce a single dot, a double dot.
So these are very controllable things.
Next, I will talk about how to measure the direction of the single electron.
We will also talk about how to change the direction of the light
from a different bias to a different direction of the electron.
Finally, we will talk about how to use the entangled photon
to produce different directions of the electron,
and how to produce entangled photons and spin pairs.
That's all for today.
Our lab is the Quantum Functional System Research Group
at the Institute of Physics and Chemistry.
Our main PI is Harucha,
and we have other partners,
such as Chenxuan and Loss,
and OIWA, a group from Osaka University.
Our wafers are provided by a German school and organization.
That's all for today.
Thank you.
Thank you, Ted, for the wonderful talk.
If you have any questions,
please feel free to ask.
If not, I will ask a question.
You mentioned that mobility is very important.
Where does mobility and phase coherence time affect quantum computing?
Why are these properties important?
Phase coherence time limits the size of the quantum dot.
The phase coherence length and mean free path of a quantum dot
can reach tens of microns.
The requirements for the process are less than 1 micron.
Silicon is much smaller, about 10 times smaller.
Therefore, it is more difficult for us to experiment or process.
The size of the quantum dot must be at least 100 nanometers or less.
What we are doing now is to control the electron in this area.
If there are still some phenomena in this area,
this is not ideal.
Basically, mobility, mean free path, and phase coherence length
affect the size of the component process.
Of course, there are different difficulties.
For example, if my SEM graph shows that
the size of a dot is about 200 to 300 nanometers.
So a dot is about 200 nanometers or less.
Silicon is super difficult to make, so it will be more difficult.
But the Galien Arsenide you show has a coherence length of 40 microns.
So even if you make it less than 40 microns,
you can still make it.
It doesn't matter if it's less than 1 micron.
1 micron is already very easy to make.
Basically, photolithography can be done.
Do you have any questions?
We are very informal, so you can ask as many questions as possible.
Hello, can you hear me?
Can you hear me?
I have a question.
Do you know how long the coherence time can be less?
What is the relaxation time after entanglement?
For electrons, it's very small.
Because it's in the Galien Arsenide, it's about 100 nanoseconds.
I see.
So it's still limited by the time of entanglement.
Basically, in the Galien Arsenide, there are many different nucleons.
These nucleons will interact with electrons.
So it can be about a few hundred nanoseconds.
In the Galien Arsenide, it's very short.
But in silicon, it's about 20 milliseconds.
Because silicon can be purified,
silicon can be purified, and silicon can be purified.
Thank you.
Any other questions?
If not, let's invite Chenxuan to give the next speech.
Okay, thank you.
Hello, everyone.
Can you see my slides now?
Yes.
Thank you, Jason.
Thank you, Ted, for the invitation.
My name is Chenxuan Xu.
I'm going to talk about 2DEC electronics and applications.
In my research, I focus on spin-orbital coupling.
So I'll start by introducing spin-orbital coupling in nanostructure.
Then I'll talk about why we're interested in very strong spin-orbital coupling.
This is our recent theoretical research.
When you have a very strong spin-orbital coupling in nanowire,
what will happen to your charge transport, current, or inductance?
Okay, let's start our introduction.
In nanostructure, we usually have inversion symmetry breaking.
These inversion symmetry breaking are equivalent to a circuit.
When electrons move in these inversion symmetry breaking,
there is a magnetic field in its inversion symmetry breaking.
This magnetic field, of course, will be coupled with its spin coupling.
In our experimental inversion symmetry breaking,
it looks like its spin and momentum will be coupled.
Because momentum is related to its orbital motion,
we call this coupling spin-orbital coupling.
In nanostructure, there are mainly two kinds of symmetry breaking.
The first one is what Ted just introduced.
Because we're going to form two decks, we'll have some heterostructure.
So in the z-direction, there's a magnetic field.
This magnetic field will cause this spin-orbital coupling.
Then we call it rush-button coupling.
In addition to this structure,
our material is usually made up of 3-5 sets of semiconductors.
So in its crystal, there's usually inversion symmetry breaking.
This inversion symmetry breaking will give us another phase.
We call it Dresselhaus turn.
I'll give you two examples.
What kind of effect does this coupling have in nanostructure?
One of the effects is that
when we continue to confine this two-deck to a dot,
which is one of the applications Ted just talked about.
Usually, after we form a common dot,
if we want to do some further spin qubits experiments,
we usually add a magnetic field.
We found that if you have a magnetic field
coupled with spin-orbital coupling,
you'll change the G-factor in the dot.
The G-factor is important here
because it affects Zeeman splitting.
Of course, it affects the nature of the dot electron.
So we have a paper in our group
discussing this nature.
That's the effect.
The second example is related to the topic I'm going to talk about today.
If your two-deck later forms a wire,
usually your wire won't have...
your cross-section won't be zero.
So you'll have some finite width.
This is the so-called quasi-1D.
This is what I call quasi-1D.
In this case, we found that
spin-orbital coupling will form some
bend-distortion properties.
I'm going to talk a little bit more about this.
First of all, in a common experiment,
we'll add some magnetic fields.
So the situation I'm going to discuss next,
the experiment is that
the launch button is far greater than the tracer host.
So I'll just look at the launch button next.
In the case of quasi-1D,
we know that there will be kinetic energy
along the direction of the wire.
So that's the term.
In the y-direction, I'll have some confinement.
I can take this part of the energy spectrum quantized.
So it's equivalent to this kind of energy splitting.
So this is my sub-bend term.
The launch button will result in
the mixing of these two parts.
I just mentioned that
the launch button spin-orbital coupling
can have these two terms.
Let's look at the first term,
which is the term related to Kx.
It's related to the momentum along the wire.
So the effect of this term is that
in the energy spectrum,
it splits the quadratic dispersion
of the upper and lower order.
So there's this shift.
If I add the second term of
the launch button spin-orbital coupling,
this term will couple these two states
in this little green circle.
So it splits the different sub-bends
with the opposite spin-orbital coupling.
If I add these two terms,
I'll find that the energy spectrum
of my quantum wire will be distorted.
This means that
if I have a Fermi energy here,
we'll find that the energy spectrum
of branch A and branch B,
which is the red and blue energy spectrum,
the Fermi velocity will be different.
So I call this bend-distortion.
This is another effect of
the launch button spin-orbital coupling.
Another one is that it may mix
the upper and lower order.
Mainly because of the spin-orbital coupling,
your spin is no longer a good quantum number.
We have some simple calculations here.
The left side is the energy spectrum.
If I have a chemical potential,
assuming that the chemical potential
is slowly tuned from the bottom to the top,
the graph on the right is equivalent to
from left to right.
We're calculating the spin expectation value
of these four different states.
We'll find that because of the spin-orbital coupling,
the spin will change with the chemical potential.
This is one effect.
The second effect is what I just said.
Because these two energy bands
have different velocities,
we can also calculate their velocities
and find that they are also related to the chemical potential.
Here is a brief introduction
of these effects.
Now, I'd like to go back to the beginning
and ask why we're interested in
spin-orbital coupling.
This question is equivalent to asking
why spin-orbital coupling is so important.
Is it because it can be eaten?
If you're in Kalucha's group,
you'll find that they can make
a double nanowire cake.
If you're a good friend of their group,
you can eat this delicious double nanowire cake.
But apart from being edible,
the most important thing for us is
that if you have spin-orbital coupling,
you can use it to achieve Majorna bond states.
This is a relatively popular material
in the field of spin-orbital coupling.
Next, I'd like to introduce
what Majorna bond states are.
This is more than 80 years ago.
Majorana was an Italian physicist.
He proposed that
in the Dirac equation,
there is a real solution.
The solution is called Majorna fermions.
They are their own antimatter.
The reason why we're interested in
condensers and solid-state physics
is because we later found that
Majorna fermions may not be able to
or we may not be able to
verify that they are elementary particles.
But they may be able to be realized
in solid-state physics,
especially in the last 10 years.
The paper by Ulrich and Dasama
tells you that
if you want to achieve Majorna fermions,
you only need some easy-to-do setups.
You just need some spin-orbital nanowires
to achieve Majorna bond states.
Because of the appearance of these two papers,
people started to notice
that we may be able to achieve Majorna bond states.
Of course, Majorna bond states
are very popular.
The other reason is that
they are thought to provide
some topological quantum computation.
So you can use them to do quantum computing.
This is one of the reasons
why people are interested in them.
Because of this nature,
you may be able to do quantum computation.
People want to know
if they can really do it.
Let me introduce the most
well-known or
carefully studied setup,
that is, using single-wire.
As I said, if you convert an electron
into a single-wire,
and if the material has a strong spin-orbital coupling,
for example,
you can use indium arsenide or indium montmorillonide.
As you know,
these materials have a strong spin-orbital coupling.
If you have these materials,
and you add some magnetic field
along the direction of the wire,
basically,
you can have this effect.
If you have large-spin-orbital coupling,
as I said,
the dispersion will be shifted.
If you add another magnetic field,
it will open a Zeeman gap
at the zero-momentum point.
If your chemical potential
is fine-tuned to this area,
you will have helical modes.
Helical modes are the electrons
on the right and on the left
with different spin,
which is called helical modes.
If you put such a wire
on a superconductor,
you will find that
at the zero-momentum point,
the system gap is determined by two parameters.
One is the pairing gap,
and the other is the Zeeman gap.
This means that you have two gap openings
competing against each other.
Both gaps want to open,
but their opening signs are opposite.
So the system gap
means that
if I put my wire on the superconductor,
my pairing gap will be fixed.
If I slowly open my magnetic field,
the system gap,
the gap of the entire energy spectrum,
will shrink,
and it will be closed at a certain point.
If I continue to open my magnetic field,
it will be reopened.
Here we find a topological phase transition.
In this area on the right,
we find that the band is inversed.
Because of this band inversion,
we find that in this area,
you can achieve Majorna bond state.
You can see that
the elements needed here
sound quite simple.
As long as you have a magnetic field,
a superconductor,
and strong enough spin-over coupling,
you can achieve Majorna bond state.
It sounds quite convenient,
so we put a lot of effort
into studying this setup.
But there is a difficulty.
Because you need a magnetic field,
the magnetic field tends to disrupt the superconductor.
In other words,
your entire gap is usually affected by the magnetic field.
your Majorna bond state
is usually in the middle of the gap.
The smaller the gap,
the weaker the protection.
So you don't need a magnetic field.
This makes people,
especially those who do theoretical research,
wonder if there are other mechanisms.
As mentioned earlier,
we need the so-called gap opening
to open the gap
and achieve Majorna bond state.
If we look at it the other way around,
if we look at it the other way around,
before the pairing gap,
my energy spectrum
is equivalent to
a spin-selected gap in my energy spectrum.
That is, the gap opening
between the upper and lower branches
is different in the momentum space.
Is it possible
to have a spin-selected gap?
People later found out that
if you have a wire
and feel the rotating magnetic field,
you can achieve a spin-selected gap.
People later found out that
in the case of a single-wire,
the conduction electron has a so-called RKKY coupling.
This RKKY coupling
can achieve a very special spin order.
This spin will automatically
generate a rotating order.
This order can be used to achieve
the very special gap we just mentioned.
That is, if you have this RKKY system,
you automatically have a spin-off coupling.
That is, you have a synthetic spin-off coupling.
If you put such a system on the super island,
you will have different competing mechanisms.
You can have band-inversion
and you can achieve Myrna-Brown state.
Our group also used a similar mechanism a while ago.
We found that if you use carbon-13,
which is different from the usual carbon-12,
it will have nuclear spin.
If you use carbon-13 nanotube,
you will find that it will automatically generate this helix.
If you put this nanotube on the super island,
you can achieve Myrna-Brown state.
Of course, there may also be different setups.
What we were doing a while ago was using higher-order TI.
In this case, your material will have this so-called
gapless-hinged state.
We found that if you put the super conductor on the material,
you can achieve two different pairings.
One is the so-called non-local pairing,
and the other is the local pairing.
You can achieve Myrna-Brown state
because of the competition between these two different pairings.
Today's topic is more related to
the so-called double nanowire setup.
You put two nanowires on the super conductor.
There are two ways for the cooper pair to enter the nanowire.
You can enter the same nanowire,
which is called local pairing.
You can also enter different nanowires.
Theoretically, you will find that
if you have non-local pairing greater than local pairing,
you can also achieve Myrna-Brown state.
This can explain our motivation.
Basically, we want to know
that we can have some spin-octal coupling nanowires
that we want to know that we can have some spin-octal coupling nanowires
that we can try to put on the super conductor.
How do we achieve this condition,
that is, non-local pairing greater than local pairing?
This is another theoretical study.
If your electronic interaction is strong enough,
you are likely to achieve this condition.
The reason is that the electronic interaction here is the coolant.
So if your coolant is very strong,
it will try to split your cooper pair into different wires.
So if your coolant interaction is strong enough,
your non-local pairing will be greater than the local pairing.
Before trying to achieve these topological states,
we would like to know that how could we reach
strong electronic interaction.
Normal, the so-called
wired electronic interaction
is described with the Tomonaga-Latinger
or Tomonaga-Latinger Liquid.
In describing its model,
we will have a parameter called Gc.
So the point is that we want to know
how much Gc we can reach.
Let's review first.
If there is no spin-over coupling,
how do we determine the value of Gc in practice?
Here I simply write this Hamiltonian.
If there is no spin-over coupling,
the so-called Tomonaga-Latinger Liquid
will look like this.
There will be some bosonic fields
to describe the physics of low energy.
The most important thing is this Gnu.
Gnu is C or S,
which is the charge or spin sector.
The most important thing is that because of the coolant interaction,
there is no spin-over coupling.
The smaller the Gc, the stronger the spin-over coupling.
So we want to know
the value of Gc in this material.
How do we know?
As you can see in the document,
if you have a Tomonaga-Latinger Liquid,
your IV curve will look like this.
This IV curve
has a so-called universal scaling behavior.
What does it mean?
If you divide both sides
by the power load of the temperature,
you will find that the right side
is only related to V divided by T.
This V is the bias voltage,
and T is the temperature.
In other words, if you draw this picture,
you will find that all the bias and all the temperature
data points are all concentrated on the same line.
This is called universal scaling.
Because this scaling is related to this α,
and this α is related to this Gc,
so if you can fit this data,
you can find out how much Gc should be.
In this way, you can know
how strong the interaction of electrons in the guide line is.
Here's an example.
Tarucha's group
uses indium arsenide as a wire.
They first get a two-deck wafer,
and then continue to convert it into a wire.
This is what Ted mentioned earlier.
If you have these wires,
they continue to measure this IV curve
with the current to the bias voltage.
Different colors represent different temperatures,
and you find that the low data is like this.
But you can rescale it.
After rescaling, you will find that all the data points
are concentrated on this line.
So this tells us that there really is
the phenomenon of the so-called Tomonaga-Rattinger liquid in this guide line.
You can get this α from this fitting.
They continue to tune
different top gate voltages.
That is, it can adjust the charge density in the guide line.
You find different densities.
The low data you get is like this.
Then you can go to fit
and find the phenomenon of universal scaling.
Their data is very beautiful.
In other words,
not only do you know that
there is universal scaling in this line,
there is Tomonaga-Rattinger liquid,
you also know that you can tune
the strength of the electron interaction.
Here is the value of their fit α
and the top gate voltage.
So the first conclusion here is that
you can have a tunable electron interaction.
The second is that your α
is about 2.5.
How do we know
what the value is when it is converted to Gc?
The most important question here is
because we know that the spin-over coupling of indium arsenide is very strong.
What we found in the file before
is that there is no spin-over coupling formula.
So we want to know that if you add spin-over coupling,
this formula will be changed.
So how do we know
what our real Gc is?
So this brings us to our research this time.
Because of the time,
I will briefly introduce it.
In the case of Bostonization,
the introduction mentioned that
you have the phenomenon of band distortion,
which is ΔV.
If you have a Hamiltonian,
it will produce a new term.
This new term is quadratic,
so you can still diagonalize it.
Then you can get the full Hamiltonian.
Because this full Hamiltonian
can still be directly solved,
we can still use it to calculate
our current or inductance.
Then we will consider two extremes.
That is, impurity,
that is, there will be different impurities in this inductance.
These impurities will cause
your electron to backscatter.
So this will affect your current or inductance.
We consider two extremes.
One is when this impurity is very strong.
If it is very strong,
there will be a tunnel barrier.
Then we find that if your tunnel barrier
is in the end of the inductance and the middle of the inductance,
you will have different scaling exponents.
So in these two different situations,
we find that
you can still get a similar form,
which is this IV curve.
It looks the same as the formula
The only difference is that this α will be changed.
Then we find that this α will be related to
where your impurity is.
Then it is also related to the bend distortion
caused by spin-orbital coupling.
This is its formula.
Let's summarize the results in this picture.
In this picture,
I first draw the whole exponent
without spin-orbital coupling.
It looks like this.
That is to say, the stronger your electromagnetic interaction force,
that is, Gc is close to zero,
the greater your exponent.
On the contrary, if Gc is 1,
that is, if there is no electromagnetic interaction force,
your α will become zero.
This is the effect of spin-orbital coupling.
We find that it affects
the strong electromagnetic interaction force.
In fact, this effect is very small
because it is very small compared to the original exponent.
That is to say, if there is a strong electromagnetic interaction force
in your導線,
you don't have to worry about whether spin-orbital coupling is strong or not.
Because it doesn't really affect
the opposite area.
If your electromagnetic interaction force is weak,
you will indeed see some changes.
We found that the changes here are negative.
That is to say, your exponent looks
smaller than it was without spin-orbital coupling.
So these features tell us
that when your experiment has measured
that your α is quite high value,
it can be said that your electron-electron
display is very strong.
This is our main conclusion.
Of course, we just said that we can consider different limits.
Your impurity can be very strong.
This is the conclusion we just got.
Your impurity can also be very weak.
If it is very weak, we are not tunnel barrier.
In this case, we consider a lot of
weak impurities.
Then we get a similar formula.
The difference is that the exponent will be different.
We found that if we take this exponent
to draw this picture,
we will find that the big difference
is that the exponent will only go to 1 at most.
That is, it will be limited between 0 and 1.
So the 2.5 we saw in the experiment
cannot be explained by this weak impurity.
So we can rule it out.
So we know that the exponent we saw in the experiment
is 2.5 because
there are some very strong impurities in the導線.
So we can get our conclusion here.
So let's make a summary here.
First, what we said in the introduction
is that if you have a導線
and you have a very strong spin-over coupling,
you can use it to achieve some
topological states.
The second point is that
our research shows that
you can still use the IV curve to measure the導線.
From here, you can deduce
how strong the electromagnetic interaction force
in the導線 is.
Our analysis shows that
the IV curve in the experiment
of indium arsenide
allows us to deduce that Gc is about 0.2.
So this means that the spin-over coupling
in the導線 is very strong.
We know that indium arsenide
has a very strong spin-over coupling.
Now we know that it can achieve
a very strong electromagnetic interaction force.
So if you add these two factors together,
it tells us that indium arsenide
can be used to achieve Majorna bond state.
Then you don't need to use magnetic field
to achieve Majorna bond state.
This is my speech today.
I'll pause here now
to see if you have any questions.
Do you have any questions?
Let me ask you a question first.
When you talk about α,
is it the gate voltage
of the conductance
or the source voltage?
Is it the gate voltage
Is that right?
Yes, the V in the IV curve
is the source voltage.
Can you explain a little bit?
Is there a more straightforward idea?
When α is equal to 0,
does it mean that this is a straight line?
What does α equal to 0 mean?
0 is the value of the current
in this IV curve.
Is it a straight line?
Yes, because it doesn't have a scale 0.
I think this is understandable.
When there is no electron-electron interaction,
you are a little bit like...
If you are an ohmic contact,
you should get an ohmic line.
When there is electron-electron interaction,
what does α mean?
When your source current is high,
you will get more current.
Let me see if there is a similar formula.
You can think like this.
Maybe I can use this.
Is there a simpler physical image?
We can think like this.
When you have an impurity at a point,
we say this is a strong impurity.
It means that your impurity is very strong,
so your conduction channel is interrupted.
So when you want to have current,
you have to pass this tunneling.
So you will have current.
This tunneling is equivalent to
density of states.
There will be density of states
in your conduction channel or lead.
When you have a strong interaction force,
when α is stronger,
it means that your density of states will be suppressed.
Because your density of states
can be thought of as the α-quantity of epsilon.
It is also a power law.
What is epsilon?
Epsilon is energy.
So your density of states will be written as the rho of epsilon.
So it is equivalent to
how many density of states you have
near the Fermi energy.
If there is no interaction,
this α is 0,
which means that its density of states is constant.
Because it is constant.
So you will have some density of states
to allow you to tunnel.
When your interaction force is getting stronger and stronger,
α will get bigger and bigger,
which means that the density of states
near the Fermi level will be suppressed.
Because the α-quantity of epsilon,
which means that epsilon is getting closer to 0,
its density of states will be getting smaller and smaller.
Because of this,
if you want to tunnel into
the liquid state,
it will be more and more impossible.
You can think of it this way.
So you need a higher voltage
to generate a certain current.
Yes, you can say that.
Wait, what about the experiment?
Did I read it wrong?
Ok, I think I understand what you mean.
When your voltage is high,
your differential conductance
will increase.
Yes, it will increase.
Ok, I understand.
So,
I think I wrote differential conductance
at the end.
Here, here.
Ok, so this is the definition of α.
Yes.
So the higher your V,
the higher your differential conductance.
Of course, if you have a linear response region,
your voltage will be lower.
Your power load is determined by the temperature.
Yes.
Does anyone have any questions?
Ok.
If there are no further questions,
I will turn off the recording.
You can continue to discuss
in the conference room.
Let's turn on the microphone
and give a warm round of applause
to the speakers.
Thank you for your wonderful speech.
Are you ready?
Please turn on your microphone
so that the speakers can hear you.
Thank you.
Thank you for your speech.
Thank you for your wonderful speech.
I will turn off the recording.