Hello, everyone. I'm the host of Taira, Hong Shih-an.
We're honored to invite Hong Wei to give a speech.
Hong Wei is now at North Carolina University.
He graduated from the Department of Chemistry at the National University of Transportation.
He entered North Carolina University in 2015.
He is mainly engaged in the study of light chemistry, energy materials, and nanoparticles.
He is interested in scientific writing and serves the science communication group in and out of the university.
The topic of his speech today is Near Field Optical Spectroscopy.
This is a very popular topic recently.
Let's invite him to give a speech.
Now you can turn on the microphone and give our speaker a round of applause.
Remember to turn on the microphone.
Let's start.
Thank you, everyone.
Thank you, Jason and Project Taira for giving me this opportunity.
Today, I would like to share the Near Field Optical Spectroscopy.
Sometimes, we also call it NAMI optical nanospectroscopy.
Today, I would like to introduce to you why we do this technology and how it is done.
NAMI optical nanospectroscopy is an application of NAMI 경찰institute for light.
For NAMI optical nanospectral?
We consider ourselves NAMI optical nanosceptical
We are located at the University of North Carolina,
at the campus of the church.
Our lab focuses on the development of NAMI optical nanospectral.
This is our program host, Dr. Joanna Atkin.
NAMI optical nanospectral is a heterogeneity.
The concept is like a chocolate wall.
If you look far away, you may only see a piece of green.
But if you look closely, you will find that it is a round chocolate wall.
And if you look closer, you may find that each shape is different.
Even the angle of each array is different.
This heterogeneity is often used in research materials.
We define it as a mesoscale structure.
This is the structure of the mesoscale structure.
The distribution is about nanometer to micrometer length scales.
Sometimes we deliberately introduce these heterogeneous structures for specific needs.
But sometimes it is inevitable.
When you generate molecules or materials, there will be heterogeneous structures.
This is a sample of a semiconductor with a molecule.
This molecule generates two heterogeneous structures.
This molecule is a very chaotic structure.
And the generation preference of the accelerator called hydrogen acetate is not available.
Most applications use hydrogen acetate for...
Some applications use hydrogen acetate for..
Long-distance scanning.
Optical Range
Optical Range.
Super Resolution Microscopy
Super Resolution Microscopy.
Optical Antenna.