Hello, everyone. Welcome to today's TerraTalk.
We are very honored to have Wang Chenghe in Germany to give us a speech.
The topic of today's speech is Coupling Cell-Cell Adhesion to Cell Polarization.
It is mainly a research on biophysics.
First, let me introduce our speaker today.
Our speaker today is Wang Chenghe.
He is currently in Germany.
He graduated from the University of Taiwan Institute of Technology.
When he was a master's thesis, he did a preliminary personalized breast cancer drug test.
After graduation, he served in Taiwan for three years in the light company.
The main thing is to do 3D laser imaging development.
After graduation, he did a measurement study of cell grafting in the Institute of Medical Sciences.
Then, from his previous field in the Institute of Medical Sciences, he switched to the field of biophysics.
Currently, he is a doctoral student at the Max Planck Institute of Cell Biology and Genetics in Germany.
What he is studying now is what he is going to tell us today.
It is the early cell-cell adhesion study of cell polarization.
We remind everyone that we have to turn on the microphone to applaud our speaker.
Let's applaud to welcome our speaker.
Thank you all. Please start.
Thank you all.
I just introduced myself. I am Wang Chenghe.
I am now in the third year of my doctoral studies.
I am going to share with you my research in the past three years.
If you have any questions later, you can interrupt me.
You can interrupt me and ask questions directly.
We can discuss at the same time.
If you have any questions, please say a phrase first.
Then ask your question.
Otherwise, I may continue to talk at once.
Because there is a lag, I am afraid that this will be interfered with.
I am currently a doctoral student in Germany.
My research is actually looking at the connection between cells and the relationship between cell polarization.
This is a very big topic.
I don't know what the background is today.
So I prepared a simple general introduction.
The main thing is to connect cells.
You should know that we have learned from high school students that cells are composed of organs.
So cells have a regular arrangement in the animal body.
It can be arranged into different organs or organs with different functions.
One of the organs is called the epithelium.
In Chinese, it is the upper arm cell.
It basically consists of cells in the animal body.
It is a cell organ that surrounds these cells.
For example, like your kidney or your stomach.
These cells will have such a cell on top.
As you can see, this is my mouse.
It doesn't matter.
Anyway, one of the features of this cell is that when it forms a cell,
it is mainly a simple single cell.
Then go around this cell to form such a structure.
You can see that the lower right corner is a multi-layer cell.
But most of them are actually single cells that form such a structure.
Why does this cell form such a structure?
And what mechanism do they have?
In fact, this has been studied for a very, very long time.
Such a single cell is connected to a single cell.
They actually have some common features to share.
One of the features is that there is a tree on top of it.
It is an epithelial membrane that does not connect to anything.
We call it epithelial membrane.
There is nothing on this cell.
It can be said that there is no contact with any cell
or this kind of epithelial membrane.
It is epithelial membrane.
Then there will be some connections between cells.
Because you know that these cells are linked together.
So it is very intuitive to think that they form a connection.
This connection is what we call a lateral membrane.
The third membrane is the basal membrane.
The basal membrane is the membrane that the cell connects to the external environment,
the ECM, or the reflection environment of the cell.
Basal membrane.
So there are only three main membranes in this cell.
Everyone is very curious about how the cell controls each cell
so that these three membranes can be placed well
and form a connection at the same time.
Then it will not form a strange shape,
but a slightly organized shape.
So this matter, whether in biophysics or biophysics,
is actually a problem that has been studied for a very long time.
To do this kind of research, you can use a lot of different materials.
You can do mouse experiments.
You can do things.
You can do anything.
You can do cell lines.
Like me, I focus on using cell lines.
So I don't do animal experiments.
The cell line I use is a cell called MDCK.
MDCK cells are mainly...
The origin of MDCK cells is the sacral tube of the dog.
So it will form a wall.
It will form a tube.
Let's say a tube.
But in fact, in a lot of research, it just forms a sphere.
OK, anyway, I don't care.
Our study model,
it looks for two cells from one cell.
Everyone knows the cell division.
After the division, it will form a cell-cell connection at the beginning.
Let me find a reference here.
Its label is green.
The green part is the connection between two cells.
The two blue ones are the two cell boxes.
OK, and then it continues to grow.
After it continues to grow, it will form the one on the far right.
The one you see now.
Blue is still a cell box.
Green is the connection between cells.
This is a plane.
What you see now is a sphere.
The red one is what I just said.
The place in the middle of the box.
It's a lumen.
It's a lumen with all kinds of liquid and all kinds of nutrients in it.
A box with all kinds of molecules in it.
It's a lumen.
Then the cells form a single cell connection structure like this.
Then wrap the lumen in the middle.
We call it cyst.
If you have ever studied MDCK culture,
you will know that if you put it in an environment where there are no cells,
it will grow like this.
OK.
If you remember what I just said,
Epico, Lateral and Basal,
three different membranes.
In more detail,
these three membranes are actually filled with different molecules.
Whether it's liquid or protein.
But what I'm talking about here is protein.
Protein on the membrane.
In Epico,
I've listed two types here.
One is called protocollicin or CrOMS.
You don't have to remember these names.
But in Epico,
please remember protocollicin first.
This protein.
Because I will use this protein in the next experiment.
To represent whether the cells have grown Epico membranes.
This thing.
Then there's Basal.
Indicator.
It's like the corner of a cell.
It will form a connection with the nucleus of the cell.
I didn't do too much of Basal.
I did it more in the previous lab.
But I'm not focusing on this now.
So I won't cover it here today.
Then there are cells.
It's like my title today.
Cellular adhesions.
Cellular adhesions have a lot of different types.
We call it adhesion receptor.
You can think of it as a plug.
Protein is like a plug.
It will connect.
It will form a cell-cell connection.
There are four types here.
I only listed about four types.
In fact, it can be roughly divided into orange and red.
Two are a kind.
It's a kind.
Then the blue and green below are another kind.
You just have to remember the green one.
E-cadherin.
Because I will use E-cadherin to represent the next experiment.
Lateral adhesions between cell membranes.
So anyway.
In short, these three domains are defined by these different protein distributions.
In past research, many people have removed these different proteins.
If you are not a biological background,
Protein's performance is removed in this cell.
It doesn't produce this protein.
Then look at what impact it has on the entire structure.
Pay attention to the sphere structure in the upper right corner.
It's a normal structure.
If you remove any protein, it doesn't produce that structure.
It means that the polarization of this cell is affected.
So after removing some proteins, you will see that it produces more than one lumen.
It means that the mechanism of the epico-membrane is affected.
Or more seriously,
Other influences may cause it to grow into a sphere.
Or grow into a very large cluster, like a tumor.
So after removing a protein,
What is the final result?
In fact, a lot of papers have already started to study this.
A lot of papers have been doing this since 2000.
But what we want to end up in this study is the process.
That is, in the entire dynamics, from one cell to this multi-cell process.
How are these proteins affected by each other?
And when are these proteins produced?
And where are they?
And when is it important?
It's important for the whole thing to grow into a normal shape.
This is what I'm mainly doing.
If you look at the three pictures above me,
You will find that the process is actually very simple.
The cells are divided into two cells.
The two cells continue to separate and separate.
Finally, it grows into such a spherical structure.
But you can notice one thing.
The red epico here is the domain of the epico.
It's actually not in the final right.
It was produced under the multi-cell situation on the right.
It was already produced when there were two cells.
In the middle of the two cells,
You can say that it is almost in the middle of the domain where the two cells are connected.
Just produced this epico domain.
This epico domain is produced in such an early state.
So we are very curious about how the mechanism tells the cell
You have to throw your epico domain there.
Instead of throwing it somewhere else.
So we are curious about this.
In addition,
It's not actually split into two from one.
It will form this domain.
This is from my own data.
You put the two cells together.
Then after a long time, it will eventually form this epico domain.
The red part is the epico domain.
The green part is the same as above.
It's the adhesion of the two cells.
So we have an intuitive idea.
Will it be when the two cells are connected?
These proteins.
I just marked four next to it.
One of them tells the cell that
OK, I have a neighbor next to me.
I now have this neighbor.
So I have to produce an epico membrane between me and my neighbor.
So we came up with a project at the beginning.
It's very intuitive.
Since it's two cells,
Which one do we want to see?
Protein
Cells connect to proteins.
It's dominated by this thing.
So let's get rid of a cell.
It's like hitting a single cell.
Let's do this.
Then we replace one of the cells with a supported lipid bilayer.
It's a lipid bilayer.
You know from the name.
It's a double-layered membrane.
We put different receptors on this membrane.
Lateral adhesion receptor.
Put it on this membrane.
Then we can see what kind of reaction the cell will have to which type.
So after we drop the cell,
Let's look at the interaction between it and the receptor below.
This receptor is on the membrane.
One of the benefits of the supported lipid bilayer above is
If you only have a fixed situation,
Cell adhesion is dead.
It can't self-organize.
It can't do what it wants to do.
So if we put it on the lipid bilayer,
It can move freely.
So after the cell goes down,
It can depend on its own
Whether it's its own internal mechanics
Or its own chemical reaction
Will produce the same result.
Ideally, we can find
Some kind of receptor
That can activate the epico-domain
Between the cells.
But unfortunately,
The cells don't like this environment.
So I spent a year and a half doing this.
The cells actually ate it.
This research is actually quite useful.
Because it purifies a lot of different proteins.
We tried to do this experiment.
But the cells don't like it.
But that doesn't mean this method won't work.
It's just that we may need a very long time at this stage.
So I gave up this method.
And I didn't do it in this direction.
I started to do this experiment
In a situation that wasn't so ambitious.
So we went back to the state of two cells.
We don't have to do bilayer.
We just observe these two cells.
What must be missing in the middle?
We didn't notice.
Because the cells don't like the receptor.
And the cells will die.
And the epico-domain won't be produced.
So we went back to the literature.
To see how it goes from one cell to two cells.
The first process is cell division.
In the last step of cell division,
Cut the two cells apart.
There is a step called cytokinesis.
Those of you who studied cell biology should know.
Cytokinesis is a very strong cytoskeletal force.
It's like a circular scissor.
Cut the link between the two cells.
After the cut,
If a cell doesn't form a link,
It will form two independent cells.
But what we see now is the epithelial cell.
Two cells will form a link.
So it's not completely cut off.
At the same time, it forms a link.
When it forms a link,
I forgot to say one thing.
Before it's cut off,
There will be a tubulin between the two cells.
Tubulin is also a cytoskeleton.
It's a kind of bridge.
A track.
It will stay there.
We call it the midbody.
This midbody will remain in the entire cell division.
The midbody is the place where the epithelial domain is generated.
Next, there will be vesicles.
These vesicles carry the proteins that form the epithelial membrane.
Or lipids.
The proteins will be transported to this place.
After the transportation,
These proteins are fused to the middle.
After being fused,
It will expand more and more.
These epithelial domains are connected.
But the proteins in the epithelial domain
don't form a link.
So we thought that
they will form a repulsive force.
And gradually expand.
This process has been studied by many people.
Many people already know
what kind of proteins are important for this delivery.
What can we do?
We care about the selection of cells.
So we think that the connection between cells
should be interplayed with delivery.
So the first thing we suspect is
the important selection of the epithelial membrane.
We think it's high junction.
OK, I haven't said what high junction is.
High junction is the picture on the right.
It's a small T-J.
So if you look at the picture on the right,
If you think of it as 3D,
The entire lumen is a sphere.
The T-J high junction is like a round ring.
Then this sphere,
You can think of it as a channel.
It's like a channel of this lumen.
Seal this lumen.
So we think that
This high junction has always been
This lumen and its lateral adhesion
The interface between its cellular connections.
So we think it has something to do with
the production of the entire epithelial membrane.
So the next question is
I have a question.
How fast is the time scale of this whole process?
OK, so from the leftmost cell division
Then to the rightmost one, it's about 6 hours.
5 to 6 hours.
Is it about the same time for each step?
Or which one is particularly long?
Which one is particularly long?
From the four schematics I drew below
I took four schematics.
The one on the right and the one on the left
It's about four hours apart.
You mean the last arrow, right?
Yes, so it's from the first schematic to the third.
Maybe only one hour in the middle.
Oh, I see.
But the last one takes several hours.
I see. OK.
OK, thank you.
So we're curious about
When was this high junction produced?
Let me introduce it to you today.
What is high junction?
If you remember, I just talked about epico, lateral, and basal.
Three domains.
In fact, there is a red band in the middle.
I didn't introduce it.
That's high junction.
It's in the interface between epico and lateral membrane.
And it will always exist in that place.
The main protein group
There are actually a lot of high junction protein groups.
Basically, what I drew here
The red, blue, and purple on the schematic.
The three are its receptors.
The main ones are occluden, occluden, and GEMS.
Of course, occluden has a lot of kinds of occluden.
Occluden has a lot of kinds of occluden.
GEMS has a lot of kinds.
So it's not just a protein.
It has a lot of kinds.
On the inside of the cell
You can see that there is a yellow, orange, and green.
Three proteins.
ZO1, ZO2, and ZO3.
It's actually a high junction.
It's connected to the inside of the cell.
It's not directly connected to other cells.
But it's connected to occluden, GEMS, and occluden.
This picture is a bit misleading.
I haven't found a better one yet.
I'm sorry.
It doesn't mean that ZO1 is based on occluden.
ZO2 is based on occluden.
ZO3 is based on GEMS.
The three are actually mixed together.
In my understanding.
It's not just based on one kind.
ZO1 can be based on three proteins.
Anyway, it's a mixed state here.
I hope everyone can remember ZO1 protein.
Because ZO1 protein is a very important protein in my next experiment.
There has been research to prove that.
Obviously, after you remove ZO1 and ZO2.
After the cells do not produce these two proteins.
The high junction between the cells will not be produced.
This is very important to my experiment.
Everyone remember this first.
Its main function is high junction.
So, as the name suggests, it's very tight.
So, it's the closest link between cells.
It's a close connection.
It's like the whole cell connection is sealed together.
So, you can imagine that the entire lumen can be considered to be sealed by this high junction.
So, we think that whether there is a high junction to produce lumen.
It will definitely have a relationship.
So, let's start the next experiment.
OK.
What I want to say here is.
I just talked about high junction.
And epical membrane.
What is the situation in the middle?
How is it produced?
Why can the high junction be produced in the middle?
So, I just went back to the schematic I just mentioned.
From cell division to lumen.
The color is a bit messy here.
Sorry, I have a lot of slimes here.
OK.
The red one represents the cytokinesis I just mentioned.
Contractile ring.
It's like a knife.
Cut the two cells apart.
The green one is the high junction I just mentioned.
It will form the lumen.
In the reference diagram.
The small schematic with the high junction.
It's a half-circle.
A diagram.
So, the blue high junction is a cell.
The blue low junction is a cell.
The red one is the protein representing the red circle.
The protein slowly cuts into the cell membrane.
Cut the cells apart.
At the same time.
It will put the later adhesions.
Remember the protein eCathctors and eHearing.
It will carry these two cells.
It's a gap now that puts the later adhesions.
It will ahead of itself.
Like I said before,
there's a mid-body.
A right center.
There's a tubulin.
creating the later adhesion.
So the mid-body is important.
But the mid-body will be cut off.
Because the two cells need to be completely separated.
So there must be a point
for the later adhesion to stop.
We think that's what Pythagoras is doing.
Pythagoras stops
near the mid-body
so that the later adhesion
won't directly invade
the area between the cells.
We want to leave this gap
so that the apical membrane can be created.
This is one of our assumptions.
The reason why I say this
is because we observe
the cytokinesis
in the process of cell separation.
The high junction and
the later adhesion,
both exist at the same time
as the cytokinesis ring.
As you can see here,
you can imagine
the cytokinesis cell
is behind the screen.
So you can see the interface
between the two cells.
There is such a large actin,
the cytokinesis countertowel ring.
It separates the two cells.
At the same time, you can see
the ZO1 and E-cadherin,
these two proteins,
are wrapped inside
the large countertowel ring
or collocalized.
So when we see this,
the ZO1 is squeezed
in the middle.
The E-cadherin
has its mechanism
to keep it outside.
The good later adhesion
also keeps the ZO1
which is the place
where the next ethical membrane
is going to be created.
At the same time,
we want to know
if there is no ZO1,
is there no
E-cadherin,
then we will
remove the ZO1 and ZO2
proteins inside the cell.
So here you can see
a cross-section
of the entire cyst.
So the wild type on the left,
the black hole in the middle
is the lumen.
The E-cadherin,
the lumen in the middle
is very spherical.
After the ZO1 and ZO2
are removed,
there is still a small lumen in the middle.
At first, we thought
there was still a lumen after the ZO1 and ZO2 were removed.
Maybe it has nothing to do
with the lumen.
At the same time,
if we carefully draw
the lumen contour,
believe me,
it will look like this.
We think it is
a flower-shaped lumen.
Based on this,
we think
whether the lumen
has something to do
with the E-cadherin.
The E-cadherin
may not have anything to do
with the E-cadherin.
But whether the lumen
can grow into a sphere
may have something to do
with the E-cadherin.
I have a question.
I have a question
and a small suggestion.
Can you try to move
your mouse,
your arrow?
Yes, I just tried to move it.
So it can't appear
on the screen.
OK, I just wanted to say
if you can see the arrow,
you can use it to point.
No, it doesn't matter.
I have another question
about this research.
In fact,
if you look at the schematic above,
it is actually very zoomed in
to the edge
that is about to be broken.
But the picture below
is a picture of the entire
large area of the microscope.
So you have to
directly see
the ABC picture
of the small area
in the process of hypothesizing.
Your microscope should have, for example,
tens or hundreds of nanometers
of resolution, right?
In fact, it doesn't have to be
like this.
The series of pictures below
is just a snapshot.
So I'm not sure
what the red schematic is.
I'm not sure where it is.
If you want to see the small area,
in fact,
if you can resolve
to 100 nanometers
or 200 nanometers,
you can see a point.
But if you really want to see
that my microscope has super resolution,
we're doing this thing.
It can resolve to
20 nanometers or 30 nanometers.
OK.
OK. OK. OK.
So can you talk now?
Yes, I can talk now.
In the ABC picture,
the red thing is acting,
right?
Yes.
You said that acting cut off the cell ring.
That is to say,
the inside of the membrane, right?
Yes.
The inside of the cell membrane.
Why is there still a layer of acting outside the cell membrane?
I didn't find this schematic very well.
It's actually...
I should have drawn it myself.
This reference is actually talking about
the state of the entire monolayer.
So the other acting he drew
outside is
the third cell.
This...
This is my mistake. I'm sorry.
That's the third cell's
acting inside the cell membrane.
Yes.
I should have made it clear.
Sorry.
OK.
I'll continue.
Let me go back.
As I just said,
a lot of proteins
interplay
in this process.
Or they appear at different points
in different locations.
The question is
when and
where does a protein
show up?
Everyone who has done cell experiments knows
that if you want to see a certain protein,
you have to
connect your protein
to something that emits light.
Basically,
it's not possible to see
dozens of proteins at once.
Because there are only four
proteins in the entire membrane.
You can't see
dozens of proteins.
How can you see so many proteins?
The method everyone uses is to fix
the cells and make them into a specimen,
and then dye them.
What I'm going to do here is the same.
Fix the cells and dye them.
But at the same time, I want to have
some information.
I want to know
how long it takes
for the cell to split.
How long does it take for the cell to split?
So I did
a little trick.
It's actually quite
ancient.
I threw the cells into the environment
I wanted them to grow in.
Then I used a large area of Brightfield
to shoot it.
I shot it once every five minutes.
At two points in time, the cells split.
You can see that there are a lot of numbers here.
The target is the cells that split
during this process.
I recorded these positions.
When I fixed the cells,
I could know that I killed the cells first.
When I made it into a specimen,
it was a few minutes
or a few hours
away from the split.
So it's not
a full-scale observation.
But you can use the cell split as a standard.
Then I knew
that maybe this cell
grew like this after four hours.
Or it grew like this after three hours and 45 minutes.
So this is
to make up for
the lack of protein
that can't be seen all at once.
But one drawback is
that I can't actually follow the entire cell.
So I made a model
from the cell split
from 0 minutes to 6 hours.
The whole process is not the same cell.
I believe that if I collect a little more,
maybe it can
represent the whole process.
Then I used this method
to fix the cells and make the dye.
I just asked you to remember
E-cadherin, ZO1, and protocloxin.
The three individuals represent E-cadherin.
ZO1 is a type function.
Protocloxin is an epico-domain.
So you can see the first five-minute
picture above.
The first one is an XY cross-section.
As you can see,
protocloxin is actually
in the middle of two cells.
It didn't run between
the two cells
in the five-minute cell split.
At the same time,
in the picture on the right,
I turned its perspective
to face the cell-to-cell
adhesion site.
So you can see that
ZO1 has probably formed
a circular state
in the middle of the adhesion site.
So it's the same as what I guessed at the beginning.
ZO1 is stored there.
It feels like
the magenta color
and the purple E-cadherin
domain
should be stopped.
Because the middle is black.
The black part is where the protocloxin is placed.
Next,
I will continue to look at it.
After 30 minutes and 45 minutes,
you can see that
the protocloxin slowly moves
from the cell to the
domain in the middle where the
protocloxin is.
Gradually, it fuses in.
As time goes by,
rumen is produced.
So it's similar
to what I guessed at the beginning.
Protocloxin was formed
at an early stage.
Protocloxin is
the area
to produce the epico-domain.
So it's the whole
process of mapping
that we came to a conclusion.
Next,
at the later stage,
when the whole thing
grows into a cyst,
we know that it's not a spherical sphere.
Its rumen looks very strange.
It's not a sphere,
it's a flower.
We are curious about
whether the rumen
that it produces
will produce rumen.
Secondly, what is the shape of the rumen it produces?
So I used
the cells that killed
the two proteins,
the cells that don't have protocloxin,
to observe for a long time.
The number on the left is 905 minutes,
about 15 hours.
After the cell division,
it's about 15 hours,
4 hours on the right.
So from the previous picture,
we know that
we will see
the epico-components
are thrown to that place, ready to be fused.
So it's been a long time,
more than 10 hours.
If it produces rumen, it should be produced.
But what's interesting is
the blue one is protocloxin,
the epico-components.
The purple one is e-catechumen.
We found that protocloxin
stopped where it should stop.
It was thrown to that interface,
but it didn't seem to be able to fuse
with the cell membrane.
So the first question is
the epico-components
were thrown there smoothly.
So its polarity
was preserved to some extent.
If we draw a cross-section
and look at
the protein distribution
on the line I drew,
we can see that
in the middle,
the purple peak is where e-catechumen is.
Where catechumen is,
there is no protocloxin.
In fact, protocloxin should be
fused into the membrane.
So it should be
colloquialized with e-catechumen.
But it's not here.
So we have a question.
OK,
there is no tight junction.
This delivery
still exists, but
this protein can't be successfully
fused to
where it should be fused.
So
this is still in progress.
I haven't
collected a lot of data.
This amount is not enough.
OK, I have a question.
Is there a comparison of wild-type?
Sorry, say it again.
There is a comparison of wild-type.
If it's wild-type,
I'm not prepared today,
but I have a comparison of wild-type.
If it's a comparison of wild-type,
I won't draw this cross-section.
Because it's a bit unfair.
If it's a wild-type,
you can see
this page
on the left is a wild-type.
So you can see
there is a beautiful protocloxin in the middle.
Then there is a tight junction next to it,
which is blue, and then e-catechumen.
So I won't draw the cross-section direction
I just drew.
It will be drawn along the later phase direction
of the protocloxin.
But I didn't prepare that plot today.
But you can see
it's a very good colloquize
on the layer.
So you mean
the yellow part
is actually with the pink part?
In wild-type, no.
It should be like this.
What I just said is not quite right.
Sorry.
If it's along...
I don't like the mark.
So if it's like this on the left,
if we draw a line along this purple line,
let's just say
we draw a line along the purple line.
You should see two very high peaks.
Then next to it is e-catechumen.
Then near the yellow part
there will be two very high blue peaks.
Then there will be a very large peak in the middle
which is yellow.
So when you draw this plot along this surface,
you will see that
all three proteins are on this surface.
Then
if it's like this case,
if it's along this purple line,
you won't see the blue line.
I just want to emphasize
that the blue one can't
go to the e-catechumen.
I hope this is clear.
Oh.
So in wild-type,
there is no e-catechumen
near the protocallicin.
Yes, that's right.
That's what I mean.
OK.
Let's continue.
I just said that the e-catechumen is removed.
In wild-type, sometimes
there are very few cells
that can't form an e-catechumen ring.
It can't
form a ring
to protect
the area
that should be protected.
So some cells can't form
e-catechumen.
So I caught these cells.
I also drew the plot.
So the plot here
shows the same thing.
There is a purple area.
If it goes like this,
there should be protocallicin in that area.
But now the purple area
occupies the yellow area.
So whether or not
the e-catechumen
can form
an e-catechumen ring,
in the early stage,
is a very important thing.
But in the later stage,
when it grows into a large cyst,
it has e-catechumen, for sure.
But in the early stage,
the mechanism of e-catechumen
is different from that of wild-type.
So how does it form e-catechumen in the later stage
is actually quite interesting.
We also want to look at this.
This is the result
I have obtained
for this mapping so far.
I haven't collected a lot of data yet,
but I should be able to
collect some results later.
Another thing I want to
discuss today
is that
I just said that
the entire e-catechumen
is a sphere.
So e-catechumen is like a magnet,
with a ring around it.
In the process of opening the entire e-catechumen,
we are curious about
how it opens.
So I took a picture of
this e-catechumen in two cells.
It's like a cell on the outside of the screen
and a cell behind the screen.
The ring of this e-catechumen
is a bit like
an oscillation
in the whole process.
It's like a big and small
oscillation.
So I went to
quantize its projected area.
As time went by,
it did seem to have some oscillation,
but it wasn't that obvious.
This is what I found recently.
I don't have a lot of data
to prove that it's really oscillating.
But I checked the reference.
It's not in
MDCK cells,
but in liver cells.
Someone found
a similar oscillation.
But you can see that
the time scale in the upper right corner
is quite different from the time scale in the lower left corner.
This may be caused by
different cell types.
But
they also found oscillation.
They proposed a physical model.
This oscillation
can be grown
by three mechanisms.
The first one is
the liquid
in it.
The liquid slowly
fills in and grows.
Because
e-catechumen
has sealed
the entire lumen,
it doesn't look like
a ball of air.
When you fill it in,
it slowly grows.
Another mechanism
is to shrink the lumen.
Why?
Because each cell
wants to
get farther and farther.
If the entire cell
is spherical,
it has the lowest energy.
So there's a mechanism
to shrink the lumen.
This is the
contracellular cortex.
Lateral adhesions
outside the lumen
constantly
want to
increase the connection
between the cells.
They want to
clear the lumen.
These three mechanisms
cause the oscillation.
But it's not.
These three mechanisms
don't cause the oscillation.
There's an active term
which is the shrinkage
of the cortex.
It's a function of time.
Because the lumen grows,
it becomes stronger.
It causes the oscillation.
I
personally
don't have
100% sure about this.
So
we propose another hypothesis.
It's not about
the size of the lumen.
It's about
whether the cortex looks good or not.
This is our hypothesis.
It needs to be verified.
But I think
it's possible.
The next
case is
I think
I should
finish this first.
Oh, no. Let me
look back.
I think it's related to the cortex.
One of the reasons is
Sorry.
OK.
If we
look at a cyst,
it looks like a sphere.
When there's or not a cortex,
we find something interesting.
It's a cyst with a cortex.
I label it as
P-myosin.
P-myosin is a motor protein
that makes the cortex shrink.
So you can see
it doesn't have a strong motor protein.
It's only on the outside.
But if we remove the cortex,
you can see the whole cell
has a strong cortex.
It makes us think
whether there's a cortex
is related to the cortex.
It's not confirmed.
It's not confirmed, but it's not true.
It's just my guess.
At the beginning,
I used green to represent
P-myosin and red to represent
P-myosin.
P-myosin is a certain density.
It's a certain density
around the P-myosin.
Because there's a lot of
contract R4 in the next two cells,
I hope I can reduce the Rumer.
Because there's a certain magnitude
of the contract R4.
Then, because these
epico-dom, epico-membrane, epico-dom,
epico-component are all being thrown
to this place.
Because of physicality, the more molecules,
they naturally want to expand.
At the same time, P-myosin
did not supplement in time.
The whole is a sphere.
So you can see the local P-myosin
density is decreasing.
Because of this decline,
then, at the same time,
it's like this.
In the whole Lumen growing process,
This is my personal guess.
I haven't verified it yet.
I currently have a simple experiment
to prove that
it's actually
contract R4 and
P-myosin interplay,
not pressure or other mechanisms.
Because I added
a certain kind of medicine to the cell.
The medicine will reduce
the contract R4,
the contractility between the cells.
What I see here is
this P-myosin ring did not grow
without contract R4.
If it is pressure,
it should grow automatically
because there is no force pulling it back.
So it can be seen that P-myosin
really confined the whole Lumen.
So I think
it's not very clear.
But this is my guess.
OK.
To sum up today's summary,
the first thing is
from my mapping,
my idea is that P-myosin
at the stage of two cells,
it preserves the space
where Lumen is produced.
So it can produce Lumen later.
Next,
if there is no P-myosin,
it does not affect
whether EpicoComponent can be thrown into the interface,
but whether it can be fused
to the membrane.
The third thing is
it will cause the dynamics
of the whole Lumen,
which is an oscillation.
Whether it grows well
or not depends on
the interplay between
EpicoComponent and P-myosin.
OK. This is my lab.
Let me introduce it to you.
I have two labs.
If there is a result,
we hope to build a physical model
for the two labs.
The lab on the left is my lab.
The lab on the right is my lab.
I have two bosses.
We have this special program.
You will have two teachers.
They both
belong to MPI,
but they work in
different fields.
Time and computational modeling,
or time and image processing.
We have such a program.
So here,
we are very close.
If you are interested in
my institute or have any questions,
my email is
chwng6601 gmail.com.
You can contact me.
OK.
These are my three institutes.
The yellow one is my boss.
The middle one is my institute.
The right one is my school.
OK.
Thank you.
Before we start,
let's applaud
and thank our speaker
for his wonderful speech.
Thank you.
Let's start
the Q&A.
Hello.
Hi.
I'm Adam.
I have a question.
There are different
size of lumen
in human or mammal.
What you do is
renal.
I want to ask
if there is any comparison
between ZO1 in
vascular or renal
or various lumen
epithelial cell expression level.
ZO1 seems to
regulate the size of lumen.
Right?
Personally,
I don't do this comparison.
But it's difficult
to do this.
If you know ZO1,
you know it's not only in junction.
There are many cytoplasmic cells.
In my experiment,
it's like this.
If you want to take out a single cell
and run a gene or something,
it's a little bit
inaccurate.
What we are doing now
is adding ZO1
with click chemistry.
It's a detail.
We add a tag on ZO1.
The tag will be connected by some molecules.
We connect all ZO1
in the cell,
even ZO1 on the membrane.
Then we can see the result.
But we don't do it in other species.
OK. I see.
I'm just curious.
If you are
over-express ZO1
in MDCK,
what will it look like?
If it's
a normal amount,
you can imagine
it's a football.
ZO1
along the lumen
is like a football.
If it's a normal amount,
you can see it's a little bit straight and crooked.
But if you over-express it,
you can see it's very crooked.
It's like
a very strong confine.
That's what I think.
But it's true.
OK. Thank you.
Any other questions?
OK.
You can think about
any other questions.
OK.
If you want to know
what Project Tyra is doing,
I believe
if I'm not wrong,
you all saw the Facebook announcement
and joined today's talk.
Tyra actually has a website.
You can see the link
of Tyra's website
under the announcement.
And how to join
Tyra as a member.
Or if you want to share your research,
or
what Tyra's ultimate goal is, etc.
If you're interested, you can check it out.
I'll ask one more time.
Any other questions?
If there are no questions,
let's give a round of applause
to thank Chen He for his wonderful talk.
Thank you.
I'm going to stop recording.