Hello, everyone. Good evening. Welcome to today's Tower Talk.
Today, we are very honored to have our speaker, Lucas Peng,
to talk to us about this. Basically, he just graduated from his doctorate thesis.
Clocked atom delivery to a photonic crystal waveguide.
And then there's the simulation part, and then there's the experimental part.
And then he used to be in the Kimball Group at the California Institute of Technology, doing quantum optics.
So let me introduce the background of Lucas Peng.
Wait a minute, I'll turn it off.
Lucas Peng's doctoral research is mainly focused on the quantum simulation platform by trapping atoms close to the surface of photonic crystal waveguide.
And then after he got his doctorate, he went to a company in North Carolina called AO Sensing,
which is currently developing quantum sensing technology.
Lucas Peng is actually a senior at the California Institute of Technology.
He was originally a biophysicist at the University of Taiwan.
And then after graduation, he went to Caltech and got his doctorate.
And now he's in North Carolina.
He's going to talk to us about the topic I just talked about.
If you want to applaud, you have to turn on the microphone.
Otherwise, our speakers won't be able to hear you.
So let's applaud and welcome Lucas Peng to give us today's speech.
Thank you.
Okay, you can start.
Thank you, Mr. Zhang, for giving me the opportunity to share my research.
If you have any questions during my presentation, please feel free to interrupt me at any time.
The topic I'm going to talk about today is my Ph.D. research.
It's mainly about how to put color atoms near the photonic crystal waveguide.
The main purpose is that if you can successfully capture the atoms near the photonic crystal waveguide,
you can use it as a quantum simulation platform.
First, I'm going to talk about our experimental system.
This is the transparent photonic crystal waveguide.
The atoms are trapped in the gap between the two waveguides.
So let me first explain why this system is different from other systems,
such as nanofiber or cavity QED.
What's the difference? What's the advantage?
And of course, what challenges will it bring?
Next, I'm going to introduce a simulation program I developed.
It simulates how atoms move near the photonic crystal waveguide.
And it calculates a 2D spectrum using these simulations.
After getting this spectrum, we can understand the behavior of atoms near the waveguide.
Finally, it will show some experiment results and compare them with the simulation results.
Then we can see what conclusions we can get from it.
First of all, the purpose of this research is to achieve a very strong interaction between light and atoms.
Why is this important?
In the study of quantum technology, such as quantum mechanics or quantum information,
we usually use light to transmit quantum information.
When the quantum information is transmitted, we hope it will be transferred to another system.
Because these systems have a longer lifetime,
the quantum information can be kept longer to do more processing.
In the field of ML, one of the research directions is to transfer quantum information from light to atoms.
To do this, we need a very strong interaction between light and atoms.
Of course, the simplest way is to focus light on a very small area,
which is about a wavelength.
Then put an atom in the focal length to interact with light and atoms.
The limitation of this method is that the area of light is ultimately limited by the wavelength.
In this way, the probability of interaction between light and atoms is very low.
How to make this probability higher?
One way is to put the atom in a cavity.
You can imagine that the light is reflected in the cavity.
Every time the light passes through the atom, it will have one more chance to interact with the atom.
In this way, the probability of interaction between light and atoms can be greatly increased.
In addition to using a cavity, you can also use a resonator structure like this microtoray.
In fact, it is a bit like a cavity.
The light will keep circling in this circle.
Every time the light passes through the atom, it will have one more chance to interact with the atom.
Another way is to increase the number of atoms.
For example, the Rieper atom.
As long as one of the atoms interacts with the light,
it will move to a high quantum number state.
In this way, it can block other atoms and continue to interact with the light.
So it seems that one atom can be equivalent to a huge atom.
What I just said is that the light is reflected back and forth in the cavity.
Another way is to imagine that the cavity changes the density of light.
So the atoms can have more states to interact with.
This is another way to look at it.
In addition to the cavity QED, there is another system called waveguide QED.
The waveguide QED is a model that can be seen as a very thin fiber and an atom.
When the light moves in this fiber,
you can imagine that it has an input capacitor,
a transmittance and a reflection capacitor.
You can calculate the reflection formula of this system.
The most important number in it is gamma1d.
Gamma1d is the probability that the light will move to the fiber after the atom decays.
Because we want a very strong interaction between light and atoms,
the higher the probability, the better.
Gamma' is the probability that the light decays to other unnecessary states in space.
The research of strong atom-photon coupling is to make gamma1d higher and better.
How to make it higher?
There are several ways to do it.
One way is to reduce the molar area.
The smaller the area, the higher the probability of interaction between light and atoms.
Another way is to reduce the proof velocity.
Proof velocity means that the slower the light moves in the fiber,
the more chance it has to interact with the atoms.
An important figure of merit is gamma1d to gamma'.
The light decays to the state you want,
which is the state in the fiber.
The light decays to the state you want, which is the state in the fiber.
The system we made in the lab is a finite crystal waveguide.
What is the difference between a finite crystal waveguide and a normal light fiber?
The point is that the distance from the light fiber to the atom is limited by the wavelength.
The ratio of gamma1d to gamma' is about 4% in the current experiment.
90% of the light does not interact with the atom, but only passes through the atom.
In theory, if the light can be captured very close to the finite crystal waveguide,
gamma1d over gamma' can be increased to about 20.
In this way, only 0.2% of the light will interact with the atom.
Why is gamma1d over gamma' so high?
The reason is that the finite crystal waveguide allows you to control the group velocity.
For example, if the light is very close to the finite crystal band edge,
the group velocity becomes very low.
For example, in our system, the group velocity can only be 1 tenth of the light.
Another reason is that the finite crystal waveguide can be made into a variety of shapes.
You can design this shape to limit the light in a very small range.
For example, the system we use allows the light to be concentrated in the middle gap.
This allows the light to be limited to a smaller area than the wavelength.
This can greatly improve the interaction between light and atoms.
In this system, light is an atom, and it can reflect almost all light.
You can imagine it as a quantum mirror.
Waveguide QED, in addition to the finite crystal waveguide called Alligator,
also has a variety of applications.
For example, you can extend the heat of the light,
and it will become a very thin light, the nano fiber.
You can also put some trees in it.
It will form some traps in the environment.
This will capture the atoms around the light.
Another system, like Huffle's Looking Group,
is also a finite crystal waveguide.
They use an optical tweezer to hold the atom,
and drag it near the finite crystal waveguide.
This allows it to interact with the guided mode in the finite crystal waveguide.
At Purdue University, they also have a system
that uses an optical tweezer to capture the atoms
near the finite crystal waveguide.
Another special feature of the finite crystal waveguide is...
One more question.
This is a general question.
What kind of material do you use for structures like this?
It depends on what kind of waveguide you want to transmit the light.
You want it to be as transparent as possible.
For example, the CZM waveguide we use is 890nm.
We use Zirconitride.
Got it. Thank you.
So you can choose the material you want based on the wavelength you want.
For example, we often use Telecom Waveband.
You can also use materials like Silica.
A special feature of the waveguide
is that you can design your waveguide
to have different wavelengths in different frequencies.
For example, this is a bandstructure graph.
The horizontal axis is the wave number,
and the vertical axis is the frequency.
You can see that at this frequency...
For example, at a certain frequency, the light can't fall inside.
This is a concept called bandgap.
At the edge of the bandgap,
you can see that the dΩdk is equal to 0.
This means that the group velocity is very small.
So in this case, the density of states is very high.
So if the frequency of the original wave is around here,
you can imagine that it can interact with many states.
This can greatly increase the probability of decaying to the state.
So we usually design the FWG to have a bandgap
that is very close to the original wavelength.
So you can imagine that the dΩdk can be outside the bandgap,
or inside the bandgap.
The first case is that when the dΩdk is outside the bandgap,
you can see that this frequency can be transmitted in the waveguide.
For example, when the original wave goes from GF to GF,
it emits a light.
This light is at the frequency that can be transmitted,
so it will move on the waveguide.
So you can imagine that the interaction between the atoms on the waveguide is as strong.
This is a region.
Another region is that if you put the frequency of the atom's wavelength into the bandgap,
because the light of this frequency cannot be transmitted inside the waveguide,
it will form an exponential decay light cloud near the atom.
So it's more interesting at this time.
The farther the atoms are, the lower their interaction.
The closer the atoms are, the longer the interaction.
So you can imagine that this can have some local interaction.
Next, I will explain how to control the two atoms in this region
to produce a convenient interaction.
So in theory, as long as you have a one-dimensional system,
you can let the atoms produce a Hamiltonian that can be engineered conveniently.
Let's start with a simple example outside the waveguide.
This is an experiment we did in our lab in 2015.
The way to do this experiment is to use a laser beam to shine on the waveguide.
It will form such an interference pattern.
You can see that the interference pattern has some intensity maxima here and here.
We call it Z1, Z2.
If the laser frequency is slightly lower than the intensity of the atom,
it will attract the atoms to the intensity maxima.
By this way, we will catch some atoms near the front crystal waveguide.
This place is above the waveguide, so it's not in the middle of the waveguide.
So in this place, γ1d over γ' is about 2.
This means that when it decays, the probability of it decaying to the waveguide is 2 times higher than the probability of it decaying to the vacuum.
What's interesting about this is that if the atoms are periodically caught on the front crystal waveguide,
if the interference between them is the wavelength of the vacuum,
an atom can interact with the entire collective state of the atom.
In this way, the interaction will enhance the number of atoms.
For example, if you have nA atoms, the interaction between them will increase nA times.
But the number of atoms decays to free space is the same.
So the more atoms you have, the more likely it is to decay to the waveguide.
This is a phenomenon similar to superradiance.
In this experiment, the number of atoms is used to control how long you have been caught.
The longer you have been caught, the more likely the atom will escape your trap.
So here you can see that when the atom is caught, the decay speed is very fast.
When you let it go for a long time, the decay speed drops.
We can see that when the number of atoms increases, the interaction between it and the state of the waveguide increases.
You can do the same experiment in the same way.
But this time we can adjust the bandage of the waveguide to the outside of the atom.
Although the wavelength frequency of the atom is inside the bandgap.
At this time, you can see that there are two traces here.
The green trace describes the intensity of the photon decay to the waveguide.
The blue trace measures how long the interaction between the atoms is.
The intensity of this interaction can be determined by the symmetry of the measured spectrum.
If the interaction is stronger, the spectrum will not be symmetrical.
So you can measure how strong the interaction between the atoms is.
You can see that when the wavelength frequency of the atom enters the bandgap,
The photon does not decay to the waveguide.
But the interaction between the atoms is still greater than the probability of the photon decaying to the waveguide.
This means that in the bandgap region, the photon is still a potential decay cloud.
Next, if you can put the atoms in the waveguide and form a string,
You can add a magnetic field to make each atom's Zeeman state different.
For example, you can use an extra laser beam to add a sideband.
The sideband can match the difference in the frequency of the Zeeman state between the atoms.
Then you can engineer the interaction between two random atoms.
For example, the system here has a one-dimensional atom array.
There are interactions between the two arrays.
The interaction between the rightmost and the leftmost sideband can be simulated.
It is a circular system.
Excuse me, can I go back to the page?
I don't quite understand.
Wait a minute, I don't quite understand.
You said two interactions.
Why does it become a circle?
It doesn't overlap the last two interactions.
For example, when you want to make two atoms interact,
You have to let...
Take a look at this state first.
There are three states in this atom.
There are two ground states and one excited state.
No, I know what's up there.
Oh, no, it's okay, I saw it.
Because my idea is,
Don't you all interact with the neighbors?
How did it become a periodic boundary condition?
That's how it becomes a circle.
You're right.
The beginning and the end also interact.
Yes, but it doesn't necessarily only interact with the neighbors.
Does it interact?
It depends on the frequency of your guiding mode.
Does it resonate with the frequency of your other state?
You can imagine that you can add a magnetic field.
It's a gradient magnetic field.
Let every atom's Zeeman state have a slightly different frequency.
So basically, you can just pick it up.
You don't have to...
You can use an extra laser frequency to pick up the two atoms.
Oh, okay, okay, I see.
Hello, can I ask a question?
Is this similar to gradient echo memory?
It's a bit like spin echo.
Gn, gradient echo memory, is a magnetic field that slowly increases.
Then every connection will have a slightly different splitting.
Yes, it's a bit like this.
Is there a difference between the two?
Who has the advantage?
I should say...
I just said that using a strong magnetic field to create a difference.
But you don't have to use a magnetic field.
You can use the AC source shape to let each state have a different frequency.
In this case, you don't necessarily need a gradient.
You can have a laser for each atom to generate different shapes.
Okay, thank you.
Next, I will introduce the Delegator Functional Crystal Waveguide we use.
This is what the whole system looks like.
First of all, the whole system is hanging on the window in the middle of the chip.
The way we interact with the waveguide is mainly through the light.
The light is stuck to the chip.
Then it can be coupled with the waveguide.
You can see that there are many other structures on the waveguide.
For example, there is a coupler here.
Then there are some mechanical structures here.
The purpose of the coupler is to pull the device so that the two beams in the middle do not stick together.
So this angle is optimized so that the center of the waveguide can maintain the gap.
In addition, these structures are responsible for the heat generated by the laser.
You will find that even if you only input a few microwave lasers,
Because the whole structure is very small, it will become very hot.
This is a device, SEM.
But you don't do active cooling, do you?
You just do it in the light.
In fact, we still have to heat it up.
Because we can't cool it down.
So sometimes you adjust the frequency to heat it up.
After heating it up, you can change its bandage.
So you don't just do it, but you don't want active cooling.
It's not that you can't do it, but we don't do active cooling.
And there's a bad thing about being too cold.
If you're cold, your laser will stick to it.
So sometimes you want it to get hotter and hotter.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
You said your structure is about a few hundred nanometers.
Then you said you need to use fiber.
Is it because this structure is very small?
You need to use evanescent wave to go in.
With the effect of atoms.
Yes.
Because in the end you want to send the light to the waveguide.
So the way we use it is to put...
You can see it on this side.
We stick the fiber to the chip.
Align it with the waveguide.
I was surprised at first.
You think the fiber is big.
The waveguide is only a few hundred nanometers.
You think its mode doesn't match.
But if you calculate the waveguide's mode.
You find that the fiber's mode matches 90%.
In fact, about 50% of the light can be sent to the waveguide.
Is the light coming from the evanescent wave?
Or is it a normal wave transmitted?
Because it's single-mode fiber.
It's like a mode built in fiber.
It just came out and it's directly on the waveguide's mode.
So as long as its mode is matched, it can continue to pass through the waveguide.
It's not an evanescent wave.
But it's not a Gaussian beam.
It's a single-mode fiber in the waveguide.
The mode depends on the gradient of the evanescent wave.
This is an experiment photo.
We stick the light on the chip.
Mount it on a viewport.
Then install the viewport into the vacuum chamber.
Let me briefly explain the CZM's energy level.
The CZM's fine structure uses 6S and 6P states.
6S is the ground state.
6P is the fine structure.
Because of the spin-orbit coupling, there are two different connections.
If you consider the hyperfine structure,
it's because of the nuclear spin and the electron spin.
The ground state is subdivided into Fn3 and Fn4.
The 6P state can also be divided into two connections.
The upper one is divided into four connections.
The lower frequency is called D1.
The higher frequency is called D2.
The design of the finite crystal waveguide allows D1 to correspond to a band edge.
D2 corresponds to another band edge.
You can imagine a simple idea.
You use a band edge frequency, D1, to capture the atom.
You use another frequency, D2, to trap the atom.
For example, if you put D2's laser into the waveguide,
and make it slightly blue detuned,
the atom will be pushed to the intensity minima.
The atom will be trapped to the thickest point.
You can use another band edge frequency, D1, to probe the atom.
Because D1 is another band edge,
the intensity will be stronger at the thickest point.
In this case, you can use one frequency to capture,
and another frequency to detect the atom.
Of course, this is a simplified model.
There will be more details in the introduction.
The main purpose of our experiment is to capture the atom in the finite crystal gap.
And we hope that each size can capture an atom.
If you can do this,
you can think about promoting it to more complex systems,
such as binary finite crystal.
Here is a brief description of the basic atom cooling and capturing techniques used in the experiment.
The methods used are MOP,
Dipole Trap,
Optical Lattice,
and a cooling technique called Degenerate Raman Side-In Cooling.
MOP is a method of surrounding the atom group.
There are six lasers in total.
You can imagine that it is like a Doppler cooling in every direction.
The atom going down will be absorbed by the light
and released from the inside,
so it will get a momentum kick,
and it will be cooled.
The purpose of adding this magnetic field is to introduce a space-dependent shift
to generate confinement.
If you have confinement and cooling,
you can make a MOP.
Another concept is Optical Dipole Trap.
As I just explained,
if the frequency of the laser is slightly lower than the frequency of the atomic moon,
it will produce a shift to your connection.
In this case,
the ground state will shift down,
and the excited state will shift up.
You can see that in the ground state atom,
it will produce a space-dependent potential.
At this time, the frequency of the atomic moon can also change.
I will talk about how to help us understand where the atom is in space.
For example, if the frequency of the laser is slightly lower than the frequency of the atomic moon,
the atom will be sucked into the Intensity Maxima.
If the light is Blue Detuned,
the atom will be blown away by the Intensity Maxima.
So if there is Intensity Minima in your potential,
the atom will be gathered in that place.
There are different configurations.
The simplest is Gaussian Beam.
It can produce a trap.
In the lab, we use two lasers to form a standing wave.
At this time, the atom can be captured in the standing wave.
It looks like a lattice.
This is called Optical Lattice.
After the atom is caught in the Optical Lattice,
we still need to cool it.
The cooling method we use here is called Degenerate Raman Sibon Cooling.
This is a very ingenious way.
The way is that you can add a magnetic field
to produce a little change in the connection between atoms in different MF states.
If the difference in energy between each MF state
is just equal to the energy of the H-bar omega
that vibrates in your Optical Lattice,
you can see that the vibrating state of under 1
is the same energy as the under 0 state of the next MF state.
At this time, you can use the Raman Transition method
to transfer the atom from n equals 1 to the under 0 state
and then pump it back.
After this cycle,
the atom can reduce the vibration frame.
By repeating this process,
in theory, you can cool the atom
to the vibration state in your trap.
By doing this,
we can cool the atom in the Optical Lattice.
Once the atom is trapped in the Optical Lattice,
the way we experiment here is to move the Optical Lattice.
As long as you change one of the laser frequencies,
the entire interference pattern will start to move.
We can use this method to let the atom pass through the Phonar Crystal Lake guy.
The purpose is that
each piece of the Optical Lattice's MF
is called a pancake.
For example, there are 500 atoms in it.
Of these 500 atoms,
only a small part will interact with the Phonar Crystal Lake guy.
But in the experiment cycle,
there are 2000 pancakes passing through the Phonar Crystal Lake guy.
Through this method,
we can try to let more atoms interact with the Phonar Crystal Lake guy.
This is a simple picture of our experiment.
First, we make a MOD of the atom in the Source Chamber.
Then we use a laser to kick it into another MOD in the main chamber.
Then we cool the atom in the MOD
and trap it in the Optical Lattice.
The Optical Lattice is a beam of two lasers.
Once the atom is caught in the Optical Lattice,
we change the frequency of one of the lasers
and move the atom near the device.
When the atom is near the device,
we can put a few beams into the waveguide.
One of the beams is a Probe Laser.
This laser adjusts the frequency of D1 of the DZM.
If the atom is near the Phonar Crystal Lake guy,
it will absorb the light of the Probe.
We can use the amount of Probe through the waveguide
to measure how many atoms interact with the waveguide.
We can also put various trapped potentials into the waveguide.
Another important component is that
when the Optical Lattice passes through the waveguide,
some light will be emitted into the waveguide.
We can also detect the light emitted by the Optical Lattice.
Through this light, we can know which part of the Optical Lattice is passing through the waveguide.
Is it passing through the waveguide at the peak?
Or is it passing through the waveguide at the valley?
Through this, we can have more data to understand
how the atom moves near the Phonar Crystal Lake guy.
This is an experimental result.
We can see that the atom passes through the Phonar Crystal Lake guy at T20.
The horizontal axis is the time,
and the vertical axis is the frequency of the Probe Beam.
We can turn the Probe Beam from negative 50 MHz to positive 50 MHz detuning.
The atom passes through the waveguide at T20.
This is the data from one of the photodials.
The photodial specifically detects the light emitted by the Optical Lattice.
When the atom passes through, it generates a periodic signal.
The frequency of this signal depends on how fast the Optical Lattice passes through the Phonar Crystal Lake guy.
For example, we are using a frequency of about 1.2 MHz to move the Optical Lattice.
The signal is 1.2 MHz.
Through this signal, we can know what time the atom is passing through the Phonar Crystal Lake guy.
Note that the time scale here is microsecond.
The time scale on the right is millisecond.
So there are thousands of Optical Lattice pancakes passing through the Phonar Crystal Lake guy in these two Blobs.
Do you know the number of atoms in each Blob?
We can know how many atoms are near the Phonar Crystal Lake guy.
At any time, there may be one or two atoms passing through the Phonar Crystal Lake guy.
We estimate that each pancake will have one atom passing through the gap of the Phonar Crystal Lake guy.
This is where we really want to catch the atoms.
The reason why we use Optical Lattice is to get a cycle.
For example, each pancake can catch one atom in the gap.
If 100 pancakes pass through the gap, we can catch 100 atoms.
The purpose of this experiment is to find a trapping cycle.
So that each Optical Lattice cycle can catch one atom.
Of course, we haven't reached this goal yet.
But my PhD research is moving in this direction.
We just saw that the setup of the experiment can produce such an experiment result.
How do we interpret this experiment result?
Through simulation, we can help us understand how these atomic trajectories correspond to the experimental results we get.
This simulation is a Monte Carlo simulation.
The atoms are scattered in the Optical Lattice.
They are then formalized and moved to the vicinity of the Phonar Crystal Lake guy.
According to the Optical Dipole Potential, each atom moves.
Finally, we collect these trajectories and calculate the spectrum we should get.
The concept of simulation is very complicated.
But there are some challenges in practice.
Because it is a periodic potential,
you need to measure a large area for the atoms to formalize in this potential.
For example, our simulation domain is a few tens of microns.
But the Phonar Crystal is a very small device.
Its size is a few hundred nanometers to a micron.
So the whole experiment is very memory-intensive.
So most of the time, it is optimized to use as little data as possible.
The concept of simulation is to let the atoms simulate how they move from a faraway place to the vicinity of the Phonar Crystal Lake guy.
Then simulate various Optical Dipole Force and Probing Beam Profile to calculate the spectrum you will get.
You can also do 3D simulation.
For example, this is a simulation result.
You can see the lines here are the atomic trajectories.
The atomic trajectories can be subdivided into different types of trajectories.
For example, these green trajectories are the gaps in the Phonar Crystal Lake guy.
These are the atoms we are most interested in.
The other blue trajectories are the ones that go around the outside of the device.
The red ones are the ones that hit the surface of the device.
Next, we're going to use these trajectories to calculate a spectrum.
How do you calculate the spectrum?
You can distribute the atomic trajectories to the top of the Phonar Crystal Lake guy.
For example, there are a few atoms here.
You can use a matrix to represent each segment of the Phonar Crystal Lake guy.
This matrix is called the transfer matrix.
The Phonar Crystal Lake guy has its own transfer matrix.
Each atom has its own transfer matrix.
The transfer matrix of the atoms depends on the location of the atoms.
We can see that the Gamma 1D is determined by the strength of the probe at that location.
The distance between the atoms near the Phonar Crystal Lake guy determines the strength of the Gamma 1D.
The transfer matrix of each atom is different.
If we multiply all these matrices, we get the total transfer matrix.
From there, we can get the transmission and reflection of the entire system.
Next, let's see what the simulation results will be.
I just explained how to get the atomic trajectories through simulation.
Next, I will explain how to connect the results of our experiment through simulation.
Here is a tool we use.
We call it the Clock Spectrum.
Why is it called Clock?
Because our apical lattice sends the atoms near the device.
The atoms are cyclically sent near the Phonar Crystal.
For example, if your chirping frequency is 1MHz, each micron will have an atom passing through.
Theoretically, you can get a cyclic signal.
The cyclic signal depends on the frequency of the atoms coming to your device.
For example, if we look at the light coming out of the probe and make it into a histogram,
we can see that the frequency of the apical lattice is a cyclic signal.
We can also detect the apical lattice signal through another photodiode.
This gives us a clock so that we can know which part of the apical lattice is passing through our waveguide.
If you fold the signals of each microsecond into an apical lattice period, you can get a histogram.
The histogram tells you how many atoms are interacting with the device at different times in the apical lattice frequency.
If you do this experiment for each detuning, you can get a two-dimensional spectrum.
In this two-dimensional picture, the horizontal axis is the time, and the vertical axis is the probe detuning.
This two-dimensional spectrum can convey some information about the atoms moving near the Phonar Crystal waveguide.
The next step is to find out how to match the atomic trajectory to the two-dimensional spectrum.
There are different modes for this experiment.
As mentioned earlier, we let the bandage correspond to the transition of C-joint D1 and D2.
Another mode is polarization.
As mentioned earlier, the bandage corresponds to when the polarization is parallel to the waveguide.
If it is perpendicular, there will be another bandgap.
However, this bandgap is far from the frequency of C-joint D1 and D2.
So for this proof, the frequency of C-joint D1 and D2 is like a normal waveguide.
Here you can see TE mode.
D1 and D2 are bandage modes.
The frequency of D1 and D2 has a very obvious x-direction structure.
For example, D2's intensity is concentrated in the thin part.
D1's intensity is concentrated in the thick part.
We mainly use these two modes to probe and capture the atoms.
TE mode, you can see that it is almost uniform in the direction of the waveguide.
Because the frequency of C-joint D1 and D2 is far from the TEM bandgap,
the frequency of C-joint D1 and D2 is like a normal waveguide.
This mode is different in that its intensity is the strongest above and below the waveguide.
So it has a very useful feature that can help us protect the surface of the device.
If you let it be a blue-D-chain, it can bounce away the atoms near it,
so that it won't stick to the surface of the device.
At the same time, it can produce a large A-structure inside the gap and outside the gap,
so that we can detect how many atoms pass through the gap.
This is a detail.
We just said that using a mode to do trapping is actually a simplification.
We need to combine two modes to produce a stable trap on the three-dimensional surface.
There is another interesting challenge.
We found that to produce a trap, the energy of two modes must have a ratio.
If there is no ratio, the trap will not be a stable trap.
But there is a problem.
The intensity of different frequencies coupled to the waveguide is different.
So we can't directly measure how much light is in the waveguide.
So how do we know the intensity ratio of two modes?
By combining the experiment results and simulation results,
we can know how strong the light in the waveguide is.
Another purpose of the experiment is to tell us the timing.
Here is a way of trapping.
When the atom enters the middle of the waveguide,
for example, it is in the state f4.
When the atom is in the middle, we pump it to the excited state at the right time.
We can see that the atom is pumped from a light potential to a deep potential.
At this time, the atom can be trapped.
Otherwise, the atom will come in and go out again.
Because this is a conservative potential.
To get this result, we need to know the time of the atom passing the gap.
The same simulation can tell us the time of the atom passing the gap.
Let's look at this first.
I have a question.
Does your simulation include interference?
For example, environmental, thermal, radiation, etc.
Because I don't know what is the background interference of Dominant.
Does it include?
Thermal radiation, compared to other modes,
For example, the strength of the output lattice is hundreds of milliwatts.
The Guided Mode contains several microwatts.
Their intensity is much greater than thermal radiation.
So we don't need to consider thermal radiation.
Is there any other known interference that needs to be considered?
There is one.
It can't be classified as interference.
This is a big factor.
Casper-Poller force.
The atom is very close to the attraction force.
If you don't consider the attraction force, the result will be quite different.
I didn't think of it at first.
But later I found it to be a very important factor.
I see. Thank you.
There are some interference factors.
For example, the vibration of the device.
We can think of it as a suspension line.
If it heats up, it may vibrate.
We have measured the frequency of its vibration.
I found that it is much greater than the frequency of the atom vibrating in the trap.
So we don't need to consider it for the time being.
Let's explain how to calibrate these three different modes.
I want to introduce a simple question first.
The question is how to calibrate the optical lattice beam.
This is not a calibration.
Because we already know how strong the optical lattice beam is.
It's just a way to verify that this is a feasible method.
This is a simulation result.
The density of the atom here is much greater than the real density.
The real density is only about one-tenth.
This simulation result can let us know how the atom moves near the device.
The potentials used in this simulation are two optical lattices and the Kessler-Potter force I just mentioned.
The atom will be attracted when it is very close to the device.
The attraction is the blue potential around it.
It is a very strong potential.
On the right, we can see the simulated clock spectrum.
The atom is attracted by the optical lattice.
So it's not coming one by one.
We can think of it as passing through the final crystal.
It will cause the biggest absorption.
It's not zero detuning.
Because the optical lattice is red detuning.
So it brings a blue detuning.
As mentioned before, the red detuning potential will reduce the ground state.
But the excited state will be higher.
So the overall frequency will also increase.
So we can see that the frequency of the atomic transition is a positive detuning.
Here we can see that it's going down.
This is a phenomenon caused by the Kessler-Potter potential.
The Kessler-Potter potential is also an attractive potential.
If the excited state doesn't change, the frequency of the atomic transition will also increase.
So it's a red detuning.
The reason is that the Kessler-Potter potential affects the excited state.
For the cesium D1 transition,
the change in the excited state is actually twice the ground state.
So the decrease in the excited state is actually twice as much as the decrease in the ground state.
So in fact, the frequency of the atomic transition is getting smaller.
So under the influence of the Kessler-Potter potential, the detuning is negative.
We can see that the left is the result of the experiment.
So we find that the two are actually quite matched.
And the size of the detuning is the same.
This means that the parameters of the simulation and the experiment are the same.
At this time, we can measure something we don't know.
For example, we can measure the length of the TM guided mode.
This is a simulation of the TM guided mode.
The TM guided mode is a blue detuning.
So it generates a negative Kessler-Potter potential above and below the waveguide.
So we can see that the atoms are ejected by the Kessler-Potter potential.
At the same time, it changes the direction of the atoms entering the gap.
The picture on the right is a comparison of the simulation and the experiment.
We can see that the simulation of the two-dimensional surface is actually very similar.
So their differences are not detailed.
However, we can see that the simulation and the experiment are very similar.
We can see that after adding this potential,
it has some impact on the two-dimensional Kessler-Potter potential.
The biggest impact is that you can see that it generates a feature that goes down.
This feature is caused by the difference in time when the atoms are ejected by the Kessler-Potter potential.
Now we can compare the light energy of the experiment with the simulation.
We can see that the light intensity of the simulation is actually less.
This is because the light intensity measured in the experiment is the light intensity in the fiber.
The light intensity in the waveguide is actually much less.
So we can estimate that the fiber coupling efficiency is about 30%.
The efficiency is the same as measured in other ways.
In this way, we can directly measure the intensity of the light energy in the device.
What kind of trajectory does this feature correspond to?
We can see that the blue feature corresponds to the blue trajectory on the right.
They are outside the device, so they see less guided modes and receive less AC short-circuits.
The trajectory that climbs up is the blue guided mode,
so it sees a longer value chain, and the frequency is getting lower and lower.
In the middle gap, the AC short-circuit corresponds to the green result.
We can see that we can use this method to know the time and location of the atoms near the device.
There are about 100 ns time resolution and 50 ns space resolution.
We can use the same method to do TMO.
We can see that it matches quite well.
Interestingly, we found that the intensity of the energy in the device is much more than what we put into the experiment.
But this is not surprising, because we are using TEMO.
TEMO's D1 detour is on the band edge.
Because the band edge's group velocity becomes smaller,
the intensity of the light inside will be enhanced.
The intensity of the light inside the VGAI is greater than what we put into the experiment.
This tells us that there is a slow light effect.
As I said, there are different types of trajectories.
We can separate them in the simulation to see what each of them contributes to the flux vector.
For example, the contribution caused by the middle atom,
the contribution caused by the outer atom, and the contribution caused by the other blue atoms.
This is a very important feature.
It tells us if there is really an atom passing through the gap.
Because this is the atom we want to capture.
So we want to know if there is really an atom passing through the gap.
We can find that if we take a cut at this time,
you will find that there are two dips.
The simulation tells us that one of the dips mainly comes from the contribution of the middle atom.
The other dip is the contribution of other atoms.
So we can observe that there are two dips at this time in the experiment.
So it can tell us that there are indeed atoms passing through the gap in the middle.
By comparing the simulation results,
we can estimate that each pancake will have one or two atoms passing through the gap.
At the same time, the simulation also tells us
when to pump the atom into the deeper trap.
The position of the dip tells us the AC structure over there.
So it tells us what frequency of the laser should pump the atom into the deeper trap.
By comparing the simulation and the experiment,
First, we can calibrate the strength of the guided mode to create the trap we want.
Second, it tells us when to pump the atom.
Third, it tells us what detuning to use to pump the atom into the trap.
Finally, let's talk about the more unexpected result.
We can probe how strong the Kasper-Potter force is.
For example, there are two simulations.
The right one has no Kasper-Potter force.
The left one has Kasper-Potter force.
The difference is that there is a feature that goes down here.
We found that this feature does appear in the experiment.
By comparing the two features,
we can get the Kasper-Potter potential.
The potential coefficient is the same as mentioned in the simulation.
Finally, let's talk about the new research I did when I left.
A new way to put the chip into the vacuum chamber is very troublesome.
You have to stick 16 fibers to the U-Port and then put it into the chamber.
It usually takes us two days.
The new generation of experiments does not require light.
You can directly focus the laser on the coupler with the microscope objective.
You can directly couple from the vacuum chamber to the waveguide.
This can greatly reduce the time it takes to replace the chip.
It also provides more optical access.
We can put more beams and have closer observation.
Another way is that we can use optical tweezers instead of optical lasers.
The advantage of optical lasers is that it gives us a lot of atoms in a short time.
It can extract the information I just mentioned.
If you want to fine-tune the position of the atoms, you can use optical tweezers.
You can fine-tune the position of the atoms on the one-dimensional waveguide.
In this way, you can probe the interaction between two atoms more directly.
This is a summary of the applications of the two-dimensional waveguide.
This is a summary of the two-dimensional waveguide.
First, I talked about why we want to do Strong Atom Photon Interaction.
Then, I explained how we send the atoms near the waveguide.
Next, I will introduce a numerical simulation.
This is a numerical simulation to simulate the trajectory of the atoms.
Then, calculate a two-dimensional spectrum from these trajectories.
It can help us adjust the strength of the guided mode.
It can help us understand the behavior of the atoms near the waveguide.
It can help us understand the time and how the neutrino pumps the atoms into the trap.
It can help us understand the attraction force of the atoms near the dielectric.
Thank you.
Thank you, everyone.
Let's applaud to thank our speaker today.
Please turn on the microphone.
Then, we can hear your applause.
Thank you for giving us this wonderful speech.
Next, we are going to have a Q&A.
Before we start, let me advertise something.
If you support what Project TARA is doing,
and support our ideas,
and support us to promote overseas scholars in Taiwan,
and share the results of our research,
we welcome you to join Project TARA as a member,
not just follow our Facebook page
and read our weekly posts.
You can find the way to join
on the Facebook post.
We welcome you
and we need you to share
the results of your research.
You can find the way to join
on our Facebook page
and our website.
Now, let's start the Q&A.
Any questions?
I have a question.
What you just said
is using Optical Lattice
to deliver your origin
to the photonic crystal?
The ultimate goal is to deliver it
to the gap between the two photonic crystals
and let the origin stay in the gap.
The current method is...
Is it possible to easily control
the gap between your lattice
and the gap between your crystals?
This is...
This is Optical Lattice's...
It consists of two Gaussian beams.
We put the photonic crystal waveguide
on the position of the Gaussian beam.
The position of the beam
is about 60 microns.
The size of the device
is about 1 microns.
Most of the origin
does not pass
near the photonic crystal waveguide.
But when each pan can pass,
dozens of them
will appear near the waveguide.
Among those dozens,
one or two may run into the gap.
I think it can be delivered one-to-one.
This is very difficult.
Because the gap is 200 nanometers.
The wavelength is not that small.
Even if you can focus on
the wavelength,
the Rayleigh Lambda will be very small.
So you can't...
It's impossible to load
such a large mod
into the Optical Lattice.
After loading,
the Rayleigh Lambda is about 2 nanometers.
It takes thousands of pancakes
to deliver one-to-one.
If you focus on such a small wavelength,
it's a bit like
what I just mentioned,
the optical tracer.
The optical tracer focuses on
the wavelength.
Relatively speaking,
you can only trap one ray
and put it near the waveguide.
It has its advantages.
The difficulty is that
you have to catch a ray
and move the ray
to the waveguide.
You can't lose the ray.
So it's difficult.
Okay, thank you.
I have a question.
I want to ask...
You said your goal is
to achieve strong
metroid interaction.
I want to ask
your long-term goal is
when you achieve strong interaction,
what do you want to do with it?
The main goal is
to simulate
the system of
many-body physics.
In addition to
the simulation of
quantum magnetism,
there is another
interesting experiment.
For example,
the cavity QED
is a classical object
with a large diameter.
You can imagine
if you catch five atoms
and put a side in the middle,
the middle is an atom again,
and the side is five atoms.
The five atoms on the left and right
is like a black mirror.
That means the atom
and the mirror
are quantum objects.
This is very interesting.
Through what I said,
you can create
pairwise Hamiltonian
in quantum simulation.
You can create
various quantum simulations
in pairwise Hamiltonian.
There is another interesting
application that I didn't mention.
This is different from
the general waveguide QD,
because it has a
dielectric structure.
This dielectric structure
forces the intensity of the light
to stick to the structure.
So you can make
the distance between the atoms
smaller than the wavelength
of free space.
This is an interesting phenomenon.
The light radiated
to the free space
is interfered by the atoms.
This can greatly reduce
the intensity of spontaneous emission.
This is something
that general waveguide QD
can't do.
If you can
greatly suppress
the frequency of decay
to free space,
you can make
a quantum memory system.
Do you have any questions?
If not,
I have a question.
Can you jump to the
Kashmir Force page?
You can explain
what you want to convey
in this page.
How do you see this?
At the beginning of the simulation,
we didn't add
the Kashmir Force page.
You can see that
this simulation
is the simplest
one.
We didn't add any
guide mode,
only probe and optical lattice.
The optical lattice
is ready-tuned.
The light in the whole system
All the atoms we see
should have
the same
probe frequency
to see the atoms.
But we found that
they all fall down.
I found that
this is the Kashmir Force.
The Kashmir Force
is an attraction.
The amount of excited state
is more than ground state.
It can make
the probe frequency
decrease.
You can see the redshift frequency.
At the same time,
you can see the same phenomenon in CM.
If I ask
in this way,
if you don't add Kashmir Force,
the simulation resolution
will be too high.
If you compare the experimental data,
how much inconsistency
does it have?
For example,
we don't know how strong
the caterpillar coefficient is.
We can extract it in this way.
I'm very interested in this.
We can get a number
which is difficult to measure.
There is a reason.
The caterpillar
has a
potential
which is
1 over z3.
It's a
1 over z3
dependent.
It's a
very fast
potential.
The closer it is to the origin,
the faster it runs.
The interaction time
with the deep place is very short.
The shift here is
negative 20
megahertz.
It corresponds to
1 millikelvin.
I don't remember
the distance.
Maybe it's
outside of dozens of nanometers.
It's almost gone.
We can match
the approximate value.
If you want to match it accurately,
it's hard to do it in this way.
Do you publish this?
Can I find the details?
Yes, we have
a paper in PNAS
which mentions this.
You can send me the link later.
The purpose of the paper is not to measure this.
I know.
My idea is
there is a potential
which can be optimized
to Casimir force detector.
Obviously, this is not the purpose.
It looks like there is a chance.
I'm interested in
Casimir force
coupled to new physics.
I remember there is a paper
which uses blue evanescent field
to balance the atoms.
It can measure
Casimir force in this way.
It's a bit tiring.
We can't design
a stable trap
to balance it.
There is a potential
which can be optimized
to Casimir force.
I think it's cool.
We can discuss it later.
Do you have any questions?
If you don't have any questions,
please turn on the microphone.
Let's give a round of applause
to Peng Lu for his speech.
Thank you.