Hello, everyone. Welcome to today's TaroTalk.
Today, we have Dr. Su Gongyi with us.
This is the first time I've called him that.
He's going to talk to us about his research in Caltech.
Today's topic is Cosmic Rays or Turbulence Can Suppress Cooling Flow
Where Thermal Heating, Momentum Injection, or Non-HGN Solutions Fail.
Let's get started.
Hello, everyone.
I'm going to talk about Cosmic Rays or Turbulence Can Suppress Cooling Flow.
This is my research in Caltech.
This is my co-author.
I'll start with the cooling flow problem.
In a large galaxy or galaxy cluster,
we usually observe very strong X-ray luminosity.
This means there's a lot of gas emitting a lot of energy.
So a lot of gas is getting colder.
So we should expect to find a lot of cold gas in the middle of the galaxy.
But in fact, we can't find that much cold gas.
So where does that gas go?
The gas may be getting colder and colder.
And then there's a lot of stars.
There's a lot of star formation.
But on the other hand, we find that
these big galaxies or galaxy clusters
have very low star formation rates.
They're basically all been crunched.
So this tells us
that there must be something
that generates heat
to re-heat these gases.
Otherwise, based on so many
inferred cooling flow rates,
we can't consistently find
so little cold gas or stars.
So this is the problem.
We've observed so much cold gas,
but we can't find the same amount of cold gas.
So this tells us that there must be something
that can re-heat the gas.
In the simulation,
this problem is called the cooling flow problem.
In the simulation, the cooling flow problem
is most likely to generate too much star formation.
If you don't have any other mechanism
to suppress cooling flow,
the gases will keep cooling down
and accrete into the center of the galaxy
and generate too much star formation.
So you can see that this is a galaxy
with 14 times the solar mass
and has a cooling flow problem.
You can see that in Redshift-0,
the star formation rate is probably
more than 2 times the observed magnitude.
Can you hear me? Hello?
The cooling flow problem is typical.
As I said earlier,
it occurs in relatively heavy galaxies.
So you can see that this plot is stellar mass
versus halo mass.
Halo mass is the mass of dark matter.
The horizontal axis is the mass of stars in the galaxy.
If you assume that all the baryons,
all the gases and all the substances
follow the dark matter,
the flow follows the dark matter
and all of them become stars,
then you can predict the virtual line.
You can see that
after a very high-quality galaxy,
the green lines below are observed.
You can see that
in a large-scale galaxy,
there will be a very large deviation.
The larger the deviation, the more obvious it is.
This is where the cooling flow problem begins.
Usually, the scale occurs in L-star galaxies,
which is probably above the Milky Way-sized galaxy.
The cooling flow problem will become more and more serious.
In the literature,
there are some ideas that everyone proposes,
which can possibly suppress the cooling flow
and solve the cooling flow problem.
These proposals include
Stata Feedback,
Fully Microphysics,
Cosmic Ray,
which is the cosmic ray from the supernova,
or Morphological Quenching,
or AGM Feedback.
AGM Feedback is the feedback
generated by the supermassive black hole
in the middle of the galaxy.
To be more specific,
Stata Feedback,
which is more likely to be related to the cooling flow problem,
is Type Ionized Supernova, or AGB Wings.
AGB Wings is a Stata Wing,
which is the continuous energy generated by the galaxy.
It will heat up or provide momentum to the surrounding gas.
Type Ionized Supernova,
which is the supernova explosion of older stars,
is usually Type Ionized Supernova.
We care more about AGB Wings
or Type Ionized Supernova
because these galaxies,
as I just said,
these massive galaxies are usually quenched,
so their star formation rate is very low.
So very few stars are just produced.
Most of the stars are very old stars.
These older stars,
their Stata Wings are usually AGB Wings.
Type Ionized Supernova is usually Type Ionized Supernova.
These things can provide energy to the surrounding gas,
and either kick them to a place
that is farther away from the center of the galaxy,
or re-heat them.
Another possibility is Fluid Microphysics.
This includes magnetic field, conduction,
especially magnetic field and conduction.
Magnetic field can provide additional energy
and provide additional pressure
to suppress the cooling flow.
This is another possibility.
Indeed, in some parts of the galaxy,
we can see that the magnetic field's energy density
is similar to the thermal energy density
in Equipartition.
So the magnetic field is very important.
Another possibility is Conduction.
If the conduction is very strong,
usually the picture looks like this.
When gas starts to move from the universe
to a place where the potential of the galaxy is affected,
it will be shocked to a higher temperature.
So the higher the quality of the star,
the higher the temperature will be.
So if the conduction is very strong,
it can transfer the heat from the hot part
to the cold part in the middle,
and then re-heat the gas that has been cooled to the middle.
So conduction is also a proposed idea in the literature.
It is possible to solve the cooling flow problem.
The third one is Cosmic Current Supernova.
Cosmic Current is usually generated by shock.
Because Supernova provides a lot of energy,
it will shock the gas next to it,
and then there will be a lot of protons
being added at a higher speed.
What we are talking about here is mainly related to
the Cosmic Current Proton of GEV.
Usually 10% of Supernova Energy
may be generated in the form of Cosmic Current.
On the one hand, Cosmic Current can heat the surrounding gas.
There may be Streaming in the channel.
Streaming is when the Cosmic Current and gas
are not completely synchronized,
it will generate all kinds of instability,
and then through this instability,
it will dissipate energy and heat the surrounding gas.
On the other hand, there is the Hadron Collider.
That is, the Cosmic Current will collide with the gas,
and energy will be generated in this respect.
Then there is Pressure Support.
Cosmic Ray also provides extra pressure.
It can also suppress the cooling flow,
preventing the gas from moving in the middle of the star system.
Another proposed idea is Morphological Clutching.
On the one hand, we observe that
when the distribution of stars is relatively round,
the star formation rate is usually lower,
and the star formation rate is higher when the distribution is more disc-like.
But someone also proposed that
maybe we just need to change the distribution of the star system,
so that the gas can be stabilized,
and then it will not move in the middle of the star system,
and it can suppress the cooling flow,
suppress the speed of star formation,
and then solve this problem.
The part on the left is non-AGM feedback,
which is the mechanism that has nothing to do with the huge black hole in the middle of the star system.
On the other hand,
the most popular idea is AGM feedback.
AGM feedback is the feedback generated by the huge black hole in the middle of the star system to the surrounding gas.
This picture is like this.
When the gas continues to accrete into the black hole in the middle,
some of the energy will be fed back to the surrounding gas.
On the one hand, it may provide momentum,
or gas around the heating,
or gas around the shock,
and produce a lot of cosmic rays.
On the other hand, it may also stir those gases,
and then produce more turbulence,
and then it may also suppress the cooling flow.
In my next talk,
I will gradually say why these on the left are not important.
The feedback on the right is related to AGM feedback,
which is the feedback related to the huge black hole in the middle of the star system.
It may be more important,
especially the two aspects of cosmic rays and turbulence.
This is my next talk outline.
I will first talk about how we set up these simulations.
Then I will talk one by one,
such as Stata Feedback,
Fluid Microphysics,
Cosmic Ray,
Morphological Quenching,
and AGM Feedback.
I will talk one by one,
why each one is important or not.
This is the setup of the simulation.
We study this problem.
As I just said,
this problem is usually more important in galaxies with a quality higher than L-star galaxy.
L-star galaxy is probably the Milky Way-sized galaxy.
Its solar mass is about 10 to 12 quadrilaterals.
We have tried three cases,
10 to 12 quadrilaterals,
10 to 13 quadrilaterals,
and 10 to 14 quadrilaterals.
We use Idealized Isolated Galaxy Simulation.
We made our own galaxy,
and then we started from an initial condition.
Then we add different feedback,
or as I just said,
those physics go in,
and then our initial condition is the initial condition based on observation.
If you don't have any mechanism to suppress the cooling flow problem,
the cooling flow problem will occur.
As shown in the previous picture,
there will be too much star formation.
So if you let the initial condition evolve,
it will soon be inconsistent with the observation.
We use this initial condition,
and then we add the static feedback,
free microphysics,
and AGM feedback.
We try to see if there is any way to maintain it in the simulation,
to maintain it in line with the observation.
The cooling flow will not be too strong,
and there will not be too many stars.
In our initial condition,
we have pre-set,
and based on the observation,
we manually set the Dark Matter Halo,
the star,
the Static Disk,
the Static Bulge,
and the Gas Disk.
This is the gas around the star,
and we have a pressure-supported Hot Halo,
which is the entire star,
this huge amount of star,
there will be a gas Halo covering the entire galaxy,
the entire galaxy.
Basically, it should be pressure-supported,
the pressure compensates the gravitational force,
and it should be a pressure-supported Hot Halo,
this is our initial condition.
The picture on the right shows that
the axis on the left is X-ray Luminosity,
and the axis on the right is Halo Mass.
These three black dots are our initial conditions.
You can see that
the X-ray Luminosity is based on the observed data.
In our simulation,
we use Gizmo,
which has gravity,
and all kinds of feedback are already in there,
and there will be a Hydro Code.
As for the Star Feedback,
we use the FIRE Star Feedback Model,
which is a very good Star Feedback Model.
It includes Supernova,
Star Winds,
Photonization,
Photoelectric Heating,
and Radiational Pressure.
For the cooling of the gas,
we follow it from 10K to 12-14K,
so the gas can cool from 12-14K to 10K.
We use different cooling methods to cool the gas.
As for the Star Formation,
when the gas cools and becomes dense,
it can produce stars.
We only allow the gas to meet the following conditions.
The gas must be self-gravitating and molecular,
and its density must be greater than 100 particles per cubic centimeter,
so that it can produce stars.
As for Cosmic Ray,
we model it as an extra fluid,
assuming that it is in line with the flow of the Hydro Code,
and we try to model it as GEV Cosmic Ray.
Cosmic Ray can do some things,
such as PDP work,
which means that it will have pressure
and will make contact with other gases.
It will diffuse to the surroundings,
and it will have a relative movement with the gas,
which will produce various kinds of stability,
and will lose some energy,
and heat up these gases.
Similarly, it will collide with the gas,
and it will heat up those gases,
and it will lose Cosmic Ray energy,
but it will provide heat energy to the gas.
First, let's talk about Static Feedback.
Is Static Feedback useful for cooling flow problems?
As we said, we have 12 quadrants, 13 quadrants, 14 quadrants,
and three different runs.
We usually enable M12, M13, and M14.
We have two different simulations for M12 and M13.
The first one is Default Run,
which has FIRE Static Feedback,
which also includes Static Feedback.
The other one is No Feedback Run,
which has no Static Feedback.
As we said, in Static Feedback,
we believe that Type Ionized Supernova
and AGB Wink are more important,
so we added more.
In addition to Default Run,
which has Static Feedback and No Feedback Run,
we also have Type Ionized Supernova Run.
We only enable Type Ionized Supernova.
Static Feedback has various channels,
so we only enable Type Ionized Supernova in this run.
In the other run, we only enable AGB Wink.
Then we start running from Initial Condition
based on the relative situation.
Let's see what the result is.
This is the result.
This is the result based on the situation mentioned above.
The result is the star formation rate,
which is the speed of the star formation.
You can see that the biggest difference is the black line.
The black line is the run with all Static Feedback.
The red line has no Static Feedback,
which means there is no Static Feedback at all.
The difference between the two is mainly in the beginning.
Without Static Feedback,
the gas stored in the center of the star will cool down very quickly
and then explore the center of the star
and produce too many stars.
You can see that there is a very high star formation rate at the beginning.
After the gas in the middle is gradually used up,
the remaining star formation is
then from the gas at a further distance from the beginning
to the cooling flow
and then cool down to the center of the gas to produce stars.
You can see that even though Static Feedback
suppressed the star formation rate at the beginning,
but later, at the end of the simulation,
you can see that in all the runs,
the star formation rate is still very high,
from several solar max per year to dozens of solar max per year.
It can't completely solve the cooling flow problem.
It still produces too many stars.
Can you talk about the nominal observational rate you want to get?
Generally, a crunched galaxy can be suppressed to 10 to 0,
which is less than one solar max per year,
especially a 14-dimensional or larger galaxy.
But dozens of solar max per year is definitely too high.
Okay, go ahead.
So Static Feedback can't solve the cooling flow problem.
In all the runs, you can see that
at the end of the simulation,
the star formation rate of Static Feedback is getting smaller and smaller.
And no matter what, it still produces more than 10,
especially in more massive galaxies,
which are more than 10 to 14 solar max per year.
On the other hand, you can see that
only the run of Type Ion and Supernova
and only the run of AGB Wind,
which is the red line and the light blue line,
in the case of 14 dimensions,
the star formation history,
the process of star formation,
is basically the same as without feedback.
In other words, the contribution of Type Ion, Supernova, and AGB Wind is very small.
Why is that?
On the other hand,
we are trying to quantify
how many variables,
which are not documented,
are in the middle of the galaxy.
So the first line is quantified,
which is the Baryonic mass in the middle of the galaxy,
and its evolution over time.
You can see that
all the Baryonic mass changes over time
in the 30-kpc sphere,
in the 30-kpc sphere in the middle of the galaxy.
You can see that it goes up, of course.
If there is no stellar feedback,
you can see that the Baryonic mass
basically has no change in its evolution.
There are still so many gas,
so many baryons,
floating in the middle of the galaxy,
which is constantly rising.
Its rate of rise has not changed,
regardless of whether you have stellar feedback.
On the other hand,
we can see that the second line is quantified,
which is the hot gas,
which is the hotter gas,
over all the Baryonic mass.
What is the ratio?
You can see that
there is no stellar feedback,
and its hot gas
basically has no change.
The third line is changed.
The third line is cold gas or Baryonic mass,
which is the cold gas
in the Baryonic mass.
You can see that
there is no stellar feedback.
Basically, very little gas
is in the cold gas phase.
Its ratio is very low.
What happens?
When the gas cools down,
if there is no stellar feedback,
it will quickly turn into a star.
Then you will have too many stars.
But this also shows that
your stellar feedback
basically changes
how much cold gas
turns into a star,
but it does not change
how much hot gas,
and it does not change
the total Baryons
in the middle of the galaxy.
So you didn't solve the cooling flow problem.
You just changed
the ratio between the cold gas
and the stars.
You didn't change
the Baryons
in the middle of the galaxy.
So you didn't solve the cooling flow problem.
Why is
the cooling stellar feedback
not efficient?
Here we use
the M14 galaxy
to explain.
In the upper left corner,
we plot the
total cooling rate
as a function of time.
In the upper right corner,
we plot the total energy input,
which is the energy provided by stellar feedback.
You can see that
all the energy provided by stellar feedback
is not enough
to compensate for the cooling.
The stellar feedback
is to provide energy
to either move the gas farther away,
or provide the surrounding gas
in the form of motion or heat.
But the gas loses energy
with a greater rate,
and the cooling rate is always higher.
So in this situation,
stellar feedback cannot provide
enough energy to compensate
for the cooling.
So the cooling flow problem will continue to occur.
But if you try to quantify
how much energy
all kinds of stellar feedback contribute,
in the lower panel,
the lower left corner is the energy
contributed by Supernova,
and the lower right corner is the energy
contributed by Stellar Wind.
The first line corresponds to
the energy produced by younger stars.
The second line corresponds to
the energy produced by older stars.
As you can see,
because stellar feedback
does not fundamentally solve
the cooling flow problem,
the star condition is still very high.
So the most energy
in this simulation
is still the energy
generated by the supernova explosion
of younger stars.
So this is still the maximum energy.
But even if you have
so many young supernova explosions,
the energy generated
is still far less than the cooling rate.
Because
the energy generated by
those older stars is
not only Type Ia Supernova,
but also AgV Wind.
So it is impossible
for Type Ia Supernova
and AgV Wind
to have too much influence
on the cooling flow.
This also explains why
we only run Type Ia Supernova
and AgV Wind.
The star condition history
is basically the same
without any feedback.
I have a question.
Hello?
I can't hear you.
What's wrong?
Hello?
I can hear you.
How are you?
Hello?
I just cut off.
Sorry. Can you hear me?
I can hear you.
There are some spikes on the two curves.
The spikes are actually very large.
The spikes on the log scale are bulging like this.
What is that?
Do you know the other three lines below?
Which spikes are you talking about?
The two lines
in the upper left panel
are the default
and low metallicity.
Default
So the cooling rate is...
I'm talking about those
small edges.
It's not that large.
It's just that
there are some fluctuations
based on the gas
at that time.
So it's not a special event.
You think it's just
a normal fluctuation.
Yeah, I think it's normal.
I didn't look closely.
It's probably the same as my average time scale.
But yeah, it's probably just...
Oh, okay.
I thought it was a special event.
And the other three are not.
No, I think it's okay.
Okay, okay.
Okay, thank you.
Yeah, those two
have a complete set of feedback.
Maybe it's just that time.
The set of feedback is a little stronger.
Or there's some gas
that's denser, and the cooling rate is stronger.
I didn't look closely.
But I think it's okay.
It's not that big.
Usually, there are some fluctuations at the scene.
That's another question.
The set of feedback is another question.
It may actually provide energy
to the Galaxy
to reheat the gas.
But in fact,
it also produces a lot of metal.
In astronomy, when we say metal,
we mean any element
greater than helium.
Any element greater than helium.
Because the set of feedback
produces a lot of heavier elements.
These heavier elements
can make the cooling rate
cooler.
It makes the gas easier to cool.
On the left,
we see two lines.
One line is the default run.
It's a normal run.
The other line is where we deliberately
put its heavier elements
in the Galaxy.
It's very, very low.
You can see if there's any of these metals.
Its star formation rate
can actually be quite different.
So,
these metals are basically
consistently from the set of feedback.
So, we can say that
the set of feedback
is basically possible to
make the cooling flow problem
worse.
Because these heavier elements
induce the gas to cool down.
So, the set of feedback doesn't work.
Let's look at magnetic field conduction
in Cosmic Graviton Supernova.
So,
let's look at these heavy elements one by one.
In the case of 10, 12, and 13,
we have a default run.
It has a fire set of feedback.
It only has a fire set of feedback.
It doesn't have any other fully microphysics.
We also have another all-microphysics run.
It has a fire set of feedback,
magnetic field, conduction, and viscosity.
In the Galaxy of 10, 12, and 14,
in addition to the default
and all-microphysics run,
we have another run,
which is all-microphysics plus Supernova.
In addition to the all-microphysics run,
we have a fire set of feedback,
magnetic field, conduction,
and viscosity.
We also have 10% of Supernova energy
in Cosmic Graviton.
I have a question about
Supernova.
I'm actually very surprised
that this is a hypothesis.
Because this can be estimated,
right?
If you observe the rate,
you can estimate the energy budget.
You can see the luminosity
and know the rate.
Can you estimate the energy budget
to solve this problem?
Or is it just a qualitative
possibility?
When we were doing this project,
we basically believed
that this was impossible to solve.
Some papers
tried to propose
that Supernova
had enough energy.
Their approach was
to compare the total cooling rate
in the center of the star
with the energy input
of the stellar feedback.
They found that
the stellar feedback
had enough energy.
But our point is
that even in the very,
very middle part,
it's possible that it's enough.
In fact, the gas
next to it is very, very large.
In the outer part,
the gas will continue to cool
and go to the center of the star.
But your star is only
in the center of the halo.
So you should calculate
the entire cooling rate
of the entire halo,
not the cooling rate
where the star is distributed.
Because you are
highly biased to
this kind of very, very localized
calculation.
Their estimate
is that
the energy input
and cooling rate
in the center of the star
will continue to cool
and go to the center of the star.
So you should compare
the entire cooling gas.
We think that
this is not enough.
And our simulation
can't solve this problem.
Okay, you go on.
It depends on how you solve it.
Thank you.
So here we have
magnetic field conduction
with viscosity and cosmic ray.
This is the star
we simulated.
Is there any magnetic field?
The black line
has no magnetic field conduction,
and the blue line
has magnetic field conduction.
In the smaller galaxy,
there is magnetic field
conduction.
You can see that
the star condition
is a little less,
but only a little.
With cosmic ray,
the star condition
is slightly reduced,
but it is the same.
As time goes by,
you can see that
in the later time,
the star condition
is basically the same
as without cosmic ray.
If you continue to quantify
how much gas
is in the middle of the galaxy,
the bottom line is
total baryonic mass as a function of time,
and the top line is
hot gas mass over baryonic mass.
You can see that
with magnetic field conduction,
it is possible that
the total baryonic mass
in the middle of the galaxy
may be slightly suppressed
by magnetic field conduction,
but it is not
the difference between
the two.
There is no way to
solve this problem.
With cosmic ray,
you can see that
the gas in the middle
is slightly heated,
but it is not
the difference between
baryonic mass and
baryonic mass.
Basically,
you can't solve
this problem.
Why can't we solve
this problem?
We have seen the
results of the simulator.
The energy per unit mass
is in different energies.
The red line is thermal energy,
the blue line is magnetic energy,
the black line is turbulent energy,
and the blue line is
the energy distribution
as a function of radius,
which is how far
the energy distribution
is from the center of the galaxy.
The first line is the energy distribution,
and the second line is
the energy distribution
over thermal energy,
which is how important
it is compared to thermal energy.
You can see that
in most of the radius,
the energy distribution
is much smaller than
thermal energy.
The energy distribution
in the middle
is not so different,
but in the cooling flow
area,
the energy distribution
is much smaller
than thermal energy.
This limit
can't affect
the cooling flow
in the cooling area.
Why doesn't conduction
affect the cooling flow?
On the one hand,
some of the reasons are
that conduction
is heat transfer
and it depends on
the direction of
the temperature gradient.
But basically,
the particles with heat
are all charged particles,
so they are trapped
in the direction of the magnetic field.
So basically,
if you want the thermal gradient
to be in one direction
and the magnetic field
to be in the other direction,
the direction of the conduction
will be projected
to the direction of the magnetic field.
This projection
will reduce
the effective conductivity.
Let's estimate
how much this reduction
is.
The middle part
reduces the effective conductivity
by at least half,
and the outer part
reduces it by 1 or more thirds.
So this is one way
to explain why
the conduction
is not very important
in our simulation.
Let's talk about
the morphological environment.
For some people,
the distribution from
a disc to a boat
is a more elliptical distribution,
so the gas is stabilized
and you don't have
too many stars.
In our simulation,
we directly change
the distribution of stars
in the initial condition.
The black line and the gray line
have feedback run,
and the black line is
the normal distribution.
The gray line is
the elliptical distribution.
We also try
the no feedback run,
which is the red line
and the peach red line.
We also change the distribution
of stars.
You can see that
if you slightly change the distribution of stars,
you can slightly change
the initial
start of the simulation.
But at the end of the simulation,
all the run
are saturated
to a very high level.
Basically, you just change
the distribution of stars
without changing the
final start of the simulation.
But why is this
not important?
There is no way to solve this problem.
Basically,
it depends on whether
your gas is stabilized
or it will continue to
become denser
and generate stars.
Basically, we often estimate
a rotationally supported gas.
We estimate its thermal Q.
This is Scale S.
Omega is its angular velocity,
and the sigma of the mole
is its surface density,
which is the density of the unit area.
Usually, if this number
is less than 1,
it means that
its density is relatively zero.
If this number is greater than 1,
it means that
it will continue to expand
and generate more density
and generate stars.
If this number is greater than 1,
it means that
it is a relatively stable situation.
You can see that
if you keep changing the distribution
of stars,
if you change the shape
of the same quality star
slightly,
the result is that
you slightly change its angular velocity.
You can imagine that some stars are
distributed in the shape of a circle or a disk.
The gravitational potential will change slightly,
but you only slightly change
the effect of
the order of unity.
However, your cooling flow
provides more gas
to the center of the star.
Basically, you can do
the surface density,
which is the density of the unit area.
If you keep changing the distribution of stars,
it means that
you will change the order of unity,
because your cooling flow
will continue to put more gas
into the center of the star.
So eventually,
although you can slightly reduce
the distribution of stars,
your cooling flow will
make the distribution of stars
bigger and bigger.
So eventually,
the total Q is always less than 1.
I have a question.
In these two simulations,
you only changed the distribution
of baryonic stars, right?
Yes, I only changed the distribution
of stars.
So you didn't change
the dark matter halo, right?
No, I didn't change the dark matter.
But for example,
the disk galaxy and the circular one,
the reason why they become like this,
their mechanism...
But this is a proposed idea.
He said that
the difference in the distribution of stars
causes the cooling flow problem.
But I tell you that
although you observe
the disk galaxy,
its star formation rate is higher,
its bulge galaxy,
its star formation rate is lower,
but this correlation
is not causal.
It's not that you just have to change
the distribution of stars,
you can change the star formation.
Oh, okay.
So logically, I can accept it.
But this is what I think.
If the galaxy morphology
is different today
because its dark matter halo is different,
if you want to study
such a mechanism,
shouldn't you also change the halo?
Although I don't know what the halo looks like,
is it possible?
It's possible because of the halo.
Or even because, for example,
your AGM feedback,
the K-dome around you,
the feedback generated by the surrounding gas
caused the change,
or the merger,
or the change caused by two stars
together.
Now, no matter why
the distribution of stars
is like this,
we can't directly solve
the distribution of stars,
and we can't change
the star formation rate.
We have to prove that this logic is not true.
I agree with this conclusion.
Okay, thank you.
If you directly put in
some numbers,
you only need
about 3 x 10 to the power of 14 solar mass
in the middle of 10 kVc.
The gas surface density
will be high enough
to self-shield.
The surrounding gas will not be affected
by other radiation,
and it can cool down to a very low temperature
of 10 to the power of 14 kVc.
If you put these numbers in,
you can get a much lower temperature
of 10 to the power of 14 kVc.
These numbers are very easy to achieve,
so eventually your gas
will become very dense
and continue to flow
into the middle of the galaxy
without solving any problems.
Okay, so we've talked about
all the mechanisms
that are not AGM feedback
proposed in the literature.
In this regard, we talked about
Static Feedback, Magnetic Field Conduction,
Cosmic Reverse Supernova,
and Nucleophage Quenching.
I believe I just
tried to convince everyone that
none of them can work.
They all still have cooling flow problems.
Their gas transformation rates are still too high.
Eventually,
they are still the same
and not the same as observations.
So none of them work.
Next, let's move on to AGM feedback.
AGM feedback is
the feedback of a huge black hole
in the middle of the galaxy
to the gas around it.
A complete AGM feedback model
should be able to consistently
model how much gas
runs to the black hole
in the middle,
and how much energy
is fed to the gas around it.
But it is very
model-dependent.
Instead of
jumping directly
into a model
we believe in,
we try to do a bigger
parameter search.
We don't care
how much gas
or stars
run to the black hole
in the middle of the galaxy.
We only care about
the gas around the black hole.
For example,
if we add different
types of energy
to the black hole,
what will happen to the gas
around the black hole?
Basically,
we inject energy
from the black hole
in different forms
and intensities
to different radii
to see if there is
a scenario
where we can
suppress the star formation rate
and quench the galaxy.
If the galaxy is successfully quenched,
does it mean that
the energy produced
in the galaxy
is equivalent to
the energy produced
in the black hole?
Is the energy
we need
in the black hole
a reasonable amount
of energy
to produce
four different types
of energy
in the black hole?
The first is momentum,
which can provide
a lot of kinetic energy
to the gas around the black hole
and then kick it
to a far away place.
The other form is
thermal energy,
which can heat
the gas around the black hole
in various ways
such as radiational heating.
It can heat the gas
around the black hole
to a higher temperature.
The other form is
turbulent stirring,
which can stir the gas
around the black hole
to produce currents
in the black hole.
It can also
make the gas
around the black hole
more turbulent
and more difficult to collapse.
This is another possible form.
The other form is
cosmic ray,
which can
shock the gas
around the black hole
to produce
cosmic rays.
This is another
possible form
of energy.
If it is momentum,
it can heat
the gas around the black hole
to a higher temperature.
There are three possible forms
of thermal heating.
The first one is
uniformly heating
all the gas
in the galaxy.
The other one is
only heating
the gas
around the black hole
to a higher temperature.
The third one
is
heating
all the gas
in the galaxy
to a higher temperature.
The fourth one
is
heating
all the gas
around the black hole
to a higher temperature.
The fifth one
is
heating
all the gas
around the black hole
to a higher temperature.
The sixth one
is
heating
all the gas
around the black hole
to a higher temperature.
The seventh one
is
heating
all the gas
around the black hole
to a higher temperature.
The eighth one
is
heating
all the gas
around the black hole
to a higher temperature.
The ninth one
is
heating
all the
gas
around the black hole
to a higher temperature.
This is because
the diffusion coefficient
determines
how much
cosmic ray
stays in the middle
of the galaxy.
So how much cosmic ray
stays in the middle
determines how much chance
the cosmic ray will
collide with other gas
and produce gamma ray.
Since the total flux of
the gamma ray in the galaxy
has a limit,
the diffusion coefficient
determines how much
the cosmic ray will
stay in the middle
of the galaxy.
Based on the speed of the
earthquake,
you can calculate
the radius of
the cosmic ray
which will
be around
20-30 kpc.
It will start to thermalize.
The cosmic ray energy
will gradually heat up.
First, let's look at
the momentum injection.
This is the flux
of 36 quadrillion
CGS.
This is the result of
sharp motion ray.
When the momentum is not very strong,
it does not affect
the galaxy at all.
However, when the momentum
flux reaches 36 quadrillion
CGS,
it turns off
all sharp motion rays.
You can see that
the green line is not
on the plot at all.
However,
the gas in the middle
of the galaxy is blown away.
You can see that
there is no gas
in the middle of the galaxy.
You can see that
there is no gas in the middle of the galaxy.
You can stop the cooling flow
and stop the sharp motion ray.
You can stop the sharp motion ray.
You can also blow away
all the surrounding gas.
It is not consistent with observation.
Next, thermal heating.
We have
uniform heat up gas.
By gas heating,
it is confined to
30 kpc or only heating
the particles around the black hole.
The energy flux of the four of us
is about 10 to the power of
43 to the power of
45.
The first one you see
is the produced
sharp motion ray
based on the energy flux and the different kernel size.
The first one you see is the produced sharp motion ray based on the energy flux and the different kernel size.
If you heat up these gases uniformly,
you basically have no effect.
Even if you have a very high energy,
it doesn't affect the sharp motion ray.
But if you put the same energy
in the middle,
heat up to 30 kpc
or
put all the energy
in the middle of the black hole,
you can have a very big effect on the sharp motion ray.
You can see that
the more energy you put in the middle,
the stronger the
sharp motion ray suppression
you can produce
with the same energy.
For example, in the black hole neighborhood,
you can suppress the sharp motion ray
with very little energy.
In fact, there are some results
that are inconsistent
with observation.
In the first column,
we draw the density profile.
In the second column, we draw the temperature profile.
In the third column, we draw the turbulent velocity
as a function of radius.
At the end, you see that uniformly
heat up the gas,
all the lines are still the same as the black curve.
In fact, there is no change
in the energy input.
But if you put all the energy
in the gas next to the black hole,
the effect is very explosive.
For example, in the second column,
you can see that
the temperature in the middle
can be added to a very high level.
In addition,
the gas is also added
to a very high level.
In other words,
the gas temperature is too high
and the speed is too fast.
In fact,
if you take
a medium-value kernel
and distribute the thermal heating energy
to about 30 kpc,
you can make it
a little more stable.
Your energy will not be so high
or your speed will not be so fast.
But you will still produce
a negative temperature gradient.
The middle is hotter and the outside is colder.
Basically, this is not the same as observation.
Basically, the observation is
that the middle is colder and the outside is hotter.
The temperature gradient
is not the same as observation.
If you really look at
your energy,
we draw this picture
that you integrate
your cooling rate
from the middle to a certain radius
and your heating rate
from the middle to a certain radius.
The heating rate is the red line
and the cooling rate is the blue line.
The first thing you can compare
is that if you uniformly heat up the gas
from the top two lines,
basically
most of your heating
is at the
outermost gas.
But if you put all
the heating in the middle of the galaxy,
the heating rate in the middle
will be much larger than the cooling rate.
Basically, this is why
you will have a very explosive result.
If you use
a kernel like 30kpc,
you can distribute
these heating to about 30kpc.
Indeed, in some situations,
you can make your heating rate
slightly
similar to your cooling rate
in a larger radius,
but the result is very fine-tuned.
And even if you are very fine-tuned,
you will still have problems
with your cooling rate.
So basically,
if you just want to use thermal heating
to compensate the cooling flow,
you don't need to be very fine-tuned.
You just need to make sure
that your heating rate
is exactly the same as the cooling rate
in each location of the galaxy.
Otherwise, you will easily heat up
some parts of the galaxy
or produce a very explosive result.
So it's very fine-tuned.
Although it may work,
it may not work.
Next, let's talk about
Cosmic Ray Injection.
Cosmic Ray has
streaming instability
and heats up the gas.
It also collides with the surrounding gas
and produces hydronic and coulomb heating.
Diffusion is set to 12.9 quadrillion
units of CGS.
Energy input is
between 12.4 quadrillion
and 12.4 quadrillion.
These are
very efficient
to suppress shock measurement.
You can see that
if you add energy
in the form of Cosmic Ray
to the surrounding gas,
you can still
efficiently suppress
shock measurement.
If you look at
the density profile
and temperature profile,
the reason why
shock measurement is suppressed
is because the temperature
is a little higher than
the surrounding gas.
If you add the same amount
of energy
to the surrounding gas,
one side is
in the form of
Cosmic Ray,
and the other side
is in the form of
hydronic,
you can see that
in the form of Cosmic Ray,
it reduces
the density
in the middle of the galaxy.
Basically,
in the form of Cosmic Ray,
it suppresses
shock measurement
more efficiently than
in the form of hydronic.
This range is still
acceptable.
I want to clarify
something.
What do you mean by hydronic?
Hydronic means that
the particle in that place
is now bigger than
V2,
but it is basically
a thermalized movement.
Do you have anything
that can transfer energy
from one to another,
such as thermal radiation?
No.
We just say that
the heat energy
of the particle
does not generate
an average momentum
in a specific direction.
No.
Another extreme
is Cosmic Ray,
because all your energy
has a very clear
momentum direction.
No.
Our model is
Lagrangian-based code,
so each particle
may be thousands of solar mass
or 10,000 solar mass.
We model
Cosmic Ray in the fluid limit,
so it has a field
that is heat energy,
and it has a field that is Cosmic Ray.
We directly add its energy
to Cosmic Ray's field.
Cosmic Ray
is the same as
general heat energy.
It has a couple of hydrodynamic equations.
Cosmic Ray
will do PDV work on gas.
It also has energy loss.
Cosmic Ray energy loss
in the channel,
such as collision heating
or streaming instability.
It will reduce
Cosmic Ray's energy
and turn it into heat energy.
Oh, I see.
Thank you.
Why can Cosmic Ray
do this?
On the one hand,
there is a possibility
that Cosmic Ray
directly heats the gas.
Cosmic Ray
may be streaming heating
or collision
and heat the gas.
However,
the panel below
is accumulative heating.
We directly integrate
various channels
of Cosmic Ray's possible heating gas
from streaming
to collision
or loss.
The black line
is the input of
all Cosmic Ray's energy.
As you can see,
there are not many Cosmic Ray
that turn into heat energy.
Especially in
the case of
Star Formation,
which has been suppressed
and Quench.
You can see that
less than 10% of Cosmic Ray
turns into heat energy.
If you try to compare
the heat generated
by Cosmic Ray
from the middle to a certain radius
and the cooling rate
from the middle to a certain radius,
you can see that
the energy input
from Cosmic Ray
is less than the cooling rate.
This tells us that
Cosmic Ray's heating
is not the main reason
for suppressing
Star Formation or Cooling Flow.
The heat provided
is not enough.
Cosmic Ray also provides
pressure support.
It provides another form
of pressure
that pushes the gas
to the middle.
We found that
this is important.
If you try to calculate
two forces,
the first force is
the gravitational force.
The other force is
the pressure gradient of Cosmic Ray.
If there is a pressure gradient,
you will produce something like a buoyancy
that pushes the gas outward.
If you try to see
the difference between
the buoyancy of Cosmic Ray
and the gravitational force,
you can see that
under such a coefficient,
the energy input
is about four to three times
greater than the
pressure gradient of Cosmic Ray.
You can see that
the red line below
is the gravitational force
per unit mass,
and the black line
is the energy input.
You can see that
under such a coefficient,
the energy input
is about four to three times
greater than the
gravitational force
per unit mass.
In this case,
you can prevent the gas
from moving to the middle
of the galaxy.
The pressure gradient
of Cosmic Ray
can suppress star formation
because of the
pressure gradient of Cosmic Ray,
not because Cosmic Ray
heats up the gas
around it.
Finally,
let's talk about
turbulence.
Let's not ask where the
source of turbulence comes from.
Of course, it may be HMDB,
or it may be for other reasons.
Anyway, let's stir the gas externally
in a 100 kV mode.
We have uniformly stirred
the gas run.
There is no space difference
between the first two runs.
We have a core-turbulent
core run,
which is the gas in the center of the galaxy.
We try to make
the energy input greater
than 100 kV
in the form of turbulence.
From 1 to 4,
the gas in the center of the galaxy
is getting stronger and stronger.
The energy is getting higher and higher.
From 1 to 4,
the gas in the center of the galaxy
is getting stronger and stronger.
This is the result of
star formation history.
The upper panel is uniformly stirred
the gas case.
The lower panel is the case
in the center of the galaxy.
As you can see,
the gas in the center of the galaxy
is getting stronger and stronger.
This is the result of
star formation history.
In fact,
there are some things
that are different from observation.
For example,
if you uniformly stir the gas,
there is no space difference
between the first two runs.
It is very easy for you
to put too much energy
into the outer part of the galaxy.
The actual luminosity
is much lower.
This is not the same as observation.
On the other hand,
if you stir the gas
too hard,
you will also
increase the speed
of the gas.
Mach number is
the speed over
the sound speed.
Sound speed is
the speed
corresponding to the temperature.
If you stir too hard,
the Mach number
will be out of unity.
Of course, this is not the same as observation.
However, in addition to these extreme situations,
there is still some space
to suppress
star formation history.
On the one hand,
you still maintain the state
that is basically the same as observation,
and you can also
suppress star formation rate
and cooling flow.
So why does turbulent stirring
work?
There are several possible reasons.
The first one we might think of
is that you stir the gas
and it produces some currents.
Those currents
may eventually dissipate into heat.
These things
may eventually turn into heat
and the temperature of the gas
will increase.
On the other hand,
when we stir the gas externally,
the input energy
is much less than
the energy dissipation energy
of the gas,
at least less than 1%.
So the energy produced
by the channels
that turn the currents into heat
is far less than
the cooling flow.
We found that the more important reason
is mixing.
When you mix gas,
on the one hand,
you mix the cooled gas
into the CGM,
into the gas
with lower density.
If you check
the gas,
the gas with high density
at first,
and check
how much of it
is dense
and the temperature is low,
and how much of it
is hot,
you can see that
half of the gas
is stirred externally.
You stir
the gas
to a higher radius
or to the gas
with lower density.
So mixing
is mixing
the cooler gas
with the denser gas
with lower density.
We found that this is the more important reason
why it can suppress the cooling flow
and suppress star formation rate.
On the other hand,
because you stirred these gases
and you provided
the extra turbulent pressure,
the gas density
in the middle of the galaxy
is also reduced.
So you reduce the gas density
and also reduce the cooling rate.
Because the cooling rate
is equal to the square of the gas density,
the gas density is reduced
and the cooling rate is also reduced.
The cooling rate is also reduced
and the cooling time is also longer.
So this is another very important reason
because the density
in the middle of the galaxy is reduced.
So we just talked about
turbulent and cosmic ray
can be more stabilized,
stably suppressed.
Cooling flow and star formation rate
are also in the case of 12 and 14 square.
We also try to
simulate thermal heating
if you confine it in a
more open space.
It seems that the thermal energy can also work.
We try to put these three runs
in a smaller galaxy,
12 square, 12 square, 13 square,
see if it can work.
These three runs are the ones we just said
are the slightly more successful runs in 12 and 14 square.
Let's try to see if these three models
can work in a smaller galaxy.
Let's see if these three models can work.
For the thermal heating part,
we scale
its total energy input
according to the
cooling rate of all its
gases.
We scale our energy input
to a smaller galaxy.
We also make the kernel size
correspond to the size of the galaxy
and make the corresponding reduction.
For the Cosmic Ray Injection run,
we directly put
the thermal energy input
corresponding to the
cooling rate of the
corresponding galaxy.
For the Turbulent Stirring run,
we first put
the scale of the stirring mode
and the kernel size
corresponding to the size of the galaxy
and make the corresponding scale.
We also put the force of your foot
corresponding to the circular velocity
above your foot's scale
and make the corresponding scale.
Because the size of the galaxy is different,
the energy input and the scale input
are different.
This is how we scale.
As you can see,
this is the star formation history
of the 10th, 12th, and 13th galaxies.
As you can see,
the Cosmic Ray Injection
can crunch the galaxy
in all cases
and the star formation rate
is very low.
As for the thermal heating,
it only works for the
10th, 12th, and 13th galaxies.
It doesn't affect
the 10th, 12th, and 13th galaxies.
The star formation rate
is still very high.
As for the Turbulent Stirring,
it can only suppress
the star formation rate
in the 10th, 12th,
13th, and 14th galaxies.
It doesn't affect
the 10th, 12th, and 14th galaxies.
It just makes the star formation rate
jump up and down.
Why is that?
Why doesn't the
10th, 12th, and 14th galaxies
have the same effect
as the Turbulent Stirring and
Thermal Heating?
First, let's look at Thermal Heating.
In the 10th, 12th, and 14th galaxies,
many gases
don't have high temperatures.
The temperature
of the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies
is around
12C to 12C.
These gases
are the main
cooling rate of
gases.
Thermal Heating
also provides
energy input,
but it also
heats up
more heavy elements
and denser gases
to this temperature.
The gases
in the 10th, 12th, and 14th galaxies
cool down very quickly.
Many gases
are placed in the same position,
which increases
the cooling rate.
The picture on the right
shows the cooling rate
of the radio-integrated gases.
The cooling rate
is from the center of the galaxy
to the outer part of the galaxy.
The black line shows
no energy input.
The red line shows
thermal heating.
The thermal heating
provides energy,
but it also increases
the cooling rate
in the 10th, 12th, and 14th galaxies.
The cooling rate
increases
the cooling rate
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies.
The cooling rate
is not that much higher
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies.
The cooling rate
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies
is not so much higher
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies.
The movie on the left
shows the
cooling rate
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies.
The upper left corner
shows the temperature
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies.
At the end of the simulation,
you can see
a lot of gas
being heated
and rising
to a higher position.
However,
when it reaches a higher position,
it cools down
and starts to
rise again.
This is a demonstration
of the cooling rate
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies.
The cooling rate
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies
is not that much higher
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies.
The cooling rate
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies
is not that much higher
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies.
and the cooling rate
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies
is not so high
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies.
the cooling rate
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies
is not so high
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies.
the cooling rate
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies
is not so high
in the 10th, 12th,
and 14th galaxies.
and the cooling rate
in the 10th, 12th.
galaxies
has a
which means
just applying
as long as your kernel size
is not so low
around 50 kbz
turbulent stream can still work
in the 12th and 14th galaxies
star formation rate can still work
in the 10th, 12th, and 14th galaxies.
this is my conclusion
the first part we said
the nitrogen feedback type solution
does not work
it only has a very small impact
the reason for the stator feedback
is that it only changes
the temperature
the main reason is that
the total energy input
is much smaller than the cooling rate
the magnetic field cosmic ground supernova
is also the same
the energy is not enough
the conduction
the big reason
is that it is suppressed
by the magnetic field line
because the direction of the temperature
and the direction of the stator
is different
let me show you
so
the thermal conduction
will be projected to the direction of the stator
so it is suppressed
we also said
the morphology of star formation
basically
the impact of star formation
does not affect the cooling rate
we also talked about
the AGM feedback
we tried four different toy models
one is
momentum
one is thermal conduction
one is stator
one is cosmic ray
only add momentum
in the direction of R
basically
if the energy is not enough
you did not do anything
if the energy is enough
it is not the same as the observation
if you
increase the temperature of the gas
it may work
it may reduce the star formation rate
and the cooling flow
but you have to fine tune
you have to
let the heat
locally fit
the cooling speed of the gas
otherwise
it will overheat
thermal heating
is not efficient
if you add more energy
the cooling speed
will be faster
so it is not efficient
next is turbulent stirring
if you stir the gas
you can suppress the star formation rate
effectively
because you can
mix the gas
on the other hand
you can reduce the density
these are the two reasons
if you
control the stirring
within 100 kpc
you will not throw a lot of gas
into the galaxy
and suppress the
extra luminosity
next is cosmic ray
this can also work
because of the pressure support
suppress the density
basically
I did not talk about rejuvenation
the result is
turbulent stirring and cosmic ray
are very important
to solve the cooling flow problem
and control the galaxy
thank you