Hello everyone, welcome to today's Chair Talk.
Our speaker today is Shuyu He.
Shuyu is now doing theoretical physics at Tohoku University in Tokyo, Japan.
He specializes in the theory of dark matter.
Shuyu He is actually a long-time friend of mine.
I'm sorry, I'm today's host, Zhang Yanyou.
Shuyu He majored in physics.
After graduating from physics, he went to Taiwan University to do his master's degree in dark matter.
He followed up with Mr. He Xiaoguang.
Then he came to Caltech and met me.
Now he's doing his PhD at Tohoku.
I don't know if I'm saying this correctly, but he should be graduating soon, right?
Next year, in September.
Yes, he's graduating soon.
The topic he's going to talk to us about today is
Hidden Monopole Dark Matter via XCO Portal and its Implications for Direct Search and Bind-Up Experiments.
This paper is actually already published in the archive.
If you look at the first page of the video, you can see the archive number.
Oh, by the way, when you clap, you have to turn on the microphone.
Only then can we hear you clap.
Let's give a round of applause to welcome Shuyu He to give us a wonderful speech today.
Thank you, Zhang Yanyou, for introducing me.
As you can see, the title of my speech is quite long.
Let me talk about a few key points first.
My speech today will focus on dark matter.
Dark Matter is the Chinese translation of dark matter.
I think if you don't usually do theoretical work, you should hear this term a lot.
Maybe through some of Taiwan's programs, you may hear the term dark matter.
Then you can see this hidden monopole in front of you.
Monopole is the Chinese translation of the word monopole.
If you have studied electronics, you will know that when we discuss electronics, we do not have a monopole.
Hidden, I will explain what it means.
Then there is action.
In my last speech, I basically made a long introduction.
But today, because of time, I should mainly focus on the introduction of dark matter.
So action, I might first mention it a little bit.
Then I will talk about the details of our model.
It is also applied in DirectSearch.
That is, directly detect the experiment of dark matter and the so-called Bindang Experiments.
I will mention these details at the end.
Let's go straight to the introduction of dark matter.
What you see on the screen now is our so-called example physical standard model.
Generally called Standard Model.
This model has been verified by a large number of experiments.
It is a very accurate theory.
Simply put, you can look at this picture.
Look at this E, this E is the so-called Electron.
This is the basic example that everyone is familiar with.
The focus is on Mu and Tau.
These examples are actually easy to find in the universe.
Then there is the so-called Mu, E, Mu, Mu and Mu, Tau is the so-called neutral value.
This is generally more unfamiliar.
But I won't touch this part in today's speech.
You can see that the red part above is the so-called Quarks.
Like this straight neutral value that everyone is more familiar with.
Basically they are not basic examples.
They are composed of these Quarks.
For example, this Proton is composed of two Up Quarks and one Down Quark.
That is the U and D on the graph.
There are heavier Quarks in the graph.
The purple part on the right side of the graph is the so-called basic force.
Everyone is more familiar with this Gamma.
That is the particle in the upper right corner.
It is the battery function that we are more familiar with.
The G below is the so-called強作用.
The Z and W are the so-called weakest.
In this regard, these two particles may not be often heard of.
Basically, today I am more focused on this Photon part.
I will introduce the so-called Hidden Photon later.
There is a Higgs in the middle of this graph.
You may hear this news often.
There is a report like this.
This Higgs is the source of the so-called Origin of Mass.
That's why matter has mass.
This Higgs has been predicted to exist for a long time.
The reason is that before it was discovered,
the history of standard models has been verified for a long time.
It is a very accurate theory.
But this Higgs has not been discovered.
This is the motivation for us to find it.
So I built a large-scale quantum detector in Europe later.
The so-called LHC.
I spent a lot of money on it.
I found it in 2013.
If I remember correctly, it was six or five years ago.
I don't know. It should be 2014.
I'm sorry.
What I want to say is that we should be able to see your mouse.
So you can move your mouse.
You can try it.
You can use it if you want.
Thank you for your advice.
Higgs was discovered in 2014.
Then, of course, the next year,
it seems that the Nobel Prize was awarded to Higgs.
It means that the last puzzle of the standard model has been found.
Although the standard model is so successful,
there are still many problems that cannot be explained.
These problems are listed on the right side of this video.
There are quite a lot.
Like the first so-called dark matter.
I'll talk about why I want to have dark matter.
There is also the so-called dark energy.
Dark energy is currently an explanation of why the universe is accelerating.
We observe that the universe is not static.
It is constantly expanding.
The only explanation is dark energy.
Simply put, it may provide some
similar
anti-gravity feeling.
There is also the so-called quantum gravity.
There is also the so-called gravity problem.
There is also the so-called gravity asymmetry.
In other words, our universe.
Our universe has the so-called anti-matter and positive matter.
But we found that our universe is basically dominant.
This matter is not anti-matter.
This is also the reason why we can't know.
This is a problem.
But although there are so many questions.
My speech today is mainly focused on dark matter.
If you are interested in this question, you can google it.
You can know more details.
Since we are talking about dark matter, we must do some basic introduction of dark matter.
First of all, let's talk about why we know the existence of dark matter.
It may be easier for everyone to understand the upper left corner of this picture.
The upper left corner is the rotation curve of the star system.
You can see the shape of this picture.
Its tangent axis is a planet
revolving around the rotation speed of the star system.
The horizontal axis is the distance between the star system and the center of the galaxy.
According to Newton's law and Newton's law of gravitation,
we can simply calculate that the rotation speed of the star system should be reduced.
If it is a galaxy, it should be reduced.
But what we find is not the red line, but the white line on the graph.
This may imply that there are some objects that we can't see.
It also provides gravity.
This gravity will produce additional gravitation to keep the star system at a certain speed.
This is the most basic evidence of dark matter.
In addition, there is a so-called gravity path.
For example, if the dark matter is in the universe,
it will cause some stars to shine.
The light will be distorted by the dark matter.
We can see the circular effect in the picture.
This is the so-called gravity effect.
There is also the CMB spectrum in the lower left corner.
This is more detailed.
I can skip it first.
The one on the bottom right is quite famous.
Someone once considered that there may be no dark matter,
but that Newton's law needs to be corrected.
There is also the so-called modified gravity theory.
Britt-Crosser is a more preferable evidence of dark matter.
You can see that Britt-Crosser has a pink and purple part on the graph.
The purple part is basically the matter that will provide gravity.
In other words, I just talked about the gravitational projection above.
We can know by gravitational projection that some invisible matter will provide gravity.
That is the purple part of the graph.
The red part is some visible matter that we know.
It may be electrons or some light.
We can detect it through binoculars or satellites.
We found that these two crosses coincide.
We found that the red part will interact with each other.
The purple part will just go through each other.
In other words, it will not have the same effect as our matter.
For example, this may also provide evidence that there is a very weak matter in the universe.
It's called dark matter.
Anyway, we found a lot of evidence from experiments or observations.
So dark matter is not just an evidence.
Its evidence is very overwhelming.
Since we believe in the existence of dark matter, we want to measure some of its data.
At present, according to our so-called cosmological standard model.
We just talked about the standard model of gravitational physics.
There is a standard model of cosmology.
Under that model, we do the measurement.
We found that the current energy ratio of the universe is like the picture.
This is what you see on the screen right now.
We generally call it cosmic pi.
We found that 70% of the universe's energy is contributed by dark energy.
Dark matter contributes about one-fourth.
Only 5% is contributed by the so-called barrier.
In other words, most of the universe can see the so-called stars.
It only accounts for 5% of the total energy.
Anyway, the focus of our speech today is on dark matter.
As long as you know that dark matter accounts for about one-fourth of the universe's energy.
What characteristics does dark matter need to meet?
First of all, I just said that we can't see it because of dark matter.
So it can't have a battery interaction.
Otherwise, we should be able to easily measure the signal with a device.
So this tells us that dark matter should be an electromagnetic.
It can't carry electricity.
Then again, its age must be older than the age of the universe.
Or it's very stable.
Otherwise, if it changes, like we know some basic examples.
It's not stable.
Uh, like the one on the screen just now.
In that standard model, it's called the second value.
For example, the second value can change to the electron.
Add some neutrons.
So some particles are not stable.
So if dark matter is not stable, it might change.
If I change, it might disappear.
Then we won't see it.
So basically, it has to be long enough for you.
In addition, from what I just said, this CMB.
And some early observations of the universe's nuclear fusion.
We found that it is a non-atomic substance.
It's not like the quarks we just talked about.
That kind of thing.
And finally, the so-called star structure is formed.
We estimate its movement speed.
In other words, particles should move in the universe.
Like the quarks I just mentioned.
It has its own velocity.
But the result of our observation is that our dark matter.
Its movement speed must be very small.
It's almost as small as the speed of light.
But to put it more directly.
It's almost as fast as the speed of light.
Compared to the speed of light.
This is easy to understand.
Do you know that dark matter itself has gravity?
If there is gravity.
They may continue to attract.
And form some kind of cluster feeling.
If the dark matter forms a cluster.
Other things like particles.
Some gravitational materials will also be attracted.
If you are attracted.
It will slowly form a star system.
Then this star system becomes what we are now.
That is to say, these stars are observed in the universe.
I found that most of the stars are large.
Most of the stars are large-diameter structures.
That means that the dark matter must move very slowly.
Because if the dark matter moves very fast.
It's hard to form a cluster.
If it's hard to form a cluster.
What we should see is.
A star with a relatively small-diameter structure.
Not large-diameter.
So the observation of large-diameter structures.
Dark matter moves very slowly.
This is basically the nature of dark matter.
Why is this nature important?
Because I just talked about the standard model.
There is no way to explain dark matter.
So it means that the standard model must be extended.
So you have to write some models.
When you write a model.
You have to make your model.
Some new substances.
New particles to meet these characteristics.
This is the basic knowledge we need to know when we do theory.
There is no problem here.
Does anyone want to know about dark matter?
It seems that everyone can accept it.
Then I will continue.
Since we just talked about modeling.
Our theorists.
Have to come up with some.
Models or scenarios to explain.
What is dark matter?
More popular is the so-called.
Weakly Interactive Massive Particle.
Generally referred to as WIMP.
Why is WIMP more popular?
Because.
If you use theory to estimate.
Find this kind of particle.
What about the effectiveness?
It's very close to what I just said in the first page.
At the same time, the quality is also very close.
So this WIMP will be very.
Close to the extent of our so-called circuit theory.
This is actually more likely to be experimentally.
Go.
Measure.
Of course, there are many.
This kind of example.
That's like the so-called supersymmetry theory.
That's like the so-called.
Some additional symmetry theory will also predict this kind of WIMP.
Candidate.
Then below me.
The blue part is.
Is.
Different from this kind of WIMP.
Candidate.
That's what I'm talking about today.
I'm talking about this hidden.
Basically, it's a.
Torque defect.
It's a topological defect.
It's very different from the general WIMP.
It's even in the early universe.
The mechanism is also very different.
I'll mention it a little bit later.
Simply put, I can simply say.
WIMP is basically.
It was created by heat balance in the early days.
You can imagine that the universe was a big.
There are a lot of particles.
There are electrons and light.
Then these particles have high energy.
Then these high energy can hit some.
Heavier particles.
That's how WIMP was created in the early universe.
That's right.
So what about these torque defects?
What about the axis?
Its formation mechanism is not the same as WIMP.
Then I will explain.
Then I don't want blue.
It's because of these.
Particles are constantly mentioned in the back.
Like the axis and the invisible light.
I didn't particularly talk about what is HIDDEN.
HIDDEN is a sector of the visible world.
For example, I just talked about the role of the battery.
Then we can.
WIMP is very thematic.
I can say that there may be another.
A weaker battery.
Then I call it HIDDEN.
Electromagnetic.
Then you will naturally have HIDDEN photons.
Then there are a lot of candidates.
Like SIMP.
SIMP is Strongly Integrated Massive Particles.
I also sent a few papers on this work a few years ago.
It seems that my first TAL speech is about SIMP.
Then there are so-called Gravity Nodes.
There are a lot of things like this.
Basically, you can write a book.
Introduce these candidates of Fragment.
Anyway, I will focus on the blue part today.
Since there is a theory, of course there is also an experiment.
So there are a lot of people in the world right now.
Whether in Japan, the United States or Europe.
Maybe a lot of time wants to detect dark matter.
Basically, they don't want to detect the so-called WIMP.
Because WIMP has more people doing theoretical models.
More people are doing it.
They all assume that WIMP.
In fact, WIMP.
It may have some interaction with the nucleus.
Of course, these interactions are not direct.
It may pass through some media.
These media may be new physics.
Maybe it will pass through some.
Even like the fingertips I just mentioned.
Basically, this is the topic of my speech today.
Through some new.
New fermions or new bosons.
Particle to do media.
Then through this media.
Dark matter can interact with the nucleus.
Then we can go.
Do the theoretical calculation.
Then compare with the experiment.
The so-called experimental comparison is like the picture on the right.
It has.
There are some upper bound.
Like the one on the picture.
It is.
The three-color interface of WIMP and Nucleon.
Simply put, it's a three-color intensity.
The horizontal axis is the mass of WIMP.
Yes.
There are a lot of pictures on the Internet.
You see.
There are already a lot of things like COPE.
Xenon.
Like this.
Uh.
There was this a while ago.
Xenon OneTown also released some new upper bound.
Like this.
Anyway, we have a lot of time to measure this dark matter.
Okay, so this is the current.
Uh.
I'm just going to do the basic.
Background introduction.
There's nothing wrong with that.
I want to.
OK.
I have a question.
Good question.
But what you're showing now is.
It's almost.
One to 10,000.
10,000 GEV, right?
Yes.
Will you discuss it in this range today?
No, it's a good question.
No.
But.
I want to.
Yeah.
Yeah, because it's actually in.
You see.
Upper bound.
In the heavy part.
His.
The trend is always.
You can predict that it will continue to go up.
Extend.
That's because.
Because.
Uh.
But we know.
We can fix that.
Dark matter.
That event.
Is.
Can.
We can know.
We can press.
Then we can know this.
Strength.
So you can go.
To behave this.
He's in.
What's his behavior in the heavy part?
For example, we.
Basically, we're just doing an extension.
Then, of course, because we're talking about this today.
Monopole.
It's very heavy.
It's even more than 10.
So.
That's right.
But basically.
We just extend this upper bound.
And then do it like this.
Is that okay?
Okay.
Thank you.
Then I have no problem.
Let's just introduce our main character today.
The so-called hidden mobile.
So why do you have to study hidden mobile?
Because it's actually hidden mobile.
He is.
To put it bluntly, he's a pretty good candidate.
Why?
There are two very simple reasons.
That is.
He is.
If you are in the universe.
Early.
If there are some changes.
That is.
It can be very natural.
Okay.
I have a simple picture.
To explain this.
That's right.
You can think of it before the change.
That is.
I.
The square on this picture.
This rectangle.
I'm talking about the universe.
Of course.
It's not just empty.
I'm just saying.
Before the change.
His.
This.
The shape of a factory is.
It's zero.
He's got nothing.
That's it.
And then after the change.
Maybe.
Well.
Some blocks in the universe.
Will.
There will be some new ones.
Maybe some.
New scalar field.
He will send.
There will be some vacuum expectations.
And then this scalar field.
There will be some random directions.
That's because the universe.
The universe is.
Do you know that the universe is a cause and effect ratio?
So we'll have some domains.
That these domains are.
Cause.
Causality connection.
Connected.
That is.
It has a cause and effect relationship.
So in different domains.
His.
The direction may be different.
This is a bit like you.
Maybe.
Electrical engineering or some.
It's your magnet.
There will be some.
That domain phenomenon is very similar.
Anyway.
So.
In the following.
I seem to have a typo below.
It should be after the change.
That's not before the change.
I just changed it.
Yeah.
So there's this random direction.
Then you might have a certain chance.
It's just like.
In this picture.
The four in the lower right corner.
He just formed a radiation.
There is no.
That's the radiation.
It's like our battery factory.
That.
Since there's a battery factory.
We can find the center.
So you can say.
What about this center?
It can be identified.
It's a.
Maybe it's a kind of.
Something with a magnet.
Yeah.
In our example.
It's a magnet.
It's got a flux.
Yeah.
So there's this magnet.
It will produce.
It will produce this magnetic field.
So.
For example, if there is a change.
These.
These objects will naturally occur.
That's the red dot on the picture.
That's it.
Then we can estimate.
This number density.
I'm on the screen.
Uh.
The data is written.
It's this nm.
It's this.
The number density of the monopole.
It will.
It will be equal to this.
1 divided by this.
Horizontal size of this.
The three-dimensional.
It's the volume.
That is to say, roughly.
It's probably an average one.
In a.
This British law.
Connected.
In this volume.
It will produce a.
Magnetic field.
That's it.
Yeah, that's it.
This.
This dh.
This horizon distance.
It's roughly.
It's about the same as this.
This.
Negative three-dimensional.
That's it.
Then we can estimate.
This number density.
It's h.
Negative three-dimensional.
Then we can estimate.
It's this.
The density.
I have a question.
Good question.
My question is.
That is.
The main thing is that molecule.
Is 1.
That is to say.
If you are in a causal.
Connected horizon.
There is more than one.
It doesn't look like.
It's a monopole.
It looks like.
It's a dipole.
Or a multipole.
Right?
Yeah, there's a lot of.
Yeah, yeah.
But.
So.
I see.
You would say.
It's one over.
Horizon size.
Because.
Basically.
You have to.
Usually.
Write a P.
P is probability.
Uh-huh.
But.
I didn't go.
To see how to calculate.
That depends on model.
Yeah.
But I'm just giving it a scale.
Like my paper here.
It's just.
It's just a number.
I can't.
It's not that I can't.
I didn't really go.
Calculate so carefully.
Because the reason is simple.
Because.
You know, there are a lot of experiments.
Yeah.
Hahaha.
Sorry.
Yeah.
How much density should this monopole have?
Or is it just density?
Because we know that density.
That's the mass density.
So it's going to be very natural in the universe.
If there's a change.
Yeah.
That's actually.
You know, there's a lot of change in the universe.
So it's very natural.
It's a natural thing.
If there's the same thing in this hidden sector.
Then this level 13.
This hidden level 13 can be produced by itself.
It's very natural.
And then there's him.
Because he's Thorpe.
Thorpe.
So he has a kind of his own.
The nature of Thorpe.
I don't know if you're familiar with Thorpe.
Like Thorpe, which is usually used to talk about Thorpe.
That's Mark Bay.
You know, Mark Bay.
It's the same as the field circle.
Thorpe is the same.
Yeah.
It's a more mathematical language.
That is to say, this kind of Thorpe.
Thorpe's object has its own.
This is quantum number.
That's quantum number.
If it's.
If it's not destroyed.
It's a very good hand.
So if it's a hand, it means.
If this model has this quantum number.
It's a very stable thing.
That chemical reaction is not electrical.
You can't.
Before and after the reaction.
Before the reaction, it's very.
Total charge is.
It's positive and negative.
And then you get negative after the reaction.
Something like that.
Yeah.
That can explain the dark matter.
This hidden model.
Why is it stable?
Yeah.
Because he can't detect some particles.
It also has the same Thorpe.
This number.
So anyway.
So this is two basic reasons.
That's the hidden model.
Good.
Of course.
Uh.
I'm in the hidden model.
So basically there are some.
Of course, some studies of the same theory.
Like what.
Su5 theory.
They naturally have some models.
But what about these models?
If you calculate it, you'll find it.
It's going to be a lot.
Yeah.
That's going to lead to.
It's going to be the same as we observe.
It's going to be different from what we observe.
Because we're in the universe right now.
The universe has no evidence of any particles.
And then that's going to lead to another question.
That's what this is.
Why isn't the universe like this?
There's no such thing as a general model.
Well, that might have to be generally explained by inferential.
Yeah.
Well, this is another one.
The bottom line is that the early universe will explode.
And then it's going to suck up the density of this model.
Yeah.
And here, it's not the same as my hidden model.
Even if I'm in the dark matter.
So.
It's going to have a lot of density.
Yeah, basically, it's supposed to be.
It has to be produced after this explosion.
If it's produced before the explosion,
It's going to be sucked up, too.
OK.
Good.
That's what I was trying to do.
You have a wrong notation.
That DH is.
Equal to H or equal to H minus.
Minus.
It should be minus.
Because you don't seem to be right about these two, do you?
I might be writing.
I might be typing.
Yeah, I might have a short time.
Yeah.
Which one is the title?
Yeah, it's supposed to be three-dimensional.
You're talking about that.
Yeah.
Three-dimensional.
OK.
Good.
Thank you.
that.
I just mentioned the experiment.
That is to say, we.
Can we measure this?
This model can measure this hidden model.
The answer is no.
Because I just said.
If you're this dark matter.
Really with.
What about the effect of this box?
I need some media.
So if it's just a.
Hidden model, this model.
Maybe there's no way.
There's this connection.
So I don't have to.
Do some extra extension.
That is to say, you have to add extra particles.
Yeah.
Let this model and this box.
There's a connection.
Good.
There are a few possibilities.
The first one is the Higgs portal.
That is to say.
In the middle, they rely on Higgs particles to make media.
That's a simple estimate.
I'm not going to explain it.
That is, I found this prediction.
This.
The war front is very small.
There's another one that wants to go through this vector.
For example, the middle is.
The media is a kind of light.
These things.
That.
Sorry.
I don't study because of this.
Toppling is very small because.
This kind of vector.
It's been limited by a lot of experiments.
So it's usually this.
It's not big enough.
So our research theme today is.
This action.
You mean.
This media is made by action.
That action is the most primitive.
The first reason is that he solved it.
Just maybe.
I didn't get this strong CP problem.
Yeah, and then in this hypothesis.
Or some super-symmetry.
It's natural to predict this kind of action particle.
Yeah, so.
The action particle may exist in the intelligent world.
Well, actually, as long as you know the action, it's a simple one.
There's no, it's a, it's a pure particle.
That's it.
It's not self-selected.
It's a spin-zero particle.
And then it's a pseudo-scalar at the same time.
The so-called pseudo means that it's in this mirror symmetry.
It's got a symbol.
I mean.
Uh.
So.
If it's a normal scale, it won't be like Higgs.
Higgs is just a normal scale.
It's in.
But the parity is in the mirror symmetry.
It doesn't have a minus sign in the mirror symmetry.
Yeah, anyway, so, anyway, so action is a.
It's a pseudo-scalar.
So, basically, what I'm doing today is assuming.
This hidden multiple.
With this, uh, uh, with the middle of the nucleus through this action to make a connection.
Oh.
Well, then it's a more complex model.
Then this side.
Maybe a lot of people don't understand.
Yeah, I'll talk about it a little bit.
The earliest.
Uh, put it out.
That is to say, a theory is very natural to have multiple.
It's this one.
He's also a theoretical physicist.
He's in the Netherlands.
And then he has a Nobel Prize.
Then he proposed this so-called SU2.
SU2 is basically a standard symmetry.
Well, to put it simply, people are more familiar with this battery.
It's a U1 symmetry.
That U1, it's a.
It's a non-exchange group symmetry.
The so-called exchange is to say.
So, as you know, people have learned to be more familiar with rotation.
Basically, the three-dimensional rotation is a.
The role of a non-exchange group symmetry.
Because you, you first turn from the y-axis and then from the z-axis.
You can turn from the z-axis and then from the y-axis.
It's different.
Yeah.
That's why U1 is an exchange.
The exchange is that it's a flat rotation.
Flat rotation is an exchangeable.
That.
Yeah, he proposed a SU2.
This non-exchange group symmetry.
The theory.
And then he added three of these.
New scale.
For example, you can see this in the picture.
Phi 1, phi 2, phi 3.
What about the structure of this theory?
What if this happens?
This self-reliance.
What about the destruction?
It will be very natural to produce this.
That he was a long time ago.
With another one.
This.
They didn't cooperate before.
They both came up with this idea.
That's it.
Yeah, and then down here is this.
The screen is some of the equations.
You don't really need to.
To understand.
You just need to know that I'm using pink to mark this.
Like EH.
EH is similar to our battery.
The battery.
Just because it's a hidden sector.
So I add an H to mark it.
It's different from our average.
This.
The size of the battery.
And then VH.
On the right.
The VH on the right is this.
The vacuum expectation value of the storage plant.
That he will.
It's related to this.
Yeah.
Anyway, it's a model.
That he will naturally have this.
That's it.
You don't have to look at it.
Of course, it's what I just said.
This model.
If there is a self-reliance.
Self-reliance destruction.
Then it will produce U1.
That U1 will become.
Simply put.
That is to say.
The role of our average battery is.
It's U1.
U1 symmetry.
So if he has a U1H.
It's natural to have one.
In the hidden sector.
This battery.
What about this alpha H?
This is the red one.
This alpha H is.
It should be the economic structure parameter.
Yeah.
That's the same.
He's in the hidden sector right now.
Oh.
Look at the time.
About 20 minutes.
Good.
That's what I just said.
If this model.
If you assume this model.
He's this.
Energy is self-reliance.
That is to say.
If his energy is finite.
That will naturally be a.
Very stable.
This.
This state solution.
It's like the solution of Soliton.
He's a model.
And then there's some of this model.
Some new particles.
That's the first one.
Gamma H is hidden photon.
Of course, hidden photon.
It's not qualitative.
It's not electronic.
It's not.
There's no magnetic field.
Yeah.
And then this alpha.
This.
This is what I just said.
Some of this model.
Scalar like this.
That's a lot of mass.
But he didn't.
There's no electric field.
There's no magnetic field.
And then the third one.
This is.
Standard symmetrical example.
We usually call it W.
The government.
He's actually talking to us.
The first page of that standard model.
That W is very similar.
That's the same.
He's in the hidden sector.
That.
That's natural.
He's going to have an electric field.
Yeah.
And then the last one, M.
That's our protagonist.
That's the model.
That's natural.
It has to be qualitative.
And then since it's a model.
Of course, it has to have magnetic field.
It's magnetic charge.
Of course.
There's a question here.
That is to say.
If it is.
He's a.
If it's a model.
Why does he have an electric field?
It's kind of weird.
That's a very interesting theory.
He was in Princeton a long time ago.
Now in Princeton.
This Witten.
A.
It's one of the most powerful.
It's supposed to be the top linguist.
He was a long time ago.
The so-called Witten effect.
For example, through this Witten effect.
This monopole.
It will also have.
This electric field.
This is quite interesting.
This is when I first learned it.
I think it's amazing.
And it's very simple.
Okay, so.
So why is there this.
Electric field?
So if you say.
If you today.
As I just said.
If you have one now.
The theory of this one.
Basically, we can also write it on the screen.
This equation.
This Lagrangian.
Okay, so back to the front.
You see this.
The Lagrangian has a cth.
That's cth.
It's called cth.
For example, we.
We can write this.
And then it won't violate anything.
No, no, no, no, no.
There's no reason.
It doesn't exist.
So we can write it down.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well, usually this term is.
We don't consider it because.
It can be written as a whole.
And in the whole.
Basically, it doesn't have any physical effect.
Yeah, maybe you're not familiar with it.
Then I'll mention it a little bit.
So when will this term have a physical effect?
That's if you have it today.
You have this.
Monopole background.
If you have a monopole background today.
Plus this cth term.
You can find out that this monopole.
It also has a background.
Well, usually I put this kind of thing with a background.
It's called Dayong.
Yeah.
But we're talking about this today.
Or just call it monopole.
Yeah.
So simply put.
If you have this cth term today.
If you have this monopole at the same time.
Yeah, because I just said.
I just said.
In this series.
There's always going to be a monopole.
Yeah.
So you have this cth term and monopole.
Then you calculate it.
You'll find that it should have a monopole at the same time.
Well, since there's a monopole.
It's going to have a monopole.
OK, so his monopole is in.
The shape of the red part in the lower right corner.
Yeah.
So that you can get a feel for it.
I'm going to show you some calculations.
Yeah, like this.
For example, you just got out of this Lagrangian.
You can write down its equation motion.
It's the one on the top left.
The one in the upper left corner.
The yellow equation.
And through our definition of this battery voltage.
It's in the upper right corner.
Like what?
FJ 0 equals EJ.
This kind of thing.
E is the power plant.
And then B is the power plant.
You can get that.
We're most familiar with the Maxwell equation.
Like that.
You know, the frequency.
The power plant.
If it's usually 0.
Well, if it's usually 0.
If there's no power consumption, it should be 0.
Yeah.
So we can say this.
This Maxwell equation.
So if you're today.
Through this Maxwell equation.
If you have a multiple.
You can do the same thing.
Calculate this voltage.
Okay.
So if you're interested.
You can.
After the lecture.
You can take a closer look at this.
It's actually pretty simple.
OK.
So you can just look at this theta H.
This theta H is in this.
In the micro-division.
In this.
In the delta dot.
So that means theta.
It's basically.
It can also be a.
Space function.
Yeah.
Because I'm going to extend it later.
It's an action.
Action.
It's a.
It's a factory.
That factory.
It's a space function.
That is to say.
If you enter today.
It's not just theta.
It's a.
It's an action.
Then this.
This.
What about the voltage?
It's not going to be at the origin.
That.
That origin.
It's going to be in space.
Through this action.
It will.
It will be carried by this action field.
OK.
Okay.
Is there any problem here?
Although it's a bit difficult.
Yes, I have a question.
So basically you.
Model will be coupled to dark photon.
But it's with.
It's you.
The coupling of monopole and dark photon.
You have to argue now.
It's like saying.
Its coupling is dependent on.
One.
A field that can change with space.
That's the theta.
And then.
You said that.
That theta.
You think.
It's a field.
So you said it.
OK.
It's x.
Is that so?
No.
That is.
You can repeat.
For example, look at me.
I'm not writing a theta.
Like this.
I can change this theta.
It's a time and space function.
You can.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So this thing is your x.
Yeah.
But.
That is to say.
You are now.
It's basically you.
It's his.
That.
That monopole charge.
So he basically.
You and.
Dark photon.
The coupling is.
Basically, I'll write it down.
It's him.
Do you know what he looks like?
Or what?
Is that what you mean?
Undensity.
Um.
What did you say?
I didn't hear it.
Hello.
Um.
Did you hear that?
Hello.
I heard his voice.
Zhang Yong.
Zhang Yong is missing.
Why?
Did the others hear my voice?
Have.
Zhang Yong is missing.
No.
Wait a minute.
He is.
Is he online?
Have.
But no sound.
Yeah.
Wait a minute.
I don't know what's going on.
I have.
I'm going to send him a message.
I pressed it, didn't I?
Wait a minute.
He's gone.
So I should keep talking and wait for him.
You have to wait for him.
Have you seen my screen?
No.
No?
I just pressed share.
Have you seen my screen?
He's gone.
I'm still recording.
Then I'll continue.
Because...
Yeah.
I'll talk to him later.
I have a question.
Is the charge
the same as our EM charge?
No.
It's different.
So you're basically
copying the EM wave again.
Yeah, it's very simple.
It's a very small coupling
to our whole world.
It doesn't have to be big or small.
It's all right.
But the main thing is that we can't
get close to it.
Yeah, basically...
I'll talk about it later.
In fact, the coupling is quite large.
That is to say...
I don't know if I'm using EH now.
I'm using the electron structure constant.
Like I just said, alpha H.
Like I'm in the back.
The numerical study is about
close to 1.
But the general...
You know, the general electron
effect electron structure constant
is about
10 to the power of 2
divided by 137 or something.
Yeah.
I'm back.
I'm sorry.
If you just answered
and I skipped it completely,
it doesn't matter.
Just ignore me.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
We can discuss it later.
OK.
Let's continue.
Anyway, this is actually quite simple.
You can see the video later.
You can push it yourself.
If I were a professor,
I would ask this question.
It's really simple.
OK.
This is my model here.
This is Benchmark Point.
Yeah.
In fact, this model has already
done some detailed research.
But so far,
no one has really considered
how this multiple
and
the numerical effect through action.
But we're...
My boss is the first one
to come up with this idea.
Then he asked me to do the calculation.
So you can see this on the picture.
This picture is made by someone else.
Yeah.
I put the credit in the upper right corner.
For example,
you can see this tangent axis on the picture.
This is the size of the energy structure.
The horizontal axis is the size of the positive and negative expectant.
It corresponds to the value of this multiple.
Yeah.
That's the red part.
We're going to consider this.
Consider the red part on the picture.
The red part on the picture.
That is to say.
I forgot to say something.
In this model,
in addition to this multiple,
you can do dark matter.
The one in the table.
W.
W positive can also do dark matter.
Yeah.
Why is this model?
It considers
I'm 100%
This dark matter is contributed by multiple.
Yeah.
So consider maybe 10% or 35% like this.
Then we use its result directly.
To do the analysis.
Yeah.
But anyway, in principle,
we can reproduce its results.
Yeah.
But our paper here is mainly.
As long as.
Estimate a number level.
Yeah.
We use its result directly.
Okay.
Then we assume that this.
Dark matter is contributed by 35%.
Dark matter is.
35% of it is contributed by this multiple.
Okay.
In this case,
the average is about 0.7.
Then this multiple is very heavy.
About 200 TeV.
Yeah.
That's for reference.
Like the one just now.
I asked before.
Is that.
The experiment of WIMP.
It's going to be 10 to the power of 4.
So 10 to the power of 4.
It's only about 10 TeV.
So it's probably still.
This is still.
Ten times heavier than the average experiment.
Above.
It can even be heavier.
Okay.
Anyway.
Then I'm going to do it again.
Our work is very simple.
Is that we.
Consider the graph on the right.
On the left.
With this.
The idea is that M is multiple.
Then N is Neutron.
Then through the middle.
This action.
No border.
That.
This action and this Neutron.
The last one is.
It's easier.
Just assume there's a.
Yukai.
Yukai interaction.
You know this theory.
Right.
Yukai should be quite famous.
It's Japan.
It's a theoretical science.
Yeah.
What's more difficult is.
How to calculate multiple.
With this action.
This interaction.
That's it.
It's going to be.
The so-called winter effect.
That is to say.
You can imagine.
This.
Uh.
More.
How?
Because of that.
His.
If there is an action.
This charge.
It will.
It will spread in space.
In some sense.
It will.
It will affect this.
Uh.
Neutron.
For example.
If you have this.
If this is moving.
This.
Neutron.
He might feel this.
This.
This movement.
Yeah.
So.
Let's say they have an interaction.
Yeah.
Through this action.
That's pretty hard.
Because of this.
We can't just write this.
This action.
With mobile.
This interaction.
It's going to be through this.
Winter effect.
Yeah.
That's it.
Some of my boss's ideas.
Yeah.
That.
If we can calculate this.
These interactions.
What about it?
We can also calculate this process.
This color scheme.
Because you remember.
We were just in time.
You have to compare with the experiment.
That time.
They measured the color scheme.
With.
The same relationship.
Yeah.
As long as we calculate it.
You can do it.
Compare with time.
And then to our model.
Some parameters.
Constraint.
Good.
Well, since we're actually.
We also consider some other experiments.
Like the so-called experience.
Yeah.
And these.
This experiment is mainly to measure some.
More long life.
This.
Some particles.
Yeah.
That action.
It's one of the possibilities.
Yeah.
We also put this.
This time limit.
Also put it in this.
Yeah.
Analysis.
Okay.
There's a lot of time in this regard.
Like this.
On the left.
See this charm on the picture.
And ship.
Yeah.
And charm is already given.
Some upper bound.
Yeah.
Some restrictions.
And ship is.
Future perspective.
That's it.
There's also this FA on the picture.
FA is basically.
This.
The intensity of the interaction.
That is to say.
If you F is super big.
But this strength is weaker.
Yeah.
We can also see this FA.
That's this.
The strength of this action.
Probably.
It's related to this FA.
You'll see it later.
Okay.
Since this is the mother.
I'll bring it over soon.
Because this is too detailed.
I'll tell you the story.
The way to finish my theoretical computing work.
That's the same.
We have this model.
Write down this Lagrangian.
And then the last one.
What about this?
It's a constant.
Now, I'm going to do this.
Let's do it.
Promoted to a.
This one.
It's a dynamical.
The field.
Like this.
That's our action.
That's the action here.
But I'm normal.
By this FA.
That is to say.
What about this?
It's not a unit.
Yeah.
That.
Once we write down this Lagrangian.
We can solve it.
To solve this.
Motion equation.
That's the equation of motion.
That's the picture.
This line below.
A little complicated.
And then we'll put in some boundary conditions.
That is to say.
We have to assume that this.
The energy of the system is limited.
It can't be infinite.
It's not going to happen.
So this action field is at the origin.
To go to zero.
And then at the same time.
It's infinite.
It's going to be.
Close to this.
A constant.
This constant is called Zeta 0.
With this equation of motion and boundary conditions.
We can solve.
Equation of motion.
Whether it's using numbers or some.
Uh, just solve it.
The picture is.
The picture is our result.
That green.
That's what.
The orange one is the result of our numbers.
Uh, that's what we're going to do.
Solve the original equation directly.
Of course, we have some mirroring.
The blue curve is the result of the number.
Then I found out that we.
The solution of the solution is very good.
Yeah, I didn't say that.
Because it's a little complicated.
Okay, so.
So you can see this action.
This, this, this distribution.
That's the picture.
It's the distance from the distance.
So the closer.
The closer to the left is the position of the model.
That's the zero part.
And then go.
To the right is.
Uh, uh, uh, uh, long distance.
So you can see when it's closer and closer.
This is this.
Well, it's not, it's not mobile.
It's the actual fuel.
The ratio of his one is getting smaller.
Well, that's kind of a simple reason.
Because I just saw.
This shop will.
The power plant will do this.
The value of this github has to do with.
So if you're getting closer and closer.
If you're far away, you're getting smaller and smaller.
You're going to send it.
Then you're going to blow up your system.
So it becomes that when you're getting closer and closer.
What about this city tower?
It's going to be close to zero.
That's how the system is going to be.
Yeah, that's the most basic reason.
So you can predict that he's somewhere.
This action, his size, he's somewhere.
To reduce.
Yeah, that's the reduction.
The location is probably.
Roughly in this part.
That's probably.
That's the one on the video.
The following definition.
Well, you don't really need to know this definition.
Why is that?
And then.
So we're basically going to end this.
The distribution of the action field near this model.
So we're going to take it as a three-dimensional interface.
That's the first one on the screen.
That's what I just said.
The action, yes.
For example, look at this one.
This is a x, a of x, which is action.
And then what's behind that?
That's the new curve.
This is a general way of doing long-term computing.
This is a familiar way of writing.
Yeah.
What about this?
Or what about the light?
We can go and calculate the probability of its color.
The color of this mp2.
Okay, so it's the shape.
Uh, his.
The result is the second line of the equation.
And then you can see that there's one in this equation.
There's a space for this x.
This kind of point.
That is to say, if we just.
We just got rid of his.
This space is distributed.
So it's natural to throw it into this point.
And then you can calculate this mp2.
And then you make the mp2 a square.
You can calculate this.
The three-color interface.
And then the result is.
The green part below, like this.
So this is the final, final, final, final theoretical calculation.
This is the result.
But after this result.
I have a question.
Okay.
My, my, my, my, actually, my question is quite general.
That is.
Ok, so you, now your monopuly charge.
And then we actually know.
Hello, the density seems to be how much.
So you can probably know.
It's your number density.
This bridge hundreds of TV.
Number density.
How much is it?
But they're all charging each other.
So.
So they can interact with each other through dark four times.
Or the repair is, you know, which is why you put together.
So you're not going to have a very strong constraint.
Is it from?
I put it in.
I'll give you a look at this.
In fact, the company has considered this.
Yeah, they're going to steal a black photon.
It's going to form, it's going to form.
What do you mean?
It's going to have a strong effect.
It's going to have a very strong effect.
Of course, we have that.
It's okay.
Yeah, okay, interesting.
Okay, thank you.
No, I didn't say too much.
So there is.
Good.
Anyway, it's very mathematical here.
That's it.
I just finished talking about it.
It's just more technical stuff.
Okay, so we're going to figure out the result.
It's a three-color interface.
I just said that time is to look at the relationship between the three-color interface and the value.
Okay, so that's the result.
And I'm going to give you two examples here.
I'm going to pick two.
Okay, that's basically what I just did.
I just don't have that.
This one.
Yeah, this one.
His signature is F.A.
And then the horizontal axis is X.
That's the same.
You can look at this green one.
Do you happen to have these parameters?
Well, basically, there's no parameter that needs to be adjusted.
For example.
Uh.
Alpha H.
We've just been given the benchmark point.
And then M.N. is the value of the box.
We know that the box is about 1G.
And then C.T.A.0 is a parameter.
And then C.T.A.
C.T.A.N.
C.N. is probably some theoretical data.
Calculate it like this.
So we don't have a lot of parameters.
In this model.
Okay.
And then we can see the result.
So we're the same.
The horizontal axis is F.A.
And then the horizontal axis is X.
And then we pick two benchmark points.
And then the red and green on the graph.
There's already a time limit.
So I'm going to use the first one.
I'm going to use the first one.
And then the blue one is going to be in the future.
It's Pico 500.
It's the same.
It's the time of a dark matter.
It's going to be measured in the future.
That's it.
So you can see that this is about the size of F.A.
It's about 10 to the 7th square.
That's it.
Okay, so it's almost time.
It's about to upgrade.
Just a little bit about this.
It's pretty simple.
It's just preparing a pro.
Uh, a pro.
Or some experiments are done with Electron.
And then he's using Proton.
And then he's going to turn a target.
And then there's some reaction in this target.
And then there's a lot of these.
Some of these rings.
And then these rings might be able to get to a lot of.
I don't know about these unknown particles.
Maybe it's the action.
That's the action.
He might not be stable.
He might be in.
He's changed before he got to the tag.
Or to say.
It's changing after you leave.
Yeah, well, there's a possibility that he's changing inside the tag.
And then it might change into light.
Ah, electricity.
Ah, aim.
Then, of course, we're on the model side.
This light will change to Hilton Photon.
Yeah, that's the one down there.
Equation is this.
We should have to predict how many events we should see.
Yeah.
That's the only thing I'm going to change.
It's very simple to say.
Of course, it's a test.
You can see the particle.
It's like light, aim, or electricity.
Hidden Photon is invisible.
But because there's a hidden.
Because it's a hidden Photon.
So it's going to reduce.
Action to the probability of visible particles.
Yeah, so it's going to be.
Uh, it's going to be diluted.
So it's going to be a little bit weaker.
And then it's like, uh.
I'm going to show you this.
Like the one on the left.
You'll find that.
That Alpha H is zero.
Alpha H means there's no Hilton Photon.
It's just.
It's none of my business.
Constraint.
It's black.
The black part.
But if you have an introduction of Hilton Photon.
Then you'll find that this.
Constraint will be.
It's going to be weak.
It's going to shrink.
Because there's a new channel.
Yeah, that's Trump.
And then the left and right is the future.
Yeah, we're the same.
Consider some of the same.
Uh, the possibility of Alpha H.
So we just had the result of the bin.
And then we have this.
Uh, the result of the direct observation.
And the result of the bin.
So we can simply combine them together.
Okay, so this is our final result.
Of course, it's a little complicated.
But let's take a look at the picture.
Back.
That's what the color counter is.
That's what the back color.
Shadow part is.
It's been excluded so far.
That's the only white part.
It's still allowed at the moment.
That's about about ten to the fourth.
Uh, ten to the fifth.
And it's about ten mv.
It's just around here.
This is the pin.
With this.
With this, uh, direct measurement.
There's an overlap.
Well, of course, we can say that in the future.
Maybe in this range.
To detect this model.
It's still value like this.
Okay, so this is our final result.
Okay, so I'm going to summarize it.
Uh, our research project is simply to study.
Uh, hidden motor.
Hidden motor and.
The nuclear, uh, through this action.
Uh, interaction.
And then we're going to calculate its three-color interface.
And then compare it with the experiment.
And then I found about two.
Two parameters space, it may be in the future.
This dark matter experiment and this ice cream experiment.
Uh, do the test.
Okay, so this is my speech today.
Thank you all.
Okay, so now I'd like to ask you to turn on the microphone.
So that we can hear our applause.
So let's give it up.
Thank you for your wonderful speech.
Um, okay.
Does anyone have any questions?
Uh, I have a question.
How do you decide this?
Uh, your input parameters.
Like, uh, and, uh, and, uh.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
It's just that.
For example, this side.
Oh, my God.
This is.
This one, this one.
Why is it?
That is, we can.
I just said we can estimate.
This dark matter.
Uh, this number density.
Right?
That's what I just said on the side of the photo.
A little bit.
Theoretical work.
Theoretically, we can estimate the number density of the dark matter.
And then we know it again.
Can we know its quality?
This is mn.
This is your mn times.
Your value times number density is.
Mass density.
That mass density will tell you.
How much of this dark matter should be in the universe?
This one.
How many potions?
Well, I just said at the beginning.
Dark matter.
He should be in the universe.
Uh.
One quarter of it.
So it becomes you.
You have a very strong limit.
So it's called fit.
That one.
This 25% of the words.
Your number.
Your alpha h and mn.
Can be fixed.
But the result of theory.
I see.
So in this model.
Exxon is not dark matter.
He is not.
But I know.
I know.
You also know that many people use.
Exxon is dark matter.
That side.
We mainly treat Exxon as a medium.
He will treat it as dark matter.
It can also be.
But his contribution should be very small.
It's almost negligible.
Compared to this.
Actually, I have one.
I have a similar.
The problem is.
So, okay.
So your halo is basically.
Or whatever.
Anyway, your.
That one.
Dark matter is monopole.
But he will still.
Couple Exxon.
That.
If today.
Really in.
For example, that kind of.
He has a very strong magnetic field.
Then he can.
It's like putting that.
Vacuum.
Exxon.
Is playing out.
A photon can resonate.
But such an effect.
Can it happen to you?
This model.
Just those side.
Exxon.
That you.
Here, because I'm here.
I'm actually not relying on the photon.
It's not a general photon.
It should.
It should be said that there is a couple.
But it should be.
Wait a minute.
Strength.
You see.
Through the general action.
With the photon.
That.
And then through that.
That's a very strong electrical field.
Then to generate exxon is not.
To be honest.
Yes, it is.
It's through a loop.
Then it becomes.
If you give him a photon.
Then it is.
Then you it through a loop.
Then it becomes a.
Uh, what is this.
It's a normal photon.
It's not a dark photon.
Yes, that's what it is.
I want to.
I want to have constraint.
But because of my action is.
It should be very.
You see, I'm actually quite heavy.
Your impression.
I see.
So, if you do.
So, because I'm actually quite heavy.
Without using.
Oh, so you came out.
It's not even.
You come out.
It's a super.
That doesn't mean.
Ha ha ha ha ha.
I see I see.
OK.
Then everyone has a question?
Why don't you consider others?
Why didn't you consider others?
direct.
That.
This article is a.
Recreational learning field.
After the Selena Gavin memo like this.
Why don't you consider others?
direct.
Uh, that Darkmatt'lll also have time to say.
Can, can I.
Everyone, see you like me.
It's says I have this mother to.
It's said that this fact is then.
It's fixed.
Spin dependent right.
This is the first one.
Then there is.
We, we, of course, pick.
We, of course, pick this concentrate.
The strongest is probably.
I'm probably here.
I'm kidding.
Why spin dependent?
This, I'm a little bit missed.
Uh, actually, I didn't explain it.
But.
Let's put it this way.
This is more technical.
That is to say.
You see this equation.
This is the result.
If you're more familiar.
If you're more familiar with theory, you'll find out.
You find this section.
It's a bit of this.
Transfer momentum.
So, if you're more familiar with the theory.
You'll find that this section.
It's a bit of this.
Transfer momentum.
What did he say?
So, anyway.
This momentum dependence.
Connection is generally spin level.
Yes, we have to consider this from the side.
So, so what you mean is.
Anyway, in general.
The result you calculated depends on spin level.
This is not an assumption or something you can decide first.
Is that right?
It should be said that we have this result.
We can.
Obviously, this result tells you.
It depends on this transfer momentum.
So it depends on spin.
Then we can find some.
Effect operator.
They.
The result they calculated is also spin dependent.
Then at the same time it depends on this transfer momentum.
Then we use its result to confirm this parameter.
But it doesn't mean that the transfer momentum has spin or something.
If it is spin independent.
You can also set some constraints, right?
You don't have to have spin.
Because.
Because it depends on momentum.
So.
Generally, spin independent seems.
It should be weaker.
You just said it's the next level.
This is a bit like.
This independent should have a leading order.
Is.
What is it?
Leading order and sub-leading order.
This kind of spin dependent should have very little contribution.
It's kind of S-wave, P-wave.
Very similar feeling.
In fact, I have a slide.
I talked about it in Dongda before.
I don't want to talk about this detail.
Let me see.
I talked about it in Dongda.
You can take a look.
Of course, there was more detail at that time.
For example, we have to consider this.
This effect operator.
Then obviously you see this effect.
Starting from this effect operator.
Now, for example, on this screen.
This Psi is the document.
Then Psi n is the new curve.
Then through this effect operator.
We can calculate its amplitude.
Then you can see that the amplitude depends on this.
This spin.
For example, that sigma is polymetric.
For example, this kind of thing is.
Spin dependent.
Then there is the same amplitude.
You can calculate its cross-section.
Then someone has already done this analysis.
So basically, I just put this equation.
For example, this yellow one.
The final result.
Then equal to the result we just calculated.
Then do the comparison like this.
So to be honest, we are a bit like.
Use other constraints to constrain our parameters.
We did not directly.
For example, you may want to do some.
More complicated calculations.
Because we haven't scored this cross-section yet.
We still have to consider some.
Neutron.
Recurrence.
But I didn't really do a deep analysis.
We just put people's results.
To constrain.
This is someone else's upper bound.
We can just extract it.
I will ask this question because.
Axiom interaction is not limited to.
Spin dependent cross-section.
You can go straight to many experiments.
Measure the axiom.
Axiom can be absorbed.
So if you just look at.
The Fermi diagram.
You can consider.
Axiom is absorbed by your detector.
So you can use xenon.
Or LZ to measure.
That's right.
Are you measuring the axiom now?
Because you have to go through the axiom.
To measure your monopole.
Right?
Because it is a medium.
So.
So you go to your Fermi diagram.
Your left side of the Fermi diagram.
Monopole and axiom coupling.
Your right side is the axiom.
Coupling with Fibre.
Any coupling between the axiom and your detector.
So basically I think.
You should also have.
You can use other bigger detectors to measure.
Because they have already done.
A lot of axiom measurements.
But I don't know about the mass range.
Except for Bindan.
If you have this theory.
Other experiments can also do.
High energy axiom measurements.
They just don't have a good theory.
The reason is because the axiom is so high.
This high mass region.
His lifetime is very short.
So it can't be a dark matter.
Right.
So these direct dark matter experiments.
They won't consider.
This kind of axiom.
He will only consider KEV's axiom.
He won't consider.
GEV or NEV's axiom.
But if you set up this model.
They can consider GEV's axiom.
Because your axiom is not dark matter.
It's your monopole that's dark matter.
Yeah.
But I don't know what you just said.
Experiment.
LZ can be.
Unlox or Xenon.
They all have a lot of.
Bosonic dark matter measurement.
Basically.
Axiom in KEV to 100 KEV.
This range.
You can imagine the axiom.
Detected absorbed.
Just like the photon.
Then you can use this.
Then you can use this to consider the axiom.
That.
In the KEV range.
What about your model?
Basically, you can also consider the axiom.
NEV or GEV range.
It was absorbed by your detector.
Uh-huh.
Of course they may.
Their detector may have energy.
Threshold may not be able to GEV.
Maybe a few NEV.
I guess.
So maybe in this.
Maybe on the left side of your picture.
This place can be set up.
Uplimit.
Are you on the left side of the picture?
There are many NEV parts.
This is about 10 NEV range.
But there are other things here.
I didn't just say that.
Yes, there may be other things.
So I don't know.
Is it other.
These large dark matter experiments.
Can also be done.
What about the region on the left side of your picture?
Because I don't know.
Where is their energy threshold?
I am doing low mass.
But.
But I look at this picture.
I think it's actually a bit like.
High mass experiment.
Want to do low mass.
The place is probably on the right.
They can do a few GEV now.
Then do a low mass.
Just do it.
So in fact, I think this one.
A lot of people want to.
There are a lot of direct experiments.
You are not the same.
This is Exxon, not WIMP.
WIMP in GEV is low mass.
But in Exxon, GEV is high mass.
No, I'm talking about it now.
In general, if you can.
For example, you can couple to a.
U1 Bosonic dark matter.
So it actually includes this side.
So I think it can.
For example, if today.
They consider.
You can be in Xenon.
For example.
Analyzation signal.
Direct absorption.
They should be able to do 0.
It's 10 to 0 to 10 to 1.
If today is.
If it's a solid detector.
I think I can do it again.
So in fact, this picture is a big piece.
There should be data to look at.
So it's possible to see.
So you might have new concerns here.
If you consider those.
Giant dark matter experiment.
I'll take a look.
Tell me about it later.
I'm actually doing a little analysis here.
Because we're doing Marana now.
We're thinking about whether we can do this.
NEV Exxon experiment.
Measurement.
Because in general.
Exxon in NEV.
Lifetime is very short.
So Exxon can't be dark matter.
But if you are.
There is a dark sector.
Or a forever thing.
Through Exxon couple to your detector.
Then you.
Exxon's lifetime can be very short.
So in theory, you can set a constraint there.
That's it.
Sorry.
Do you have any other questions?
I think we.
If you want to discuss it later.
But do you have any other questions?
If not.
Let's applaud again.
Thank you.
Thank you all.
That's it for today.