The most direct benefit of this design is that,
on average, each symbol's value,
its frequency, and the frequency we represent.
With this design, we can immediately see that
by doing this, we can compress the data to theoretically the lowest length,
which is Shannon Entropy.
This is a pretty classic result.
I guess a lot of people already know about it.
But the discussion here is more like
assuming that we already know the probability of X and Y.
But in actual application,
we usually don't know about it.
We have to learn about it.
Next, we will mainly discuss how to learn PX and PY.
Next, we will relax the assumption a bit.
Let's assume that we don't know PX and PY anymore.
But we know that this input, 0001, 001,
represents a person's routine.
This person's routine is basically only
sleeping, eating, and running.
Let's assume that we know this,
and we know that 00 means sleeping,
and 01 means running.
It's easy to predict what the next one will be.
Because we know that this person is sleeping.
The next thing he will do is probably running.
So the next two symbols will probably be 01.
Let's assume that we know
that the source of this signal is a Markov chain.
Then we can use the method of counting to know
what the next step will be.
For example, if we count to 10 times,
6 times is running,
2 times is eating,
then we know that PY is probably equal to 0.6.
But this is still not the same as what we actually encounter.
Because we don't actually know if this 001, 001, 001
represents a person's routine,
or DNA, or a picture.
So what do we do at this point?
Later on, Leopold Zip came up with the idea that
we assume that it is a Markov chain.
We keep cutting the inputs.
If we encounter a new chunk that we have never seen before,
we treat it as a new chunk.
For example, if the original data is A, B, R, A, C, A, D, A, B, R, A,
Leopold Zip said, OK, we see A,
so A is a chunk that we have never seen before.
B is also a chunk that we have never seen before.
R is also a chunk that we have never seen before.
When it comes to A, we find that A has actually been seen before.
So we can add E to A,
the frequency of its appearance.
So after R, the frequency of A's appearance is E.
Next, we look at A, C.
A, C is a chunk that we have never seen before,
so it is a unit of its own.
A has also been seen before, but A, D has not.
And so on.
After we chunk it up,
we can treat it as a separate unit,
and then count the frequency of A after B,
and the frequency of R after A, C.
In this way,
we will be able to know
the probability of each symbol.
This is basically what we do on the computer.
For those of you who are writing programs,
we might use GZip or WinZip
to compress these programs.
When these WinZip and GZip programs are compressed,
they are actually doing this thing
to predict the probability of the next byte.
And then do the arithmetic coding based on that.
But there are a few drawbacks to doing this.
There are two main drawbacks.
The first drawback is
that it does not use all the information
in this whole string of words, A, B, R, A, C, A.
For example, if we want to answer this question,
what is the probability of seeing A after B, R?
At this point, we haven't chunked B, R,
so it might just use the number of times A appears.
But we see that at least in this segment,
after B, R appears, A always appears.
So we know that the probability of A is very high.
But if we use Lampell's Zip to chunk,
we don't actually get this information.
This is the first question.
The second question is,
let's say we want to know
what B is after R, A, A.
Because R, A, A is not in our chunk,
so we just take the number of times B appears.
But here, we already have
the number of times A appears after B.
We already have this information.
Or if we have a lot of different prefixes
that we can use,
Lampell's Zip will only use one logic.
If we have A, C,
it will choose one randomly.
At this point, it might not choose the right one.
These are the two main shortcomings of Lampell's Zip.
So how do we solve the shortcomings of Lampell's Zip?
These shortcomings will be solved
in the context-free weighting algorithm.
The first shortcoming of Lampell's Zip is
that some prefixes,
although it sees them,
it doesn't parse them.
To solve this problem,
it's very simple.
We don't skip the symbol.
Every time, we use one symbol
to see how many prefixes are in front of it.
This way, we can get all the prefixes.
For example,
let's say our data is 0100110.
Let's record what happens
after each prefix.
We can see that after 110,
there's a 0.
So we can see that
after 110,
we can see that
after 011,
there's a 0.
So we can record that
after 011,
there's a 0.
And after 001,
there's a 1.
So after 001,
If we do this slowly,
we'll get a more comprehensive
summary than Lampell's Zip.
So this solves
its first problem.
Lampell's Zip has a second problem.
Let's say
a lot of prefixes
don't satisfy
the query we want.
Which one should we choose?
Specifically,
let's say
we already know
the data is like this,
and we want to know
the probability of the 8th symbol
being 0.
We can frame this problem
into
the probability of 0
after we see 0.
At this point,
let's say
the first symbol is 0,
and the second symbol
is a 1.
So the first symbol is 0,
and the second symbol is 0.
and the second symbol is 1.
We'll have the same result.
The probability of 0
after 0 is 0.5.
But we can also answer
the 8th question
from the perspective
that the first symbol is 0, 1.
If we look at it
from this perspective,
we'll find that
if the first symbol is 0, 1,
there will be a 0 after that.
If the first symbol is 0, 1,
So if we see 0, 1,
the probability of 0
is 100%.
So we should
choose
which pattern
to represent
our probability.
To solve this problem,
we can
use
some
principles
of natural
philosophy.
One of the principles
is that
this is a philosophy,
but we'll see
how to define
this philosophy
to define it.
In this philosophy,
if there are many different
theories that can
explain a phenomenon,
we have no choice
but to keep all the theories.
We can't say
which theory is better.
As long as the evidence
is consistent,
we'll see
how to
define it.
Here,
we can
think of the problem
as
we already have the data.
Which model
should we use
to explain the data?
There are many different models.
The first model is
that we don't care about
the probability of
the next 0 or 1.
This model
is more
complicated.
It may use some
prefixes.
This model is more complicated.
Which model
should we use?
If we accept
this principle,
it means
we have to give
each model
a weight.
How do we give
each model a weight?
This is what we
are going to discuss.
Here,
we mainly want to
use this model
to
visualize
the weight.
If we want to
see the next 0 or 1,
we can
think of it as
the weight of this model
and this model.
For this model,
it is the weight of
this model and this model.
For this model,
it is the weight of
these five models.
From the image,
we can see
two small models.
Is there a way
to know
the weight of
this large model?
Let's assume we know
the weight of the small model.
Here, we have
five parameters,
w1', w2', w3'.
In the
wide field,
this number
may have
an exponential value
of 2.
We need to
calculate this number.
Can we not
calculate
such a large number
of numbers?
Can we not
use such a small number
to calculate the weight?
This is a problem
we encounter in practice.
To put it
simply,
the main
insight here
is that
we can
use the concept of
multiplication
to do
recursive
calculation.
The main concept is that
if
p is equal to
this,
these two
equations
are like
a cross-product
of these four
models.
These four equations
seem to
describe
these four equations.
In the wide field,
let's say
we define
a larger
model.
If we simply look at
0, 1, 0, 1,
and then add
the numbers below
to make
a cross-product,
we will get
an N-square.
If we define
this weight,
this seems to be
an intuitive approach.
In fact,
this approach is correct.
There are a few reasons
why it is correct.
One of the reasons
is that
when we define
these weights,
w1', w2', w3', w4',
and we use
recursive
to define them,
we will find that
these w1', w2', w3', w4',
and w5'
are intuitive.
For example,
if we know that
the number below is equal to 1,
then the number above
must be equal to 1.
This is the first good quality.
OK.
There is
a second
intuitive
recursive
model
to prove
that it is a good model.
The second
good intuitive
argument is that
if we do this,
we actually
multiply
the tree
of the
two-dimensional
number
by its weight,
which becomes
the sum of
the two dimensions.
For example,
there are many trees here.
How much weight
should we give to this tree?
Basically,
1 minus the position
here,
multiplied by 1 minus the position here,
multiplied by the position here,
multiplied by the position here.
If it is not lift,
it is 1 minus w.
If it is lift,
So basically,
what we are doing is
giving these trees
a weight,
which is the sum of
the two dimensions.
Let's say
there are
some practical examples.
Let's say
there are
these trees
of the
two dimensions.
We will find that
these w
meet this formula.
For example,
if the top is 1,
the next
is 5.
If this side is 1,
the top is 5.
If we do this,
we will find that
if we want to
specify a tree,
we need so many information,
so many bits.
Because we have
different things
to describe the
two-dimensional
tree,
so we need
two-dimensional bits
to describe it.
This is a big tree.
Can we choose
these w
roots,
so that
we can use
a shorter
symbol to
describe it?
In fact,
there is.
This way is to
turn these w into
one-half.
When we describe
a tree,
we use
its
prefix code
to describe it.
For example,
this shape
is 11000.
Its length
is 5.
We don't need
so many
bits
to describe it.
So,
when we put these things
together,
pw
is about
this formula.
This formula can
describe so many
trees in a classic way
to give it a reasonable weight.
If we look at
this formula again,
we will find that
after we do this,
the weight of
these different models
is actually
the same.
For example,
the bigger the tree,
the smaller the weight.
In short,
we are using
a common
physical or
scientific principle,
Occam's razor.
The simpler the
explanation,
the more likely
it is.
After doing this,
we put
all the things together
to do a
theoretical discussion
to summarize
pwz
is a good
compression.
If n is large,
it basically means
that we already know
whether it is a
human shape,
walking,
or eating.
For example,
if n is large enough,
we can always
chunk it to the
original chunk.
There is a detail
here.
Many textbooks
say that
pwz
is an optimal
compression.
The compression length
minus the length
divided by n
is equal to
1 divided by log n.
They say
every symbol
has an error of 0.
However,
pwz is not optimal.
Strictly speaking,
it is not optimal
because the error
is not the fastest.
pwz
jumps over
a lot of things.
For example,
when there are many explanations,
pwz only jumps over
an explanation
that is not
easy to understand.
However,
if we do this,
we will find that
pwz has an error of
log n divided by n.
However,
pwz is faster
than pwz.
Here is
an example of
what the original
source tree is.
pwz
is optimal,
but strictly speaking,
it is not optimal
because the speed of
pwz is not fast enough.
In conclusion,
we can discuss
from a theoretical perspective
that the speed of
pwz has
a limit.
This limit is given
by Riesenbaum.
Riesenbaum said
the compressed length
minus the real length
is always greater than
k log n.
So,
let's go back
to the
asymptotic rate of
ctw.
In fact, ctw is
the fastest speed in
theory,
which is log n divided by
n.
Suppose
k is
the freedom
of the original
signal source.
The more complex
the model is,
the greater the error
will be.
Even if we use
the strongest learning algorithm,
the more complex
the model is,
the greater the error
will be.
So,
in general,
how to compress
from better
intelligence to better?
This is the complexity itself.
We know that
traditionally,
it is solved by
arithmetic coding.
In fact,
there is a bigger problem.
This is
the price of learning.
actually the biggest problem
in practice.
Because this problem is
proportional to the length of the data.
We can only compress it to the length of log n.
And it is not only
proportional to log n,
but also directly
proportional to the
freedom of the problem itself.
The more complex the problem is,
the higher the price
of learning the problem.
The rest is
what our
researchers
want to reduce to zero.
We want to come up with
a good algorithm
to use
a bad
estimator.
For example,
we use a bad estimator
to compare with
the most efficient estimator.
We should
find a way to use this to zero.
In summary,
compressing is
about three-thirds.
We want to turn the last part
to zero.
We can see from the above
that CT context tree weighting
is close to
the fastest speed
in theory.
It is a very efficient
estimator.
This is
the part of the theory.
The theory sounds
perfect and amazing.
Does this theory work?
Here is
an example.
We want to compress
this article.
This article is
Lincoln's
Gettysburg Address,
in English,
7 years ago.
This article
has a capacity
of about 1K.
If we compress it
with common
compression methods,
it can be compressed
to this size.
However, if we use CTW,
it is more efficient in theory.
If we use a better
learning algorithm,
we will find that
it compresses less.
This means that
the better our
prediction ability is,
the less we can compress
in total.
This theory
is correct.
We have
proved that
we can get better
compression from
a better learning algorithm.
What is more
interesting
is how to
get better
compression.
Let's say
every computer has
WinZip.
We can use WinZip.exe
to do machine learning.
Or we have a better
compression method,
TZ.
We can use TZ
to do better machine learning.
I want to prove
this thing
from the point of view
that
we just said
that wisdom is unpredictable.
If we change the definition of
wisdom to
pattern,
or to be more specific,
if we treat wisdom
as a non-supervised
learning,
unsupervised learning,
can we prove
that a better compression
can do better
unsupervised learning?
I guess
if we can do
unsupervised learning,
we can do a lot of
smart things,
like condensed
method research,
astronomy research,
or more.
To be more specific,
when we do unsupervised learning,
we want to answer
if there are
A, B, C,
is A closer to B?
Or is A closer to C?
Or is B closer to C?
So,
unsupervised learning
is about
measuring
how close
or how different
two things are.
This is a
simple
structure to
calculate
the distance
of two random things
using
this
unsupervised learning
algorithm.
Let's say
anything can
become 010101.
Let's say
x is a
0101 string,
and kx is
the length
after the compression.
Let's say
we put x and y
together
to get this length.
We know that
when the compression
is good,
kxy is
roughly equal to kyx.
This is
the notation
for conditional probability.
Let's say we have
given x,
how much
extra length
do we need to
reconstruct y?
The definition
is kxy-kx.
In other words,
ky given x
is the
information
in y but not in x.
With this
conditional definition,
we know that
for a good
compression,
we only need
0 length to
compress x.
This
ky given x
is the total length.
If we want to ask
per unit symbol
or per bit
information in y
but not in x,
we can just
multiply ky given x
by y.
This is
like
using a smart
program to
measure
the information in y
but not in x.
The information
in x
can be calculated
as how different
the distance between
y and x is.
This is like
the general purpose
of unsupervised learning.
Or the distance
between two things.
But this
has reached
our intuition.
But there are some drawbacks.
It's not symmetric.
If we
make some
changes
to max and max,
we'll find that
it's symmetric.
And when
y is greater than x,
it will come here.
Or if x is greater than y,
So if we define
this as
the distance between
two things,
it's symmetric.
If we define it like this,
we'll find that
the length is too
short.
So this is like
giving a compressed
program, winzip.inxe,
to calculate the distance
between two things.
So after we
push it like this,
we'll find that
this method can give us
a compressed program.
We don't know what it does.
But if it's good enough,
it can help us
figure out the distance
between two things.
So this idea
is good in theory,
but in practice,
is it useful?
Today, I'll give you
two examples
to show that
it can be useful.
In the first example,
we want to solve
biological problems.
To be precise,
we want to solve
a problem
among mammals.
It's a problem
they care about.
This debate
is a common
debate in
biology
in the early 2000s.
They debate
whether humans
are closer to pigs
or mice.
Some people
say that
humans are
closer to
pigs or mice.
But if we
look at other data,
we'll find that
humans are closer
to mice.
Can we use
a compressed program to
answer this question?
To put it simply,
if a monkey
has this DNA,
GTTAT,
and a pig
has this DNA,
and we run
a compressed program
to calculate
the information
between these two
DNAs,
can we answer
this question?
We do this
because it's
quite different from
traditional biology.
Traditional biology
uses a lot of
biological information.
For example,
traditionally,
we would
do an alignment
to these primitive data.
This part
should be compared
with GTTAT.
For example,
three RNAs
can form
a condom.
The third one
in the condom
is more likely to
mutate,
so we ignore it.
It's like doing
what we call
feature engineering
to get a result.
Can we
do feature engineering
to compress
raw data
and get
a pretty
correct result?
It looks like
we can.
The picture on the left
is a winzip
or gzip program.
We get
the classification of
animal blood
and DNA.
We can see
that it's
pretty good.
Horses and donkeys
are pretty similar.
Mice are the same.
Humans and stars are the same.
But it still has
some problems.
For example,
this flying monkey is
a monkey,
so the monkey should be here.
It also says
that humans
are closer to
pigs and
mice.
This is gzip.
We know
that gzip is
doing Lampel's Zip.
When it predicts
the next bit,
the accuracy is not as high as
CTW.
If we use a better
prediction of the future,
we will find
that the results
are better.
It has
categorized the animals
and said that humans are
closer to pigs.
This result
matches
traditional biology.
The results are
pretty consistent.
This is
the first example.
We can use
simple compression
to get results
that are more
like traditional biology.
It makes sense.
We can also
do
different types of classification.
We can also
do some research
on SARS
virus DNA.
Many people
know that
SARS virus
was a big disease
10 years ago.
The mortality rate
is very high.
We still
don't have a vaccine
in 2019.
Why do we
have such a high mortality rate
and no vaccine?
Can we try to
answer this question?
We use
compression to answer this question.
The main concept is
to compare it with
other
family viruses
and do a classification study.
We use it
to do a study
on the virus of
colds, pigs, and mice.
Our study
has no
feature engineering
or
heuristic.
We use
compression.
Traditionally,
biologists do
a lot of
heuristics.
For example,
biologists
do DNA research.
They use a database
to calculate
the probability of
A mutating to D amino acid.
They use
a table
to find
the probability
of A mutating to D amino acid.
They use
the probability of
A mutating to D amino acid.
If we
use
the compression
and do the
heuristic,
we can see
that
phylogeny
looks like this.
We can see that
SARS is
very different
from other
known coronaviruses.
It is a family.
Moreover,
coronaviruses
have a family
of mice and cows.
Group 2 is
a family of mice and cows.
Cats and dogs
are in the same family.
This is the result
we get
from a wide
compression.
This result
matches
the science
in this paper.
The research
shows that
coronaviruses
are divided into
these groups.
SARS is
very unique.
This explains
why SARS has
such a high mortality rate
and has no vaccine.
It is very different
from other viruses.
To sum up,
we have
not only
compression,
but also better compression
to get better intelligence.
Many people
have
applied
compression
to
measure IQ
and intelligence.
We can use
compression to measure IQ.
If IQ is better,
intelligence will be better.
This is like
a more scientific way
to measure intelligence
than the traditional
IQ test.
To be more specific,
we know that
human brain
compresses English
one bit per character.
This is like
the goal of artificial intelligence.
Next,
the second important message
is that
the most basic principle
in science
is
the simpler the explanation,
the more we should pay attention to it.
This is a very
correct philosophy.
It can be transformed
into a very quantitative way
to measure
these different assumptions.
It is not only
helpful to
natural scientists,
but also very useful
in artificial intelligence.
This is
the end of
today's lecture.
In the end,
I think
lecture
or class
should be interactive.
This is a
very simple quiz.
For example,
if we look at
this compressed format,
the developer
is not a
random person.
He is a serious person.
This compressed format
eventually
compresses
the information
to zero.
Is this right?
Is this possible?
This is a small quiz.
If you are interested, you can go back and think about it.
That's it.
Thank you.
Thank you,
Fu Ming.
Do the
audience
have any questions?
Hello.
I have two
questions.
The first one is
about
the experiment
on supervised
learning.
Do you have
other
research on
computational
biology?
I'm not familiar
with computational biology,
so I'm curious.
The second question
is
about
unsupervised learning.
Are there
other
applications
like
this?
It's similar to
the classification of DNA.
In the past,
people collected
a lot of documents
to do unsupervised learning.
For example,
all novels
written in English
can be collected
to do unsupervised learning.
But
when doing
literature learning,
the authors
usually have
a literature background.
So, to achieve
a certain goal,
they need to
process the documents
like biologists.
For example,
if I want to classify
a group of
literary works
to do unsupervised learning,
I may not get
a good result
with raw data.
Because each author
has his own habits,
and each author
will become a group.
So, they need
some methods
to do unsupervised learning.
For example,
cutting out outliers
with high or low frequency.
I heard
that there is no research on this.
I'm curious
about the result
of compressive approach.
This is my second question.
Yes,
this is a very good question.
Sorry,
I talked too fast
about the details of the experiment.
We compare
traditional literature
with
classical literature.
In traditional literature,
there is a way to measure
which method is better.
The main problem is
that we can't
calculate
the distance
between two things
in the same way
as in classical literature.
So,
the main way
to measure
the distance
between two things
is to use
phylogeny
to compare
the distance
between two things.
To be more specific,
when we
study
the evolution of
proteins,
we use
mitochondrial genes.
For example,
in your second question,
there are many different methods.
In addition to
mitochondrial genes,
we use them
because
they were
completely decoded
earlier.
Therefore,
there are more documents.
Later,
when people's technology
develops,
they will use
different kinds of genes
or a series of
transmitted amino acids
to classify.
Here,
we mainly use
the most traditional
mitochondrial genes
to classify
and compare
with the research
on literature.
For example,
in the study
on mammals,
the later research
may be different
from the earlier research.
However,
here,
we use
mitochondrial DNA
to classify
and the results are
quite similar.
In fact,
SARS-CoV-2
has several stages.
Here,
we mainly use
the S-protein stage
to compare.
S-protein is
the shell of SARS or
coronavirus.
We know that
the virus shell
contains a lot of
kind of needle signals.
So,
SARS-CoV-2
will mutate
its shell
to pass through
the membrane of
another cell.
The reason why
we choose S-virus
is because
we can use
the same data
to compare
with the
literature on SARS.
In fact,
the S-protein
is not the only
variant of SARS.
There are many
other variants of SARS.
I guess
we can also use
the S-protein.
So,
the first question
is how to compare
SARS-CoV-2
with SARS-CoV-2.
The second question is
what is the difference
between SARS-CoV-2
and SARS-CoV-2
in other fields?
I know that
there are many
applications of
SARS-CoV-2
in other fields.
For example,
I know that
some people
apply the SARS-CoV-2
and
some people
apply the SARS-CoV-2.
Can we
describe
the similarities
in the literature
by saying
this group is
SARS-CoV-2
and this group is
SARS-CoV-2?
I know that
we can use
punctuation
to unify them.
Or we can
remove the blanks.
When we don't do these things at all,
we can classify the literature
in a good way.
In addition to the literature,
I guess
anything can be
generalized.
As long as it becomes 0101,
it can be compressed.
For example,
we have these
MIDI files.
When we classify them,
we will find that
this group of MIDI files
seems to be in the style of Bach.
This group of MIDI files
is in the style of Beethoven.
We can classify them.
I know that
in science,
for example,
in astronomy,
we classify
this group of light
with the change of time.
It probably has this change.
It may be a cycle
or it is a change
that goes up slowly.
And this group of astronomical objects
may be this picture.
Its light curve looks like this.
When we classify these series,
we will find that
this group of astronomical objects
are all supernovae.
They probably look like this.
This group of objects
is a supernova.
So I know that
it can be applied
in other fields.
Yes.
Thank you.
Are there any questions
from the audience?
I have a question.
Yes.
I want to ask
about the CTW
compression method.
It is successful in many areas.
Is there any situation
where it doesn't perform so well?
Do you know why?
Yes.
CTW
has a problem.
The algorithm
must know in advance
how long
the tree is.
For example,
our example is 3.
Theoretically,
if we
only count
the prefix to 3,
the pattern
of this data
must be
or 5 symbols
before.
If we only limit it to 3,
logically,
the algorithm will learn
the pattern.
This problem
has a specific
representation
in the data of the image.
We know that
the pixels on my left
should be
the same color.
Not only on my left,
but also on my top and bottom
should be the same color.
But if we change
the pattern
row by row,
we will find that
the upper and lower pixels
should be the same color.
The pattern
depends on
the width,
for example,
600x400.
It depends on 400 pixels
and 400 symbols
to learn the pattern.
I guess
this is the main reason.
The reason
we can't
extend
the depth of the tree
is because
to build a tree,
the memory
needs
the growth of the
pixel type.
The growth of the pixel type
is hard to
calculate
because the
number of pixels
is small.
I guess this is
the biggest problem.
I see.
Hello,
Fumi.
A-Pad.
I want to ask
a question
that is not
related to
randomness.
For example,
if we put a
bunch of data
into the tree,
will it
get any result?
For randomness,
we will find
that
if we
follow
the formula,
we will find
that the kx
is equal to
itself.
We are trying to
find the probability.
If we
follow the formula,
it will be equal to itself.
The data
is the only
data in the world.
I guess
the result is
something special.
I see.
Yes, intuitively.
Does anyone
have other questions?
Can I ask
one more question?
Sure.
You mentioned
that CTW cannot
be compressed.
In fact,
there are a lot of
compressed files.
Compressed files
are designed to
look up and down.
Can CTW
be designed to
look up and left?
Something like that.
And then build the tree.
That's it.
I guess
it is possible.
For example,
if the tree
has only two branches,
I guess
the tree can have
more branches.
I know
a lot of papers
are working on
this kind of improvement.
I guess
some people's improvement is
that CTW
is designed to
look up and down.
Some papers
are
designed to
skip some syntax.
Skip some syntax.
Hello?
I wasn't talking just now.
I'm afraid my internet is broken.
Okay.
I'd like to ask
if there are any other questions.
Okay.
If you haven't joined
TaiwaR,
please use the link in the chat.
Thank you again for
the wonderful speech.
Thank you.
If you have any questions,
you can discuss in private.
You can also
use the link in the chat.
Thank you.
See you next time.
Bye.