Hello everyone, welcome to today's Taiwan Radar Talk.
I am today's host, Shi-An Hong.
I am currently a post-doctoral student at the University of Michigan.
Today's speaker is Dr. Hwang Chung-Ren.
He is currently a post-doctoral student at the University of Tokyo, Japan,
and the Japan Research Institute for Human Materials and Materials.
His research focuses on the application of crystalline materials and their structural characteristics.
This is his main interest.
It seems like you are about to get your Ph.D.
Yes, I am a bit busy recently.
Today's topic is the metallurgy of quasicrystals.
So let's welcome Dr. Chung-Ren to give us a speech.
Before we start, please remember to turn on your microphones so that the speaker can hear you.
So let's give him a round of applause and let the speaker begin.
Please remember to turn on your microphones.
If we have any questions, can we interrupt you, Dr. Chung-Ren?
Sure, no problem.
I didn't prepare a good presentation today, so there might be some points that are not clear.
You are welcome to interrupt.
Okay, let's give Dr. Chung-Ren the microphone.
Okay, first of all, thank you for the introduction.
We have known each other for about a year, right?
I think so. I've been a bit lazy lately.
So what I'm going to talk about today is the metallurgy of quasicrystals.
As you all know, in 2011, Dr. Dan Shepman discovered that he had won the Nobel Prize for violating the principles of traditional quasicrystals.
So today I'm going to focus on the difference between quasicrystals and ordinary crystals.
And why they are called the third state of solid matter.
First of all, this is the first picture.
As you can see, it's actually not a flower.
When Dr. Dan Shepman discovered quasicrystals, he was in a quickly solidified aluminum alloy.
But this thing was actually a big challenge at the time.
Because this thing is not a stable quasicrystal.
So this flower is what happens when it produces quasicrystals.
At a low temperature, it will suck out a second phase.
At that time, Linus Pauling also challenged Dr. Dan Shepman because of this.
He said that there is no quasicrystals in this world, only Poseidon.
So you can see that this is actually the original picture.
This is a picture taken by a general SEM.
And then it became like this after mapping.
The reason why quasicrystals attract me so much is because it is really beautiful.
As I just said, when Dan Shepman discovered quasicrystals, he was actually an Italian.
He found that quasicrystals were actually discovered when he was doing sabbatical at NIST.
In fact, he was very excited when he found this thing.
Why does this kind of quasicrystals appear symmetrically?
You can see this picture below.
Someone used the aluminum-palladium-manganese alloy to make a STM picture of potential energy.
We can see that it is really beautiful.
And then you can see this pentagonal thing everywhere.
This is when Dan Shepman was analyzing the structure of quasicrystals.
He is a very famous thermo-mechanical master at NIST Sabbatical and John Kahn.
But in fact, why can quasicrystals win the Nobel Prize?
I really want to commemorate my boss.
Unfortunately, he did not participate in our quasicrystals seminar this year because he was not in good health.
He died instantly when he was on a business trip to Taiwan.
Mr. Kahn's two most important contributions to quasicrystals were that he synthesized a thermo-mechanical stable quasicrystals in 1987.
The synthesis of this thing led to the continued development of quasicrystals that have been around for more than 30 years.
His second most important contribution was that he successfully produced a two-dimensional crystallography in 2000.
What is so special about this two-dimensional crystallography?
It can replace a lot of atoms in real space.
This allows them to better observe the structure of the crystallography and make a more detailed real-space analysis.
We actually have a workshop in Japan for quasicrystals.
Everyone calls Mr. Kahn a god's hand.
Because many stable quasicrystals have been synthesized by Mr. Kahn according to the rules of his doctoral class.
Mr. Kahn's most important contribution was that he successfully analyzed 12 kinds of quasicrystals related to the 5-axis 20-dimensional system when he was an assistant professor in Northeast Asia.
This is my outline today. I will briefly introduce what quasicrystals are and what quasicrystals are.
How are quasicrystals discovered? Why are they quasicrystals? How do we define quasicrystals?
Why can quasicrystals be stable? I will also briefly introduce the nature and current development of quasicrystals.
I hope that today's speech will allow more people to join the research field of quasicrystals.
I think it's beautiful, but many people may find it useless.
First, let's talk about quasicrystals.
Actually, I want to skip this part.
Because I think everyone should have a basic common sense that quasicrystals must comply with Bragg's Law in quantum mechanics.
But when we look at the electromagnetic microscope, there are two electromagnetic microscopes here.
I'm so bad at talking like this.
Anyway, in the case of 200kV, the lambda is very, very small.
Then we can see...
Oh, it's broken.
Then we usually have an input wave here when we are radiating.
It can be an electromagnetic wave, an X-ray, a medium-wave, a sum-house, anything.
When we are radiating, it must be in line with the number of lambda.
This is a very basic high school physics.
But when we are radiating with an electromagnetic microscope, the input angle is very, very small.
And at this time, it will produce a sphere.
Because the radius of this sphere is very, very large, it can be regarded as a plane.
So we can project its wave onto a plane.
When its lambda value is less than d, sinθ can be close to c.
This is the low value when we are at the bottom.
This is a wave length of electromagnetic when we are at 200kV.
This sinθ angle can be regarded as a distance from this origin to any location.
According to this relationship, we call this thing the Euclidean space.
Why is it called the Euclidean space?
It is a completely opposite space.
If the radius of these two planes is d, there will be a d star here.
If we define this position, this big d is equal to 2π.
There is a big d star here, which is in this position.
It's obviously longer, but it's a little bit farther away.
That's about it.
Next is the difference between crystal and non-crystal.
This should be the non-crystalline matter at the beginning of the definition.
The crystal is obvious.
When we know its position, it has some very standard surfaces.
But in the crystal, we see that it is completely messy.
It may have an average spread.
When we sum up the definition of Bragg,
we can get a crystal with a very obvious spot.
We call it the color spot.
But in the case of amorphous,
in the case of non-crystalline,
it may show some ring-shaped spots.
Next is,
if we list different atoms,
what should it look like in the Euclidean space?
We see that no matter where it is cut,
its position is the same width.
When we surround it,
we may find that the arrangement of the crystal
is very similar to that of the electron-surrounding group.
But here,
the above picture is a square.
You may not see any difference here.
It's all very obvious,
almost the same geometric shape.
But at the bottom,
you will see that
this is the arrangement of the crystal.
Here, it's a hexagonal arrangement like this.
But here, it turns 90 degrees.
This is related to how to build a Euclidean space.
I don't want to talk about it today.
The most important thing is to talk about
the periodicity of the arrangement of atoms.
We can find a unit
that can exist at the same time
in its electron-surrounding group.
If we want to meet this condition,
there are two more important features.
I forgot this thing.
Anyway, we will find the same geometric shape
in the Euclidean space as in the Euclidean space.
In the crystal,
when we know an atom,
as I just mentioned,
when we know where an atom is,
we can infinitely deduce
where the atom exists.
Because the periodicity of each place is the same.
I drew a line.
I can continue to extend it.
Of course, these constraints
and geometric shapes are imagined
to make it easier for us to identify some things.
Then it will slowly extend, extend, extend, extend.
In other words,
knowing a place,
we can know all the places.
We can describe
all the positions in the actual space.
The second is
that if we only use one unit
to fill it,
like this place is square,
it must meet this.
I turned 90 degrees,
turned 90 degrees,
it's still the same.
It may not be so clear here,
so I open another one.
Can you see it?
OK? OK.
Suppose we turn now
to this triple axis.
This is a cubic structure.
This is a L1-2 face structure.
Then we turn it to the triple axis.
We find that the light color is at the bottom,
and the dark color is at the top.
Can you tell?
This color is yellow.
No, light blue.
Lighter.
Then we follow it at this time.
This should be the triple axis.
So when we turn 60 degrees,
we will find
pay attention to this position.
It will be light, dark, light, dark, light.
When we turn 120 degrees,
it will be the same color moving.
This is a symmetrical relationship.
It's the same when we turn to the double axis.
If we turn to the double axis,
we use 120 degrees to turn it.
It's a mess.
Use 90 degrees to turn it.
It will run back and forth.
This is a state
that we have to find that it meets
the whole symmetrical axis.
So if we can only use
one shape to arrange,
we can see
that if we only consider
each unit is square,
or we consider a rectangle,
these things can be arranged
into quadruple and quadruple.
If we consider a triangle,
you will find that
we can easily use one shape
or a hexagon like this,
we can fill the whole surface.
What about octagon?
Octagon is very similar to quadruple.
I forgot to draw here today.
If we try to connect here,
if we try to connect here,
this position,
when the line comes out,
the line comes out,
its point is different.
Its point is different.
It doesn't meet the so-called
symmetrical axis.
What about pentagon?
When the pentagon comes out,
it can't be arranged
with a single shape.
If you are sensitive to shape,
you may find that
in this place,
the so-called naked places,
we can actually
split it into other shapes
to describe it.
I will continue to talk about it later.
That is to say,
in traditional polygons,
in various different polygons,
it seems to have many possibilities,
but in fact,
in addition to the general
two-axis, three-axis, four-axis, six-axis,
we can't just use one unit
to fill the whole plane.
So the so-called 5, 8, 10, 12
seems to be symmetrical,
but in fact,
it does not meet
the conventional theorem of
traditional algebra.
So,
to sum up,
according to the theory of the line of the pentagon,
the so-called conventional pentagon
must have one-dimensional symmetry.
That is,
we know the position of an element,
we can easily use
a multiplication method
to describe the position of all elements.
That is to say,
if its D space is 1,
I may be 1D, 2D,
3D, 4D, 5D, 6D,
and so on,
to find the corresponding element.
What is the second one?
It only accepts
the rotation operation of 1, 2, 3, 4, 6 layers.
Okay,
then we come to
the concatenation.
In fact, the concatenation
was not proposed
by Dan Shetman
at the beginning.
The concatenation word
is just a
long and interesting thing.
However,
he just said
why there is a
completely
against
the concatenation of a
symmetrical existence.
As I just mentioned,
if we can
find a
congruent graph
in the
electromagnetic graph,
then we can
connect in the actual space
to find a
arrangement
with the same
geometry.
But this thing
doesn't seem to be able to
completely fill
the whole plane.
So isn't it
congruent?
But as we just mentioned,
if
the color spots are shown,
when these color spots are shown,
it seems to have to be congruent.
So what the hell happened?
Okay,
this is a
electromagnetic graph
made by Dan Shetman.
We use
a very traditional
algebraic way
to make it
according to its rotation angle
to find all of its
symmetrical
directions.
And finally,
it's possible that
this is
a form of
icosahedron.
This thing
has six pentagons,
ten triangles,
and fifteen
quadrangles.
The position of the quadrangles
is in this position.
We can see
the zero position.
The triangle is
obviously the
position of this triangle.
This is the position
corresponding to
this triangle.
The pentagon is
the vertical
from this point.
Here are five
triangles
combined into this position.
Okay,
this thing is
very interesting.
So,
in fact,
in 1976,
Penrose,
a very famous
teacher,
was thinking
how to use
the smallest set
to lay out
all the plane
or how we
can arrange
all the polynomials
into a plane.
This is
one of the
patterns of
Penrose.
In fact,
Penrose patterns
have many
different forms.
Finally,
this thing
is the most
similar to
quadrangles.
McKay
also contributed
to quadrangles
very well.
He was doing this
at the beginning.
This is using
Fourier transform
to transform
from
one of
Penrose patterns
to another.
If we go back
and see,
it's a little bit
similar to this pattern.
In fact,
they knew each other
at that time.
But
they didn't know
each other.
So,
no one could
use a reasonable
mathematical model
to describe
what exactly
Penrose's
tiling looks like.
Is this
the way
to arrange the atoms?
Then,
later,
at that time,
Paul Steinhardt
was
actually
he kept
claiming that
he thought
it was the tiling he found.
In fact,
the term tiling
was also defined by him.
At that time,
he was also inspired
by Penrose patterns.
There has always been a theory.
But
until 1984,
there was no
material coming out,
so he didn't publish it.
In fact,
when he published
this article,
it was only a little bit
later than
Dan Shatman.
As soon as he published it,
he sorted out
this article
and threw it out.
Pay attention to
the pattern
of this pattern
in this article.
This is from Dan Shatman.
This is a pattern
in the fast-acting
aluminum alloy
in Dan Shatman's
article.
This is very similar.
Later,
Steinhardt
did not publish
this article
because
he thought
it was the tiling
he found.
This is
the pattern
in the
fast-acting
aluminum alloy.
The pattern
is very similar
to the pattern
in the
fast-acting
aluminum alloy.
Dan Shatman
did several
experiments on this
and tried to observe
these things.
He did a very
beautiful paper
on the mathematical
model and
this thing.
From the theoretical
calculation
to the actual
arrangement,
he did
everything
he could
in the
experiment.
But
at that time,
there was no way
to see
where the
original value
was.
So at that time,
most people
used the
mathematical model
to see
what the
actual situation
was.
But this article
is really
beautiful.
If you are
interested in
this kind of
calculation,
you can
take a look.
But
before that,
although
many people
made very
difficult
calculations
and
very good
electromagnetic
graph,
many people
did not
believe in
this thing.
Why?
Because
people thought
they could
not see
the real
thing.
Because
at that time,
it was
only possible
to make
this kind
of crystal
structure
in a
fast
way.
Like
you can
rotate 36 degrees
to form
a small
group
and then
it becomes
a state
that is
symmetrical.
Can you
see
that
one
on my
side?
Can you see
it?
Can you
see
it?
Can you
see
it?
Can you
see
it?
Can you
see
it?
Let me
mate it.
I don't think it's too clear.
Let's see.
Mating.
Lag.
You see
it.
Ah!
This is
if we look
at this place
.
This is
this is a direction
of the pentagon.
It is
along this thing
like this.
Hey.
Up five, down five.
There is a positive five here.
There is a negative five here.
Then you
I'm sorry to let you imagine.
Just look at it from here.
You will see
there are ten things.
At that time, he felt
that he was
like this.
A rotating
twin like this.
Um.
OK.
Then at that time
until 1987
Professor Tsai An-pong
he was
uh
he was originally
made of non-metallic alloy
and then made a picture
Oh!
It seems
to look like gold.
He started
to think it was interesting
because he thought it was beautiful.
Why
can you make so many spots?
He saw a lot of points
and he was very happy.
Then he started to make gold.
Then at the beginning
in fact, this alloy
this thing
he was very early
very early
in the 1930s
there was already an image.
He was in a very quiet area.
He did not
he wrote a question mark.
Then he
just tried it at that time.
Just go around there
and do it
do it
Then he thought
what is it?
Just
Oh!
It's done.
Then heat treatment
He started to do
quench
is to do
fast cooling
and then
do the general
alloy
and then
found that after the heat treatment
Hey!
He is the same thing.
So
at that time
it was called
heat-stable
heat-stable crystal.
Then we can see
here
he has a very beautiful
Dodecahedron
a shape
This is
one of them
Dodecahedron
Then here we will see
Generally in the index
When quenching
We will use
six indexes
This is what I just said
Because quenching itself
has no cycle
So we have to
project it to the end
Do
After using two indexes to describe it
Go again
Write it out
So here we are
We will know
The definition of quenching
There will be a few conditions
It must have
Traditional quenching
non-existent
The first is
The rotation property of the crystal
Then the second is
It must be
Have a
Quasi-periodic
Ordered
This thing
Because it has a
Very sharp
Diffraction spots
Then we describe
When this quenching
We will at least
Need to use
Three axis of導之空間
To describe it
That
The more interesting thing is
In fact, if
Uh
For
The golden ratio is very interesting
This tau is the golden ratio
Actually
Uh
The pentagon
This
When it cuts
We go to find it
Some nodes
Go to both sides
When doing a subtraction
Will get a golden ratio
This is the thing
That's why
Quenching
Will be like this in the array
That
I seem to have a structure later
I'll talk about it in detail
Why is it like this
Okay, everyone will be curious
Quenching in actual space
What will it be like
In fact
If we look at it from the second dimension
Its array is a
Just
This penrose
This penrose pattern
This is in
Uh
The two-dimensional state in space
What about the three-dimensional state
That's what I just said
In fact, we use it more often
Is this
Icosahedron
In fact, so far
The development of quenching
There are already various
Different clusters
Various different forms
Even
Actually
Linus Pauling
Although the quenching
Is not a
The real
Material state
But its drive also tells
Uh
Another thing that comes out
Is the so-called
Quenching crystal
Everyone take a look
Can you see it?
Take a look
These two things we can see
Top
Let me compare the top ball
This one
Yes yes yes
The big red cluster
These two things
It's actually the same thing
But
If you are in the case of quenching
It will be like this
Keep connecting
That may be less connected here
Only three and a half units are connected here
When you keep extending
You will see different situations
If you are interested, you can come and visit
We are
On the platform
Then the other one is
Pauling
At that time
To quench
He just thinks
This is actually just a kind of
Uh
In the cubic
A double crystal structure
So your
Uh
Quenching crystal
It will
Uh
It may exist in a certain position in its corner
Then continue to combine
Combine
That
This is actually
We later
It is a kind of
Uh
We call 110 quenching crystal
Or 11 quenching crystal
Or
Uh
32 quenching
21 quenching crystal
Or 32 quenching crystal
That
This is in the case of high-dimensional projection
His
Long-edged brush and short-edged brush
A
Convex state
Then there is
Uh
It is
A
Convex
Then there is another state
Is
Purely 10-axis symmetrical
This thing
We call
Uh
Delta
Um
Decagonal type
That
This thing will appear in
Also appear in the aluminum convex crystal
That
This thing
It will have a very strong
Impression
Because
We are from this
If our
It will actually have a lot of
Phonon drag
With some
Radiation
Because it has more
Phason
Ah
Phason can actually be understood as
Uh
A defect in the convex
Or dislocation
The part
Then it is here
It is a very symmetrical
A symmetrical structure
Uh
So his side
Um
That kind of radiation
What
Isolation rate
Will be
In
Vertical
That
Very, very much
Um
That
This stable
Stable convex crystal in thermodynamics
Just for
Our
This
The crystal brings a new definition
Because in the past
What I just said
The definition of the so-called convex crystal is
Uh
In a solid
Its atoms are all
Have a
Stable
Line
And it can be
Flat
And it has a certain
Rotational properties
That
What is the new definition
Is
We can all
In
That
Causing the space to find
Any symmetry
When
We will call it
Is a kind of convex
That this
This is a new view of matter
Ok
Then I will now cut into
The part of the eye is
Uh
Stability of the convex crystal
In fact, this is
At the beginning
Mr. Tsai is doing this
He also said
He just wanted to say
Ah
Why can I make aluminum copper iron
Other
Is there any other way
Can
Uh
So
This
You can use this
It's all
Ah
The third is
Uh
One of the more important points is
His
Average electronic density
That
In the aluminum alkyl
We have one
More common E over A value
We call E over A value
Called 1.8
Then we are in our circle
We call magic number
Then the second stability factor is
We can start with this
Average electronic density
And our
Uh
From that
In the electromagnetic radiation space
See his
The amount of G
We can assess
Say his
That
Polycarbonate
With
Phenol
Uh, our phenol
In fact, it is a
Phenol
Because in fact, we can't really estimate it
We just use a static value
Go to him
To solve him
This thing can be seen
He is
It has something to do with his E over A
Then
We can get
Such a relationship
Then we see
Aluminum alkyl
Is
This is the aluminum alkyl with the transition element
Aluminum alkyl
He will follow this relationship
But in this aluminum alkyl of Cd
His
E over A is actually equal to 2
That
This thing
He later
We have observed that he has a
SPD track
The effect of miscellaneous
Will cause in that
Near the aluminum alkyl
A widening of the track area
Then this
So currently actually
Aluminum alkyl
In this so-called E over A
There is no one
Better
Or more complete
Regulation
Then this is also one of our
Challenge now
That
But this is a
More controversial
That is
Generally we know that aluminum is
Three elements
He wears three
The same normal
He has an electrolyte
Wear one
Then why is the iron
About negative 2.66
This is
In the previous
Calculated one
A
The probability of splitting the track
A probability
Iron in this system
He must be in
Negative 2.66
That this is also a
Very interesting place
That is
How do we use this
Full element
Go
Um
Use elements of aluminum alkyl
Go
Adjust some of his features
Is he
DS
Or his
Some of the effects of track miscellaneous
That time we went to iron
Rutanium
Then
Oslim
Sit down like this
Find out
They are in the same group
Under the circumstances
Their outermost
Electrolyte state is the same
These can be done
Very stable nodule
Then
I made a mistake
Ah
I put the wrong side
This TMG
This line
I'm sorry
That
It's about 1.8 here
In this part
More people are doing
Is
Developing towards hot metal
Or
They go
Want to see
Inside a cluster
If he lacks a
Will it lead him to the whole
That
Metal sword
The price
Ah
A transfer phenomenon
At present
They use that
That
The way of man-made engineering
In
Make this prediction
What is the element of half the number
Um
Some of you
Composite
What is that
Composition
What
Ah
This is actually
His
It's all 100
This is the original ratio
Ah
Then we will follow this original ratio
Let's say
Ah
This aluminum is
With three additives
Multiply by 3
Then this is multiplied by 1
That 12 is multiplied by 2.66
Then finally it is a total of 100
Divide by 100
We can calculate this
A value of 1 over a
Um
That this is currently a
A more stable nodule
A list
If you are interested
You can take a look
Hey
Maybe it's related to your
Uh
You can take it and do it
There are some
In the structure
Some more
Different or special
Some things
That is actually the easiest now
Applied by the business
Maybe it's this
Aluminum and the transition element
This part
Because it also contains more
The price is cheaper
So
More suitable for mass production
That if it is for
Say
Do basic research
Will be more
If you are interested
Isn't this guess
Teacher Cai
Ah
That this
You can go from here
He will
Can make
More likely to make
Two-dimensional nodules
This thing
Uh
On the combination of nodules
The concept is a little different
Then I will introduce a little bit
Nodule
It's in
It's obviously made of metal
That
Oh, yeah, from the picture just now
You can know
Most nodules are made of metal
That
Let's take a look at it
In
Different
Its hardness and its
Uh
Um
Electrode
When it's low temperature
Uh
In fact
Nodule
It is a
Negative temperature factor
It's a negative temperature factor
So you see
That
Iron, aluminum, copper
When it's high temperature, the electrons rise
It's obviously a combination of aluminum and copper and iron
When it's high temperature
It's a drop
thing
So
In this place
It's on the electromagnetic field
It's closer to the semiconductor
That
It's not that it's all semiconductors
We usually call it metal
That
This thing
Its attraction
At the moment at high temperature
Some people will target its phasing
That's what I was talking about
That
In the so-called full space
Some interactions
The state
They think it's like this
There is no better explanation yet
Interpretation
That
If you look at it from the age
It's got a microscope
That
Only electrons can see that
Microscope
It may block some of the effects
Or let it jump
Um
In terms of hardness
Uh
This is the general
Steel is iron
Iron alloy
Then
Their hardness is very, very low
It's very, very hard when it's combined
Ah
If you look at it from the defect
You can say that the whole body
It's all defects
It's very, very hard
But on the contrary
It's also very, very crisp
That
This is currently more likely
And possible applications
In fact, there are quite a few
That
Because like I said
It's very crisp
So usually we use the way of the body
To do
Uh
Some crystal products
Or by coating
Because we want to make the body smaller
We can ignore it
Some
Some harder temperament
That
Like
It's more interesting in this part of the blowing
Many people will use this crystal
Ah
He went to do that
Get rid of the aluminum in it
That's like copper, iron
Copper itself for
Uh, carbon dioxide
It has the characteristic of blowing
Its copper just happens to be on some specific
Edge
In the corner of the crystal
At this time it will
Because it has some special
Uh
Double crystal structure
So it has a better impact on the blowing
I think this part is more interesting
That there is another part
In that
Metal
The part of the metal compound
Now the metal compound
For the crystal
There are mainly two directions
One is mainly
Put the crystal into
Uh
Aluminum alloy
Lala
Boil it up
The other way is to use
Aluminum alloy
After making the aluminum alloy
Then suck it out again
And then at high temperature
Rebound
Uh
A high intensity effect
That crystal
Because the surface of the body is very low
So it has a very low friction factor
Then
Also very brittle
Then I will show you later
Uh, some of the current
Crystal products
Ah, there seems to be a film
Ah
Okay, how did the crystal come out?
I just talked so much
How did the crystal come out?
This is a
More traditional
The production of a crystal
Ah
A metal
The relationship of manufacturing
That generally uses
Uh
Metal steam or metal liquid
If you start with metal liquid
Very reasonable
Uh
Very reasonable to understand
Is like
Casting ah
Aluminum alloy ah
These methods
If we cool down quickly
Will get this
Aluminum alloy
Then we cool down slowly
Will get the crystal
In fact, thermodynamics
Stable crystal
In fact, when you cool down slowly
It can also get a crystal
Then I just talked about
Extracted from aluminum alloy
Stable crystal
It's easy to get out of the treasure box
Ah, the alloy of the treasure box
Then use the method of actual effect
Let it suck it out
This is
From
Uh
A part of the crystal to the crystal
That
From the non-crystal
There is also this thing
There will also be this thing
That is, Mr. Tsai
Why did you start
A reason for making a stable crystal
That
Like
At present, someone will also use
That
PVD
PVD way to make a stable crystal
But
Uh
In terms of the control of the treasure
Or some conditions
In fact, to make a very high quality
Uh
Stable crystal
Will be
It's still a big challenge
That
This is what I just summarized
Uh
The so-called processes just now
In fact, this side is
We are more common
Some
Some methods of manufacturing stable crystals
Including
Just the general
Traditional casting
There is also that
High-speed cooling
Uh
Beat
The cooling speed per second
It's probably more than 3000 degrees
Very fast
Then this
This is also a very fast
Cooling
Uh
The latter two are relatively rare
I just
Another one is to use mechanical alloy
Is to put a bunch of elements
Put it together
And then it's high energy
It's like doing high-speed alloy
Someone does it
And then like that
This is the general
Uh
PVD
PVD like this
But there is a very important point
Is that
If it is not processed
It's actually very rare
Very high quality
Unless it is
Certain
Some very specific stable crystals
Can get a better way
Uh
A better one
Structure
That
Finally, let me introduce
We just mentioned so much
Uh
The crystal will become
The crystal can run out of the stable crystal
Uh
This is a thin one
And then
Can we
Let the crystal
Directly become a stable crystal
This is our recent
A
A new discovery is that we can
Indeed
In a special way
Uh
Make the crystal
Gradually become a stable crystal
Then we get a composite material
Then
Here is a
The one I just saw
One of the shapes of the dodecahedron
And here
The composition may not be very good
Just happened to take a pretty picture
Ah
Next is
The one I just mentioned
Tolstien Hart
He is
He thinks
Nobel Prize should be given to him
Why didn't you give it to him
He also wrote a letter to protest
Anyway
He is still very passionate
He is
In that
In a meteorite pit in Russia
Found the so-called natural dodecahedron
This is a picture of a high-density
You can see a very beautiful one
A pattern of a dodecahedron
Uh
I just talked to Sol
He still says
We were 45
45 years ago
You can find the dodecahedron
It must be in the universe
Tell us what the message is
Is it
Dodecahedron is a
A very common state in the universe
But if you finish watching
Just introduced the dodecahedron
How did it come out
You should be able to understand
Actually in the process of falling like this in the meteorite pit
It's a little bit like
After melting quickly
Quickly cool
That is, it happens to be very likely
A substance that will produce this
I think it's pretty reasonable
But
I also think he's right
If we can
Understand whether the dodecahedron is in the universe
Very stable
Maybe for the future
Application is a great help
That may be in recent years
In the dodecahedron
A part that everyone pays more attention to
Mainly in that
In the dodecahedron
Some of its special physical properties
That includes
I have found this
Eterbium in that
Quasi-crystal
Uh, in the dodecahedron
That one
Uh
Additive ratio
Then another one is
Magnetic connection
Its magnetic and
It's also found in the dodecahedron
And then there's the so-called
The superconductive
It's usually oxidized dodecahedron
Superconductive
Then we are in a very low temperature
Someone found a simple dodecahedron
You can also find this thing
Is that in the future we can also start
The so-called
In their research
Use that so-called
The dodecahedron and the dodecahedron
Comparison together
That is a
Periodic
A comparison of periodicity and periodicity
Found this thing
That's the last one
I just talked about
A product of our dodecahedron
I'm not sure if I can see it
That's the bottom
This white part
This is what we do
A product of dodecahedron
That we didn't add any oil
I didn't add anything
Just put the eggs on top
Roasted
Look at the top
This
The part of the oil has been covered
But the bottom is completely dry
So we are doing dodecahedron now
I hope
There's no way to make a high-quality dodecahedron
And then maybe in the near future
Replace the dodecahedron as soon as possible
In the entire national market
Even in the shipping market
This is what I did this year
At the European conference
We discussed a few questions
We are not yet
To discuss these things in depth
But if you are interested in joining the dodecahedron in the future
You can continue to do this
Includes
How to make a larger
A better dodecahedron feed
And then do a partial
Electronic communication characteristics
Exploration
Because dodecahedron itself is a
A lot of things
The other is
This is the part that I didn't follow
Is it
Phenomenon or non-phenomenon
There's really a phenomenon
So we've been talking about
Dodecahedron surface
But he really has
This is
Because we use a lot of dodecahedron models
This thing is a
In
Mathematics may be more
Challenging thing
The last one is me
I always feel like
We should go find a
New dodecahedron
Because now the dodecahedron is actually
Relatively low melting point
Since it's so good at high temperature
We can't find
A higher temperature dodecahedron
This thing may be for the future
Whether it's on the aircraft
Or on the ship
Will be better help
Then I will make a concluding remark
Is
Yes, dodecahedron is the third kind of solid matter
Then its thermal stability
In fact, compared to the general
High entropy
Alloy or
Amorphous
It has better thermal stability
That
Dodecahedron
It can be found in many nuclei
And even in the universe
That
The following is
In fact, the most important thing is this
How are we going to
From dodecahedron
We can understand
What is the definition of a new structure
Are we going to define it in three dimensions
Or in
Causing space to define it
Or we can define it in six dimensions
This is a very worthwhile question
That's the last
Thank you for listening
Then we can take a look
The picture on the right
I chose
The picture on the left is not very good
I picked a little bit
In fact, it looks like
It looks like a dodecahedron
But if we put
After all the lines are drawn
Will find
Hey
This thing is what we just saw
That penrose pattern
Is exactly the same
So sometimes our eyes
Can't see the real situation
But electrons can be our eyes
Let us see
Hey
What does the real atom look like
That
Today
It's almost time
Thank you all
If you have any questions
Welcome to discuss
Applause
Ok
Hello everyone
Thank you
Hey
OK
Is there anything you want to ask
Any questions
For those of you
who want to know
Hi
Just
Hello
Well
I want to know
Is that you
How do you define
Its three-dimensional structure
How do you define its
Defects
For example
Dislocation
Or stacking fault
Or grain boundary
Oh
This thing
Is
In fact, we are now
I don't know how to discuss
Yes
But
This is the general whole
A situation of actual atomic array
In fact
It is difficult for us to find a complete cut
You see, it seems to be flat here
It seems to be flat
But it's broken
So we usually define
When it comes to accuracy
Let's look at that defect
Look at this
This two fat
One is fat
That rhombohedron
And the other one is flatter
That
Hey
Can I use the performance
No
Usually we
When it comes to the defect of accuracy
It's that the origin is always moving
It's always changing
But it's always
The form of stable accuracy
No matter how it alternates
It's always
A form of stable accuracy
I'll give you an example of a cluster
It's like
It's got a very strong polarity
It's a very strong polarity
How do we define dislocation
It's actually a bit difficult
But we can use it
If
Hey
Today
One of the fatter things
This
This thing
It's a relatively big thing
If it suddenly
These two yellow ones go this way
This green one goes this way
We will only define such a defect
We call it a defect of phasing
So if it's dislocation or
Uh
Stack and fold
We don't have a clear definition
Hello
Sorry, can I ask a question now?
But the first one seems to be
Hi, welcome
Okay, so my question is actually very simple
You just said
Most of the clusters are in
Intermetallic
Found in the middle
That's the reason
Is there a possibility that
Uh, for example, in oxidized materials
Or other substances
Found in clusters
Oh
In fact, this is also a very interesting topic
In fact, in 2008
A lot of people in that
In the clusters
Found the so-called seven symmetries
With some special
Inexplicable symmetries
Do you have this?
Yes
But is it really so intermediate?
We can go and see
This pentagonal intermediate array
It can be so full
It's because it happens to be able to use two
Symmetry to put it up
In fact, this
This pentagonal intermediate array
It has many ways to fight
If you say
Is it possible to happen in ceramics?
But you have to think about ceramics
It has a stronger
So it might be more
Forced to be in a certain
In an agglomerated position
So I'm not sure if it's going to form
That kind of framework
But if it's a high-density
It's true that someone found out
I don't seem to have answered the question
Thank you
Did I answer your question?
Sorry
No problem
I'm just curious about the reason
Because it's yours
Is the size of your atom the same?
Or is it related to the metal ring itself?
You mean why?
I don't quite understand what you mean
You can talk about it again
That's what you just said
Your answer is more biased
Just because your
The size of the atom must be biased
So it can fill this
That's the edge
Is that what you mean?
No, because your atom is too big
Just keep pushing it
Push, push, push
It doesn't necessarily push
What you want
But most importantly
If the atom is too big
It can't fit in at all
We're going to put it in today
In a specific space
We
In general, we have to say
Because like here
It has an atom
Atomic Size Factor
The size of the atom
If this thing
When the radius is too big
It's a little bit
It's going to form a very large force field
This force field may make it
The whole structure will collapse
I see
Like there's a fat guy
There's a fat guy going to the cinema
The people next to him were knocked over
He just didn't feel well
I see
So how did he get sick?
It's kind of like the law of physics
Oh
I see
Then you have a
What is the density of the atom
Does this have anything to do with 1 and 3?
Or
1 and 3 themselves
There is no absolute relationship
Because this is actually the third point
We got it from the experiment
A
Experienced
If you look here
It's true that we're in this kind of
Green
In the three-dimensional solution
It will meet this condition
But if you are in the second dimension
Or some
In the case of fractured orbit
Or in
It will have some
It's a separate experience
But you have to meet three at the same time
What's the second one?
The second one is that the density can't be too big
Otherwise, the atomic property will be too strong
How to quantify too much
It's really a good question
Um
In fact, we usually say
Don't exceed
Density of 20% or more
1 and 3 is also the density
No, the second one is the density
The second one is the density
I thought it was some kind of formula
In fact, I also want to say
We've been discussing it before
Right right right
Hi
Oh, I see someone
I'm here
Um
Decagonal products are less
Is there any reason?
Because I only listed it today
Um
Stable
Oxide crystal
So decagonal is less
Because most of the decagonal
It's more like
Metastable
It's a stable state
That
In fact, we have been discussing in the past few years
One of the more important points is that
We know how to make stable accuracy
But we still don't know
Why is the accuracy stable?
What is its origin?
We still can't design
A better experiment to verify
Why is the accuracy stable?
Sorry to go back to that question
You said that you still can't determine
Why is the accuracy stable?
From this point, there is no way to do
DFT or quantum chemistry
Go from the structure of the generation
Or the electrical structure to understand
Why is it stable?
Oh, I think this question is good
But usually we have to do DFT
Or when you do this
We have a very important thing
Your wave function must have periodicity
but
Yes, yes, periodic boundary conditions
Yes, yes, yes, yes
But the accuracy, it has a periodicity
This accurate periodicity
It's a magnetic fraction
So you can't do DFT
But we are also in the current stage
There are some advanced ways to do
We put the accuracy
In a specific cubic structure
It will be very similar
It has a very similar symmetry
You can do it in this case
But so why is it actually a magnetic fraction
It's easier to find than accuracy
A lot of people have been like this recently
Yes
Then if it's because like DFT
Periodic boundary conditions are very important
What if it's a quantum chemistry method?
For example, Gaussian
Or it doesn't need periodic boundary conditions
It is directly
It's not using pseudo-potential
It is directly using the real atomic orbital
Then calculate some of its
It's the electromagnetic wave function
It does not consider the periodic brogue wave
Oh
Because of this part
I didn't follow it so carefully
We can discuss it in private later
Okay, thank you
I think this is quite interesting
But I remember someone did it
But it seems like I'm not sure
I might have to go back and look at the information
Because I remember someone did it
Can I ask a question?
Please say
I want to ask
I remember
Linus Pauling
He had a big argument before
That is to say
This quantum or an approximate
Will all produce a similar electromagnetic brogue wave
Yes
How do you actually distinguish these two things?
Ta-da
In fact, the main thing is
When the quantum is in the inner circle
There must be
For example, if we see a pentagon here
There will be a negative pentagon inside
But we see a pentagon here
But it's a cubic structure inside
This is the main thing we can see on the diffraction pattern
Quasi-crystal and approximate difference
This is because now
If we can make better feed
Or better electronic microscope resolution
I can see it
After all, like the earlier
If you take this pattern
You will find that you can see it
But its spots are not so beautiful
What did he just ask you?
Quasi-crystal and approximate
Linus Pauling
He argued at that time
If I put some specific pentagons in the cubic
Then make a double gold
I will get the same 10-fold diffraction pattern
But the two structures
The folding is different
But its periodic is different
So they must have different symmetry
Or you can just look at this diffraction pattern
Yes, so these two pictures show
It's the difference on the diffraction pattern
Should be able to distinguish
Yes, yes, yes
Now it's easier to distinguish
It was harder at that time
And the most important thing is
There is no stable crystalline at that time
So it will be an argument point
Oh, there is another follow-up question
That is, has anyone tried to do it under low temperature
Similar structural analysis
Because in this case
You are less affected by the phaseon
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes
This is someone doing this thing
Because I'm not following the low temperature side
Just look at its physics
So if you are interested in this
We can also discuss it in person
I didn't follow so much
But I'm sure someone is doing this part
OK, thank you
I want to know about its electricity
That's why you just said
This thing is actually more like a semiconductor
Yes
Then why is it
It looks like metal added
Why does it become a semiconductor
Generally, metal is added casually
It won't be like this if you participate in a magazine
Yes
This is also why crystalline is so interesting
Usually we can have a few points to think about
Because it's actually a bit complicated
The first one is that it contains
Posi-periodicity
Will it cause its electronic
Frequency
Let's say we consider today
In micro-spatial motion
Its posi-periodicity
It will make its wave function
There will be a lot of destructive interference
It can't transmit very well
But at high temperature
Is it because of this energy
Because of pseudo-gap C
There is a second point
This point is one of them
The second point I think is more common
Because pseudo-gap itself
It's an energy state that can only be seen by electrons
In fact, when I was doing X-ray recently
Because the resolution is not enough
You have actually found some special phenomena recently
But there is no way to see the pseudo-gap
Did it actually change
When this temperature rises
This temperature dependence will make
Electrons jump through this pseudo-gap
So it makes the oscillation better
This is also one of the main reasons
Wait a minute, can you explain
Why is there a pseudo-gap in this thing?
How did the pseudo-gap come
Is this the same thing as the pseudo-gap of superconductivity?
Sorry, let me think about it again
The word pseudo-gap
It's usually a word that appears in high-temperature superconductors
You just found a gap
So you call it pseudo-gap
You can say that
But in fact, this pseudo-gap
The most important thing is that
When we stabilize the crystallized compound
The so-called
Because we went to see the bandgap structure
In fact, it is
What is the combination?
I forgot
Anyway, its gap
The most important thing is that it has something to do with Fermi sphere
We found that the pseudo-gap
Do you think it has anything to do with high-temperature superconductivity?
I don't think it doesn't matter
Because we are now
Because I'm not doing this specifically
But the author will usually mention
I only know the reason for the pseudo-gap
But I don't know
Does it have anything to do with the pseudo-gap of high-temperature superconductivity?
Your pseudo-gap refers to
The pseudo-gap in the bandgap structure
OK
In its structure
There is a gap in the bandstructure
Yes, there is a low energy point
OK
So it actually
Anyway, you said
Anyway, the result of the calculation
There is a gap
So it looks like
It's a bit like a semiconductor
How big is the gap?
Because each is not the same
And in fact, the pseudo-gap of high-temperature superconductivity cannot be calculated
What I just said
The so-called pseudo-gap is all from the near-term solution
How much is the near-term result?
I didn't remember this
I'll send you the data later
This is quite interesting
Sorry, I just talked about
You talked about the pseudo-gap
This should be able to use
Apex to measure
You can measure the bandstructure
I really want to measure it, but I have no chance
Because
As you said, the pseudo-gap cannot be calculated
In fact, the best way is to use Apex
But
I think if there is a chance to make better data
It is indeed a point to try
Because I recently found
The pn-reverse phenomenon in the pseudo-gap
This phenomenon may be with
Because its structure has not changed at all
But its
Eoverlay has not changed
But it has a very obvious pn-transition
So
If you can use Apex, please tell me
No, no way
I really want to do it
Because I think
Because there is no way to do it directly
Apex usually can only measure
Measure the valence band, right?
You can tell me
To be honest
I have never done Apex
I saw a lot of
Data is
Bandstructure
Apex seems to be able to measure
I'm not very sure
Because I don't have it
Usually need to move
I see
So you can see this thing
Yes
But
In fact, it is not very accurate
Because of the problem of feed processing
If you don't do it very well
Just for reference
I see
Can this material be used for doping?
This question is really good
Because we thought about it before
Try to do doping
But you know
This thing is already three-dimensional
If you do doping
The structure may be broken, it will be too complicated
Someone wanted to say before
This structure looks like a lot of defects
Is it possible to put cyan in it?
It's not really doping
But it's a new material
But after entering, you will find that its structure will collapse
So now we are less
Really do doping
Is it really doping?
Is also a problem
Because you can't make it go very smoothly
There is too much difference in each place
Then the second point is
If we talk about doping
We will only use substitution at most
Maybe substitution
We assume to add a substitution
A certain element in the cluster
To change its nature
There is no way to do
Really do doping
Because the structure may collapse
Is its doping
More like BCS?
Or is it exotic?
Its doping is actually super bad
Just have that phenomenon
It just found this phenomenon
There is no breakthrough in the weather
Just because it doesn't
Interfere with anything
But I saw this phenomenon
But the temperature is super low
So there is no application value
But it's interesting to study
Why don't we use anything
It has this feature
Most of the metal
Will have BCS doping
Yes, that's right
So this thing
I'm curious about this thing
Because it's metal
So it may be a BCS doping
You said it looks like ceramic
Like semiconductor
It may not be normal doping
Yes, it's not normal
It's not normal
They don't particularly study
Does it match BCS?
They are just mentioning a phenomenon
Because if it can be mentioned
It should not only be communication
So they just test it
Because like I just said
Our final challenge
How to make a better test
For a smaller area
Because what is it
It's really a little bit difficult
Because it's not that easy to control
You have to make a big one
A lot of phasing
A lot of defects
It's easy, but you have to do it
It's a little bit difficult
Do you have any other questions?
Okay, let's thank Zong
For bringing us a wonderful speech
And a great Q&A
Thank you
If you have any questions
If you are really interested in BCS
Because my speech is not very good
If you are interested
You can come back to me
I think
It's a little bit difficult
Because it's a little bit difficult
If you are interested
You can come back to me
I think it makes me think a lot of questions
I hope everyone
If you are interested
You can join this field
You see so many people in front
Cosmology
Actually it's ok
I will turn off the recording now