Hello, everyone. Welcome to today's Chara Talk.
Today, we are honored to invite Dr. Wu Jiazhen,
who is currently at Winstead University,
to share his research with us.
Today's topic is
MicroBioEcology of Activated Carbon Block
Point-of-Use Drinking Water Filters.
There are several special terms here,
which he will introduce to us later.
Before we get started,
I would like to introduce Jiazhen's background.
Jiazhen is an Environmental Microbiologist.
He got his Ph.D. from the University of Michigan.
Before he got his Ph.D.,
he studied Public Health at NTU,
and his Master's Degree was Environmental Engineering.
Before that, he did research on tap water in Taiwan.
So it makes sense that he started to focus on this direction.
He is currently at the Institute of Environmental Health Science
at Winstead University, Detroit, Michigan.
The main topic he will share with us today is his research.
In addition to his research,
of course, I believe that research is also one of your interests.
Jiazhen is also a pianist and a hiker.
Let's give him a round of applause.
Thank you for the introduction.
Jiazhen just gave a very complete introduction.
When I was at NTU,
I did research on microorganisms.
When I entered the Institute of Environmental Engineering,
I studied microorganisms in tap water.
Because of these past experiences,
I started to read my Ph.D. at the University of Michigan in 2013.
I read a lot of books about the microorganisms in tap water.
I will use Chinese and English to introduce my Ph.D. thesis.
The topic I want to talk about today is
the study of biochemical and biological microorganisms in tap water.
The so-called activating carbon block point-of-view
drinking water filter is actually a very common filter
that can be seen in the market.
This filter uses carbon dioxide to remove some chemicals.
In fact, from my past research on microorganisms in water
or in tap water,
I gradually discovered that
the changes in microorganisms in tap water
and the chemical reaction between microorganisms and tap water
are very complicated and change a lot.
Since my background is not in the field of environmental engineering,
I will briefly introduce tap water.
Tap water enters the water supply system
through the water supply system.
This diagram shows that
in the water supply system,
there are various reactions in the process of
delivering tap water to various households
or buildings in large water pipes.
In fact, there are a variety of reactions
or various interactions in the process of delivering tap water.
For example, the bacteria may live in the liquid.
There may be competition between different bacteria,
and they may grow more or less.
At the same time,
they may also be inactivated by the disinfectant in the tap water.
So there will be growth and death.
There may also be absorption of
some particles in the tap water,
or absorption on the tap water pipe,
and then form a biofilm.
This biofilm may also be re-returned to the tap water
through the purification of the tap water.
In fact, in our household,
if you open your chest,
the water that flows out of the chest,
and the other bacteria,
there is a lot of water in the tap water.
There may be more than 10,000 to more than 10 million bacteria per liter.
There is a word in our topic just now,
Point of Use.
It is simply the meaning of the word.
The so-called point of use.
We don't just look at the water quality after the tap water comes out.
We are looking at the water quality
through the tap water system.
It may be one day, it may be several days,
or it may be a few hours.
At this time,
when it comes to our household,
our company, and our school,
after opening the tap,
that place is called the point of use.
This is the concentration when it first comes out.
There are tens of thousands of bacteria per liter.
It sounds terrible,
but in fact, most of the bacteria are not necessarily harmful to the human body.
Traditionally,
the so-called bacteria that are more concerned
are related to intestinal or feces pollution.
Like intestinal fungus,
like intestinal fungus,
like Shigella,
which is the most traditionally recognized bacteria
for decades.
So there are rules to regulate the concentration
of more than one CFU per liter.
The other type of opportunistic pathogen
of the disease
may not necessarily harm everyone.
Opportunistic means
the population that is more sensitive.
For example, the elderly,
the people with chronic diseases,
or people who are addicted to alcohol.
For people like this,
if they encounter such a pathogen,
they may get sick.
These pathogens include
lupus,
leukemia,
and mycobacteria.
Because of the advancement of technology,
we slowly found that they can still be detected in the water.
These pathogens may be
more than one CFU
or ten CFU
per liter,
in epidemic areas.
...
for disinfectants
and chemicals.
...
Third,
bacteria resistant bacteria.
...
and
....
...