Hello, everyone. Welcome to the last Tera Talk this year.
We are honored to have Dr. He Shuai-Pu at Princeton University.
He is going to talk about Large Millimeter Volumetric Array for CMB Observation.
Let me introduce Dr. He first.
He got his Ph.D. in Physics at Princeton in 2017.
He is now working as a postdoc at Princeton.
His main focus is Experimental Cosmology.
His main work is Detector and Readout Development.
He has participated in several flagship CMB experiments.
Such as ABS-Atacama BMO Search, ACT-POL, Advanced ACT, Simons Observatory, and CMBS-POL.
Before I start, I'd like to say that
our goal is to share our progress with Taiwanese students around the world.
We hope to increase the opportunities for cooperation and exchange.
If you are interested in participating in our project,
we hope you can sign up for our talk next year.
You can sign up for our talk on our Facebook page.
Without further ado, let's welcome Dr. He.
Hello, everyone.
I'm going to talk about Large Millimeter Volumetric Array for CMB Observation.
The topics I'm going to cover are mainly two experiments.
You can see ACT-POL on the right side of the page.
There are some collaborations.
They are mainly founded by NSF and Chile Conocet.
The other one is Simons Observatory.
You can see that the collaboration has become larger.
It's mainly founded by Simons Foundation.
Okay, let's move on.
There is a beautiful starry sky with our telescope.
You may be familiar with this picture.
On the left is the starting point, Big Ben.
Of course, there is an argument.
There is no Big Ben.
As time goes by, it becomes where we are now.
I mainly study cosmic background radiation, CMB.
It is the first light we can see.
It originated about 400,000 years ago.
Or 380,000 years ago.
What can we learn from this study?
When we look at CMB,
the first thing we look at is its intensity.
This is Planck's intensity map.
There are hot spots and cold spots.
It is a full sky observation.
In addition to intensity,
there is a weak signal, polarization.
It is mainly from electrons and photons.
There is Thomson scattering,
which causes linear polarization.
When we observe this polarization directly,
you will see a cross mark on the left.
There is a 45-degree cross mark on the right.
This is called Q and U.
This is the map we can observe most directly.
This means that we have observed polarization.
We usually convert it into E mode and B mode.
You can see that E mode has symmetry and B mode does not.
This is the map we can observe most directly.
We usually convert it into E mode and B mode.
You can see that the temperature of the power spectrum is 10³µKv².
It is actually a very weak signal.
But the signal of polarization is smaller,
about one tenth or less.
So we can measure the temperature very precisely.
But when you want to measure polarization,
you need a more sensitive instrument to detect it more accurately.
This is a theory model.
And this is the data obtained from recent experiments.
This is a map of the universe.
If we look at the CMB directly,
we can know how old the universe is.
Although we know that the universe is more than 400,000 years old,
we want to know more precisely.
The shape of the universe and its structural formation.
But we also have more secondary anisotropy to understand.
Because light passes through so many things in the middle and reaches our eyes.
We can know some secondary effects from it.
For example, gravitational lensing or SZ effect.
We can also know that there are some stars or galaxies in the middle of the universe.
So why is it difficult to measure CMB?
As I said earlier,
just look at the temperature and anisotropy,
the temperature signal is about 10 to the 3 microKelvin squared.
You can see that there is a Cyan line here.
But in between CMB and our eyes,
there are many other things in the middle.
The main components of CMB are dust and synchrotron.
The red band and the green line.
When you see the polarization signal is weaker,
you can see that the impact of dust and synchrotron is deeper.
This means that we need a way to decompose the different components.
To understand the character of dust and synchrotron at different frequencies.
Then you can remove it to get pure CMB.
Therefore, when we develop instruments,
we need to have different frequency bands.
The more cover, the more frequency band.
The more cover, the more sky.
In this way, we can remove these extra signals to get pure CMB.
From the beginning,
of course, there are so many dust and synchrotron in the outer space.
You don't want to interfere with your observations from other sources.
So, the cleanest way is to transfer everything to outer space.
There is COBE satellite, WMAP, and Planck.
You can see that the sensitivity is getting higher and higher.
But sending everything to outer space is a very expensive thing.
Another way is to build a telescope on the earth.
But that requires a longer period of time.
And your instrument needs to be more sensitive.
So, there are two main places where we build telescopes to observe CMB.
One is Atacama Desert, Chile.
The other is Antarctica.
In Atacama Desert and Chile,
there are ACT, Polar Bear, and Klaus.
They are mainly focused on CMB observation.
In Antarctica, there are mainly SPT, BICEP, and Keck Array.
So, in the five ground-based experiments we just talked about,
the technology we use is called Transition Edge Sensor, or TES.
TES is a barometer.
When the photon comes in,
the barometer has a weak thermal path to the T bath.
the temperature of TES will rise.
TES is a very sharp transition.
When the temperature of TES rises,
the resistance of TES also rises.
The dual power of TES will decrease.
TES is in a stable state.
How do you read the signal of TES?
We use a coupler to an inductor.
The inductor is coupled to the screen to amplify the signal.
This is a simple way to read the signal.
What does TES look like?
This is a typical TES design.
You can see that TES is in the middle.
The temperature of TES depends on its material.
We have just mentioned the two cases.
We want to maintain a certain temperature,
we want to maintain a certain temperature,.
The primary weak point of TES material is its thinness of silicon nitride leg.
This is why we call it TES Island,
because it is made up of four supporting legs,
and the fabrication is very delicate.
C stands for Thermal Conductance or Thermal Conductivity,
and Platinum Gold.
C stands for Heat Capacity.
We control the amount of Platinum Gold in the TES Island
to determine its heat capacity.
The width of the TES is 280 microns,
and the length is twice that,
560 or 600 microns.
It is a very tiny component.
We use TES to measure the CMB signal.
The main CMB observations are measured by TES.
Since 2009,
we have been building these experiments.
As time goes by,
there are more and more detectors on the telescope.
This is because our TES technology has reached a limit.
This means that the current TES is already in good condition.
How do you enhance the sensitivity of the telescope?
The more detectors on the telescope, the better.
We have used up to 3,000 or 3,000,000 detectors.
This is a map of Atacama Desert, Chile.
It is a very desolate area.
The sky is very clean,
and there is little dust.
We live in a 2,500-meter-high desert.
The act, polar bear, and Klaus are on top of the mountain.
The act is on the left,
the polar bear is on the top, and Klaus is on the bottom.
This mountain is about 5,200 meters high.
This is our act telescope.
The main component of this telescope is that we have a ground screen outside,
which is about 12 meters high.
We want to reduce silo or pick up from the ground.
We built a ground screen outside our telescope.
We have a primary mirror and a secondary mirror.
The primary mirror is about 6 meters in diameter.
The secondary mirror is about 2 meters in diameter.
The resolution of the entire telescope is 1.4 seconds.
The receiver is at the tip of the arrow.
The field of view is 1 degree.
We use a dilution refrigerator,
which allows continuous operation of 100 millikelvin,
which is very important for sensitive detector functionality.
This is one of the tubes.
There are three tubes in the receiver.
From 300K, which is room temperature,
all the way down to 100 millikelvin.
My main job is to focus on the array module of 100 millikelvin.
The picture shown above is the act camera of different generations.
What did we put in the act?
In 2013, the camera in the act was called M-Vac.
I was involved in the act since 2013.
The central frequency of the detector is 150 GHz,
or 90 to 150 GHz.
These are all polarimeters,
which can observe two polarizations at the same time.
M-Vac can only observe intensity.
Since the beginning of PA3,
we can observe two polarizations at the same time.
We can observe two polarizations at the same time.
We can use the same pixel to double the detector count.
Since 2016, we have upgraded to Advanced Act.
Interactions
Synchronous Congistion
Yama is the logo of AQPoL
Miss Katya is the logo of AQPoL
Miss Katya is a cute mouse
I have a question
I think your logo is super cute
My question is
If you have different bands
You can observe them
You can keep averaging
And the noise will get lower and lower
If you have multi-band
Can you keep reducing the noise
And increase the sensitivity?
Or will it be limited by dust?
I think it's limited by technology
That's what CMBS4 wants to do
We want to put more than
What I'm showing now
More than two-digit
Detector count
They want to observe for five to ten years
The length to be observed
Has something to do with your funding source
We haven't reached that limit yet
So at least
From this chart
Let's start from mid-2016
Because the Advanced AQPoL
At least it's not cut off
It's extended to the outside
So at least in the years after 2020
As long as you continue to observe
The sensitivity can keep going down
Upward
That's what it means
Thank you
But in 2021
It's supposed to be decommissioned
Now
Let's move on to
The left side of the chart
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6
There's a little square
That's our so-called pixel
What's the component in this pixel?
You can see the TS I just showed
The left side is called yts and xts
They are measured in different polarizations
How does it know
What is the accepted polarization
We use the one in the middle called
Orthomode transducer
Like a arrow
Light hits
And they go up and down
And one go to the left and right direction
And they go to the left and right direction
Then there are some on-trip filters
And  sink to TS
And sink to TS
The bottoms are the channel on-trip filter
You can separate by 2 pixel
Let 2 ff
The number left 4tx
The number left 2tx
The number left 150 Ghz
The number left 90 GHz
The number left 90 Ghz
The number left Google Sachan
The numbers on the right
The numbers on the left
Size is different
I have a question
Usually your bandwidth is how many?
I think it's
False 20
Yes, so it's the bandwidth
We will design the bandwidth
Don't go to 0.2 line or 0.2 line
That's what we want to avoid
We can control our bandwidth
2.30 is on a 0.2 line
Yes, but we didn't avoid it
Our design is 2.20
So the bandwidth is super narrow
20 is 1.50 or 1.90
They might have more error
So on-chip filter
I will talk about it later
On-chip filter is important
Because it controls the most precise bandwidth
Like our VHORN
And some optics
To control other bands
So after the optical design
We will make sure it doesn't cross
The side region we don't want
Here you can see
The right one
The OMT size is only 1.3
And the left one
The OMT size is 2mm
So you might think
What does it matter
Well
OMT is a film
A film
The circle part
Is transparent
It's a very thin film
And this film
Is like a metal
On the film
So you need to control
The film
On 1.3mm
You can imagine
How hard it is
To grow the film
On a 6-inch wafer
Or 4-inch wafer
It's not easy
The left one
Is the first generation
Pixel
And the second generation
On the wafer
Our wafer
Is 3-inch
75mm
Now we move the technique
To 6-inch
Wafer
We want to
Closely packed
Pixels on the wafer
So you can see
Instead of a square packed
Square design
We have a
Rhombus
Pixel design
So we can put more
Detectors on it
And
The left one
3-inch
Wafer
We can only put
244 channels
But the 150mm
6-inch wafer
We can read out
More than 2000 channels
One channel is one TES
So you can see
Double the size
We want to
Push the sensitivity
So we have to
Put more detectors
On the fixed focal plane
This is what I just said
Detectors
In addition to on-chip filter
The OMT
OMT is
Under the right image
OMT couple detector
It couple to
Feehorn
It's a cone-shaped
It can control
Your light path
From the top
To the OMT
You don't want
The light go through the OMT
You want to
Make best use of
The light source
So you have to put a
Facture
Like a cover
To make sure
The light will not
Go through the OMT
And make extra noise
To your signal
All of these
Are made out of
Silicon
The horn array
We take
500 microns
Wafers
And we use
Three
Three edges
To make a circle
And
Each layer
Has a circle size
We call it silicon horn array
The main reason
To use silicon
Is to make a thermal match
With the detector wafer
We want to make sure
There won't be any thermal
Contraction issue
And make the detector break
So
This picture is
To show
How to read out
With detector array
And
It's not
About reading out
But
About
How cumbersome
The assembly is
So we have a detector wafer
And we put it
On a base
And we need to
Do a lot of
Wire bond
To make a connection
To
Silicon component
So we can connect it
To
100mC stage
So we need to
Push it layer by layer
To 1k, 4k, 40k
And
Eventually to room temperature
So
It usually
Takes about
A year
To make an array
On the left
Is the array
And on the right
Is the advanced array
And
For Ack
The average time
To make an array
Is about a year
Usually
You will
Start the next
Array assembly
And
At the same time
You can put it
On the base
So
In summary
We have
PA1 and PA2
1000 TS detector
PA3 has 1000 TS detector
But
PA1 and
PA2 have 1000 TS detector
PA3 has 1000 TS detector
And
For EO
The more you know
The more time you spend
And the more you learn
So it's bad at first
But it gets better
50%, 70%, 80%
And
For
Advanced Ack
PA4
HF array
HF array is
220GHz and
150GHz
And
HF array
Has 2000 TS
And
MF array
Has 90GHz and
150GHz
And
MF array
Has 1700 TS
And
It's
Improved
For EO
The same result
For PA4
70%
For PA6
90%
And
For EO
For TS
Sensitivity
If the array
Is only 50%
You have to
Observe
The device
Or
Put the same array
To get the same sensitivity
So we want to
Achieve 100% EO
But for CMB
Camera
This is
The best
I haven't heard of
95%
I have a question
What is
The main problem
For EO
Wirebond?
Mainly for wirebond
And
Readout
Readout component
It's hard to fabricate
It needs
Many steps
So usually
For EO
And
For readout
It's a problem
You can see
Interconnect
Flexible cables
And
Usually
Wirebond
To
Detector
Or readout
The failure
Contribute
Thank you
So
Your squid
Is made by NIST?
Our squid is made by NIST
I see, thank you
I haven't mentioned
Readout
It's another in our talk
But our app
Mainly uses TDM
Time domain multiplexing
I haven't mentioned multiplexing
But
With so many detectors
It's impossible to readout
So we need to do multiplexing
You need to group
Some detectors
And readout
To
Speed up
Data speed
The last
LF array
Will be released in January
This array
Is challenging
You can see
The same wave
But not many pixels
And each
OMT
Let me see
Every OMT
Is much bigger
Compared with
MF and HF
About 1 cm
As i said
The transparent part
Is membrane
This membrane
Distress
And metal
It's a
Difficult technology
So
It's challenging
In R&D
But we made it
And
Initial testing result
Is reasonable
We will release it in January
Hopefully
I see some light
The next one
Is Simon's Observatory
I was talking about
Act
Our new plan
Is to build
A new observatory
Next to Act
This observatory
Is mainly
Composed by
On the right
We call it
Large Aperture Telescope
L-A-T
It's a 6m cross-dragon
Telescope
L-A-T
Let us see
Small-scale signal
Act is sensitive
To the power spectrum
L is greater than 200
To
Above
The power spectrum
So
Usually
You want to build it bigger and bigger
So
And
It's limited by technology
So
This telescope
Is designed
13 optics tubes
But
We will only put
7 tubes
And each tube
Will have 3
6-inch detector
Array
So
The receiver
Will have 21 detector array
Compare to Act
Act has 3, L has 21
This
Observatory
Is a giant
2.8m
In length
The whole
Platform
Has
About 15m
Height
Another small aperture telescope
We call it S-A-T
Sensitive to L below 200
Like
Bicep
Polar bear array
Mainly
Focusing on
Primordial BMO
The mirror is
0.5m
And
Baseline is
3 S-A-T
Each S-A-T
Can have 7 array
So
About 21
Detector
With funding
4 S-A-T
28 detector
So
The total
Detector count
We have
2 technologies
And we will
Deploy
The first
NIST
MF
UHF
And
220 and 270 GHz
So
NIST will focus on
These two
Detector type
Another
Berkeley
They will
Do another array
Their
Central frequency sensitive to
30 to 40 GHz
This is another technology
The same
TS technology
In total
It will have
60,000 TS
Barometer
When we deploy
60,000 TS
Barometer
So
Magnitude
More than
At
So
This is
Summary
Assignment of
Plan
Supposedly
We want to deploy S-A-T
Next year
Sometime
Then
Deploy
The rest
S-A-T
And
Populate
S-A-T optics
So
This is
My role in assignment
Mainly
Scheduling
Besides
The detector and readout
Plan
So
Today's talk
Ends here
Thank you
Yama
Any questions?
Let's
Turn on the mic
So the speaker can hear
Applause
Thank you
For the wonderful talk
Then
Before Q&A
I want to say
This is so cute
There is no such cute logo in the lab
And this
OK
Any questions?
I have a question
That
The new array
It is
Work independently
Interferometry
It is
Uh
In
Our array does not work independently
They are
Scanned at the same time
Yes
Will you do
Interferometry
There are three telescopes
Coordinate observation
But
They can cross-check
We will cross-check
You
If they see the same sky
Then
We will cross-check
Make sure
No systematics
We build
So many small
At the same time
Not a bigger
Or something
You can
Remove the systematics
Which is really big
Telescope
So
There is no way to make it
Like a
Baseline
There should be two baselines
At least you can
I don't know if resolution is important to you
I think you can use some techniques
But I think
Idea should be different from interferometry
OK
Every time
What time scale
Time
Uh
Every integration
How long
Very fast
I forgot
Anyway, it's fast
There may be no way to do this
You
You usually don't see time
Interference
There may be some interference
OK
Then
This picture
The reason why it's so far
And every thing has a show
Don't want to be affected by others
Because
If you hit this
Then hit another panel
Um
Then I ask another question
OK
Is
In the end
These things need
Because generally speaking
In traditional astronomical observation
You want better reflectivity
Make the mirror bigger
Then make the detector bigger
There is a bigger field of view
But I see you
Still a few meters
That is
What is the reason
Because now
It's easy to do
12 meters or even 20 meters
There should be no problem
That
Detector size can't follow
What is the reason
Go up
Bigger
We are
I want to be smaller
But the area
No, the area should be bigger
Should not say detector
The field of view is mainly
The size of the focal plane
The focal plane is the population
You have a focal plane
How many detectors are there
Yes
You should be talking about
The bigger the focal plane
How many inside
The bigger you do
The more detectors inside
Increase the field of view
But
We are mainly limited by
We just want to do this
2.8 meters long
Receiver
It's already big
Every stage is already big
Because we have to cool down
To 100 millikelvin
Cryogenic technology is very strong
Then you
We need a lot of pulse tube
And dilution fridge
Our pump
May need more
And just imagine
You this
300k
Window
At first we thought
Can we find such a big window
Or every individual
Optics tube
Have your own shape
That material
It's hard to control
Hard to go
And every stage
We have filters
Define the low pass band
That filter
Size is also a problem
I don't think
We are not
Current ground base
The biggest mirror is SPT
They did 10 meters
Yes
But consider
All kinds of technology
And efficiency
The final decision is
Choose 6 meters
Then
Any questions?
I have two questions
The first question is
Your wafer
Back short
You said it's silicon
Is it pure silicon?
Or you have etched
My question is
Back short
The top
It's a flat surface
It's a
Pure silicon
There is a
Back short cavity
You can see
It's magnified
It has a groove
It has
Feature
It covers
TS
It won't see
Light leak
From other TS
It covers TS
It has
Some design
Determine
We can
Obtain all light
But won't let TS
Contaminated
No cross talk
I see
It's like
Blocking
We'll
Back it
We'll use
Sidecast
Ok
I see
So
It's purpose
You're a barometer
You want
Reflection
Collect energy
Is it?
Yes
I see
Ok
I have another question
I think
We should wait
So
Any other questions?
I have a question
Please
You
Observe data for CMB
And
Other groups
Do other science?
Yes
A big part
Analysis people
They do
Secondary
They often
With DS
Or
LST
Combine
Act
Some people
With Subaru
Many
Collaboration
Many useful data
Can be applied
Not only
Pure CMB
Act is doing well
All data
Released publicly
Everyone can
Reproduce
And
We welcome
And SO
To that direction
But no data
Do you want to collaborate?
This skill is different from mine
In a few years
Ok
Any other questions?
Time is up
Let's applaud
Thank you
For your wonderful speech
That's all
Thank you