Hello everyone, welcome to the 7th of March, this week's Tara Talk.
We are very honored to invite Dr. Jason Hong to tell us about his research.
The topic he is going to talk about today is Exploring Graphic Physics for Optical Sensing.
He said that this is his work when he was studying for his doctorate degree at UC Berkeley.
Let me introduce Dr. Jason Hong.
He graduated from the Department of Physics in Taiwan.
He later studied for his doctorate degree at UC Berkeley and Lawrence Berkeley National Lab.
After his doctorate degree, he is now working as a doctor in Michigan.
His field of expertise is super-fast light in physical and physical applications.
His main field of expertise is optical sensing, two-dimensional semiconductor exciton and cavity exciton polariton.
He is going to talk about his work in his doctorate degree, Graphic Optical Sensing.
We are going to give him a round of applause.
But we need to turn on the microphone so that our speakers can hear our applause.
Let's welcome Dr. Jason Hong to give us a speech.
Thank you, everyone.
I am going to focus on optical sensing in graphic physics.
I won't talk too much about super-fast light.
If you want to know more about super-fast light, you can go to my previous talk at TerraTalk.
Hello, everyone. I am Jason Hong.
This is today's outline.
First of all, I am going to talk about motivation.
I am going to tell you why we need to use graphene or, more broadly, two-dimensional materials to make optical sensors.
What are the advantages of using them?
What are the side effects of using them?
I am going to give you two examples of what I am doing.
One is to use graphene to observe electrochemistry.
Electrochemistry is the chemical reaction that occurs between a solid state and a liquid state.
We can use graphene as an optical sensor to observe these electrochemistry reactions.
This is because we developed a method called Diffrational Vibrational Spectroscopy.
We can see the signals of the small molecules on the graphene.
Another example is that we want to observe neurotransmitters on graphene.
Neurotransmitters produce electrical signals.
These electrical signals are the methods of transmitting information in our brain.
We put neurotransmitters on graphene and use graphene to observe these neurotransmitters.
This is because we developed a method called Waveguide-Based Imaging.
We will introduce this method in detail later.
Let's start with Motivation.
Before talking about Motivation, let's learn about what is a two-dimensional material.
Can you see the figure on the left?
Can you see my mouse?
Yes, I can see it.
This is graphite.
The structure of graphite is a layer of carbon atoms.
When a layer of graphite is separated, it is called graphene.
When a layer of graphite is rolled up, it is called carbon nanotube.
When a layer of graphite is rolled up, it is called fullerene.
Historically, we first discovered the structure of carbon nanotube.
We have never discovered the structure of graphene.
Of course, we know that graphene exists in the structure of graphite.
But we have never seen the existence of graphene alone.
What is the reason?
In order to calculate the properties of graphene, nanotube, and fullerene,
the theorists already know the properties of graphene.
The properties of electricity and light are already known.
Before the discovery of graphene, there was a theory.
When the two materials of graphene exist separately, they are thermodynamically unstable.
The thermodynamic effect causes ripples on the surface of the two materials.
In the end, the two materials will stick together and become a bunch of wrinkles.
Therefore, the previous theorists thought that the two materials alone could not exist.
In 2004, the two Nobel Prize winners, Andrew Gamm and Novoselov,
discovered that they could use a very simple method.
They put graphene on a tape and peeled it off layer by layer.
Finally, they put it on the silicon wafer.
They observed that a single layer of graphene could exist.
The main reason is that it is not an isolated 2D material.
It also has some ripples.
But because there is a substrate underneath,
you can put the two materials on the substrate to make them exist in the world.
At that time, many people were trying similar things.
There are many strange methods.
In the end, they found that the most effective way was to use tape.
In fact, there are many interesting stories.
We can share them later.
After the discovery of graphene,
we know that the two-dimensional material can exist alone on the substrate.
Later, a series of two-dimensional materials were developed.
Today, we focus on two-dimensional materials related to light.
In fact, there are many different materials,
such as two-dimensional superconductors or two-dimensional magnetic materials.
For light, the most important thing is the bandgap of this material.
You can see that there is no bandgap between graphene and molybdenum and molybdenum disulfide.
Graphene is a semi-metal,
and there is basically no bandgap.
Molybdenum and molybdenum disulfide are two-dimensional superconductors,
and there is a bandgap.
Graphene is an insulator,
and there is a very large bandgap.
We have all kinds of two-dimensional materials,
which can cover the entire spectrum of light.
In fact, in each spectrum,
in each region from microwave to visible,
people use two-dimensional materials to do something.
The interesting thing is that two-dimensional materials give you a lot of new degrees of freedom.
For example, you can change the number of layers,
you can change the doping of electrons in the two-dimensional material,
and usually the two-dimensional material is a hexagonal structure,
so it has two different values.
There are two minima on the bandstructure.
And these two-dimensional materials are very easy to integrate.
What we can do now is that
we can use some methods to pick up these two-dimensional materials,
and then we can stack them layer by layer to the place we want.
The important thing is that
you have to match the lattice.
For example, in the past, the structure was used to grow.
The way to grow is to make sure that
the lattice of the base and the thing you want to grow is the same.
Otherwise, you will have a lot of strain.
It will lead to a lot of constraints for these devices.
But the two-dimensional material does not have this problem.
You can put it wherever you want.
So we can do a lot of things that we couldn't do before.
These two-dimensional materials have a very strong effect on light.
We will see these effects later.
When you have this two-dimensional material toolbox,
and there are so many new degrees of freedom,
we can do a lot of different things.
For example, someone is studying how to use two-dimensional materials to make photodetectors and modulators.
There are LEDs and lasers for light.
There are also people doing nonlinear optics or single photon emission.
In short, I think this field is quite developed.
And there are a lot of new ideas that need to be tried.
And none of them have been tried.
So we don't know what will happen.
Why do I choose graphene as a light sensor?
What are the advantages of graphene sensors?
From the perspective of two-dimensional materials,
the first is that it has very good sensitivity.
The second advantage is that because it is a two-dimensional material,
we can easily change its electron doping.
From the perspective of optics,
when you want to make a sensor,
you need to pay attention to the light.
If you use light to detect or compare to other methods,
such as electromagnetic or other hardware,
the advantage of light is that it is non-invasive.
And you can penetrate the lower part.
So when the light hits your sample,
you will not cause damage to the sample.
And the more interesting thing is that light can do spectroscopy.
So you can get a lot of extra information.
And it can do imaging.
Sometimes it's what you really want.
For example, we want to do the structure of neural cells.
How do we imagine it?
This is a very important thing.
Sorry, can I interrupt you?
No problem.
OK, I want to ask.
Because we are also doing 2D material.
You said that it is easy to do doping on 2D.
But I want to know your strategy.
Because we encountered a big problem.
In fact, we found that it was not so simple.
Or doping is actually unstable.
The doping I'm talking about here is mainly electrical doping.
We add an electrode.
Then inject the electron directly with the method of electrolysis.
It's actually gate control.
Yes, it's gate control.
OK, so I misunderstood.
OK, thank you.
I think you want to talk about chemical doping.
Similar.
It should be called twin Fermi level.
Later, when I talk about examples.
You will see how we tune the Fermi level.
I think this degree of freedom is very important.
And it's a new degree of freedom.
So I think it's quite useful.
Graphene is the first two-dimensional material to be discovered.
It is a one-layer atomic layer.
Everyone says it has very good electrical, optical, chemical and mechanical properties.
Electrical has very high mobility.
Optical has a very strong light response.
Interestingly, a single layer of graphene can absorb 2% of light.
This is actually quite interesting.
You can imagine that a single layer of atomic layer can absorb 2% of light.
Another interesting thing is that you can directly see graphene with the naked eye.
This is also something that people may not have thought of before 2004.
Chemical properties.
Graphene is actually a structure of many hexagonal carbons.
So it has a very strong pi-pi reaction.
Many people use this pi-pi reaction to functionalize graphene.
Then you can do different things.
Mechanically, graphene has a very strong elasticity.
So it is very flexible.
I think the most important thing is that graphene is a single atomic layer.
So all the material is on its surface.
This material is very sensitive to its environment.
If there is a little movement outside, graphene will react.
I think this is the most important thing for the optical sensor.
I have a question.
Is there a selection rule for the interaction between graphene and light?
What is the interaction between graphene and light?
Is its mechanism a dipole?
Yes, it is a dipole.
Graphene is a Dirac cone structure.
You can imagine that it is a band-to-band interaction.
From the bottom valence band to the top conduction band.
Because the bottom is filled with electrons and the top is empty.
So this transition is allowed.
That transition is the 2% assumption I mentioned.
There are also intra-band transitions.
There is also acetone in higher energy.
This is the band structure of graphene.
Brinois zone is hexagonal.
There are Dirac cones at the edge of the Brinois zone.
Its energy and momentum dispersion are linear.
General semiconductors are parabolic.
If you calculate like this, the density of state is also linear.
You can see that the density of state is equal to the Fermi energy.
When the Fermi energy is zero, the density of state is very small.
What does it mean?
When there is some external influence,
which causes some doping in the graphene,
the Fermi energy will move very fast.
If it moves fast, it means that it is easy to change the optical transition.
This causes that the external influence of graphene is very large.
One of the effects is that the electrical energy is also very large.
What I show here is a field effect device.
Basically, graphene is on silicon dioxide.
Silicon dioxide is an insulator.
Silicon is a conductor.
Graphene and silicon form an electrolyte.
When you add a voltage, the graphene will be electrically doped.
The electrons will go to the graphene.
Or you can extract the electrons in the graphene.
The graph on the right shows that when you change the gate voltage,
that is, when you change the number of electrons in the graphene,
its resistance will increase and decrease.
This is a very important phenomenon of graphene.
The external voltage can change the resistance of graphene.
The change is very drastic.
Many people use this principle to make graphene's electrical sensor.
Another advantage of graphene is that it is flexible.
This means that it can be compatible with biological materials.
It can make all kinds of flexible devices.
It can also do chemical binding.
For example, you can add DNA or protein to it.
In this way, you will have some chemical selectivity.
Next, I will talk about two examples I made.
Let's start with the first example.
The first example is to use graphene to look at the chemistry near the electrode.
Do you have any other questions before I talk about it?
Okay, no.
Then I will continue.
There is a very important problem.
In fact, we often use graphene as an electrode in our daily life.
For example, your home's carbonate battery is also used as an electrode.
You know that the battery has to produce chemical reactions.
These chemical reactions are actually produced on these deliberate cross-sections.
How to understand these chemical processes is a very important thing.
We developed a method.
We use IR light to detect the molecules near the graphene.
This is the main mechanism of IR infrared vibrational spectroscopy.
These molecules have different vibration modes.
These vibration modes have different frequency.
When you put a IR light on these molecules,
it will excite these vibrations.
Then the IR light will be absorbed.
Because the IR light will only be absorbed at that frequency,
you can see what kind of vibration structure these molecules have.
Of course, different molecules also have different vibration structures.
So you can tell which molecule you are hitting now.
In fact, you can know the arrangement and appearance of these molecules in more detail.
For example, you can see that EXO's spectrum is light energy.
This is about three microns of light.
These peaks represent several different vibration modes.
There is a problem.
Because the chemical reactions on the surface are very rare.
Very few molecules are involved in the reaction.
Because usually only one or two layers are enough.
How to see this one or two-layer molecule structure is a big problem.
In general, the absorption of one-layer molecules is about 10 to the power of 3 to 10 to the power of 4.
You have to spend a lot of time to integrate the signal to see it.
We developed a method called diffractional spectroscopy.
In general, people do IR spectroscopy.
When you hit the light of the IR, you can see its reflection.
At this time, the electric field can be imagined as the electric field from the substrate.
The electric field from the substrate and the electric field from the molecule are quite close.
The difference in intensity is the electric field square.
When you expand this, you will find that it is two times one from the molecule divided by one from the substrate.
This is about 0.2%, which is about 10 to the power of 4.
The method we use is to make graphene into a periodic grating shape.
Only on the surface of the graphene will there be these molecules.
You can imagine that these things are grating, so they will produce one-layer reflection or two-layer reflection.
Of course, we only look at one-layer reflection.
Because the interface between the substrate and the solution is actually non-periodic,
it does not participate in the diffraction.
Only graphene and these molecules can participate in the diffraction.
At this time, the electric field from the substrate and the electric field from the molecule are close.
As mentioned earlier, the absorption of graphene is about 2%, which means that its electric field is about 1%.
The electric field from the substrate is about 10 to the power of 3.
When you do the calculation like this, you will find that it is the electric field from the molecule and the electric field from the graphene.
This thing is obviously much bigger, and now it becomes 20%.
In theory, it can suddenly increase the sensitivity by 100 times.
This thing is likely to allow you to detect single-layer molecules.
Can I ask a question?
Does the original reflection affect the mechanism just now?
Will it affect the signal that you finally gradient?
The original reflection will be at the angle of the reflection.
But at this time, we can choose to only look at the angle of the diffraction.
Oh, I see.
Then we look at this angle and there will be a very strong signal.
Thank you.
Then we make the graphene into the shape of the grating.
On the other side of the graphene, there is a platinum electrode with a voltage.
This is basically a battery structure.
When the light hits it, of course you will have a reflected signal.
But there will also be a diffraction signal from the periodic structure of the graphene.
We can basically use the method of light to select that we only need to look at the diffraction.
Basically, what we see is the intensity of the diffraction.
You don't have to look at the red line first, just look at the black line.
The dots are experimental.
You can see that the charge control point is basically the graphene at Fermi energy equals zero.
There will be some diffraction.
When you increase the electron in the graphene, the intensity of the diffraction will decrease.
When you add more, it will increase again.
The first thing we need to understand is how the diffraction occurs in the graphene.
We can understand that there are two kinds of transitions in the graphene.
One is the interband transition.
The graphene balance band is full of electrons.
The graphene conduction band has no electrons.
When the light comes in, it can go from an electron state to a state without electrons.
This is the transition allowed.
The light will be 2% absorption.
When you change your Fermi energy,
For example, the low-energy light has some electrons in its conduction band.
These electrons can't go up.
This transition is called forbidden.
It can't produce this transition.
These lights will be transmitted.
Basically, we can see that when the light is 2EF,
there will be an onset.
It can be absorbed above 2EF.
It can't be absorbed below 2EF.
When you change the Fermi energy,
the onset will be changed.
Another kind of absorption is called free carrier response.
It is called the interband transition.
The graphene electrons jump from the balance band to the balance band.
This is not possible in light theory.
Light has a very small momentum.
This is the scattering caused by the phonon or defect in the graphene.
When the free carrier increases,
when the doping increases,
it also increases.
Doping is a Drude behavior.
It is a Lorentzian type of behavior.
When you add these two things together,
you will find that we can calculate the optical conductivity of graphene.
The optical conductivity is basically equal to the diffraction intensity.
You can see the graph on the right.
For example, let's look at 0.13EV.
When the Fermi energy is 130mEV,
on the right is the interband transition.
There are some absorption here.
There is an onset here.
This is 2EF.
The area of 3000 is 2EF.
The upper part is the interband transition.
The lower part is blocked.
The bulging part is the interband transition.
When the EF increases,
the interband transition increases.
The onset of the interband transition is shifted to the right.
Our experiment is done at about 3000EV,
which is about 3.3uEV.
You can see that when the Fermi energy is very small,
it is mainly an interband transition.
This causes a large diffraction intensity at the CMP.
However, when the doping occurs,
the interband transition is gradually blocked.
The intensity starts to drop,
which is about 0.8 to 0.4.
Finally, when you continue to increase the doping,
the interband transition will start to participate in the absorption.
You will see a strong diffraction intensity.
We can understand the diffraction of graphene in this way.
Next, we will do a demonstration.
We put a molecule called Ctab.
It is a long-chain structure.
These long-chain structures like to run on the electrode of graphene.
We use IR spectroscopy to look at these Ctab molecules.
They are on the channel of diffraction.
We see that the spectrum is similar to this.
Basically, the diffraction is the interference of the electric field of graphene
and the electric field of the molecule.
The diffraction intensity you see is also like this.
It has a background.
This background is from graphene, which is about 0.85.
In addition, these peaks are from these molecules.
There are many CH2 and CH3 in this long-chain molecule.
We can compare these with the database.
We can know which vibration mode each peak represents.
For example, this peak may be symmetric CH2.
This peak may be anti-symmetric CH2.
This peak may be CH3 vibration.
This spectrum is taken in 0.1 seconds.
We can compare the contrast with the detection you do directly with reflection.
The contrast has increased by 50 times, which is about 100 times as we expected.
The density of this molecule is actually only 0.16 monolayer.
It is actually a very small density in graphene.
We can already see it.
This means that this method can enhance our sensitivity.
We can see 0.16 monolayer changes in 0.1 seconds.
Excuse me, can I ask?
Is the size of this molecule and the size of this graphene similar to what you show on the picture?
Or is it not different at all?
The size of the molecule?
What do you mean?
Do you mean the picture on the left?
Yes.
This picture is a memory map.
So the CTAP is much smaller than the graphene.
I'm just a little curious.
So what is the width of the graphene?
Because I didn't see it when you showed the picture.
I forgot.
It should be around 1 to 2 microns.
Because you can imagine that our light goes in three microns.
So if you want to separate the first order and the first order, it's probably in that order.
I see. Thank you.
Next, we will demonstrate that we can directly observe the chemical reaction on the graphene.
And it's timely.
Because we can see 0.16 monolayers in 0.1 seconds.
So you can actually see these reactions very quickly.
Basically, CTAP and graphene will produce a reaction when your gating is large enough.
They will produce a reaction like this.
CTAP will throw an electron and produce these reactions.
You can see the picture we just showed before the reaction.
After the reaction, the spectrum has changed.
And the first thing is that the background has changed.
The background means that the graphene was originally 0.85.
The intensity is about 0.85.
Now it's more than 2.
This means that the graphene has been doped.
And the Fermi energy of the graphene has changed.
So the intensity of the background has changed.
Another thing you can see is that you can see the anti-symmetric CH2 and CH3.
The anti-symmetric CH2 is still there.
But the CH3 peak is significantly redshifted.
This means that when these molecules are on the graphene,
Because the packing is tight, the vibration of CH3 is redshifted.
This means that the chemical reaction has occurred.
So we can see these small spectrum changes.
This is a demonstration.
We can observe these chemical reactions near the graphene in an in-situ way.
We can use the diffraction method.
In this experiment, we developed the diffraction spectroscopy method.
This method can improve the detection sensitivity and surface specificity.
We think that this method can be applied to electrolyte and electrode.
Because it is very easy to make the shape of the graphene into a grating.
So I think this is a very general method.
I think it can be used as a reference for those who do chemical engineering.
Next, I will talk about how to use graphene for biosensing.
The main thing we need to measure is bioelectricity.
It is the electrical signal of nerve cells or heart cells.
The electrical signal of nerve cells is a very hot topic.
Although it has been a long time, people do not know much about it.
We know how a single nerve cell transmits electrical signals.
But we do not know what the electrical signals mean on a network of nerve cells.
What does it mean that I am happy or sad?
How is the information stored and processed in the human brain?
This is actually a very interesting question.
But we do not have good tools to study this issue.
Currently, there are two ways to detect the action potential on the market.
The action potential is actually the electrical signal of these nerves.
One method is the multi-electrode array.
There are many small electrodes.
When the nerve cells are placed on the electrode,
the electrodes detect the electrical signals.
The other method is the voltage-sensitive array.
The voltage-sensitive array detects the electrical signals of the nerve cells.
But two things are important.
The first thing is that we do not want the nerve cells to have labels.
It is very troublesome to label the nerve cells one by one.
The advantage of the multi-electrode array is that it does not need to label.
But the trouble is that it is not parallel.
Parallel means that you have to connect a line to each electrode.
Then use an amplifier to enhance the electrical signal.
So you have to use an amplifier for each electrode.
This is very difficult and expensive.
The advantage of the multi-sensitive array is that it is very parallel.
Because you use light to detect the signal.
So you just take a camera and keep taking pictures.
This thing is very easy.
But the other thing is that you have to display each cell.
So you need to label the cell.
When you label, you will have a lot of problems.
Some voltage-sensitive arrays are toxic.
It will cause the nerve cells not to respond.
Some are said to cause abnormalities in the nerve cells.
Even though it is emitting a signal,
If it is an abnormal cell,
There is no point in studying it.
Labeling causes the reaction of the nerve cells to be different.
So we want to find a method that is both label-free and parallel.
The detection scheme we want is
Sensitivity is about 200 microvolts.
Spatial resolution is about 10 microns.
10 microns is the size of a nerve cell.
We want to have real-time detection.
The duration is about 1 millisecond.
We are a optical detector.
So we want to have total internal reflection.
Because we want to remove the scattering of nerve cells.
Then we start to consider.
The first thing to consider is whether your signal-to-noise is enough.
Can graphene detect electrical signals from nerve cells?
If we use the general method of transmission.
When you shine a light,
You can imagine that the electrode is a nerve cell.
When you add an electrical signal to the electrode,
Will the absorption of graphene be changed?
We can estimate that the change is about 10 to the power of 4 to 10 to the power of 5.
If we want to do this detection,
The detection limit is 2 millivolts.
This is actually a very bad sensitivity.
Because the electrical signals that nerve cells can generate
It's usually between tens of microvolts to hundreds of microvolts.
This is actually very, very bad.
So our question is whether we can increase the modulation depth.
The method we use is to put graphene on a planar waveguide.
In this picture,
Basically, this tantalum pentoxide has a relatively high refractive index.
It is our planar waveguide.
The light will spread inside.
The graphene is placed on the planar waveguide.
When the light passes through the graphene,
The light will be absorbed.
The absorption of light will be changed.
The graphene will be changed by the electrical signal.
The silicon dioxide layer and solution have a relatively low refractive index.
The light inside is evanescent.
So it will be confined to the planar waveguide.
One of the concepts we use is called critical coupling.
Basically, it looks like this.
We put graphene on the planar waveguide.
You can imagine that when the light comes in,
Because this is an evanescent wave,
The coupling of R1 will go into the waveguide.
When it reflects back,
Some light will be absorbed by the graphene.
So we write it as 1-α.
α is the absorption of graphene.
So its reflection is R2.
It is 1 minus the absorption of graphene.
When you consider these multiple interferences,
Basically, you can write the electric field in this form.
It is the square root of R1-R2 divided by the square root of R1-R2.
If you are doing photonics,
You will find that this is exactly the same as the ring resonator.
Basically, you have a beam of light coming in.
The ring resonator has a coefficient of T1 that will go into the waveguide.
Here, we have a coefficient of R1 that will go into the waveguide.
It goes through an α-absorption.
Here is also an α-absorption.
It goes back to the ring resonator.
If you are familiar with the ring resonator,
You will know that this thing has a critical coupling.
The meaning of critical coupling is
Because the R-absorption of the waveguide can be changed,
We set R1 to a constant and change R2.
When R1 is a constant, we set it to 0.95.
When R2 is small, R1 is about 1.
You can put a value in and you will know.
When R2 is 1, the reflection is also 1.
When R2 is a small or large value, the reflection is large and the absorption is small.
But when R2 is equal to R1,
There is a place in the middle where the reflection is 0 and the absorption is 1.
The picture looks like this.
If we can change R2,
When R1 is small, the reflectance is large.
When R2 is large, the reflectance is also large.
But there is a place in the middle where the absorption is very large and it can reach 100%.
This is what we call critical coupling.
Because R2 is the absorption of graphene,
We can use dopamine to change the alpha.
Let R2 be equal to R1, then we have the largest absorption.
This is what the reflectance looks like.
Basically, if we put a neurotransmitter in, the Fermi energy will change slightly.
We will see that the reflectivity will also change slightly.
The concept is like this.
This is our optical setup.
Basically, we use a prism to couple into the waveguide.
Our light comes in like this.
Basically, we look at the reflection of graphene and put it directly into an imaging system or a photodetector.
This is an experiment.
Basically, we do this.
The first thing we do is to use an external voltage to change the Fermi energy of graphene.
When you change the Fermi energy of graphene, the absorption of graphene will change.
Its relative reflectivity will also change.
You can see that when the Fermi energy is small, the absorption of graphene is large.
Basically, it will not be coupled in.
When the Fermi energy of graphene is large, the absorption will be small.
It will not be coupled in, and the reflection will be large.
Only when the absorption of graphene is just right, when R1 is equal to R2, there will be critical coupling.
The reflectivity of this place will be small, and the absorption will be large.
This is the place where the sensitivity is the largest.
We put the neurotransmitter in this place.
We put the external voltage field in this place.
When the neurotransmitter comes in, a light signal will come out.
We do this.
There is a DC value of 0.5.
We add an AC signal on it.
We can directly see the change in the reflectivity of graphene.
According to our test, we can see that if we give a millivolt AC voltage,
the change in reflectivity is about 10 to the power of 2.
Compared with the previous transmission method, it has improved by about 100 to 200 times.
We can see a change of about 15 microvolts.
We can directly see the action potential.
This is an imaging demonstration.
We can not only see the voltage change at a single point,
but also see the voltage change in the whole region, and it is timely.
Finally, we do a bio-test.
We put a heart cell directly on graphene.
We can see the electrical signals.
The interesting signals are from the heart.
Heart cells can move.
There are electrical signals and mechanical signals.
We use a chemical called burblast.
This chemical will make the heartbeat disappear.
There will be no more mechanical beating.
We can directly see the electrical signals.
This is a biological demonstration.
Can you go back to the previous page?
This page?
Your sharp peak is the electrical signal.
The first one is parallel, the third one is parallel, and the fourth one is crooked.
This cannot be directly compared.
Before we add this chemical,
the heartbeat beats very regularly.
It beats once every two seconds.
However, when you add this chemical,
the heart cells die slowly.
When we add this chemical, the heart cells die slowly.
Finally, we use a camera to see the electrical signals.
We can see the electrical signals in the brighter area.
There is no electrical signal at the beginning.
The electrical signal comes from the left side of the screen.
It enters the middle and goes to the right side.
It goes beyond the detection range.
Each frame is about 5 milliseconds.
This is very timely.
The frame size is about 1 millimeter.
It is very accurate.
We demonstrate this method.
We can see the electrical signals in one frame.
In conclusion,
we use the properties of graphene.
First, it is very sensitive to the environment.
Second, it can do doping.
Doping can change the optical transition of graphene.
We develop optical sensors.
The first sensor is the chemical reaction near the graphene electrode.
The second sensor is the electrical signal in the graphene.
If we put nerve cells or heart cells on the graphene,
we hope to see the electrical signals.
This is our main work.
This is the end of my speech.
These are my collaborators.
The first one is my boss.
These are PhD students or postdocs I have worked with.
These are other teachers.
Thank you.
Let's applaud Jason for his speech.
Do you have any questions?
Can I ask you a question?
Sure.
Can you go back to the first two PowerPoint slides?
In this setup,
you have a prism with light coming in.
It interacts with the surface of the graphene.
This setup is often used to generate local plasmonic fields.
Do you consider this?
Or is it something you will look at in the future?
The structure looks like local plasmonic.
But the concept is completely different.
There is no metal here.
It's all dielectric.
Our focus is on this.
We can control the thickness of the evanescent wave.
Our focus is on controlling the thickness
to change the light coupling coefficient.
When you adjust the coefficient to the same as graphene,
you can design it to be the same as graphene.
This is when the critical coupling occurs.
The assumption is 100%.
So the sensitivity is theoretically infinite.
If all the light is absorbed,
a little change will cause a change from 0 to a certain intensity.
This is theoretically an infinite sensitivity.
This concept is the most important part of this device.
I see.
We think this is a better way than plasma.
We are thinking about using this method to replace plasma.
Many people are using plasma enhanced biosensors.
Their claim is that they don't need labels.
They can do the same thing.
But I don't know if their sensitivity is as good as the claim.
The main problem with plasma is that it can't be imaged.
We can image this.
This is correct.
The sensitivity we are looking at is similar to plasma.
Our system is not yet fully optimized.
0.5% of the light is still not absorbed.
If you want to optimize this process,
what do you need to change?
Do you need to change the quality of the substrate?
Or do you need to make it more optimized?
So far, the only thing that hasn't been absorbed is graphene scattering.
Do you mean graphene vibration scattering?
Or other photonic scattering?
No, graphene is not homogeneous.
It's not homogeneous in space.
Oh, so there's still a bit of revo on it.
I see, I see.
So if I have a completely flat graphene,
in theory, I can get 100% of it.
If you can get the same amount of graphene in every place,
then it should be very good.
Okay, I see.
But the graphene we use here is actually all CVD.
It's in the palm of your hand.
When it's in the palm of your hand, it's in pieces.
There are still some gaps in the middle.
I see.
So if you use a single crystal graphene,
for example, when you turn the CVD,
you don't want it to grow very big.
If you use a very small graphene,
will you get a very good result?
You just collect a very small signal.
Yes, that's the theory.
But what we want to demonstrate is that
we can have a large-scale detection.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
If you want to do imaging,
you need a large-scale detection.
I mean, as long as you don't let the graphene stack up,
it may be a very small point.
Then if you use the ENCCD to collect the whole thing,
you will get the same signal at every point.
You will get the same image.
As long as you don't let the graphene stack up,
it's okay.
Yes, that's right.
But now I don't know how big a single crystal can grow.
I remember it was about 10 to 20 microns.
So how big should each data point be
for you to collect such a good signal?
Oh, you mean...
Our spatial resolution can be up to about 10 microns.
What is the limit of this thing?
For example, at 10 microns or lower,
under the ENCCD resolution scale,
these five microns...
Okay, so in our pixel,
it's 10x10 microns.
But maybe in some pixels,
the graphene coverage is 80%.
In some places, the graphene coverage is 50%.
Then the response of these two places will be different.
When one place is critical coupling,
the other pixel will not be critical coupling.
Okay.
So on average,
you won't be completely critical coupling.
So have you ever thought about
getting a sample out of a tapestry?
We haven't thought about it before.
Actually, we can try it.
Because what we've been thinking about is
that we have to find a way to make it very large
so that we can see the entire neural network at once.
Got it. Thank you.
Anyone else have any questions?
No questions?
Anyone has a question? Sorry.
No, thank you.
Thank you.
Very good talk.
Okay.
Thank you.
If there are no questions,
let's give Jason another round of applause
for bringing us today's talk.
Okay, that's it for today.
I'll turn off the recording first.