Hello, everyone. Welcome to this week's TerraTalk.
I'm your host, Emma Lin.
I'm currently working on CO2 reduction in Caltech.
Welcome to our talk today.
First, I'd like to introduce our speaker for today, Du Yixiu.
Du Yixiu is a doctoral student at Stanford University.
She graduated from the University of Taiwan's Department of Physics.
During her time at the university,
she worked as a postdoctoral student at the Zhu Shiwei Laboratory.
She did research on silicon photonics.
During her time at the university,
she went to Berkeley Department of Physics for a year.
At the time, she did research on graphene synthesis.
Yixiu is currently in the Department of Physics at Stanford.
She did her Ph.D. in physics for a year.
She is currently doing her Ph.D. rotation in Professor Gao Sunhong's lab.
The lab she is currently working on is
sound imaging and neuroscience-related research.
Her next interest in the doctoral program
is to combine nanophotonics and neuroscience
to do applications.
The topic of her presentation today is
the research she did with Professor Zhu Shiwei at the university.
The topic of this presentation is
about the rapid development of silicon memory circuits.
People have always wanted to combine silicon
and nanoparticles in a chip
to achieve a real photonical IC.
However, silicon components are relatively large,
so they want to understand
whether they can reduce the magnitude to nanometers
to achieve greater density
while maintaining the nature of nonlinear light.
The topic of this presentation is
the great enhanced photothermal nonlinearity
in a silicon nanoresonator.
Let's give a round of applause
to welcome our speaker today, Du Yixiu.
Thank you for having me.
I'm Du Yixiu.
I don't think there are a lot of people here,
so if you have any questions,
please feel free to ask.
I'm Du Yixiu.
I don't think there are a lot of people here,
so if you have any questions,
please feel free to ask.
I'm Du Yixiu.
I don't think there are a lot of people here,
so if you have any questions,
please feel free to ask.
I'm Du Yixiu.
I don't think there are a lot of people here,
so if you have any questions,
please feel free to ask.
I'm Du Yixiu.
I don't think there are a lot of people here,
so if you have any questions,
please feel free to ask.
I'm Du Yixiu.
Nowadays,
there are some people writing their article
in 2010 called
''The Logical Next Step of an Optical Transistor''.
Now this person publishes his article in 2010 called
The article talks about
two important points
for nano photonics devices.
We want great density
to match the electrical IC.
We also want a good enough functionality.
This functionality is like
an electrolyte.
We want a good enough electron-electron interaction.
Through this electron-electron interaction,
we can control the device.
Can optical do the same?
Let's take a look.
Recently, there is a very popular field
called Silicon Photonics.
You can see the timeline.
In 2003,
it was Silicon Nanophotonics' birthday.
That day, everyone thought about
how to combine
nanoscale silicon waveguide
and micronscale optical fiber
through a technique called
tapping.
Then we can extend
the optical fiber technology
to silicon waveguide technology.
I want to emphasize that
in the past 10 years,
Silicon Photonics' field
has developed rapidly.
Looking back to modern science,
it is hard to see such a rapid development
in 10 years.
Silicon Photonics is
a very popular field.
Next,
I want to talk about
why everyone wants to
use silicon
to realize electronics.
First,
we know that there is a lot of silicon in nature,
so it is very natural abundance.
On the other hand,
silicon has very mature fabrication technology,
so we can make very small devices,
but we can also make a lot of devices.
For various reasons,
electronics has developed rapidly,
so people want to
expand it to the photonics platform.
The reason is that
if we expand to the photonics platform,
we may have
very high speed potential.
We can potentially reach
a very high speed switch.
I want to show you
the technology that combines
photonics and electronics.
Everything in the same platform.
This is an article published in Nature
in 2018.
The left half of the article
is the electronics device, transistor.
On the same chip,
we can see the photonics device.
If we take a closer look,
we can see that
the electronics device
and the photonics device
are all on the same chip.
If you look closely at this scale bar,
there are countless electrical devices
on the same chip.
We can make very good
electrical-based integrated circuits.
But in the case of the photonics device,
we only have one.
Its scale bar is 10 microns,
like this microresonator.
You may ask,
why don't we make it smaller?
Why do we have so many electronic devices?
The reason is that
we want to reduce the footprint
from 10 microns to 100 nanometers.
That's what people think.
But if we want to reduce the footprint,
we have to consider other problems.
For example,
if we reduce the footprint,
we will have the same functionality
as a large size.
One aspect of the functionality
is optical nonlinearity.
The optical nonlinearity of silicon
is very small.
The definition of nonlinearity is
if I increase the intensity of my illumination,
my refractive index
will also increase.
This coefficient represents
the nature of the nonlinearity of the material itself.
Because our silicon
is a very small nonlinearity,
can we increase its intensity?
Well, people think like Lipson.
In Columbia,
Lipson thought about
whether to use a resonance structure
to make the resonance bigger.
For example,
the structure of the microresonator,
the SEM2,
can reach a very sharp spectrum
and symbolize a very high quality factor.
With such a resonance structure,
we can increase the functionality of our devices.
However,
we want to make a very small device.
Is there a way
to make such a small device?
Although the quality factor is very low,
can we use other ways
to reduce the quality factor?
Can we find other nonlinearity mechanisms
to make our functionality
maintain the same?
This is the most classic example
of a resonator in a microresonator.
The so-called mixed resonator
provides a resonance
at a very small magnitude.
If we look at this SEM2,
it has different resonance
colors,
such as blue,
green, and red.
This microresonator is size-dependent.
There is a lot of research
on this matter,
especially in the past 10 years.
The so-called high-index material
has a very special resonance phenomenon.
It was published in 2017.
It is Yusuke Nagasaki,
my collaborator.
He did the research.
It is a silicon-on-top-of-quartz structure.
This structure can fine-tune
the width of each silicon nanoparticle,
such as Wx and Wy.
With different combinations of widths,
we can get a rainbow-like structure.
This rainbow-like structure
tells us that
we have a very good ability
to fine-tune the resonance.
Our future research
will use a similar sample.
The next thing I want to talk about
is that since our nanostructure
has such a weak resonance,
is there any way
to increase it with other mechanisms?
We all know that
photothermal is a solution.
Is there any other mechanism
to maintain its nonlinearity?
The answer is that
we can combine photothermal
and nonlinear resonance.
As you know,
the photothermal effect
is a very large nonlinear effect.
In a small-scale nanoparticle,
it is a very efficient optical heater.
In this paper in 2017,
he sprinkled silicon
on the surface of SiO2
to show that
in a specific dimension,
the silicon nanoparticle
has a very strong optical heating effect.
We can heat this silicon nanoparticle
to about 600K.
Because of these two reasons,
it is a very efficient optical heater.
So maybe we can
use it to combine
nano-resonance to achieve
a greater nonlinear effect.
So our work combines two things.
The first thing is a very weak
nano-resonance,
but it is a very small nanostructure.
The other part is
the photothermal effect.
The photothermal effect provides
a very large nonlinear effect.
If we combine these two things,
we can get a greater nonlinear effect.
If we compare
these two things,
we can get a very small nanostructure
and a very good photothermal effect.
If we compare
the photothermal effect,
we can see that
in ordinary materials,
the nonlinear coefficient is about
10 to the power of 9.
After the enhanced nonlinearity
of the photosynthesis,
we can increase the nonlinear coefficient
by 3 orders.
This is the process we are going to discuss.
This is our system.
We want to achieve
resonance.
We need to characterize
the resonance.
So we use a dark field system.
This dark field system
allows us to get a spectrum
This is a confocal system.
The light follows the orange light.
It hits the object
and passes through the gobbled mirror
to select the particle you want.
Finally, it enters the spectrum meter.
On the other hand,
we want to stimulate the photothermal effect.
So we use a 5.6E laser.
It passes through the gobbled mirror
to control where we want to hit the particle.
It illuminates the silicon nanostructure.
We also use a dark field system
to get a background-free,
clean image.
This is the resonance we get.
We can see that by controlling
different nanostructures,
such as Wx and Wy,
we can get a very colorful image.
This colorful image tells us
that the resonance of each particle
is completely different.
So we can expect
a different photothermal effect.
If we look at this line,
we can use a 5.6E laser
to do photothermal illumination.
Under this illumination,
we can see that
there are three peaks
of scattering intensity
at three different degrees.
This result is quite similar
to the simulation.
So we can say that
in the silicon nanostructure
at 100 nm,
there is a magnetic dipole,
an electric dipole,
and a magnetic quadrupole.
Why do we choose a 5.6E wavelength?
Because with a 5.6E wavelength,
we can see different resonance peaks
at the same time.
Different resonance peaks
affect the nonlinear behavior.
With the same 5.6E wavelength,
we can trigger
two different absorption peaks.
This is why we choose a 5.6E wavelength.
I have been talking about
nonlinear effects.
In fact, what we want to discuss
is that if we increase
the excitation intensity,
what will happen to
the optical properties?
If it is a linear case,
if we increase the excitation intensity,
the scattering intensity
will also grow linearly.
However, if it is a nonlinear case,
the scattering intensity
will saturate.
Since we want to control
the intensity of the light,
we need to adjust the power.
We can adjust it like this.
Or we can
make good use of
our scanning system.
We can move the beam like this.
By moving it like this,
we can also
saturate the nanostructure
at different intensities.
In this case,
we can see that in a linear case,
there will be a linear scattering growth.
In a nonlinear case,
there is a hole in the middle of our image.
It has a dominance shape.
This dominance shape tells us that
at the center point,
where the intensity of the light is the highest,
we have a relatively small
scattering behavior.
This is a very strange phenomenon.
If we want to quantify this phenomenon,
this is the result of
one of the size 190 nm nanoparticles.
When we increase the excitation intensity,
the scattering intensity will
have a saturation phenomenon.
We will see the point spread function
of this dominance shape.
Similarly,
for example,
we will also see
a saturation phenomenon.
In 170 nm nanoparticles,
we can't find particles at low intensities.
But when we increase the
excitation intensity,
the particles will suddenly come out.
The scattering will suddenly increase a lot.
One thing to note is that
this phenomenon is reversible.
We can restore it.
It is not related to the damage
caused by the light.
To summarize,
different nanoparticles
have different scattering deviations.
Scattering deviations like
100 nm nanoparticles
will have a decrease in intensity.
In 170 nm nanoparticles,
the intensity will increase a lot.
This phenomenon is not only
a nonlinear phenomenon
on this diagonal axis.
In fact,
in different combinations of
Wx and Wy,
we can observe
this very large nonlinear effect.
Why do I say it's very large?
Because in the
nonlinear effect of
normal silicon itself,
we will only produce
about 10 to the power of 9 percent optical modulation.
But in this case,
we will only produce
about 500 percent
or minus 70 percent
nonlinear modulation.
In addition,
I want to talk about another thing.
We just saw a summary.
The nonlinear behavior of
different nanoparticles is different.
What is the relationship between them?
We can see that
in the negative nonlinearity,
like this saturation,
the spectrum on the resonance
is a peak.
On the other hand,
this 170 nm nanoparticle
looks like a dip on the resonance spectrum.
But we won't catch all the peaks.
For example,
this 130 nm nanoparticle
is a scattering peak,
but we can't observe the nonlinear behavior.
Why is that?
We will explain further
with the photo thermal effect we just mentioned.
First of all,
the photo thermal effect
does exist in our system.
We have experimental evidence
and simulated evidence.
In the experimental evidence,
we can use the Raman microscope
to observe how many degrees
the silicon nanoparticle has risen.
Our answer is about a few hundred degrees.
This is quite consistent with the literature.
In the simulation,
we can see that
the silicon nanostructure
only has a very strong temperature increase
in a specific geometry.
This is the photo thermal effect we observed.
If we heat up a silicon nanoparticle,
the photo thermal effect
produces heat.
This heat
increases the refractive index.
This increase in the refractive index
leads to the change in the mean resonance.
This leads to the nonlinear effect we mentioned.
We simulated
this blue curve.
Our scattering
is the blue curve
for different size distributions.
When we increase the radius,
we get the red curve.
Because different particles
have different refractive indexes,
the cross-section of the scattering is different.
If we combine these two lines,
we get the black curve.
This black curve
is very consistent with the experiment.
This black curve is very consistent with the experiment.
This explains the effect of our observation
of the photo thermal effect.
In addition,
we simulated these three
170 and 190 neoparticles
as a single nonlinear curve.
This is very consistent with the experiment.
This further proves that
the photo thermal effect
is the nonlinearity mechanism.
If you hear the word photo thermal effect,
many people may think
that if the device is controlled by thermal energy,
it may be very slow.
But in fact,
the photo thermal effect is not necessarily slow.
In terms of magnitude, it is very slow.
But in terms of magnitude,
our experiment and simulation
have shown that
the photo thermal effect observed
on the silicon nanostructure
is very fast.
At this point,
if we turn on the 785nm laser,
there will be a large drop in the velocity.
This time scale is about 2ns.
This simulation also tells us the same thing.
If we look at this picture,
we can get a very fast thermal response
of 1GHz.
It tells us that it is a minus 50% nonlinear effect.
So we can make a device
with a 50% deviation.
But it still maintains a very fast speed of 1GHz.
Another interesting observation is
that when we
When we
can we go back to the screen?
Can we go back to the screen?
What is the input image?
The x-axis of the laser...
The insert...
You choose a peak and not a z-axis,
because the laser...
you can choose any size to reach the peak
Our sample is placed at room temperature
but the Photo Thermal Effect is a local thermal effect
So the sensitization of the very small thickness
but the surrounding area is maintained
Thank you for the question
Another interesting phenomenon is
if it is a Photo Thermal Effect
then we change the surrounding thermal diffusion
For example, if the thermal diffusion is changed
then we should see a different phenomenon
The result is that our Point Spreading Function
has a very sharp transition
This is our profile
When we enter high laser intensity
we will have a very strange triangular change
This triangular change tells us a very shaky phenomenon
But we don't know how to explain it yet
Let me make a conclusion
We observed a very large Photo Thermal Nonlinearity
We combined two things to achieve this result
The first thing is that we want to reduce the size
So we will use the material of Mean Resonance
We use the material of nanometer
Usually we think of Mean Resonance
Although the quality factor is very low
but we have other ways to solve this problem
So we meet the size requirement
How to meet the functionality requirement?
We use a very powerful natural
change of Photo Thermal Nonlinearity
Combining these two things
we can create a Photo Thermal Effect
larger than the original Bulk
Because of the Enhanced Mean Resonance
So we can get a very large Nonlinearity Effect
Like this picture
When we increase Excitation Intensity
Scattering Intensity saturates
and even creates a donut shape
Another thing is that
this Photo Thermal Effect
is not necessarily as slow as the large scale
In fact, in a small scale
we have proven the recovery speed of a nanosecond
This allows us to make a 1GHz
about 50% deviation device
So I want to thank you for listening
and thank you to my advisor
at Taiwan University of Physics
And I want to thank my co-authors
like Yusuke Nagasaki
He is at Osaka University
I was lucky enough to go to Osaka University
for a while
and got to know them
They gave me great help
Finally, they helped us with
fabrication
So thank you for listening
I am happy to take any questions
Thank you
Thank you Yusuke
Any questions?
The first question is
I want to know how fabrication is done
Where does silicon-on-quartz come from?
We bought the silicon-on-quartz structure from Company
How does it work?
It uses pure silicon
to oxidize the bottom layer into SiO2
The top layer is cut off with ion beam
Wait, you said you bought the SOI structure?
Yes
Usually the SOI structure is made of silicon
The silicon is thicker
But the SOI structure is different
It's made of quartz
It's made of two layers
So it's wafer-bonding?
Yes
Another question is
I want to know how the donor shape is formed
If we move the excitation beam from left to right
Because the excitation beam is a Gaussian shape
When we pass through the nanostructure
The excitation of the nanostructure
is from the small innumeration to the big innumeration
When the big innumeration occurs
The Gaussian beam hits the nanostructure
So when we do confocal scanning
We are also varying the power density
So the image you show is not the real image
It's a scanning image
The raw data we get is like this
So the image is scanned?
Yes
It's processed at the end
The last question is
This kind of mini-resonator
It has a large load
And it's not easy to couple
My understanding is that it's hard to couple to nanofortanites
Is there any way to solve this problem?
This is a great question
For coupling
Because the mainstream of nanofortanites
Is to use the silicon waveguide
So it's hard to couple to the silicon waveguide
That's right
But we don't necessarily
It can be made like a gate
Like this
This is a potential application
We have a silicon waveguide
We put a mini-resonator on it
If the intensity of my silicon waveguide is very strong
Or we put a high beam on the right
To heat the silicon nanofortanite
We use another kind of wavelength
To communicate
Although the load of the mini-resonator is large
But its load will not affect the communication wavelength
Why not?
Because it's a bit like a pump probe
We use an irrelevant wavelength to pump it
Its purpose is to increase the temperature
Of course, the on-off ratio can be done very well
But your signal will always have a loss
No matter if you have a gate
The loss of your waveguide will always be large
It should be like this
Yes, because it's more of a scatter
But I think we can use engineering
To make the loss smaller through different wavelengths
Like this picture
If we look at the absorption on the right
It's about 800 nm or more
The silicon itself has no absorption
So through different wavelengths
With different geometry of the mini-resonator
We can adjust the absorption
To make the loss as small as possible
Is the main current of silicon waveguide 1.5μm?
Why do you want to do it in the visible range?
Because in the visible range
We have enough absorption
If it's 1.5μm, we don't have enough absorption
Does this become a point to pay attention to in the future?
Because most waveguides should be at 1.5μm or 1.1μm
Yes, so the communication we want to send
Should still be in the range of 1.5μm
But what we emphasize here is
Our nanometer structure can produce enough heat
This heat can be enough to change the refractive index
You mean you still have to use visible to pump
Then you use 1.5 to probe
This is the application in my mind
So the potential structure we saw just now
It hasn't been done yet
Will ThermoLight affect your 1.5?
Will the evidence of this not being tested be affected?
No, this will be the next project
Hello
Will the refractive index be affected by visible light?
If you choose, like you just said, there are about 5 or 6 waves
If you choose differently, maybe
I think it's about the same
I didn't hear it clearly
No, because the picture you just showed
There are about 4 or 5 peaks
I just asked you why you used the 750-pixel picture
Oh, yeah
But the other lasers
The other wavelength lasers feel more difficult to obtain
A little bit, yeah
Yeah
It's okay, 400
A little more than 400, so there's a chance
This is done in the collaborator lab
Their equipment is only 785
But I think in terms of quantity
I don't think Timescale will guess a lot
Hello
Any other questions?
I have a general question
Because I'm not involved in this field
I want to ask
Basically in this field
The current level of development is
You just said you want to scale
When you want to scale smaller and smaller
You want to maintain the quality of the laser beam
And reduce other costs
In this field
Are there already a lot of people doing it?
Or are you the pioneers?
And besides this direction
What other directions do you think
Have the potential to improve this problem?
I think
The interaction between light and light itself is very small
So generally everyone will try to
Make the resonance structure bigger
Solve this problem through geometric methods
The most famous example is
Microlipson's microbeam resonator
The structure shown in the beginning
So I believe
Photonic's mainstream is something like this
But everyone is still trying
So they haven't thought about how to make the device smaller
Are they just proposing ideas
Or have they already made some prototypes?
Photonic has already made something
Many companies are already selling this kind of device
So what are they doing with the microbeam?
Waveguide
Waveguide control
How do they use the microbeam to control?
Usually
If
If I have a beam
If I have an EM wave
Passed through the waveguide
If the frequency of my EM wave
Just meets the resonance structure of the nanostructure
Then it will be completely trapped in this structure
Will not continue to propagate
So it can play the role of off
The biggest discovery of Microlipson
Is that he put a
Put a potential
Electrical potential
Put a gating
This gating will cause the refractive index to change
So it can choose which light to pass and which light not to pass
I have seen a similar structure before
But it seems to be like
You just
The light is from top to bottom
But it seems to be
A very similar structure
It can go from top left to bottom right
But it can't go from bottom right to top left
But
But I think this thing
I didn't understand at that time
I just looked at its abstract
It can do this
But I wanted to ask you
Do you know how he did it?
I don't know
You can find the abstract
I don't seem to be
Glenn Davison
A professor at Maryland
They are also doing Microlipson
So what you said is that it can only pass in one direction
It can't pass in another direction
Although it uses a pathway
Yes
So I thought it was amazing at that time
But I didn't take a closer look at it
Have to find it again
So what is the biggest advantage of its circular disk type?
Compared to your general straight line web guide
Because it will have a resonance structure
It will have a resonance structure
Called Whisper Gallery
So the energy is stronger
The signal is stronger
I remember you have a picture
It will have about four
Two peaks
I remember in the front or the back
This one
Yes
Their separation
It probably has something to do with the radius of this ring
Or the size
Or the voltage
Of course
So how much is the Q of this one?
This Q is probably 10
5-quart scale
5-quart scale is pretty good
Microcality is also about 6-7 quarts
But in Mi Resonance
The quality factor is probably only 1000
So there is a difference of 3 quarts
So I can only use other mechanisms
To achieve the same energy
Sorry
Mi Resonator has 1000?
About 10-100
Ok
So the picture you just showed
Is about 10-100
Yes
Scale
Ok
Thank you everyone for your passionate questions
Anyone else has questions?
No
Du Yixiu
You can
If any of you
Have other questions after the talk
You can contact Du Yixiu
Through his email
And Yixiu you can leave your email in the chat
If you want to ask
Click on the chat on the right
Can I type?
You can
Can you hear me?
Yes
I want to ask
Thank you for your talk
You mentioned that
It has a nonlinear effect
So it changed the N2 part
The current nonlinear effect
Is what I want to compare
Yes
If you have a strong current nonlinear effect
You should also have a strong 2-photon absorption
In this device
I want to say
The question is
If you have a strong 2-photon absorption
You can directly use the 1.5 wavelength
Or use a more transparent wavelength
To achieve a strong nonlinear effect
Nonlinear effect
I don't know if you've tried it
Some people do it like this
But
To trigger the 2-photon absorption
We need a very strong intensity
So they use a femtosecond laser
I see
So you guys
Don't have a femtosecond laser
Not that I don't have a problem
We want to use the minimum intensity
Minimum intensity
To trigger the nonlinearity
I see
I can ask
I'm not sure if you compare like this
But I want to
Understand a little bit more
If you put your excitation
These power density
Then you normalize it
Absorption cross action
You probably
How many photons do you need
To start seeing these nonlinear effects
Can you say it again
Because your excitation
Most of the light
Doesn't really couple to
Its resonant mode
Because its gathering cross action is very small
But if you put your
Excitation power density
To normalize its
Absorption cross action
Which means that you
Really excite the structure of the photon
How many photons do you need
To be able to see
Its nonlinear phenomenon
Or
Because you emphasize that it is very strong
You may be able to see very small power
Just
See this nonlinear effect
Do you have some
More quantitative
Comparison method
How much power
Or how many photons
Do you need
How much intensity
If it is
Megawatts per
square meter
Right
General nonlinearity is
10 to the power of 9
I see
In our case
There will be a very large deviation
I see
So if you
10 to the power of 9
If there is such a phenomenon
Then I almost have to
5 times 10 to the power of 9
To be able to use
Absorption of two photons
To achieve a similar effect
I see
I see OK
Then I can probably
Thank you for your answer
Thank you
OK
Thank you all for your questions
Then I will stop
That's all for today's speech
I will stop recording