Hello, everyone. Welcome to today's Project Terra talk.
I'm the host today. Just call me Ted.
Today's speaker is Don Yen-Yong from Caltech.
He works at NASA JPL in Caltech.
Today's topic is Connected Inductance Detector for Next-Generation Dark Matter Search.
So, Yen-Yong, it's your turn.
Hi, everyone.
Today's talk is more like an update on the latest situation.
I think I've talked about what I've done a year ago.
Actually, the content is pretty much the same, but there's a new progress.
Some parts of the talk might be fast, and some parts might not be clear.
If you have any questions, feel free to ask.
To be honest, I've been very busy lately, so I've only started this morning.
So if you don't ask questions, it'll be over soon.
Today's topic is connected...
Let me add that when you come in, you don't have a microphone on.
So if you want to ask a question, you have to turn on the microphone.
So you can ask the question and hear it.
At the same time, you can also ask the question in the chat next to you.
Okay, sorry. Yen-Yong, let's get started.
Okay, I have another question.
Can you see my mouse?
Can you see it?
You can see it, right?
Because I might talk about this and that a lot, so I need a mouse.
Okay, so today's topic is Kinetic Inductance Detector for Next Generation Dark Matter Search.
So as you can see, there are two parts to the topic.
One part is that we're thinking about looking for dark matter.
At this stage, we're going to look at future development.
The other part of this talk is that we think we can apply this.
We call it KIT, K-I-T, Kinetic Inductance Detector.
As the next main, we think it's going to be very competitive.
This technology to do this.
Okay, and then this work is mainly from where I am.
Caltech and NASA JPL, which is the Jet Propulsion Laboratory.
Of course, this whole work is actually based on a bigger project called Super CDMS.
I'll talk about it later.
But I want to emphasize that KIT is not a CDMS project yet.
So it's more like our own R&D.
But we're doing it in a big collaboration.
Okay, so now you see this first page.
The first page is our current prototype.
That gives you a sense of the size.
This circle is 3 inches.
Its diameter is 3 inches.
It's about the same size as a palm.
So now you see this little rectangle.
It's about a half to one millimeter in size.
And then there are 80 little islands on it.
I'll explain what it is.
Okay, and then this box.
It's basically hanging on a dilution refrigerator.
So it can be lowered to the temperature of the mini Kelvin level.
So I'll explain why we're doing this.
Okay, first of all, today's outline is why.
Because we don't have a particle physics background today.
And there seems to be a problem, right?
So I'm going to explain a little bit today.
Why do we think there's dark matter?
What the hell is dark matter?
So I'm going to use an association here.
What's more important is that this is our focus.
Why do we think this low-quality, low-mass dark matter is an important topic now?
So we want to do this.
Okay, this is an opening.
And then I'll talk about the super CDMS detector called HVEV.
HVE is high voltage.
EV is the electron volt.
He's actually talking about what we're doing in a high voltage mode.
Under this operation, we can have EV resolution.
Okay, so I'm going to start by saying that this is a CDMS project.
What did we learn from this?
So what did we get?
So where's our sensitivity?
So from here, I'm going to motivate.
So why the third part, the kinetic inductance detector, this thing.
It's going to be something that we think is very potential.
So now the CDMS proposal is written to 2025.
So we're actually talking about this thing.
Dark matter search beyond 2025.
What kind of outlook do we have?
What do we think?
Okay, let's get started.
Then I welcome you to ask me any questions at any time.
Otherwise, this talk is really going to be pretty fast.
And my speech is actually very fast.
Okay, the first part, low-mass dark matter.
Okay, first of all, I remember two or three weeks ago.
I have a very good friend, He Shuyu.
He talked about a talk.
He's actually doing the theory of dark matter.
So why is there dark matter?
What the hell is dark matter?
I just have this page today.
So if you're interested, you want to know more details.
You can go see his talk.
He's a very good speaker.
He taught very well.
Then I'll summarize here.
This is some evidence that we think there is dark matter.
First of all, you see this picture in the upper left corner.
The y-axis of this picture is the speed of the planet's rotation in the Milky Way.
What about this horizontal axis?
It's the distance between these planets and the center of the Milky Way.
Okay, so now you see that there are dozens of lines here.
And then more than 20 lines.
If we take a few steps.
These lines, each line is a galaxy.
Then you can go to the galaxy.
There are a lot of planets in the galaxy.
The speed of rotation to the center.
And then the distance to the center.
You see a line like this.
It's a galaxy, a galaxy, a galaxy.
According to Newton's law that we learned in high school.
If today we assume that Newton's law is correct.
Or relative theory is correct.
Then we think he's right.
OK, what about this line?
What should it look like?
It should look like this.
It's from the top.
The closer to the center, the faster the rotation.
And then it goes down like this.
And then the closer it is to the outside, the slower it rotates.
OK.
But in fact, what we see is not like this.
In fact, what we see is.
The speed of rotation of these planets.
It's going to pull up from the center.
Of course, it's very close to the center.
We don't understand.
Because there are a lot of planets in the middle.
A lot of electrons and so on.
Then we get rid of the middle.
He saw that it was almost flat.
OK, almost flat.
That means.
Of course, we can say.
Then this may be.
The theory of gravity is incorrect.
This is possible.
But gravity has been experimented by a lot of experiments.
From classical gravity to the theory of gravity.
The theory of gravity has been very, very accurately verified.
So then we can think about it in another way.
Is that?
Hey, we have quality.
It exists in that range.
But we didn't see it.
We can't see these qualities.
So we miscalculated.
But if we add these qualities.
We can recover like this.
This is the center of gravity.
The speed of rotation of this curve.
OK, this is a hint.
That is to say, there may be some matter over there.
We can't see it.
We call it dark matter.
But OK.
So you can imagine this dark matter.
Under this picture.
Like a fluid or a gas.
It's a continuous.
And then it's distributed smoothly in that space.
In the middle of the galaxy.
OK.
But we don't know its particle nature.
That is to say, we can understand.
For example, air or water.
But we can't find that molecule.
That H2O.
OK.
Now in this upper right corner.
What you see is a bigger scale.
This simulation.
You are in this simulation.
Every little light spot you see.
It's all a bunch of galaxies.
It's no longer one by one.
It's a bunch of galaxies.
OK.
Then this picture is actually white.
So you can see the black part.
What about this black part?
That is, if we assume.
There is a gas in this universe.
It's not going to be with other gases.
This is the interaction.
But it has weight.
So it's going to have a denser place.
Because gravity attracts.
And then it's going to form.
Like this spider web structure.
And then these spider web structures are denser.
Gravity is heavier.
It will attract these gases.
These we can see.
These normal.
These substances.
Gather together.
And then form a galaxy.
Then we found out.
We must be in our computer.
In this simulation.
With this kind of content.
We can.
Simulate this.
The evolution of the universe.
And then we produce what we want.
The density of this galaxy.
So we think this is also a proof.
That is, there is a kind of matter that will not interact.
Dark matter.
This is Bully Cluster.
I won't talk about this.
Everyone can go.
This can be googled.
This is a bit complicated.
But basically, he said.
If there are two galaxies colliding today.
We can see the quality inside.
Will hit and will not pass.
The difference in quality.
Then we found out that he had to have a part.
Will not touch.
Passed by.
OK, what about the last one?
This is a very, very accurate evidence.
This is what we see.
The change in temperature in the whole sky.
I call the background color of the universe.
And then he changed this.
And then we found out.
If we assume that this change is from.
When the universe was very, very early.
These substances.
This process of gathering together.
The moment of that temperature.
OK.
That.
These condensed substances.
It must have a certain proportion.
Will interact.
A certain proportion will not collide with each other.
That proportion can be very, very accurate.
Fixed.
This is the case.
OK, so we know from here.
Oh, that.
We can calculate very accurately.
In this universe.
20 to 30% will not interact.
Of this substance.
Then about 5% will interact.
What about the rest?
This is another energy content.
Dark energy.
But we won't talk about it today.
So these are the evidence of dark matter.
That's a bit like a science.
Do you have any questions?
If you are interested in any of these.
I can talk a little bit.
Otherwise, we'll go.
What does this angle scale mean?
Why is the angle scale?
Oh, OK.
So this picture is like this.
You can of course.
This thing.
It's the color next to it.
The whole universe.
Just put your temperature on it.
Different temperatures have different colors.
But you can do this today.
A map of the 2D map.
But it's a universe.
So his.
It's a bit like you're doing it.
Frequency spectrum.
But his frequency.
That dimension is the angle.
OK, OK.
Is it OK?
He's doing it.
It will look like this.
OK.
But that.
Because I'm doing particle physics.
So we care more about this thing.
That's what I just said.
There's a group of gas in the universe.
It's not going to work at all.
So if we break it down.
This is the smallest.
This is the constituent.
So what is it?
Elementary particle?
It can be one by one.
Very, very heavy.
But his number is very small.
Or he can be one by one.
Very light.
But he's very, very many.
So in the same volume.
It's produced in that cube.
The quality inside is the same.
It's in line with what we just did.
The observation of these big gases.
I got the density of this quality.
Okay, but he's in the particle nature.
It's going to be very different.
Now, what you see here.
OK, this is.
This is.
This quality unit.
So if you're in this background.
You don't have to explain to me.
What is EV?
If you don't know this.
What unit is this EV?
I'll give you a sense.
From this K to M.
Sorry.
From this K to M, this neighborhood.
It's the X-ray that you usually take.
OK.
If you're in this.
This is not.
This is just the unit.
EV this range.
It's visible light.
Energy and quality can be exchanged.
So the strength of this energy.
This is visible light.
This is X-ray.
And then this is very, very powerful.
And then this is here.
It's very, very light.
It's like coming here.
It might be the usual.
The radio wave on the phone.
And then go further.
It's very, very light.
Light to the particle.
The length of the material wave can be long.
This kind of astronomical scale.
OK.
Okay, so this is.
This mass.
OK, this dark matter candidate mass.
And then what's below?
It's all kinds of us now.
This theory.
And then you can see that this is almost.
You can go to the sky and say whatever you want.
It's the heaviest you can get.
This is the unit of solar mass.
He can't use this EV anymore.
But if we cut this part out and look at it.
From here to the other end.
It's dozens of orders of magnitude.
OK.
We don't know this thing at all.
Basically, we don't know this thing at all.
What is it?
OK.
Good.
So here's a lot of this model.
That.
Uh, now I'm going to draw this orange frame.
OK, this frame.
Sorry.
It can be said that in the past 30 or 40 years.
All I want to know is the particle.
The experiment of dark matter is focused on this frame.
There's a reason for this frame.
The top line of this frame.
There's a theoretical top line called Unitary Bond.
If this single particle of this dark matter.
If it's heavier than this one up here.
He will, uh, have this mathematical theoretical problem.
That is to say, it will exceed Unitary.
I don't know why, but OK.
So, in theory, we can say that he won't go beyond this.
Unless he looks really weird.
For example, he is a black hole or something.
This thing is going to be astronomical observation.
That's what we're not going to talk about on the single particle.
OK, what's next?
You can see that this is a very clear picture here.
What does it mean?
It's his interaction, or his own quality.
Or the energy he can carry.
It's probably in this weak interaction.
The energy scale of this interaction.
He has a very strong reason.
I'll talk about it later.
But you can see that the more important thing is.
So all the design of the experiment.
Including, uh, in the collision machine.
Whether it's a Japanese collision machine, a European collision machine.
China may build a collision machine in the future.
Everyone is basically aiming at this orange box.
Find Dark Matter inside.
What about all the experiments that don't do this collider?
Basically, now the major experiments are also in this box.
OK, but you can see it right away.
There are 30 orders of magnitude here.
It's only less than one-tenth.
OK, so why do they aim at this box?
Let's talk about it first.
What kind of technology is this limit?
Or what kind of technology are they based on?
They will focus on this box.
In fact, the concept of measuring Dark Matter is very simple.
It's like hitting a ball.
OK, this is the earth.
Then this is us.
Then we took some of the materials that people can manipulate.
To do any of our experimental equipment.
Then these equipment are nothing more than a bunch of seeds and seeds.
Here is a seed or seed.
The earth is in the solar system.
The solar system is in the galactic system.
Then the galactic system is full of what I just said.
The gas of Dark Matter is drifting in the entire galactic system.
So when our solar system revolves around the center of the galactic system.
We are constantly like being blown by the wind of Dark Matter.
OK, so at this time, if we take this seed and seed.
To build an experiment on the earth.
Dark Matter will keep going through.
We think it's very, very small.
Of course, we haven't measured it yet.
But it is likely to exist.
It won't just go through.
It will hit our experiment and then bounce away.
At this time, there will be some of this dynamic being picked up.
On this seed or seed.
Then we will measure this seed or seed.
We can know how heavy it is.
Hit down.
It will pick up such a large amount of energy.
We call it Recall Energy.
OK, let's bring all the numbers in.
We probably know that.
Dark Matter to choose.
How fast we blow the wind of Dark Matter.
OK, so we know how heavy the seed or seed is.
Then we can be different.
This hypothetical Dark Matter Mass.
To calculate how much energy we can pick up.
We pick up this recall energy.
The most efficient scenario is exactly the same as hitting the ball.
If there is a very heavy thing today.
Hit a very light thing.
Or a very light thing.
Hit a very heavy thing.
The speed of the two people is almost unchanged.
So this will not pick up energy.
But the most efficient time.
It's the thing that comes across.
With the thing that is hit.
The two of them are almost just right.
So let's estimate that.
OK, if we assume now.
Hit Dark Matter.
The quality of this particle.
Exactly.
It's with us to do this experiment.
The seed is just as heavy.
What about the energy that he transferred?
It's probably an X-ray energy.
So if we can build an experiment today.
We can measure X-ray.
This energy.
We can probably measure this kind of Dark Matter.
What's the problem here?
This is high school physics.
Okay, no problem, I'll go on.
Then you assume the weight of the dark matter.
Because all of your detectors are magnets.
It's similar.
Isn't that like this?
You have a predicted dark matter.
It's about the same weight as a magnet.
Okay, this is a very good question.
I'll talk about it later.
You can imagine.
So if Dark Matter today.
It's a super-heavy thing.
Or a super-light thing.
I say relatively compared to.
For example, Proton.
It's a super-heavy or super-light thing.
It hits.
Your experiment doesn't actually pick up any energy.
Right?
Yeah, or it's super light.
Yeah, he's gone.
Yeah, that's right.
That's what it is.
So you can say.
Use an order of magnitude estimate.
Just say OK.
So you use this kind of target particle.
Basically.
You set yourself up first.
It's probably in this order of magnitude.
To measure the weight of this particle.
If it's heavy or light, you won't be able to measure it.
Because the energy transfer will become small.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Right?
All right, yeah, all right.
Okay, let's go back to the other side.
Well, in general, if you go to a dark matter meeting.
This is what people usually see.
What is this picture?
This picture is.
This is the imaginary.
Dark Matter Mass.
From here is the 10 to the negative 5 times of the GV to the 10 to the 3 times of the GV.
Uh, okay.
Okay, so what about these 10 lines?
It's an already completed experiment.
Sorry.
What about these long lines?
It's about to be released.
Uh, the results of the experiment that will be released in a few years.
Okay, what about those dots?
It's something like conceptual design.
Or something like, uh.
Calculate it out and say I project.
If I have completed this concept, where can I go?
It's not so realistic.
Okay, so I'm going to draw a line here.
It means that I'm done with this experiment and I'm going to put it all back on top.
Okay, what does that mean?
It means.
I open my experiment and then I keep waiting and waiting and waiting.
I know how long I've been waiting.
I know how heavy my experiment is.
Therefore, I know how many protons or neutrons I have waiting there.
Wait for a long time.
I didn't wait for anything.
So I can say.
How big is it according to my experiment?
How long have I been waiting?
And then I didn't see anything.
I can say with enough confidence.
Dark matter passes through me.
The probability of being blocked.
It's not going to be more than a number.
Otherwise, I should see something.
This sentence is a bit long.
Can you understand?
Okay, so based on.
I didn't see any results of the experiment.
But I know very clearly.
How long have I been waiting?
How many things did I use to block?
Can't block.
So I can say.
Dark matter and protons and neutrons.
The probability of interaction will not exceed a number.
Then I can.
For each different assumption.
The quality of dark matter.
To calculate a number.
So in the end, it's a line.
Then I'll empty it out here.
Draw it black.
That is to say.
Okay, dark matter.
The interaction.
If today is.
If it's EEV.
It's definitely not.
The interaction is 10 to 40.
Must be smaller.
If it's bigger.
I should see it.
OK.
So these lines are what it means.
So you can see.
The current limit is.
This way.
That is to say.
We have to keep going down.
Keep digging down.
Until one day we see.
Dark matter really.
Always in the detector.
it is good.
Then.
Go back to the question that Ted just asked.
Now all the experiments here.
There is sensitivity.
You can measure.
You can set a limit.
Constraint like this.
But it's probably around here.
It's all gone.
And then there's almost no way to measure it any lower.
Why?
Because all of these experiments.
It's all paper and seeds.
To block dark matter.
So for these.
Lighter possible dark matter.
When it hits.
The remaining energy is very small.
In these experiments.
It can't be measured.
OK, I can't measure it.
Then I can't say.
What should I do here?
So there's a threshold here.
Further down.
We can't measure dark matter.
This is the first point.
The second point.
There's a yellow one down here.
A very large piece of stuff.
What is this?
This is a constant.
The seeds of the earth.
Now all the experimental design.
Basically, there is no clear.
The way is to say.
I can be very efficient.
Distinguish between dark matter and seeds.
The difference in this signal.
So if I keep digging today.
I keep going down.
Keep drawing.
It's about this long.
Here.
If I keep drawing here.
Dig it out.
I still don't see the dark matter.
Next, I'll go crazy.
There's always a signal.
But I probably will.
We all think.
Oh, that should be the sun.
It's coming out.
Or the radioactivity of the earth.
Out of the seeds.
We can't do it again.
Continue to measure this part.
At least in the foreseeable future.
No technology can do this.
OK.
Why are these experiments still so focused?
Dig this part.
For example, from 10GbE to 50EbE.
That's the reason.
Now I'm going to draw these models.
You can see it.
It's full of models here.
That's what I just said.
It can even extend to 10 to 30.
No problem.
But all of this.
What you can dig here is MSSM.
This is called super symmetry theory.
Between the 1980s and 2000s.
Everyone is very confident about super symmetry theory.
I think it might be.
It's a very important theory.
It also provides a variety of variations.
It depends on what kind of super symmetry theory you are.
The dark matter candidate.
So everyone is confident.
But keep digging.
But in fact, the earliest version of super symmetry theory.
In fact, its prediction should be around 10 to 38.
It's already been dug up.
And be ruled out by more than 10 orders of magnitude.
So much.
OK, so now we see this P or C or N.
What about this super symmetry theory?
It's all very fine-tuned.
OK, so now we generally think.
OK.
Within 5 to 10 years.
These experiments will be completed.
The dotted line they draw.
Unless we are either in this range.
We found the document.
Otherwise, these experiments are based on technology.
There will probably be a lot of difficulty.
Extend down.
Because it will meet neutrino.
This is the first point.
The second point is.
In fact, if you are.
It's a theory that needs to be very natural.
Not very artificially.
To find a very difficult to produce.
The combination of parameters.
In fact, those natural.
Theoretical prediction.
It's already been dug up.
OK.
But back to this point.
In fact, there are still a lot of models down here.
OK.
So we want to do.
Uh.
We want to find better technology.
In addition to digging here.
We want to be able to cover the remaining dozens.
This order of magnitude is not measured at all.
Or it's hard to measure.
OK.
So what are we going to do?
I just said.
We want to block a very light particle.
We can't use a very heavy magnet or seed to block it.
Because of this.
This energy will be very little.
So that's another thing that humans can control.
In addition to the magnet and the seed is the electron.
In fact, there is not much else.
OK.
Then I change it to an electron now.
Then I bring the number in.
The electron is instantly 100 times lighter than the magnet and the seed.
No, sorry.
1,000 times.
2,000 times.
Almost 2,000 times.
To a very, very light quality.
So now I can block it.
The energy consumed is probably.
I can be sensitive to 100EV.
That's dozens of EV.
Let's talk about dozens of EV.
But if you use a magnet.
It's hundreds of EVs that can be measured.
That is to say, if I want to eat more.
Eat this light particle more efficiently.
Give me the energy.
I have to use light things to block.
So our idea now is.
Electron as the target of being hit.
OK.
Okay, because he's an electron.
So he actually has another interaction.
He will directly put the light.
Light is the electromagnetic wave.
So if there is a model today.
Is.
Will convert to light or light.
He will absorb it all.
At this time, it is not the opposite.
And then eat some of the energy.
But we will put all this energy.
Just like his quality, so much energy.
The quality will become his energy.
Eat it all.
Then we can also measure this.
If you use electrons.
OK.
So we are now.
I think we should use electrons.
To replace the straight and neutral.
To produce for lighter particles.
This sensitivity.
Then we will.
It's a definition of this talk.
That is to say, we will talk about low mass later.
Low mass is probably GEV.
Or lighter particles.
Then emphasize it again.
There are so many here.
For example, dark sector.
This is the metric.
Freezing, etc.
OK.
Of course, there are.
Uh.
We are still experimenting with this.
I just talked about this.
The mechanism of hitting the ball.
But in fact.
For example, like the theory.
Uh, he predicted that.
There will be very natural.
Can produce this.
It's not a particle at all.
It's more like a bunch of.
That's like this.
We can actually measure it.
But of course we have to assume that.
Assuming he's going to do this.
This kind of behavior.
Then we can use this method to measure.
So in other words, we can.
If there is such a behavior.
What is his probability?
That's for me.
Uh, like we do experiments.
A more important point is.
How do we really.
To do such an experiment realistically.
Like I just said.
We want to maximize this.
Momentum energy transfer.
So we have to be very light.
This target the particle.
Of course, we want very small, very small noise.
OK, because of this.
We can only see a very small signal.
So there will be enough.
Signal to noise ratio.
OK.
Back to just now.
We want the sensitivity of sub-Kev.
OK.
It takes a few tens of EVs.
Probably below.
Then do this.
GEV or lighter particle.
To see things.
OK.
Of course, there is also a very important thing.
We must be able to know very clearly.
The signal I see now.
It's from the Dark Matter hit me.
Instead of inexplicably.
Things in the environment hit my detector.
But if the energy is very high today.
This thing is relatively easy.
Because of this kind of energy in the environment.
This kind of radioactivity.
In fact, relatively few.
Otherwise, in fact, people are dead.
OK, but if you reduce the energy to very low.
In fact, you are next to the phone.
Cell phone signal.
It looks like that energy.
If you put it in an experimental environment.
The temperature of the experimental environment.
Black radiation.
That light is also this energy.
So it started to become very, very much.
Low-energy particle.
Keep hitting the detector.
We need to be able to distinguish.
That's the only way to do this.
So in fact, it is relatively challenging.
OK.
I won't talk about this picture.
This picture is actually the thing.
Ok.
Ok, I'm done.
The first part is our motivation.
Do you have any questions?
Hello.
Do you hear me?
Yes, yes, yes.
Then I want to.
I'm the one who does Neoscience.
So I don't have a background.
But I want to ask.
That's how everyone is.
Is it that?
Neutrino.
Oh.
How do you do it?
Is it?
Neutrino.
This question.
Is it?
OK.
You say.
What if it's Neutrino?
How do you do it?
Because the sun will emit a lot.
That's right.
This question can actually be divided into two.
The first one is.
I'm not sure.
What you want to ask is.
How do we know?
Neutrino can't be a dark matter.
Neutrino can't be a dark matter?
It's still our detector.
What about the signal you see is not Neutrino?
How do you know?
It should be said that the sun will emit a lot of Neutrino.
If you have to first exclude.
Is it possible that Neutrino is not?
And then do this experiment near the Earth to make it feasible?
Because the sun if it is.
The sun is not a very strong interferer.
That's right.
Okay.
The first point.
We can use the solar system.
The solar system.
Why is it called Neutrino now?
This is that.
Neutrino's distribution is not the same, is it?
But why is Neutrino's distribution the same in all three cases?
It's because of the black matter in it.
Black matter is functional.
There's no our detector has the data.
You are now with us.
More swing neutrino.
Neutrino does not form, and now it's coming.
Linking together.
Really?
Then let's talk about the dark matter.
It takes a long, long time.
It will slowly gather into what we want now.
The density of the spider web I just showed.
Then attract other particles in.
That time is far more than we know.
The age of the universe so far.
Then the amount of planets produced.
So we know that such a light particle.
Then its interaction is like Neutrino.
Because we actually know a lot about Neutrino.
But it's a good feeling.
But that is to say.
We know the strength of its interaction.
So we know.
It can't be the dark matter we want.
OK, unless there's another version of Neutrino.
That's not.
That's also new physics.
So we know Neutrino.
The first is not to do dark matter.
The second is if today.
OK, then the sun will still shoot.
We know that kind of Neutrino.
How do we know?
The signal we see is not Neutrino.
The answer is we don't know.
But we know one thing.
We know how hot the sun is.
We know how much light it emits.
We also know almost.
The principle of emitting this light is.
Which few.
The chain of fusion reactions.
So we know.
Based on its brightness, its heat.
Look at these fusion reactions.
It emits the flux of Neutrino.
How much should that flow be?
Plus we know.
This kind of Neutrino through our detector.
What is the probability of being blocked?
OK, so we know.
Now the detector sees.
It won't be.
It won't be Neutrino.
Because in theory, in the whole experiment.
The duration will be blocked.
Maybe it's a few zeros.
In other words, it won't be blocked.
So we know there's no problem.
But based on what I just said.
I know how hot the sun is.
So how many Neutrino have been through the earth.
Through our experiment.
When our experiment is getting more and more sensitive.
Can be sensitive to.
It's worth 47, 48.
For example, here.
48, 49.
At this time, we will be very sensitive.
To be able to see that kind of Neutrino.
At this time, we see any signal.
We can't say.
It is Dark Matter or Neutrino.
So here to dig this yellow line.
This is what I said.
The experiment will stop here.
Because we basically don't have it now.
Reliable technology can tell.
Is it Neutrino or Dark Matter?
OK.
Thank you.
But in fact, there is a potential way.
If I can distinguish its direction.
They all come from the sun.
Then I will say that people from the sun.
The probability of Neutrino is very high.
I don't look over there.
OK.
But what I'm talking about now is.
When this particle hits.
The energy it leaves.
We only measure energy.
We didn't measure.
The direction of this incoming particle.
So in fact.
Unless I can identify this thing.
Otherwise, I can't tell Neutrino.
The answer is no.
OK.
Excuse me.
Can I ask another question?
Please say.
Just.
Because I don't understand this at all.
That.
That is, the particle accelerator can.
Can.
Think of a way to find these heavy particles.
Heavy quality particles.
That.
But for example.
Very light particles.
Is there no way to find it with an accelerator?
So.
You are looking for Dark Matter.
Assuming this.
This.
There is a very light particle.
Then it could also be Dark Matter.
You may.
You are looking for Dark Matter.
It may also be.
Solve this.
For example, find a particularly light particle.
Then.
Maybe the theory can't be predicted.
Or.
Some theories have been predicted.
That's it.
But I don't know.
Yes.
So in fact, the accelerator can find Dark Matter.
And a lot of people are looking for Dark Matter in the accelerator.
But.
Looking for Dark Matter in the accelerator.
Like you said.
In fact, basically.
The concept is completely different.
It is.
You use your known example.
Think of a way.
Create Dark Matter.
Right.
But.
It has a very, very practical reason.
It's very difficult to do in the accelerator.
That is.
You take two examples you already know.
Put it together.
Explode.
In addition to producing a Dark Matter.
It will produce a lot of other examples.
In other words.
Your.
Next to these.
After measuring these explosions.
These products.
These detectors.
It's like being constantly.
It has a certain amount of brightness.
As long as you do it.
It will produce a lot of this.
This kind of showering.
This kind of background.
That.
You basically can't see it.
If you want to see something.
It's smaller than the background of this shower.
Because what you see is bright.
So.
Because of the mechanism of the confrontation.
Their lower threshold is probably hundreds of GV.
It's probably here.
So.
It's probably the accelerator.
Probably the best.
Is.
From here.
Above.
They can say with confidence.
If I see something.
It's Dark Matter.
But they didn't see it either.
So they're also drawing a line.
But down here.
They can't have that confidence.
Say I didn't see it.
Because their environment is too bright.
No, it's too big.
But that's right.
You can find it in the accelerator.
Ok.
Is there a problem?
So.
My question is.
That.
Uh.
I mean.
That is to say.
Standard model.
Also.
That is to say.
Assuming there is a lighter example.
That.
Uh-huh.
Not only in the accelerator.
I can't see it.
That standard model.
I didn't predict it either.
But again.
That's right.
In fact.
There is.
Uh.
There is a high possibility of Dark Matter.
That's it.
So.
Uh.
You are looking for Dark Matter.
If you find a lighter model.
Standard model.
I can't predict it.
That.
Of course.
It's a new.
New.
Physics.
Is that right?
Correct.
As long as we see Dark Matter.
It must be new physics.
Ok.
Because Dark Matter itself.
It's not in the Standard Model at all.
Ok.
Correct.
Hello.
Uh.
Ian seems to have a problem.
Ian.
Hello.
Because I can't see the projection now.
So you have to read it for me.
Hey.
Ian.
You have to turn on the microphone.
To ask.
Can't see.
Do you want to talk?
Ah.
Ok.
He said that.
Assuming.
Oh.
Uh.
Assuming now.
Dark Matter.
Uh.
Yeah.
OK.
He only said.
I have to turn back for my microphone.
On the sound history.
He can finally speak.
Then there may be time to turn back.
Because...
The moment he speaks simple.
He wants to make.
You have to be able to say everything in English.
What?
What are you saying.
It's OK.
Don't need to be altered.
It doesn't matter.
It's OK.
You only have to be able to.
You worked hard.
It's OK.
We'll do this.
And there's another question.
Yes.
Which is.
What Light matter model.
Is considered to be without dark matter.
Is considered.
Oh, no.
Yes, this is his question.
This thing is like this.
Just.
You take something very heavy.
To hit something very light.
What will the result be?
You take something very heavy.
Hit something very light.
We can imagine.
Take a truck.
Hit a window.
The light is hit very far.
Yes.
In fact.
The first signal you see.
It will be completely Nonsense.
Will be super big.
Then it's gone.
But in fact.
He just went through.
He won't leave the energy.
Sorry.
Uh.
I just said it wrong.
Because he will go straight through.
He won't put energy.
So he transferred the energy.
It will still be very strong.
Uh.
I have an equation here.
OK.
So this.
This is that equation.
That is to say.
If you go to calculate.
He left.
Hit.
Because in fact.
Hit is the two people.
Common response.
He doesn't care.
Who hit who.
Because in fact.
In his execution.
They are hit.
You can't tell who hit who.
The most effective way.
Is to hit.
Hit.
The most effective way to pass energy to.
Another person.
Is.
Big M is greater than small M.
But whether it is.
Or is small M greater than big M.
This number will be close to zero.
That is to say.
You won't leave the energy.
So.
This question is more like.
If today.
Dark Matter.
Really move like a proton.
Then we use electron.
Is it a good candidate?
The answer is no.
Because we will leave.
Very, very small energy.
We still can't measure.
But this thing.
Effectively.
Is all these experiments.
What to do.
But they didn't see anything.
So.
I want to try.
I have a question.
I want to ask.
You just said.
We can control.
Just.
Of course.
At first.
Use paper.
More.
More people use.
The method.
Then.
Because I can't find it.
So use electrons.
So you.
You just said.
We can control.
Paper and electrons.
What do you mean by control?
What does it mean?
If.
I said control.
In fact, it is.
You can spend money.
Easy to buy materials.
OK.
So.
Yes.
I will talk about some.
More exotic.
Yes.
Ah.
If the electronic.
If you can't find it.
Is it possible to use electricity?
Because in fact.
Electricity.
Electricity and electricity.
In fact.
It's about the same.
No.
OK.
Percentage.
That's about the same to me.
What we're talking about now is.
If you can find.
Smaller things.
For example, that kind.
Uh.
What is it called?
Dirac.
It's super.
So effectively.
You can destroy one.
For example.
Quasi-particle.
That's all possible.
But.
Very.
Expensive.
Ah.
Yes.
Good.
OK.
That.
Good.
Then I'll talk about it first.
That is.
Super CDMA.
HPEV detector.
This thing.
What is it?
Ahem.
OK.
Sorry.
Good.
Now here you see a picture.
This picture.
Is trying to describe this.
Germanium.
This.
The crystal.
OK.
It's a gold.
Black.
That's the white line.
Like this.
Hit him.
Then bounce away.
OK.
Then he left some energy.
What about this energy?
Will come out.
Ahem.
This will come out.
Shake this.
This crystal lattice.
So he'll shake there.
Vibrate.
That vibrates this thing.
It's actually a.
Signal.
It's called Fona.
OK.
And then.
At the same time, he'll hit this.
Electronic electric team.
Because he has enough energy.
He can.
He's next to the electronic electric team.
Sorry.
So.
Hey.
Then we have two signals.
Can measure.
One is this.
Lattice vibration.
It's called Fona.
Ah.
The other one is this.
Electronic electric team.
Ah.
So now.
How do you do it?
It's just that we put a big piece of this.
Crystal.
This is.
10 centimeters.
OK.
This is 10 centimeters.
What about its thickness?
It's 4.5 centimeters.
It's 5 centimeters.
It's a big piece.
You don't seem to be any.
The thickness of silicon used by TSMC.
It's a big one.
And then.
Let's take this thing.
Let it work.
Ah, when it's hit by Jack Berry.
At the time.
These fans will drift to it.
This one.
To Spread to this.
This crystal surface.
This one.
Hey, this electron pair is, too.
We'll pull it to the surface of a power plant.
What about now?
We're on this surface.
Do this microbi Britt consideration.
We're doing a guided circuit.
So, we're going to use this sugar to rival the arrows.
Interrupted by these two signals.
It really changes to measure the two clicks.
First, we calculate it.
We calculate pi 2025 by zeros.
And then we measure pi.
Well, we can adjust it.
Interrupt change to measure the Bacon and that organization.
Okay, this is the concept.
Okay, then he's got a lot of them in our video to do a different operation mode.
But what I want to talk about first is this.
I don't next to meet you.
Well, it's real, it's a side classical.
Now, come in hop okay.
Generate an otmomert here.
It's all electronic.
Okay, and then I'm here to give him a super big power plant.
Okay, then he's going to pull this electronic and electric, and he's going to rush up and down here very quickly.
Okay, and in the process?
Because this electronic electric will be far more than he can travel in this lattice.
The highest terminal velocity.
So what he's going to do is he's going to start generating.
He's going to lose or he's going to generate more energy into this.
Crystal inside to balance his speed, he's going to stay at terminal velocity.
So you're going to have a lot of this green arrow.
This is a secondary phenomenon.
Okay, so you can imagine if we give him a super big bias voltage.
He's going to generate a lot of wind.
So we basically just put an electronic electric signal.
Let him become a big power plant.
Let him become a super big wind signal.
And then we use this method to recover.
Oh, so we created a few electronic electric teams in front of us.
Okay, so we're going to use this method.
We just have to give him a few dozen to a hundred or two hundred volts of this power difference.
Then he can produce dozens of times to a hundred or two hundred times of this.
This is our approach.
Then we basically measure this purple piece, which is the sensor.
Okay, this is a piece of paper we published last year.
We made an R&D device.
This device is 2 centimeters.
This edge is 2 centimeters.
This is a silicon crystal.
It's 4 kilometers thick.
So it's 0.4 centimeters.
Then we added him.
We added him 150 volts of this.
Okay, so we're going to use this high voltage method to generate a lot of secondary.
Then we use this piece of silver.
I'll talk about it later.
To measure this wind.
Okay, so we can use this method.
What we get is this signal to noise ratio.
It's 0.7 percent of the electronic whole pair.
For example, this is a single electron hole.
This is a horizontal energy.
Then the axis is the histogram.
It doesn't matter what it is.
This is a single electron hole pair.
This is a signal of two, three, four electron hole pairs.
And what about its width?
It's about 7 percent.
That's what it means.
So we have resolution to see.
Counting this single, single, single, electron hole pair.
Okay, so we found that we can do it without fear.
Add this bias voltage to super big.
We can't see the super, super big signal to noise ratio.
The answer is no.
Because when we add more than one breakdown voltage.
This whole crystal becomes like a semiconductor.
It's like an island.
It's been crazy, it's been passing through.
It will smear.
We can count this dark matter signal ability.
So we do this breakdown voltage.
We found that we don't want to go beyond this breakdown voltage.
We operate at the bottom of the breakdown voltage.
We see that it will always have two or three hertz like this.
Two or three signals every second.
Then keep coming out, keep coming out.
The part that comes out is the pink part.
It's completely different from what we expect.
The signal that dark matter can produce is different.
So our assumption is that.
OK, there's a background here.
We don't know why.
It keeps leaking.
OK, but we don't know.
But based on such a background.
We can also set a limit.
Is it consistent with this background being or not?
OK, I'm going to do this calculation.
What about the calculation?
You can see the picture in the upper right corner.
OK, CDMS Run 1.
I just said.
In traditional experiments, we are all at 10 GeV.
Or higher to a few TeV to draw this limit.
But now I'm going back to the experiment.
We put this detector in our refrigerator.
Then I gave it a day and a night.
Then this detector is very small.
This detector is as big as a rubber band.
OK, we immediately set a world leading limit.
What is the world leading limit?
It's very simple.
It's not very sensitive to the very bottom.
It can measure very small probability.
It's just because we can be sensitive to very small energy.
So we drew a place where no one has ever been able to draw.
OK, you can see this place.
This is sub-mEV.
So 1 GeV is here.
10 GeV is what I said.
WIMP Search is from here to the right.
So we immediately drew a big piece here.
This is last year.
OK, let's say this is just a demonstration.
This concept is very efficient.
Then we are this year.
OK, we have to be very formal.
Let's make this thing a measurement on the ground.
Then we are actually yesterday.
We just unblinded all our data.
So we should be within a month.
Everyone doesn't have to sleep on Christmas.
Then we will put the pair on the archive.
So there will be a new one in a month.
Then stay tuned.
I can't talk about numbers, but I can say.
We redesigned this R&D device.
Because we are from here.
Then go over here and compare it.
Theoretically, this should be a resolution detector.
Then we see the difference.
Then we understand it.
We redesigned.
Then the resolution is significantly improved.
Then what's more important is.
Back to just now.
Because I said it would have two or three hertz of leakage.
Because I don't understand this leakage.
So if there is a leakage to a certain extent.
I said OK.
Then cut it off here.
The above is a good detector.
It's hard for me to say anything below.
Because my background is too high.
So the most important, the most crucial, is to set a limit.
In fact, it is to reduce this leakage.
Then we are actually Achieve Leakage Current Reduction Goal.
So this is very important.
What's more interesting is.
We have been in this year or so.
In fact, nearly two years.
We know more about Silicon Crystal.
Interaction with its environment.
So we can model.
That is, these can be produced.
Not quantized signal.
What is the distribution?
Then we can model it.
So basically, I can say.
We project to set again.
We're leading limit.
If not discovery.
So stay tuned.
This is what happens.
Okay, so here is CDMSHVEV.
Is there a problem?
This is a concept.
Because it's more like saying.
I want to talk about technology later.
But if you have any questions about this part.
You can ask now.
OK, if you don't have any questions.
Welcome to take a look.
This 180410697.
This, right.
It should be HVEV and Sensai.
Are the two that can be set to the lowest.
What is this called?
Gathering the cross-section experiment.
Right.
Okay.
Then go down.
The rest of the part I want to talk about is this.
Before I talk about it.
I want to talk about it first.
In the detector I just showed.
What is his technology?
OK, now you see a little.
A little, a little, a little, a little.
It's a piece of metal.
Then we put it in this.
It will become a super conductor.
OK, then.
If there is a pink part today.
The pink part is just that.
The big piece of that.
If I produce this interaction today.
Then it will float up.
Then go into this silver part.
OK, it will destroy this.
Then this will float in all the way.
What about this floating in?
Sorry, it destroys.
It's called QP.
Then it will change this.
The state of the conductor.
OK, it will be from.
This is the original conductor.
The horizontal axis is the conductor.
The horizontal axis is the effective temperature.
That little silver effective temperature.
OK, he was originally a zero conductor.
Will be very fast transition to.
There are nine conductors.
It's a normal conductor.
Then we just put it.
In this state of this transition.
As long as there is a little temperature.
Or the change of energy in this film.
This little inside.
We can see a big signal.
We use this method to measure.
But there are some problems.
His problem is.
This is a phase transition.
So his range is very small.
From a little energy to.
It's full, it's just a little bit.
So his dynamic range.
Is very small.
That's usually what you need.
Extra.
Circuit.
And it's going to be in the fridge.
To help him dissipate energy.
Or help him divert that energy.
Feedback, so we can.
It's really stable.
Operate our detector in this.
Transition.
And then, because he's actually a film.
He's from a zero conductor to a conductor.
It's also a super small conductor.
So he's a conventional.
The impedance of this electronics.
Is not match.
So he usually requires.
This is a cryo electronics.
To do this.
When it's time to do it.
Low impedance match.
So this is usually.
This is a very troublesome thing.
And the most important thing is.
Typical can be used to do this.
Transition edge sensor material.
It's actually not suitable.
Come to this.
So it really has to be produced.
A ts sensor that can catch phonon.
We also have a trapper.
Put these phonons.
Let him run over there, so there are several layers.
Then this micro fabrication is very complicated.
Then why do I want to talk about those?
Because those are basically this kid.
The problem of the customer service.
Then I'll talk about how to do it.
This operation is good.
The same energy comes in today.
This picture is the earliest paper.
He was imagined to be hit by light.
But you can imagine.
After he broke up.
He's on that.
The effect of the metal on it.
It's not just the change of the conductor.
It will also produce.
The change of the electric sense.
The change of the electric sense and the change of the conductor is not the same.
The superconductor.
It's been produced all the time.
He won't have a conductor.
Until the transition.
Suddenly, a lot of changes.
And then he went to the normal state.
But if today is.
Inductance.
The change of being broken.
In fact, it is relatively low function.
He can operate at a lower temperature.
That is to say, as long as I have one.
Enough ice in the refrigerator.
The transition temperature is much lower than mine.
I can operate.
In fact, I do not need to care.
Do I have a very complicated electronic?
Can control it?
This is very important.
What I'm talking about today is the change of the electric sense.
How do we make it a good sensor?
This is a variable electric sense.
I put it together with a capacitor.
It becomes a vibrator.
OK, so if today.
This electric sense is.
Eat a little energy.
A little change.
That's frequency space today.
OK, so frequency space.
This is F, this is S21.
If you do micro wave S21.
Then there is a resonance.
He will run.
And because there are more inside.
This thermodynamic activity.
In fact, it is a quasi-particle recombination.
So this resonator.
Or this resonator.
This quality factor will be reduced.
So it's not just this.
Resonance frequency will run.
Its fat will become fat.
So it will be like this.
From this black to the dot, then run back.
Then we look at this.
OK, we will know that.
Oh, here is the signal.
In fact, how do we realize such a circuit?
Actually nothing.
Just put it all together.
We have a lot of this little.
LC, LC, LC.
Then put it all together.
Then I measured its transmission.
Or S21.
I just put all these.
These resonators.
The resonant frequency is slightly adjusted to be different.
Then I measured S21 today.
You will see one by one.
One by one, one by one, one by one, one by one.
OK, then this resonance.
Will map to, for example, I know.
By design, this person.
He should resonate at this frequency.
This person should resonate at this frequency.
So I just monitor this one.
I know he was hit.
This one runs.
So this.
This is how we do this pixelization.
This concept.
In fact, you can see that this is a waveguide.
Then this is a.
Electrical circuit.
Then this is a capacitor.
This waveguide is coupled to it.
In fact, everyone will see it like this.
There is a waveguide here.
Up and down, up and down, up and down, up and down.
OK.
Then every little island.
It's all a pixel.
Sorry, but we can go back.
Compare to say.
What if you use TES?
Because the TES is too small.
Small to measure.
You have to put a lot of this little island.
All connected.
So in fact, these people are all connected.
Make a sensor together.
These people are all connected together.
So this chip.
2 cm by 2 cm.
It's just two channels.
The signals are all clamped together.
But a 3-inch wafer like this.
It's 80 channels.
Then we now think that 80 channels.
Do this.
Positioning is good enough.
So we don't actually have to push this detector anymore.
We may have to take this detector.
To do the dark matter search.
But we are for this thing.
Some analysis of robustness.
I don't know if there's a paper here.
If you can go and see.
We think we can put 200 channels.
Then there will be no confusion.
So basically.
This is the future super cdms no lab detector.
There are a lot of little dots.
But they are all connected together.
So in the end, this big piece is a pixel.
This big piece is a pixel.
It probably looks like this.
It has 6 pixels.
Then we have 80.
Then we can do more than 200.
Because in fact.
Energy resolution wise.
We have measured.
Comparable energy resolution.
But more importantly.
Recent results suggest.
We can do sub-EB resolution.
Then of course.
In money wise.
It reduces 60% of fabrication complexity.
Because in fact.
This whole piece.
Is single layer film.
So.
Compared with this.
We are actually a mask.
Then deposit.
Then etch.
Then we have a complete whole circuit.
So we reduced.
60% to 70% of this.
If we go to calculate the steps.
Then the chemical used is much less.
So this fabrication EO is much higher.
And we can easily do.
100 times of this.
Pixelization.
Is multiplexibility.
Then.
We don't need thermoelectric feedback.
We just need to.
Make it much lower than TC.
Then we don't need.
Squid amplifier.
Because in fact by design.
This waveguide is 50 ohms.
So we only need 50 ohms.
Just connect two coax.
So this is very simple.
This is very important to CLR.
Then this is the second page.
Then let's talk about.
How high can we expect?
Because we are dominated by.
Low-noise amplifier.
So in other words.
As long as I can lower my.
The noise temperature of the amplifier.
I can.
Increase my.
Resolution here.
Then we use this amplifier now.
5K noise temperature.
Then our collaborator in JPL.
He made a low-noise.
Low-noise amplifier.
So I just change this to me.
I have a factor here.
OK.
Then.
We found one thing.
We have to do this match filter.
Filter what is noise.
What is this pulse template.
If we have this today.
This pulse decay time.
This time constant is longer.
We can be on this match filter.
Filter more of this.
Noise spectrum.
Then this characteristic.
If the characteristic time of this film becomes longer.
We can.
Increase better signal to noise ratio.
In this paper.
Demonstrate that they can put this time.
Increase to 3ms.
Then we are now 100 microseconds.
So OK.
Then I put this factor in.
Do I put this factor in?
OK.
Let's not say 3000.
Let's say 1500 microseconds.
This is actually my boss.
Another experiment.
They put.
This part.
Made into material.
What does it mean?
He put this sensitive inductor.
Really we can measure.
Material.
The other part.
Another kind.
The gap is bigger.
Bigger material.
So they won't eat the wind.
By this difference.
Just by this geometric ratio.
He can increase his sensitivity.
Then we can do the same thing.
That is actually one more layer.
Much less than TS.
Then we add it up.
This ratio.
Then.
Recently.
Recently, there is one in Europe.
Do that group.
They are doing this thing.
They propose a very interesting one.
We actually have to calculate.
How much we have created.
So if you are today.
This superconductor.
Very small.
You can break a lot.
So they used this.
Low gap.
Very small.
This material.
We use aluminum now.
They can use it.
From 0.2.
0.2.
0.05.
This is also a change.
So we put everything.
Has been demonstrated.
Bring it all in.
We will.
Bring in the resolution we already have.
Rescale.
The result we get is 36.
That is to say.
We are no longer doing.
Or we do.
Ionization counting.
We basically have 36.
Resolution.
Of course, we can take this thing.
Take it instead of TES.
Continue to put it on the silicon substrate.
Test this.
Or this ionization.
Then we can do another thing.
Is that we put a bunch of kids over there.
Directly take the kids to the dark matter.
Then we can count.
This kind of quantum.
This is our plan.
Summarize.
We think now.
Within 5 to 10 years.
Humans can either find WIMP.
Or we will have a long one.
No progress.
So everyone is now.
Working hard to think about it.
Can we shift to low mass dark matter?
There are still a lot of models.
Not tested yet.
We need to have.
Electron recoil and nuclear recoil.
Two at the same time.
Because in fact.
In addition to electronic recoil.
Can measure very small energy.
Nuclear recoil can help us distinguish.
What is the signal?
What is the background?
This is an important thing to start now.
Requires substantial improvement.
In low-threshold technology.
This is the second part.
CDMX HPEV demonstration.
We have the ability to count.
We give it a day.
One day on the surface of the lab.
We can set a good limit.
Of course, our detector.
Has been taken to the tunnel.
So the next round.
Will be the underground round.
One day on the surface of the lab.
We can constrain.
0.4 MeV dark matter mass.
The most important thing is the KIT part.
We demonstrate competitive energy resolution.
The most important thing is.
It is actually.
Theoretical prediction.
If we put all the design numbers.
It is quite consistent.
Then we are confident.
So we can adapt.
What others have demonstrated.
Assuming we really have.
So many resources to adapt.
Each one.
Its outlook is 100 times.
Resolution improvement.
It is.
Flexible optimization.
You want good energy resolution.
Just make a pixel.
Let all the photons hit you.
Or you can do 500 pixels.
Then you can have a good.
Position reconstruction or tracking.
In other words.
You can reject the background.
When we really want to run dark matter devices.
This will still need to be redesigned.
And then the point is.
It is very easy and reliable fabrication.
This is very important for the future.
Because the students know.
It is very likely that the device has not been done well.
So if it's easy to do, it's very important.
OK.
Because it is very simple.
It basically does not have.
Just put in an amplifier.
Then you can run.
OK, that's it.
Thank you.
Hello everyone.
Does anyone have a question?
We are good.
Good.
I want to ask.
That is.
Is that Ding Zhaozhong.
His group is looking for WIMP.
And this is not even about to the device?
To the space or test.
The test is actually done on earth.
If we want to.
The environment of this experiment.
A better environment.
Not actually going to the sky.
Because we actually measured directly.
We hope to go through everything we already know.
All kinds of things.
And then hit our detector.
But our environment is full of cosmic rays.
So we actually have the best environment.
It's underground.
It can be very natural to use the earth's shell to help us isolate the cosmic rays.
But we already know.
Can go through almost everything.
You go to the bottom of the moon.
Relatively, you show off the more cosmic rays.
But the rate you leave.
That is.
So most of our experiments are.
Eventually, it's going to be done underground.
For example, mines and so on.
But Ding Zhaozhong's experiment.
If you're talking about AMS or AMS.
What if it's 02 now?
He's not measuring dark matter.
He's measuring cosmic rays.
The anomaly.
And then if this anomaly.
It's a very, very strong anomaly.
They can try to explain.
So is there any dark matter?
For example, decay.
Or produce such anomalies.
For example, suddenly there is a certain kind of energy.
On the spectrum of cosmic rays.
There are a lot of non-continuous peaks.
Then it might be dark matter.
So they're actually measuring cosmic rays.
So they want to go to the strongest part of the cosmic rays.
So they want to go to the atmosphere.
Because the atmosphere will actually block the cosmic rays.
So they went to the space station.
The principle is probably like this.
OK.
I want to ask another question.
It's a bit of an unexpected.
But.
I want to ask if there is anyone.
You're measuring those photons now.
Right?
And then magnify the signal.
Is there anyone.
Like using that legal.
That is, he measured.
For example, you hit it.
Then there may be some very small particles.
Yes.
I actually.
I really like this kind of research.
Because.
You can ask a very legitimate question.
That is to say.
In fact, we are now.
All dark matter will be blocked by us.
Interaction is imaginary.
Because the only thing we know.
Dark matter will really interact.
Observed is through gravity.
If I say I'm going to design an experiment.
Is to use gravity as gravity.
To measure dark matter.
How sensitive do I want to be?
Or what kind of model is dark matter?
I measured it.
Basically, your question is like this.
The answer is.
Someone is thinking about this.
It's not that I can't do it.
But the first dark matter is very, very heavy.
How heavy is it?
It's about 0.0.
Planck's mass.
I don't know if you know Planck's mass.
We think all gravity.
The theory will break down the physical limit.
Now.
Now we are discussing these scales.
What 30 times.
No, sorry.
Then.
This is what they are thinking about.
They can use laser.
Put some nanoparticles.
Press it with laser light.
Hold nanoparticles.
Then take it.
Line up in a vacuum chamber.
These nanoparticles.
If the little pig is hit by dark matter.
No, sorry.
It is passed by dark matter.
Then the weight of the dark matter particle.
Will affect the position of these little pigs.
Then they will start to shake.
It's like a gravity wave.
The mirror of LIGO.
They can use this method to measure.
But I think this is a good question.
And someone is doing R&D.
This is very interesting.
Can I ask?
Strange details.
Why do you use such a thick wafer?
Or is the whole piece of silicon?
Yes, the whole piece is silicon.
Ok, I'll leave it here.
In fact, this thickness is so thick.
This is 10 cm.
This is 4 inches.
4 inches wafer.
The thickness is a big piece.
It's like a big piece of silicon.
You don't cut it into pieces.
You cut it into pieces.
This is not a wafer crystal.
Why do you do this?
Because we found one thing.
Of course you can say that my thickness is 1 km.
And then I have 10 pieces.
Or my thickness is 1 cm.
But I only have one piece.
Its total mass.
Or the total number of neutron protons it gives you.
It's the same.
So in theory, your experimental sensitivity is the same.
But we found one thing.
In the whole process of fabrication.
And in the process of transportation.
The cosmic radiation has been constantly hitting.
And then there's a lot of dirt in the air.
A lot of radioactivity has also been touching our wafer.
And then there's a lot of radioactivity has also been touching our wafer.
Whether it's sticking or producing.
These elements.
So minimize the surface area.
The total radioactivity of the whole experiment.
So we want it to be a big piece.
Not a lot of small pieces.
Does this make sense?
But I mean, why is it so thick?
Because it's very thick.
It means that it's very small on the same quality.
Or we have the same thickness.
Or we have the same total weight.
We can also use a thin piece of stone.
But its surface area is very large.
Ah, I see what you mean.
Can I ask a question?
How do you do calibration for detectors?
This is a bit complicated.
Let me talk about this first.
This HVEV.
We actually hit it with a laser.
We have a fiber.
Because you use a pulse laser.
We can see this spectrum.
This is calibration.
Rayleigh active source 1k EV.
Rayleigh warranty veteran.
Hello, is there anyone who has any questions?
Okay, let's give one last round of applause to Rayleigh.
Okay, I'll end the recording now.