They can do this.
Bacteria can get energy source.
So they can do thermotaxis.
This is the result we just showed.
Bacteria will gather at intermediate temperature.
But the temperature they like,
which is the temperature they reject,
will change with the temperature gradient.
Will change with the temperature gradient.
This is our main result.
Of course, we have some control results.
What is the result of control?
For example,
How do we know that bacteria change their preferences
because of temperature gradient?
Maybe they change their preferences
because of temperature range.
The range is different from the gradient.
So we have to make sure
that they don't change their preferences
because of temperature range.
Then we do the following experiment.
For example,
the temperature gradient is originally 59 to 19 degrees.
We change the temperature range,
but maintain the same temperature gradient.
To see if the bacteria are concentrated at a similar temperature.
How do we do it?
We put them at 5 degrees.
From 59 to 19 degrees to 54 to 14 degrees.
In this way, the temperature gradient is still the same.
It's all about 40 degrees difference.
But the average temperature drops.
Right?
Let's see the result.
The red one represents 31 to 48 degrees.
The blue one is 26 to 43 degrees.
Their temperature gradient is the same.
But the temperature range is different.
We will find that the temperature of the bacteria
in the red curve
is about 37 degrees.
37.5 degrees.
The blue one is 37 degrees.
36 to 37 degrees.
So we claim that
although they are not completely overlapping,
their preferences for temperature are similar.
You will find that
there are some systematic differences
on the left and right.
Mainly because
we surround the wall.
These parts are close to the wall.
If they are close to the wall,
there will be a non-linear force
in theory.
But we don't discuss it here.
OK.
Finally,
we have to make sure that
although in theory,
we have calculated that
bacteria need 300 seconds
to complete the environment exploration
in this size.
But it's still a theory.
How do you know it's actually like this?
Right.
So we did one thing.
Before we take data at the end,
we take data in the middle first.
What does it mean to take data in the middle?
After the bacteria enter the temperature
from the beginning,
it takes about 240 seconds
to reach the middle.
That is to say,
let's take a look at
the time given to the bacteria
in 240 seconds.
Is the specific temperature
the same as 360 seconds?
If it's the same,
we claim that
at least between 240 to 360 seconds,
the selection of temperature
has been fixed.
That is, it has reached
the equilibrium state.
This proves that
although there is no complete overlap,
it is qualitatively the same.
At 240 seconds,
they like 31, 32 degrees.
At 360 seconds,
We choose the steepest temperature
for this temperature gradient.
OK.
That's about it.
Conclusion.
In our device,
because the people before
did a lot of experiments,
but those devices
may not be well-defined.
We want to provide
a well-defined experiment
to make sure
or improve
the research on thermotaxis.
We can create
a very linear
and one drop,
that is to say,
a gradient from left to right,
which is a very simple
temperature gradient.
And this temperature gradient
is very steep.
The nutrients we use
are bacteria that
cannot grow inside.
That is to say,
there is no chemo-attractant.
So there will be less
confounding factors.
Then,
the time we take,
the bacteria need to reach
the equilibrium time
is relatively short
and reasonable,
about 300 to 400 seconds.
Finally,
because of the H-filter,
all the bacteria we take
are all mobile bacteria.
Our conclusion is that
bacteria can be
concentrated in
intermediate temperature.
So it's different from
the previous research.
The previous research found that
bacteria will only be concentrated
in the hottest place.
No matter how you increase the temperature,
it is concentrated in the hottest place.
Because of the relationship
between pseudo-thermotaxis.
But we found that
it can actually be concentrated in the middle.
However,
what is more surprising is that
the temperature they concentrate,
that is, the temperature they like,
will change
with the temperature gradient.
OK, that's it.
Thank you.
Now,
let's see if there are any questions.
Wait a minute.
Let's see if there are any questions.
OK, do you have any questions
for the audience?
Then I have a question here.
Please ask.
I just want to ask
why this experiment
is done with E. coli,
instead of other bacteria.
Oh, that's actually
the reason.
In 1976,
the reason is a bit
very simple.
Because in 1976,
when Maeda did the experiment,
he used E. coli.
And then people
might just want to learn it,
so they used E. coli.
Then I personally
as far as I know,
the other reason is that
E. coli
moves at the fastest speed.
So,
in the same scale
and size environment,
E. coli takes less time
to complete thermotaxis.
So,
this is probably
the main reason for using E. coli.
Because other bacteria
move too slowly.
OK,
so it's possible that
there is research
that allows different bacteria
to move faster?
I don't think so.
It's not like that at the moment.
A lot of people do it.
For example,
yeast,
which is yeast bacteria,
or the larger
thermotaxis for microorganisms.
Or even C. elegans.
But in terms of bacteria,
most people,
I should say all people,
use E. coli.
Just different types.
Like we use 4, 3, 7.
Some people use different types.
Oh.
So, in your field,
you can hold a
bacteria race
to see who can make
their own bacteria faster.
They can't come out
because
their speed
is spread out.
So,
they don't run in a straight line.
Right?
But it depends on
who is faster.
Yeah.
Oh,
OK.
Got it.
Any other questions?
Yang Bo,
I have a question.
OK.
Do you think
that
in your research,
what do you think
is the hardest
or the biggest
challenge?
This is
a good question.
The biggest problem
I encountered
was
the source of our nutrients.
At first,
the source of our nutrients
was something called
lactic acid.
But somehow,
the bacteria
kept gathering
in the hottest place.
So,
we kept thinking
why.
Then we found out
that lactic acid
is a nutrient.
So,
although it is a nutrient,
the bacteria
don't like
too much lactic acid.
Then,
we found out
that
there is
thermophoresis.
That is to say,
if you put lactic acid
in the temperature,
most of the lactic acid
will be concentrated
in the lower temperature.
Right.
Then,
the bacteria
will go to the hotter side
because they don't like lactic acid.
So,
we spent a long time
to change our nutrients.
We changed it to
lactic acid oil.
Because lactic acid oil
doesn't seem to
attract or
exclude bacteria.
So,
it doesn't matter
even if there is a drop.
Then,
the second one is
the measurement of temperature drop.
We used a dye.
But during the measurement,
before we know
thermophoresis,
we will find
the brightness of the dye.
Because the density of the dye
will also change
because of temperature drop.
But we didn't know at the beginning.
So,
the whole measurement
has been inconsistent with the theory.
Then,
when we found out,
everything became
smoother.
About these two points.
Right.
Is it OK?
Dr. Yang,
you mentioned that
no one has used this method
before.
You mentioned it before.
Maybe I didn't hear it clearly.
Yes.
So,
if you are
a reviewer
and you are asked
how to evaluate
this method
compared to
the previous method,
is it better?
Do you have any index
or what kind of measurement?
We
probably
don't have any index.
So,
we
probably use
if it is
in such a situation,
we should say
that
although our devices are the same,
but we use
a smaller magnitude.
It's a very
simple step.
But it's
much better
than before.
There is another
lucky thing
is that the reviewers
didn't ask this question.
So,
we don't need
to answer.
Yes.
But if you want to ask,
we should say
that we have
controlled the magnitude well.
Unlike before,
they used random magnitude.
So,
they caused
some problems
that they couldn't
predict.
Yes.
Thank you.
Are there any other questions?
I have a question.
Please ask.
So,
you said that
the biggest contribution
of your research
is to
find
the
right
thermal
test
on
the
right
platform.
Yes.
Before doing
this experiment,
we
already
guessed
that bacteria
like 37 degrees.
We need
someone to
prove this.
But somehow,
there is no way.
What we see
is not like this.
So,
we feel strange.
Is it because
Thermotex's mechanism
and the
thermal test
on bacteria
are exactly the same
as Chemotex's?
So,
before the experiment,
the theory has already
analyzed that
they should like 37 degrees.
There are many
papers on
Thermotex's theory.
But there is no experiment
that can prove this.
So,
we
could have
proved this.
But somehow,
we created
a more complicated problem.
That is,
the temperature
that bacteria like
is related to
the temperature.
But at least,
we can prove that
they do like
the temperature
but not
37 degrees.
But,
we can't prove
that they do like
37 degrees.
So,
we have to
go forward.
Yes.
I have a question.
Hello.
Hi.
I have a question.
Okay.
Please ask.
You said that
the temperature
that bacteria like
is related to
the temperature.
Yes.
So,
if we
can prove
that
bacteria like
the temperature
but not 37 degrees,
is there a more
probable reason?
Actually,
there is.
I have
explained this
to my boss.
But he didn't
want to add
it to the paper.
But I saw
the reviewer
was also asking about it.
So,
there is.
Let me explain
why it happened.
So,
if you still remember
the pseudo-thermal text
mentioned
at the beginning,
that is,
without the ideal
temperature,
the bacteria will move around
and accidentally move
to the hottest place.
Because the temperature
is high,
the bacteria move
slower.
The temperature is low,
the bacteria move
faster.
So,
the bacteria will
gradually move
to the high temperature.
Let's call this
force 1.
This is the first example.
That is,
somehow,
there is an
invisible force
that pushes the bacteria
from low temperature
to high temperature.
At that time,
I claimed that
if there is another
force,
that is,
there is another
force that pushes the bacteria
from high temperature
to low temperature,
right?
I claimed that
this force
will increase
as the temperature
increases.
But the first force
will not increase
because the temperature
increases.
So,
it's a bit like
when you change the
temperature and temperature,
it's like these two forces
pulling each other.
When the temperature
and temperature
are small,
the phenomenon
of pseudo-thermal text
still dominates.
Then they will
move to the high temperature.
When the temperature
increases,
the bacteria will
start to move
to the low temperature.
But when we
did the simulation later,
we found that
the distribution
is still different
from what we did
in the experiment.
So,
we didn't put it
on.
But I guess
this is
at least
a part
reason.
Is this
OK?
Yes.
OK.
Thank you.
Hello.
I have a question.
OK.
Go ahead.
Based on
Dr. Yang's
current research,
what do you think
is the next question
you want to
tackle?
Next question?
In fact,
this device,
let me think about it.
There seemed to be
a lot of people at that time.
In fact,
at present,
we are
at the end of
the stage
of research.
But this is
actually very bad.
Yes.
But if you want to
continue to study in the future,
I think the biggest
key should be
like
the question
that my classmate
just asked.
That is,
why do bacteria
choose different
temperatures
under different
temperature scales?
Is it really
the reason
I just guessed?
Or are there
more different
details?
At this time,
we may not
use this
statistical way
to do experiments.
It is more suitable
for experiments
with single bacteria.
That is to say,
you have to focus
on a bacterium,
give it a temperature scale,
and then you have to
trace it.
It's a bit like
recording.
Look at it
in, for example,
a moving state
within 10 minutes,
and then the
direction of the
hair rotation.
Because we can
use that to
determine
whether it is
swing or
tumble.
So it may be
a single cell
study.
That is,
you focus
on the
temperature scale
and see
how it
decides
the final
temperature
over time.
Is there
any other
questions?
Hi,
can I
ask a
question?
That is,
uh,
hello,
hi,
that is,
I just
saw
that
you said
the
temperature
is
higher
than
the
temperature
.
I
want to
ask
that,
but I
think I
may have
missed
it,
that is,
uh,
you mentioned
that you
use that
container,
it is,
uh,
that buffer
is less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium
,
so
it
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
movement
of
any
hybrid
prime
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
So
I
think
that
the
bridge
medium
is
less
interference
than
the
bridge
medium.
Thank you.