Hello everyone, good morning, good afternoon or good evening. I am in California now, so I am very early now. Welcome to today's TerraTalk.
If you have participated in TerraTalk, you will know that we actually have an academic speech every week. The academic speech is actually for all our members to come up and share their research progress, but we are more special today, so there are more people.
Our topic today is what to do after Ph.D.
Youth Researchers Post-Graduate Development Conference
I will say it again, what to do after Ph.D.
Today is not a single speaker's speech.
The three speakers we mentioned today are Dr. Zhang Mujie, Dr. Zhou Yuxun, and Dr. Su Haowei. They are now distributed around the world in Taiwan, Israel, and Boston, USA, so they are also distributed in various cities.
Come and share with us that they are looking for their teeth, this change, and the new path of different positions now.
Let's not say much, let's invite the three speakers to introduce themselves separately.
At the beginning, I will use the name first, so that everyone does not know who to start with.
Can we first ask Mujie to introduce himself?
Hello everyone, I am Zhang Mujie, and I am now a assistant professor at the University of Taiwan's Department of Chemistry.
I returned to NTU in August last year, so it's been about a year, so if you have any questions, especially those related to Taiwan, you are welcome to ask.
Can you talk about your university, master's degree, and doctoral degree?
My university and research institute are both in NTU Department of Chemistry, and after I graduated from my master's degree, I worked as a research assistant for a little over a year.
Then I went to the University of Hollingham in the Netherlands to study for my doctorate, and after graduating from my doctorate in 2016, I went to Chicago University in the United States to do post-doctoral research, and came back in 2018.
So I did post-doctoral research for about two years, a little more than two years, and that's about it.
OK, let's ask Haowei to introduce himself.
Hello everyone, my name is Su Haowei, and I am now at Fitbit in Boston. We are a company that makes wearable devices called Fitbit, and I have been working here for about four years, and I have been in Boston for almost nine years.
I studied in Taiwan when I was in college, and then I came to the United States to study for my master's degree after I graduated from my doctorate, and then I stayed to work after I finished my studies.
In the field of work, I studied imaging in college, such as ultrasound and MRI, and then came here to do research in microfluidics. Now I mainly write algorithms and do some human experiments at work.
A small question, so you said that you have been in this company for about four years, and you have been in Fitbit for four years, but you have been there for almost ten years, right? So basically your PhD is in the best school in the world, is that right?
Yes, because I am talking about this from Caltech now, so I think it should be quite persuasive.
Don't be in school, don't be in school, really the best school.
Okay, so today we have three speakers, and Hao Wei is one of them in the industry. So if you have any questions about the industry, or want to go to the industry in the future, or want to do more applications, you can also ask questions.
Thank you, Hao Wei. Next, Yuxun, please speak.
I am completing my PhD.
It is a marriage proposal.
I am doing research in Israel.
Sorry, I am interrupting, because it seems like a lot of people can't hear Yuxun's voice.
I am not sure if Yanyong can hear you.
I can hear a little bit.
I can't hear you well here, and sometimes there is no sound at all, and sometimes there is a little bit.
Let me turn up the battery.
Can you hear me now?
Yes, I can hear you well now.
That's good.
Okay, let me quickly introduce myself.
I am an assistant professor at Caltech.
I finished my master's degree in physics at Caltech, and then I went to the National University of Transportation to do my research on nanoparticles.
After I finished my research, I went to the University of Michigan to do some physics-related research.
During this year and a half, I was very lucky to have a chance to go to Israel to do my research.
I got a fellowship and went to Israel to do my research.
During this time, I tried to join the so-called Einstein Project.
I was very lucky to get this project.
So today, I would like to share some details and skills needed to apply for the Einstein Project.
Also, I would like to share with my friends who are currently studying for a doctorate, what preparations they need to make in order to have a higher application rate for this project in the future.
Okay, so today...
Sorry, let me take a look.
So today, Yu-Hsuan will basically answer your questions about the process of applying for the Einstein Project and returning to Taiwan.
In fact, we have another speaker who has also applied for the Einstein Project.
So there should be different opinions, which you can discuss later.
Okay, give me a second.
I just opened a file and turned it off.
Okay, do you have any questions for the speaker about their background?
Is there anything you want to ask or would like to know more about?
Okay, so...
Hey, did you play in the e-sports scene before?
Yes, I did.
I think I know you.
Oh, really?
Yes, yes, yes.
I used to be in the e-sports scene.
I think you played in the e-sports scene for a year or two.
Or was it after Star Cup?
Yes, I played Star Cup for 30 seconds.
Just like Lin Shuhao.
No, no, no.
Impressive, impressive.
Okay, okay, okay.
Let's continue our serious discussion.
Okay.
The person I just talked to is Ted.
He works at Tokyo University as a quantum computer scientist.
Okay, let's get straight to our first question of the day.
I'd like to ask the three speakers to briefly summarize
their journey from starting to studying for a doctorate
to studying for a doctorate.
After finishing the doctorate,
they now work in different jobs.
What are their plans for the future?
What are their thoughts?
And what are the actual changes
that they've encountered?
What is the process like?
Let's change the order.
Why don't we start with Yuxun?
Okay.
Because...
So...
Um...
Let me share my screen.
Okay.
Can you see my screen?
Yes, I can.
So, basically,
I've already introduced myself
as a student.
So, I won't go into details here.
Um...
I have a passion for science.
But, um...
It's like this quote.
I think the world is full of wonderful things
that you can explore.
But you need to have enough wisdom
to discover them.
This so-called enough wisdom
is actually my personal interpretation.
If you want to do anything,
you have to start over.
That's right.
But you have to know how to do it.
So, why do I say you have to know how to do it?
At the moment,
it's very difficult
to be a researcher.
If you are passionate about research,
your first goal must be teaching.
But, in reality,
I'm not very determined
to be a teacher.
So,
during my studies,
apart from
attending some academic activities,
I also often attend
some vocational lectures
and even some
vocational talks.
At the same time,
I also check out
some talent recruitment websites
like LinkedIn
or 104,
which are often used in Taiwan.
I check out
the relevant knowledge
that I've learned
in the current mainstream companies.
Do they need talents like me?
If they do,
what skills do they need?
So, I occasionally spend some time
learning from them.
Of course,
my life went quite well
as I expected.
So,
when it comes to
interviews in the industry
or
working in the industry,
I can't share too much.
So,
I'll leave this part
to the two of you
to share your experiences.
So,
my major is
nanoradiation
or semiconductor radiation.
So,
for me,
if I want to
become an excellent researcher,
I must have two identities at the same time.
One is a good teacher.
Why should I become a good teacher?
Because I must
take the knowledge
I've learned
and pass it on
to the next
students
or those
who join this field later.
In addition,
I must also be
a good scientist.
If I become a good scientist,
I can get a privilege
that I can know
the secret of the universe
earlier than others.
Then, I can study it thoroughly
and try to manipulate
these physical or scientific phenomena.
I feel excited
about this.
So,
my first goal in life
is to become a researcher.
So, I spend most of my energy
on research.
My goal in life
is to create a good
research environment
for all excellent students
to join my lab
and conduct cutting-edge research.
I want to apply these cutting-edge research
to the world
and the human race.
In other words,
I want to benefit the human race.
It sounds like a lot of nonsense,
but this is what I thought
when I was in high school.
So,
my personal
job search is going well
and I focus on the academic field.
So, let me make it short.
When I was a student,
I focused on
academic development.
So,
I focused on
academic development.
When I was in the lab,
I focused on
receiving awards
such as
a book award
or
a research paper award
an engineering degree.
In my field,
I joined SPIE
or IEEE Engineering School.
There are some student awards
on the list.
The advantage of joining these schools
is that you can
participate in some academic activities
and try to apply for some academic awards.
These academic awards
will play a very important role
in your future application
for a postdoc
Besides the academic activities,
don't forget that
as a researcher,
as a scholar,
one of your most important missions
is to pass on knowledge.
As I mentioned in my last PowerPoint,
it is very important to pass on knowledge.
So, during my postdoc
and my PhD,
I spent some of my energy
to train some students
in the Department of University Studies.
Some of the students
in the Department of University Studies
received
some student awards
at some international conferences.
These student awards
are not only their own achievements,
but also
my guidance
to them.
I can't say it is a guidance,
but it is also
a credit for me.
So, I often hear
that some students
spend a lot of time
on their postdocs
or postdocs.
I think
you need to correct
your thoughts
because the students
who receive these awards
prove that
you have the ability
to lead a team
and build a team.
When you write
the Einstein Project,
you have the ability
to build a team.
So, I think
both research and teaching
are very important.
So, I put some effort
into both research
and teaching.
Looking ahead,
what I have done
is meaningful.
These are some of
my thoughts
during my PhD.
I am an academic,
so I can't share
much about the industry.
So, I will end
here.
I feel like I am wasting your time.
No problem.
Thank you.
If you have any questions,
you can type them
in the chat.
We will help you.
If you
want to say something,
remember to turn on the microphone.
Some people join later.
Next,
let's welcome Hao Wei.
He is doing a
calculation on Fitbit.
Hi, everyone.
I am Hao Wei.
Now,
should I introduce
my job or
what I thought
during my PhD?
You can start
now.
How did you
decide to
choose this path?
Did you meet
any opportunities?
When I
started my PhD,
I was very happy
when I applied to MIT.
I thought I got a lottery ticket.
But I didn't know
how to use it.
I asked many professors
what I should do
to become famous.
What kind of professors
should I find?
A professor told me
that the research field
has changed a lot.
You may not be the most famous
when you are studying.
You don't need to pursue it.
I wanted to continue
making videos.
But the professor told me
I should try new things.
I went to
study
bioengineering.
I joined
a lab
for stem cell
microfluidics.
My PhD
was a struggle.
I had to learn
new things
that I wasn't familiar with.
I started to raise cells,
kill mice,
and other things
that I wasn't familiar with.
During my PhD,
I learned
about cross-field research.
how to respect professionals
and how to learn
what they are good at.
In our lab,
there are chemical engineers,
biologists, mechanical engineers,
electrical engineers,
and scientists.
Everyone is different.
How can you
understand what others are doing?
Sometimes you can even
talk to them.
During my PhD,
I was happy
to learn
different things.
During my PhD,
there was a postdoc
in our lab.
He just started
his PhD.
He did research there.
I thought
this company was interesting.
He thought I was suitable
for that company,
so I became an intern.
If you are not sure
whether you want to
become a student or an intern,
if you have a chance
to explore different opportunities,
it's different to
become an intern.
You get to know the industry.
After you graduate,
your chance to work
in the industry
will increase.
We were lucky
to be an intern
for three months.
It was fun.
After I graduated,
I went back to the company.
As for
what I am
doing now,
there are
many people
from different fields
in our company.
We have sleep technologists,
exercise physiologists,
mechanical and electrical
engineers.
What I am doing now
is a team lead.
I handle a big project
and finish it together.
Yes.
I have a question.
Where should
a student
choose to study?
Or,
where should
a student choose
to study?
For example,
what is the relationship
between the teacher
and the community
in the industry?
As far as I know,
biotechnology
is very popular
in Boston.
That's right.
I think it's important.
If you want to
work in the industry,
go to a place with
many companies,
you can easily
get to know
what life is like
in different companies.
In Boston,
we have
a BTBA organization.
We are all Taiwanese
and have a BTBA association.
Many people
work there.
We have an annual conference
to share what we are doing.
I think it's important
to choose a place.
If you are a professor,
you can ask
other professors
or people
in the lab,
even foreigners,
to grab a coffee
and chat
about their
views.
Thank you.
Let me see if there are any questions.
Let's finish
our talk.
We have a question
for Yuxun.
Let's hear from
Mujie.
Okay.
I'm like Yuxun.
When I was young,
I wanted to
become a scientist.
I didn't know
what I wanted to do.
I decided to study chemistry
when I was in high school.
At that time,
I found chemistry interesting.
So I chose chemistry.
I kept studying.
I was different from
most people.
I decided to study
in the Netherlands.
Most people
went to the U.S. or the U.K.
Before I went abroad,
I asked
my teacher
if I wanted to
go back to Taiwan
to be a professor.
If I went to the Netherlands,
would it affect me?
If you google the name of the university,
it's not
the top university in the world.
My boss told me
that if you really
want to get a job,
your name is not that important.
What's important is
what you got
in the course of studying.
Did you prepare yourself well?
It's like
what you said earlier.
You need to know
where you want to go
and
prepare yourself well.
So I went to the Netherlands
to study.
When I was in the Netherlands,
it was interesting.
You mentioned
joining a lab.
It was a new lab.
I was the first
PhD student
of my boss.
I learned
how to build up
your lab
from a young faculty.
After I graduated
from my PhD,
I joined a new lab
and was the first
PhD student of my boss.
I didn't choose
these places on purpose.
Of course,
I had some considerations.
I think you need to
pay attention to your personality.
You like to stay in the city
or go to
university-like places.
I think this
will affect
your daily life.
I like to go to
less crowded places.
So I chose these places.
Although Chicago
is a big city,
it's a bit helpless
because as a
PhD student in Europe,
it's relatively difficult
to find a postdoc in the US.
Your boss doesn't help you much
because he only knows people in Europe.
He rarely knows people in the US.
At that time,
I flew from
Europe and the Netherlands
to the US for conferences
to meet some young
PIs.
I took a few interviews
and went to
those PIs.
He mentioned that
he had a position
and I went to
talk to him.
Although I didn't
talk to him,
it's because of
other financial reasons.
I think
sometimes
you don't have
many choices.
So you have to
be prepared.
If it's not your first choice,
what will be your second
or third choice?
This is
my overall
opinion.
Let's see if
there's anything else you want to know.
Thank you, Mu Jie.
We actually have a lot of questions
and the questions came out
faster than we can digest.
Some of them
are about
things to discuss later.
Let's ask a question first.
Chen Yixuan
wants to ask Yuxun.
During your Ph.D.
and looking for a job,
did you ever want to give up or
change your career?
How did you
change your mind?
Of course.
This can be divided into
two parts.
One is an internal question
and the other is an external question.
The internal question is
when I was in my
fourth year of Ph.D.,
I had my own paper.
Before that, I didn't even have
a second author's paper.
In the process,
I thought
if I was not
suitable for
academia.
In academia,
you need to have enough research
to be able to
continue.
This is the internal part.
The external part is
when I was in my
fourth year of Ph.D.,
I went to work
at a tai chi shop.
Although I
saw them complaining about
their busy schedule,
I saw them buy a car,
buy a house, get married,
and have kids.
Even my high school
graduates
bought a car
and bought a house
and had kids.
I wondered
if I was mentally ill
and wanted to take this path.
Of course, there were times
when I wanted to give up.
Every time
I wanted to give up,
I wanted to try again.
Your life is only once.
If you don't try,
if you don't push your limits,
you will never know
how far you can go.
I was trying
as much as I could.
On the other hand,
I am very grateful
to my family and friends
for their help.
I don't have any financial
difficulties.
To be honest,
I don't have any financial difficulties.
Compared to other Ph.D. students
I know,
I am relatively lucky.
I am lucky
because
I know some people
who are not so lucky.
They've made it
and survived.
It's a great motivation
to me.
They've made it
and survived.
It's a great motivation
to me.
So I will spend
my days
thinking about
these three things.
I will hang out
with my friends
and chat a lot,
or take a walk
and listen to
other people's stories
in lectures.
I even go to
bookstores
to see how
some of the
drugs are good
depending on how you use them.
Sometimes you need
positive energy
to support you.
This is my answer to this question.
Very positive.
Thank you.
Our next question
is related to
some of the questions
that have been raised.
For example,
if you want to go to the industry
but have not done an internship,
do you need to do postdocs
before going to the industry?
Another question is
if you have studied for many years
and want to transition to
the industry,
will there be a deduction?
Our next question
is to ask
how the academic research
can help you
and the advantages and disadvantages.
Can you give us a general analysis?
Let's sum up these questions
and let Haowei answer them.
Okay, no problem.
I think
the first question
is
whether you need to
do postdocs
before going to work.
Postdocs is a time for relaxation.
If you want to go to the industry,
you can find a new city
or an interesting topic.
That topic is very needed
in the industry now.
It is a good opportunity
to be a jump board.
If not, it's okay.
If you have not done postdocs,
if you can find
a similar job,
it's good.
But in fact,
if you want to apply
what you learned in PhD
to the industry,
for me,
what I learned
in PhD is
soft skills.
How to make a presentation,
how to
do a literature search,
present your idea to others.
I think these soft skills
are more important.
As for
hard skills,
it depends on
whether there are elements
in the topic of PhD.
For example,
you can talk to your friends
in the industry
about which skills
the industry needs.
When the industry is looking for talents,
it depends on your experience
and your skill set.
There are two ways
when the industry is looking for talents.
One is fresh grad.
I take you in and train you again.
It depends on
your experience.
It depends on your luck.
Any other questions?
I'm curious about
a similar question.
When did you
start to want to work in the industry?
Did you do the internship
because you wanted to work in the industry?
Did you decide
to go this way
after the internship?
Or did you decide
to go this way
after the internship?
I'm more interested
in the industry.
First,
I don't like to write papers.
I think
it's a waste of time
to write papers.
I want to do something
that makes me feel
accomplished.
I started to work in the industry
in my third or fourth year.
After I saw
the algorithm,
millions of people
were using it.
I felt accomplished.
Any other questions?
Besides
hiring people in the industry,
are you interested in
starting your own business
or starting a new company?
In Boston,
the start-up culture
is very strong.
I'm a member
of the Yushan Technology Association.
We advocate
start-ups
and resources
to hold events
to add these things.
We have investors
who fund us.
We have entrepreneurs
who have started a business.
We have local
technology scientists.
We have these resources.
We hold events every year
to see if we can create something new.
I have a friend
who is a doctor.
He also started a company
in Taiwan.
He does AI and healthcare.
I might
be interested in
starting a start-up company
after a while.
I might give it a try.
You may not know.
I just asked this question.
Hao Wei
is very active
in Taiwan's industry
and start-up organizations
and clubs.
If you have any questions,
you can contact him
to discuss or collaborate.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
I'm Yiting.
Yanyong asked a lot of questions.
Can I go back
and ask more?
Sure.
He asked
if you need to
be a postdoc.
He also asked
if you want to
become an intern
after completing
a PhD.
He also asked
if you want to
become a postdoc
after completing
a PhD.
I'm curious.
Can you share
your thoughts?
Hi.
This question
is very specific.
It's easy to find a job
in electronics.
But it's not easy
to find a job
in bio.
Most people
can't find a job
after completing
a postdoc.
I think
it's important
to ask people
in the same field
how to use
their skills
in the industry.
Thank you.
Yiting is in Europe, right?
Yes.
I'm in Switzerland.
You're a world-famous person.
Yes.
Today is a special day.
It's not a regular day.
I can participate.
We're usually
in North America.
It's a suitable day for us.
But it's a world-famous day.
Okay.
Mu Jie
said something
interesting.
Let me ask you.
I think Mu Jie
is an expert
who works with young professors.
He works with young professors
at every stage.
He's a young boss now.
Can you share
with us
if you're worried
that it's hard
to find a job
with a young boss
or a boss
who's not
as good as Mu Jie?
Do you have any
suggestions
for young people
who want to work with young bosses?
I think
it's very risky
to work with young bosses.
You don't know
their past records.
You can only check
their past publications.
It's risky.
But
another advantage of young professors
is that
you can be sure
they won't fail.
After all,
they're under pressure.
So you can be sure
they won't fail.
If you meet a young boss
who's not as good as you,
you can
leave
after a few years.
Because
even if
your boss is very influential,
to a certain extent,
if he's
very influential
and helps you
make progress,
to a certain extent,
you'll be influenced by him.
If he's a good boss,
I don't think it's a problem.
If he's not a good boss,
he might help you
find a job.
He might start to tell you
or suggest you
that he helped you
and you should help him.
It's hard to say no.
Another idea
is to
take a risk with them.
It's a high-risk, high-reward.
I had this idea
when I was young.
You work with young professors.
When they become famous,
you're still a student.
When they become influential,
But if you work with an old professor,
who will help you after he's gone?
It's a similar idea.
So I think
young professors
are at risk.
When I was making these choices,
I interviewed
those bosses.
You have to talk to them.
You have to know
what they expect you to do.
I think
it was special at the beginning.
In the Netherlands,
you interview
the boss.
He'll give you
a clear question
about what you should do.
Before I left,
I knew
what kind of personality
my future boss would have
and what kind of question
I should ask.
So I knew
I could start working
right away.
As for POSA,
I thought
I could get along
with them.
So
I decided
to go to POSA.
Another reason
I went to POSA
is that
I didn't want to
wait too long
to get a job there.
So that was
the only offer I had.
I asked
my college classmate
in the US.
I asked him
how to get a job at POSA.
He said young professors
usually have those positions.
Young professors
just got here,
so they must have
a few POSA positions.
So they must have them.
If you go to
well-known labs,
they can't help you.
They might have a POSA position,
but half a year ago,
it was booked.
So you can't find it.
So you have to
beg for a POSA.
So I think
it's not the same.
The most important thing is
to select your boss.
At least talk to him.
Don't just follow him.
Then decide
the next few days.
Another important thing
is if you don't think
it's suitable,
leave early.
Be brave and say no.
Give up earlier
is better than
giving up later.
Because
when you get to
the level of POSA,
at least some people
have families
or a stable partner.
If you're not
in a good mood,
it will affect more people,
not just you.
So that's about it.
Okay.
Did anyone
want to ask a question?
Do you want to apply for a doctorate in the Netherlands?
Yes. Let's expand
this question.
Why did you want to apply?
For example, the Netherlands.
Did you only apply for the Netherlands?
Or did you apply to other European countries?
At that time,
the situation was like this.
The application in the Netherlands was different.
It's not like the United States or Taiwan.
You have to apply at a fixed time every year.
Because every year,
you have to submit something
The doctor in the Netherlands
is very similar to what I just said.
Because it's a very specific topic.
So it's actually the boss's
application plan.
Then he will get a doctorate position.
When he gets this doctorate position,
he will advertise it.
So basically, you can apply all year round.
The point is whether the boss has received the money or not.
So he can apply all year round.
So he has
a lot of free time.
At that time,
I was preparing for the application in the United States.
But it just so happens that
there was a student in our department
who was studying for a doctorate in the Netherlands.
He said that there was a new teacher
in their school and there were several positions.
Then I saw the topic and thought it was quite interesting.
So I made an appointment with the teacher.
This interview was actually before
I sent out the application in the United States.
After the interview,
the boss
was willing to give me a position.
So I didn't apply to the United States at the end.
Oh, you didn't apply at all?
I had everything ready.
I was actually going to send it out.
Because I told him that
I asked him when he would give me a reply.
Then he gave me a time.
Because I told him that if he gave me a reply,
I would go if he was willing to.
Then I would stop all the applications in the United States.
So I was willing to do this at that time.
Just go.
So if you want to apply for a doctorate in Europe,
most of the time
you have to take the initiative to look at
all the teachers' websites
or all the schools'
HR websites.
Then there will be some positions on it.
Yes.
So like this,
because you have a classmate
or a junior who knows this information,
but you just said
most of them will directly post
information like this
talent or real person.
Is it the same as
applying for a doctorate
in the Netherlands?
Or where can you find this information?
At least I'm sure it's on the same platform
in the Netherlands.
Because it's really
like going to a company to find a job.
It's a bit like
going to a company's
website's HR section.
Then it will list all the positions.
So it will list
that it may have a faculty position
or a Ph.D. position.
So it's actually found here.
I forgot to mention that
the reason why I chose the Netherlands
is because when I was in the university,
my teacher
asked me to go to the Netherlands
for a meeting.
So I went there for some exchange activities.
I had a good impression of the Netherlands.
So I decided to go to the Netherlands.
Someone asked
how competitive it was.
Actually, it was very competitive.
Yes, it was really competitive.
Yes, but I think
actually...
I'm sorry.
Actually, finding a faculty position
is...
I think people often have a misunderstanding.
It's like someone is very good
but he didn't get a faculty position.
I think this is very strange.
But actually it's not like that.
The reason is
you have to look at
what kind of person
your target department
is.
For example, in the field of chemistry,
I'm just saying.
It's not that our department is looking for it now.
Let's say our department wants to find
an organic chemistry person.
You apply for a person
who is super good at physics and chemistry.
Basically, his chances are very small.
Yes, the reason is
that we don't have that shortage
in physics and chemistry now.
Because I often find faculty
to satisfy
their expectations
for teaching in the future.
Yes, so I think
don't be too self-absorbed.
Why do you think the person
who applied is worse than me?
Why can he still go?
But it's mainly
because of this reason.
Especially if you are
going to a more advanced school.
Yes, and sometimes
because
the direction you are going
is that there is a young teacher
or there are already a lot of people
doing this direction,
so you can't get into that department.
Yes, so it's often...
So part of the competition
is actually here.
And this is actually
a place you can't control yourself.
So I often say that
sometimes when you are looking for a teacher,
you actually need to ask
your former teacher
about it,
which direction this time
he wants to go.
Yes, so that's probably it.
In fact,
if you want to lose postdoc,
no, sorry, you want to lose the faculty position,
this department
has a very important
future plan for its own research.
But how high do you think the opportunity is
that you can use
what you are good at to break it?
For example, they wanted to find a light school,
but you are, for example,
super strong, so strong that you can
make them rather give up or
re-adjust their future plan.
Or is this basically impossible to happen?
This is definitely possible to happen.
Because if you go to a
research-focused school,
the chance of this happening will be higher.
Yes, but it will become
an extra person
to help you.
Yes, but
another problem is that
in Taiwan, faculty positions
are actually limited.
So if you happen to
meet a faculty today,
there is only one person left.
Then the difficulty will increase a lot.
Because after he hired you,
even if you are very good,
what about the gap in teaching
in the next two years?
So there will be this.
There may also be such a situation.
So like I said,
it's actually very important to find
someone who can help you.
Because they will also know
if there is a way to
argue with the school for some positions.
Because in fact, these can all be discussed.
How good you are actually depends on
how much the department is willing to help you.
Yes, if you are really super strong.
Suppose you are
in Caltech today and
you are an assistant professor
and you are willing to come back to Taiwan.
Then I think the space that will be willing to help you
is already much bigger.
This will definitely be a big news.
But this is just an exaggerated example.
But what I mean is that
the more powerful you are,
the more willing to help you.
So even if you find out
that it is not your own field,
but you will still encourage you to apply.
You just don't have to
do it because you have it or not.
Yes, yes, yes.
OK, now that we have talked about
looking for this job,
this academia job.
In fact, we have arranged
a very good video
prepared by Yuxun.
You can tell us about
his application,
such as Price Postdoc Fellowship
and independent research funding.
They all applied for this
Einstein project.
Otherwise, let's invite Yuxun
to share his video now.
OK, no problem.
Can you see it now?
I just saw it,
but I can't see it now.
Can you see it now?
Yes, yes.
OK,
because of the limited time,
I will directly cut to the point.
OK, so here you can see
the review key points
of the Einstein project.
It includes the applicant's
ambition,
and then your research
topic,
how important it is to society,
what kind of contribution it makes to society,
and how to train the research team.
The Columbus project is basically
the same as the Einstein project.
It just has one more
international cooperation experience
and an important plan
to serve the International Academy of Sciences.
So let's talk about
it one by one.
When you apply for this project,
what kind of preparation
do you need to do?
Hello.
OK, so basically
the above review key points
are a bit confusing, right?
First of all,
the most important thing
is your
first item.
The first item is to ask
the applicant
how important
the project is
and how long
it will last.
So you have to
try to describe
how important
and how long
your project is
in your plan.
Because the plan review
is one of the review opinions
that applicants often encounter.
But the applicant is not an expert
in this area.
So when you write
the background of the study,
you have to focus on
some key points.
For example,
how to get the reviewer
to catch
your point
quickly.
So
I think
there is a very good
way to get
the reviewer to catch
your point
quickly.
You can ask
some friends
who are not in the field
to introduce
the background of
your study.
Because they are not in the field,
they will know
where the blind spot is.
They will tell you
when you apply,
they will tell you
your study is
application type,
orientation type,
or basic research type.
These are the three types.
So when you apply,
if you are
basic research type,
it's basically like this picture.
The person on your right
wants to cross the river to the other side.
For a mathematician,
if you are a smart mathematician,
you basically
shrink the whole two-dimensional plane
into a point.
You fold it over,
and the person can jump over the river.
So this is called theoretical research.
In other words,
it has nothing to do with application.
It is a more basic research.
For example,
if you want to study
in another field,
where the gap is between
basic research and
basic research,
it may not be able to
apply immediately.
What is application type research?
Basically,
what kind of problem do you want to overcome
if you want to cross the river?
How do you build a bridge?
If you build a bridge,
what kind of earthquake
can it withstand?
This is called application type research.
Based on application type
and basic research,
it is basically like this picture.
You feel like there is something
that can be done,
but it is not so practical.
You are not sure
if it is really possible in the future.
But it seems to be able to do it
and seems to be applicable.
This thing is called
orientation type research.
So whether it is orientation type research,
basic research,
or application type research,
you can first explain
the importance of your problem.
For example,
why do people cross the river?
How difficult is it to cross the river?
After crossing the river,
what can you do to help
these people?
If you change to
a practical case,
you have to explain
the relevance of your research
to Taiwan.
What can you do to help Taiwan?
For example,
after solving this problem,
how much can you improve
Taiwan's academic status?
You can write a KPI.
You can find a way
to give a qualitative
or quantitative value
to let the reviewer know
how much help
your research will have
in the future.
In other words,
where is your contribution?
If you are applying type research,
you have to find a way
to write how much value
you can contribute.
What kind of talents
can you cultivate in your plan?
What kind of help
can these talents
bring to Taiwan's industry
or Taiwan's academics?
So try to use
some slogans
in your plan.
Don't write too much.
You have to be specific
about what you want to do.
This is more acceptable
to the reviewer.
I applied for the Einstein Project
twice.
The first time,
I didn't write too much.
The second time,
The third time,
I didn't write too much.
The fourth time,
I just wrote down
what kind of talent
I want to cultivate
and what kind of value
I can contribute.
I just wrote down
what kind of talent
I want to cultivate
and what kind of value
I can contribute.
I just wrote down
what kind of talent
I want to cultivate
and what kind of value
I can contribute.
So tell me
what kind of talent
you want to cultivate
and what kind of value
I can contribute.
So tell me
what kind of talent
you want to cultivate
and what kind of value
I can contribute.
Your plan will reflect
your ambition and vision.
So it's important to create a vision.
In this picture,
I just showed you
what I said in my self-introduction.
Let me say it again.
The so-called vision is very important.
What kind of dream
do you want to achieve
through this plan?
For example, you are a doctor.
You want to cure cancer
and save all humans.
It sounds very ambitious.
But in fact, this plan
hopes that you have
such an ambition.
It also hopes that you can
challenge what others can't.
So don't think
what you wrote
is unlikely to happen.
As long as you think
your idea is good
and helpful to humans,
and you are confident
that you can make it happen,
you should write this plan.
Why did I say that?
It's because
when my sister applied
for a college in the U.S.,
she thought
she wasn't good enough
to apply for a good school.
So she asked
her school's consultant.
The consultant told her
whether she was good enough
wasn't up to her.
It's the job of the consultant.
So she encouraged her sister
to apply for a good school.
Don't give up
because you think you can't do it.
I want to tell you
don't give up
because you think
your plan is not good enough.
It's up to the consultant
to decide
whether you are good enough
or not.
Don't give up any chance.
Let's go back to
the application process
and the past performance.
Now,
I'm going to talk about
the past research performance.
The past research performance
is about
what papers
you submitted
in the past research.
Of course, this is a superficial idea.
You need to look at
your research
in the past research.
Why is your research important?
So,
I'm going to echo
what I just said.
Your past research
gave the
reviewer
a direction.
Through your past research performance,
you got some credits.
These credits
make the reviewer believe
you can do it in the future.
So,
when you are writing a research plan,
you need to
have a background
to explain
your experience
in solving
this problem.
What international teams
did you work with
in the past research?
What important journals
did you publish
in the past research?
How many credits
did you get in the past research?
What honors
did you get
in the past research?
How hard is it to get these honors?
You need to explain
to the reviewer.
Sometimes,
you may think
these honors are important
in your field,
but the reviewer
may not know.
For example,
he may not know
what is the
Wu Moqing Prize.
It is just a
certificate of excellence.
The name of the
sponsor is
Wu Moqing.
So, when you
describe your honors,
you need to explain
how hard it is
to get these honors.
The people who
get these honors
are from
world-renowned academic institutions.
For example,
I got a
Zuckerman Fellowship
in my postdoc.
The people who get
this fellowship
are from
MIT, Harvard,
or Stanford.
So, when I write
these honors,
the reviewer
will know
that I was
trustworthy.
In other words,
I did not
lie.
When you say
you want to do
something great,
why do people
believe you?
Because you did
something great.
The third part
is the
Global Cooperation Experience
and the Future Plans
of the International
Academy,
Professional Society,
and Important Jobs.
Sorry,
my PowerPoint
is a bit messy.
Let's continue.
Global Cooperation Experience
and the Future Plans
of the International Academy
is a part of the Columbus Project,
but I recommend
people applying for
the Einstein Project
to refer to it.
When you are
writing a project,
you need to
write a research background.
You can emphasize
which teams
you worked with
in the field.
It is important
to know what problems
you have solved together.
You need to
make a name for yourself.
If you get
the project,
will you
continue
to work with
international scholars?
For example,
will you invite
international scholars
to give a speech
or a workshop
in Taiwan?
Will you
bring international
research and development
to Taiwan?
This is important
when you are
writing a project.
If you get
the approval of
these scholars,
you can include
your name, email,
or even your signature
in your project.
This will increase
the credibility of
your project.
Your reviewer
will be able to
trust you
when they see
the teams
you worked with
in the past.
Next is
the future plan
for international scholars
or professional organizations.
You can write
your experience
as an SCI
or SSCI editor,
organizer,
host,
or agent.
For example,
I have a friend
who worked
as a conference
host
in Taiwan.
He wrote
his experience
and was
recognized by
the reviewer.
If you have
held a similar
conference,
don't be shy
and try to
write your experience
as an SCI
or SSCI editor.
For example,
how many articles
you have reviewed,
how many meetings
you have held,
how many cooperation
plans you have created,
or even
whether you are
able to lead
cross-domain
or cross-team
in the past.
Here,
Columbus
asks you
your future plan
for relevant positions.
So,
you have to
explain
how to use
your past experience
as an editor,
reviewer,
or SCI
to improve
Taiwan's academic ability.
As we all know,
being an academic editor
or
being
an
academic leader
has a very
important role
in improving
Taiwan's academic status.
For example,
you can recommend
foreign scholars
to do research
in Taiwan.
So,
being an academic leader
is very important.
So,
when you write your plan,
you can try to
figure out
how to become
an academic leader
and how to
achieve this goal.
Next,
Columbus asks you
your future plan
for relevant positions.
So,
you have to
explain
your past experience
as an editor,
reviewer,
or SCI to improve
Taiwan's academic ability.
As we all know,
being an academic leader
has a very important role
in improving
Taiwan's academic status.
So,
you have to
explain your past experience
as an editor,
reviewer,
or SCI to improve
Taiwan's academic ability.
Next,
Columbus asks you
your future plan
for relevant positions.
So,
you have to
explain your past experience
as an editor,
reviewer,
or SCI to improve
Taiwan's academic ability.
So,
you have to
explain your past experience
as an editor,
reviewer,
or SCI to improve
Taiwan's academic ability.
So,
you don't have to
explain your past experience
as an editor,
reviewer,
or SCI to improve
Taiwan's academic ability.
So,
you don't have to
explain your past experience
as an editor,
reviewer,
or SCI to improve
Taiwan's academic ability.
So,
not only can I
lead Taiwan's students
to research,
I can also
work with students
from different countries,
different religious backgrounds,
and even different skin colors.
So,
what kind of research
did these people do
under your leadership?
You can talk about
all of these.
Another part is that
if you have a lecture,
don't be shy.
You can just bring it up
and let SCI know.
Why?
Because the foundation of
research teams and training
is very important.
How do you teach?
How do you mentor?
If you have a TA award,
you can talk about
what kind of problems
you encountered in the course of teaching,
what changes you made,
and how your team
worked well.
Also,
you can talk about
your research results.
So,
I hope you can
talk about
your past experiences
so that SCI
can clearly understand
that you have the ability
to build and train your team.
Yuxu,
hold on.
We have 10 minutes left.
This segment is a bit long.
Let's stop here.
If you have
any additional questions,
you can email me.
I can answer
your questions individually.
Yuxu's email
is here.
You can copy it.
If you want to copy it,
I can listen to it.
You can write your email
or if you have
any questions, you can chat.
If we have time,
we can come back and continue.
We have one more question.
I believe
everyone cares about
whether our speakers
have experience in
other countries or
Europe or
Israel.
What do they think
about the cultural differences
between Taiwan and
other places
in terms of
industry and
industry energy?
How do they decide
to return to Taiwan
or stay abroad?
Or how do they see
the future development?
Let's start with Hao Wei.
Okay, no problem.
I think
your question is
about the difference
between Taiwan and
the United States
in terms of
industry and
industry energy.
Hello?
Can you hear me?
If you can hear me,
you can continue.
I'm just repeating your question.
Okay.
I think
as a Taiwanese,
we always think
even if I stay here
for 10 years,
I still think
I might return to Taiwan one day.
I think Taiwan's energy
is quite strong
when it comes to
industry and industry energy.
So I actually thought
I might return to Taiwan one day.
But the biggest difference
is probably
the capital
and the
idea of
starting a business
is quite different.
So the size of the company
and the idea of investors
are quite different.
So the capital
and the business talent
are probably more professional
when it comes to the company's valuation.
On the other hand,
in terms of business,
Boston's energy
is really strong.
It's one of the best places in the world.
So
it takes a lot of capital
to do the research.
So it's just starting in Taiwan.
So we have a lot of BTBA
friends who will return to Taiwan
to help
build these things.
So I hope one day
we can really build up
Taiwan's biotechnology
or medical technology.
I think even though we're still in the US,
we can still help a lot
with these links.
Yeah, that's it.
I have a question.
Sorry.
Let me adjust my network.
Why is it like this?
Sorry.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
My question is
about
wanting to return to Taiwan.
Do you have any experience
or have you heard
whether Taiwan's current industry
or the government
has any
willingness to cooperate
or any plans
for Taiwan?
What are their motives?
I think
after Minister Chen Liangji took office,
he proposed a lot of
plans
for returning to Taiwan.
So he can
let you find a job for a year
and then you can find
the job you really want to do.
He has provided some plans
to make it more smooth.
So I think it's not bad.
OK.
But when it comes to
job opportunities,
it really depends
on the industry.
The prices in the US are higher,
so you usually get paid when you go back.
But this is expected.
Yeah.
OK.
So do you think,
at least as you mentioned,
the government
has expressed its willingness
and actually has plans
to help you
return to Taiwan
or get a job in Taiwan?
Yes.
It's called LIFT.
Oh, OK. LIFT.
You can check it out.
I've heard of it before.
I'm not familiar with it,
but I'm sure you can find it on the Internet.
Can we ask Mu-Jie
about your experience in Europe
and in the US
since you've just been here for a year?
What do you think is the difference?
What do you think is the difference
between good and bad
and what do you think?
I think
in the US
or other places other than Taiwan,
I think everyone knows
that the salary is higher.
In the US,
you have the smartest people
in the world.
Most of the outstanding students
are in the US.
I don't think
we need to emphasize the benefits.
But I think
now,
especially in the academic world,
if you're willing to come back
at this time,
I think it's a good opportunity.
The reason is that the current minister
and the overall social atmosphere
probably all know
that fewer and fewer people
are willing to come back.
I'm not just talking about
the Colombo-Einstein project.
It's not that everyone can get it.
But regardless of
your general plan,
in fact,
there are quite a few
increases in salary and annual income.
But in my own field,
in the past,
you might have a one-year or two-year plan.
But now, the meaning of the minister
is to give people
three or even four years.
The amount of salary
will be higher than before.
In addition,
the current social atmosphere
has been saying that
the salary of professors in Taiwan
is very low.
Now,
all professors in Taiwan
still have the same standard
of paying salary.
But each school
actually has
a lot of different
basic salary plans.
So I think
at least in the early stages,
you don't have to worry
too much about money.
Whether it's research money
or your salary money,
you don't have to worry too much.
Of course, in terms of absolute numbers,
it's impossible to compare
with the U.S. or other countries
because the prices are different.
So I don't think
you need to worry about this.
When I came back before,
or other young professors
told me that
Taiwan's current atmosphere
is more and more like
as long as you do well,
you don't have to worry
about your salary
or your research money.
There must be
a lot of different
flexible salary plans.
For example,
I know someone
who is a professor in Taiwan.
If you really do well,
there are a lot of different bonuses.
There are some additional bonuses.
After you get the bonuses,
technology will match
your research money.
There are
other professors
who told me that
the advantage of Taiwan,
especially in the academic world,
is that you have a high chance
to pass your plan.
But at least
you can do
what you want to do.
Of course, if you say
you need 30 million or more devices
to do an experiment,
that's another story.
But in general,
I saw Zhang Yanyong shaking his head.
In general,
there should be no problem.
I and Ye Yong
are shaking our heads.
I didn't see the other one.
I think this is the current
atmosphere in Taiwan.
I think
I wanted to come back
for a part of the reason.
I don't know if you know
Chen Yunlong,
who often appears on TV.
The reason is very similar.
I like living in Taiwan.
I like living in Taiwan,
so I'm willing to come back.
At that time, I thought
if I stayed in the United States,
I would only go to the industry.
If I really want to be a teacher,
I will think I want to go back to Taiwan.
Because I think
if I want to teach the next generation,
I will want to teach
people on my own land.
I don't know if you have seen it.
Yuan Jian also reported that
Chen Yunlong's mother
said that
if he didn't come back,
his mother would tell him that
she could only see him
in Taiwan.
I know when you are young,
you think it's good to travel abroad.
But I have discussed with
some people around me.
Many people think
if I stay in the U.S. or abroad
for 10 or 15 years,
I still want to come back.
It depends on
whether you are willing to
take these 10 or 15 years
to spend time with your family
and friends
or if you are willing to
find a job in the U.S.
or other countries.
Whether it's economic or
other aspects,
it's a better return.
I don't think this is wrong.
It's just that everyone's
views are different.
Overall, I think that
Taiwan's support for young teachers
is quite high.
This also involves another thing.
If you are really willing to
travel abroad,
you may want to
inquire about the atmosphere
of each school.
The atmosphere of
different schools
may be different.
You may want to
inquire about
the support for young people.
I am quite lucky that
our school is quite good.
Some places may be worse.
You may want to
find a job in the U.S.
or other countries.
It's a good return.
It's a good time.
Actually,
we are running out of time.
I think we have covered
a lot of interesting points today.
Of course,
everyone still has a lot of questions.
Otherwise,
can we ask the three speakers
to summarize in two or three minutes
what they think about
changing the job of
PhD students and post-doctorate students?
In the process of summarizing,
everyone can think about
if there are any questions.
You can type them in the chat.
At the end,
we will have a short Q&A.
Let's start with Yuxun.
I think
the global population is expanding.
There are 7 billion people now.
Even if it is a school,
it is difficult to promote.
Although I am
a survivor,
it is not very convincing.
But what I want to say is
don't be too persistent
and have to go a certain way.
Let yourself stay flexible.
When I was studying
for a master's degree,
I spent a lot of time
studying stock trading.
So I thought about
if I want to do research,
whether I do research or not,
I need money.
If I do research,
it is difficult to make a fortune.
So if I invest in finance,
I can maintain my basic living expenses.
It feels good, right?
In addition to studying finance,
I also attend
some
lectures
on communication skills.
To sum up,
don't go too far
and try to
stay flexible.
As I said at the beginning,
do what you want to do,
but do it in the right way.
Go in the direction you want to go.
But don't set the direction
too narrow.
Make it a wider direction.
Don't make
precise mistakes
even if it is wrong.
This is what I want to
share with you today.
Don't ask me
what I want.
I have invested in stocks for so many years.
Hello?
Can you hear me?
I can hear you now.
Can you
summarize
your thoughts?
Okay, no problem.
I think
it is good
that everyone is willing to
participate in this event.
I think the most important part
of NPS is networking.
You need to get to know more people
and know what everyone is doing.
After graduation,
these networks will continue to grow.
For a long time,
like what they said,
Ph.D. is looking for the next job.
70% of them are introduced by people they know.
So,
networking is really important.
I hope everyone can
get to know more people
and know more about what this world is doing
in the life of a postdoc or PhD.
Of course,
the academic world is really competitive.
According to statistics,
those who can become
a professor
are the top 10%.
Many people will eventually
enter the industry,
but there are still many opportunities
for you to develop
and do what you want to do.
So, I hope everyone can explore more.
And there are many
top things
that you can do.
This is really cool.
Thank you, Hao Wei.
Mu Jie, please summarize.
No problem.
I don't think what Hao Wei said is right.
I don't think
the top 10%
come to the academic world.
I think a big part
is that everyone's career path
is different.
Many people who are better than me
eventually choose to go to the industry.
Then I can find
something to live for.
Actually, I think
my point of view is very similar
to what Yuxin said.
I think
you have to choose
what you really want to do.
No matter
if you choose a research topic
or whether you want to go to the industry or the classroom.
I think this is a very important thing.
Especially when you can still choose,
it's actually a very happy thing.
So when you can choose,
try to choose what you think you're interested in.
Because I think what you're interested in
is what you're willing to spend time and effort
to do it well.
Because when you're a professor,
it's actually quite tiring.
Because there are a lot of mixed things.
But when you like to do this,
you can really do it well.
I also think what Yuxin said
is very good.
Don't worry about
giving yourself
the courage
to correct your direction.
Correcting earlier
is always better than correcting later.
Don't feel like
I have to be a professor.
In the end, you really can't be a professor.
Or no matter what the reason is,
you decide not to be a professor.
Don't be afraid of what others will think.
Because no one will be responsible for your life.
Only you have to be responsible for your own life.
So I think the most important thing
is actually this.
Thank you.
I think the three speakers
talked very well today.
Please turn on the microphone now
so that the speakers can hear our applause.
Please give a round of applause
to thank the three speakers
for sharing with us today.
Thank you.
Because our time today
is a bit short,
but I guess there are still people who want to discuss,
so I will turn off the recording first.